import{_ as d,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as y,U as c,F as w,p,e as f,f as j,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},T={class:"review-title"},S={class:"review-content"};function N(e,a,u,g,t,r){return i(),o("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",T,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(u.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",S,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(u.poem.answer),1)])])])}const x=d(q,[["render",N],["__scopeId","data-v-3772a032"]]),I=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 新型コロナウイルスのワクチンに使っている技術の研究をした2人が、ノーベル賞の生理学・医学賞に決まりました。アメリカのペンシルベニア大学のカタリン・カリコさんとドリュー・ワイスマンさんです。2人は、遺伝物質のmRNAをワクチンに使うための研究をしました。mRNAは、人の体に入れると炎症を起こすことが問題でした。カリコさんたちは2005年に、炎症を小さくする方法を発表しました。新型コロナウイルスのワクチンは、薬を作る会社がこの技術を使ったため、とても早くできました。ワイスマンさんは「研究のお金をもらえなくなった時がありましたが、諦めないで研究を続けたので、今があると思います」と話しました。カリコさんは「私たちは賞のために仕事をしているのではありません。大切なのは、人の役に立つものを作ることです」と話しました。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。- ワクチン: 1）感染症のもとになるばい菌などから作った薬。これを接種して、その感染症にかからないようにする。- ノーベル賞: 1）学問や世界の平和のためにつくす立派な仕事をした人に、毎年与えられる賞。化学者ノーベルの遺言で、この制度ができた。- 賞: 1）ほめる。たたえる。2）ほうび。3）味わって楽しむ。- 遺伝: 1）親の特徴や性質が、子や、そのあとの子孫に伝わること。- 物質: 1）見たりさわったりすることができるもの。- 炎症: 1）体の一部が熱をもって赤くはれたり、痛んだりすること。- 起こす: 1）（横になっていたものを）立たせる。2）目を覚まさせる。3）（何かを）始める。4）生じさせる。5）ほりかえす。- 方法: 1）ものごとを行うやり方。しかた。- 発表: 1）多くの人に広く知らせること。- 諦め: 1）もうだめだと思って、やめる。"},{"question":"Lengkapi ukara ing ngisor iki:Maryam nganggo topi ing ...A. SikilB. TanganC. SirahJawaban:","answer":"Jawaban: C. Sirah"},{"question":"Crie uma pergunta sobre o jogador de futebol Ronaldo.","answer":"Em que países Ronaldo jogou durante sua carreira?"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe kintana?","answer":"Ny kintana dia bola plasma (etona mafana be) izay voatazon'ny hery mampifanintona mba tsy hiparitaka. Manjelatra izy noho ny fiota niokleary ao anatiny. Hazavana sady hafanana no avoakany, miaraka amin'ny tana hafa izay tsy hitan'ny maso toy ny tana radio, tana X ary tana gamma toy ny tana ankoatry ny volomparasy (UV). Samihafa ny anjaran'ireo tana isan-karazany ireo arakaraka ny haben'ny kintana."},{"question":"\\"Aktiviti Patriotik\\" merupakan contoh amalan perpaduan. Yang manakah antara berikut bukan dikategorikan sebagai aktiviti patriotik?","answer":"Membuat pertandingan lumba haram bagi meraikan Hari Kemerdekaan"},{"question":"Dönel kavşak ne demek tdk?","answer":"Dönel kavşak ya da halk arasındaki adı ile göbek, Kıbrıs'ta yaygın olarak çember, araç trafiğinin dairesel biçimde hareket ederek çeşitli istikametlere dağılmasına imkân veren kavşak türü."},{"question":"iza ny anaran’I nenifara?","answer":"ny anaran’I nenifara dia mamisoa"},{"question":"Voltooi de zin: Stalin was vastbesloten de bevrijding van bezet gebied voort te zetten, een plan dat zijn eerste grote succes had aan het eind van 1942 met","answer":"Operatie Uranus, wat leidde tot de bevrijding van Stalingrad. De Slag bij de Djnepr was bedoeld om de bevrijding van de Sovjetrepubliek Oekraïne te bereiken en het zuidelijk deel van het front naar het westen te bewegen. Met het oog op het verder verzwakken van de Duitse verdediging werd de Slag bij Smolensk tegelijk ingezet waarmee Duitse reserves naar het noorden werden getrokken. Beide operaties waren onderdeel van hetzelfde strategische aanvalsplan om zoveel mogelijk Sovjetgebied uit handen van Duitse controle te halen."},{"question":"西门庆的死因是什么？","answer":"西门庆的死因在两部小说中有所不同。在《水浒传》中，西门庆是被武松杀死的。在《金瓶梅》中，西门庆是因纵欲过度而死的。"},{"question":"താഴെ പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക: ഞാന് സ്വപ്നം കാണുന്നു... പക്ഷെ ഇപ്രാവശ്യം എന്റെ സ്വപ്നം തകർന്ന്‌ പോകുന്നില്ല. ഞാന് ഒരു വലിയ മുറിയില് പ്രവേശിക്കുന്നു, അതിലെ മതിലുകള് അലമാരകളുള്ള അലമാരകളുള്ള അലമാരകളാണ്:","answer":"ഷെൽഫുകൾ"},{"question":"அரச இலையில் தீபம் ஏற்றி வழிபாடு செய்வதால் என்ன பலன்கள்?","answer":"அரச மர இலையில், மண் அகல் வைத்து, தீபம் ஏற்றும் பட்சத்தில் நாம் செய்த பூர்வ ஜென்ம பாவம், நம் ஜாதகத்தில் இருக்கக் கூடிய சனி தோஷம், ராகு கேது தோஷம், நவக்கிரக தோஷம், சர்ப்ப தோஷம், அனைத்தும் தீரும் என்று சொல்லப்பட்டுள்ளது. அரசமரத்தின் வேர் பகுதியில், பிரம்மாவும், நடுப்பகுதியில் திருமாலும், மேல்பகுதியில் ஈசனும் வாசம் செய்வதாக புராணங்களில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது. இதனாலேயே இந்த மரத்திற்கு ‘ராஜ விருட்சம்’ என்ற மற்றொரு பெயரும் உண்டு. இதோடு மட்டுமல்லாமல் அறிவியல் ரீதியாக அரச மரத்தை வலம் வந்தால்  குழந்தை பேறு கிடைக்கும் என்பது நிரூபிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.  அரசமர காற்றை சுவாசிக்கும் போது, கருப்பை பிரச்சனைகள் குணமாகும். திங்கட் கிழமையில் பிறந்தவர்கள் மூன்று அரச இலைகளை வைத்து, அதன்மேல் மூன்று அகல்  தீபங்கள் ஏற்ற வேண்டும். செவ்வாய்க் கிழமைகளில் பிறந்தவர்கள் இரண்டு அரச இலைகளை வைத்து, இரண்டு மண் அகல் தீபங்கள் ஏற்ற வேண்டும்.  புதன்கிழமை பிறந்தவர்கள் மூன்று அரச இலைகளை வைத்து, மூன்று மண் அகல் தீபங்கள் ஏற்றவேண்டும். வியாழக் கிழமை பிறந்தவர்கள் ஐந்து அரச இலைகளை வைத்து, ஐந்து  மண் அகல் தீபம் ஏற்ற வேண்டும். வெள்ளிக் கிழமை பிறந்தவர்கள் ஆறு அரச இலைகளை வைத்து, ஆறு மண் அகல் தீபங்கள் ஏற்ற வேண்டும்."},{"question":"မြန်မာလား၊ ဗမာလား။","answer":"ဗမာပြည်ကို ဗမာလူမျိုးအစဉ်အဆက်ကတည်းက ဗမာပြည်ဟု ခေါ်တွင်ခဲ့သည်။ သို့သော် စစ်အစိုးရက ဒီမိုကရေစီအရေးတော်ပုံကြီးကို ရက်ရက်စက်စက် ဖြိုခွင်းပြီး တစ်နှစ်အကြာ ၁၉၈၉ ခုနှစ်တွင် စစ်ခေါင်းဆောင်များက ၎င်း၏အမည်ကို မြန်မာဟု ရုတ်တရက် ပြောင်းလဲခဲ့သည်။ထိုအချိန်တွင် မြန်မာနိုင်ငံသည် နိုင်ငံတကာ၏အပယ်ခံဖြစ်ခဲ့ပြီး ၎င်း၏ပုံရိပ်ကို မြှင့်တင်ရန် မည်သည့်နည်းလမ်းကိုမဆို လိုလားတောင့်တခဲ့သည်။ နိုင်ငံတကာတရားဝင်မှု၏ အရိပ်အယောင်ကို ရရှိနိုင်ရန် ကိုလိုနီခေတ်က လက်ဆင့်ကမ်းခဲ့သော နာမည်ကို စွန့်လွှတ်ပြီး တိုင်းရင်းသားစည်းလုံးညီညွတ်မှုကို မြှင့်တင်ဖို့ ပြောင်းခဲ့တာဖြစ်တယ်လို့ ဆိုပါတယ်။ အဆိုပါ အမည်ဟောင်းသည် နိုင်ငံ၏ တိုင်းရင်းသား လူနည်းစု အများအပြားကို ချန်လှပ်ထားသည်ဟု တာဝန်ရှိသူများက ဆိုသည်။"},{"question":"Мындай үлгү берилди: ажырашуу : достошууУшуну карап туруп, төмөнкү варианттардын кайсынысы туура келээрин аныктап бер:(А) баруу : келүү(Б) жолгушуу : көрүшүү(В) бөлүнүү : жоготуу(Г) унутуу : эстөө","answer":"Үлгүдө берилген \\"ажырашуу\\" жана \\"достошуу\\" деген сөздөр бири-бирине карата толук антонимдер. Үлгүдөгү сөздөрдөй болуп толук антоним байланышта жана биринчи сөзү терс маани, экинчиси оң мааниде болгон варианттарды караштырабыз. Мындай айкалышта болгон бир гана вариант \\"(Г) унутуу : эстөө\\" болуп жатат. Ошентип, туура жооп төмөнкү болду: (Г) унутуу : эстөө"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي يجب قراءتها في كل ركعة في الصلاة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفاتحة"},{"question":"पाटनमा रहेको कृष्ण मन्दिरको निर्माणमा रहेको वास्तुकला प्रतीकको व्याख्या गर्दै यसको सांस्कृतिक तथा धार्मिक महत्वलाई बुझाउनुहोस् ।","answer":"पाटनमा रहेको कृष्ण मन्दिर जटिल प्रतीक रहित वास्तुकलाको चमत्कार हो । यस्ले हिन्दू पौराणिक कथा र संस्कृतिका विभिन्न पक्षहरूको प्रतिनिधि गर्दछ । यो मध्यकालीन नेपालको कलात्मक उपलब्धिहरूको प्रमाण रहेको छ ।"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phù hợp với nội dung: Sáu tác phẩm sơn mài của các họa sĩ Việt được đưa ra đấu giá trong phiên \\"Khám phá hiện đại: Cuộc gặp gỡ\\" của Sotheby's Hong Kong, diễn ra theo hình thức trực tuyến từ ngày 22 đến 29/7. Trong đó, bức Quang cảnh vùng trung du Việt Nam, đề tên Cao đẳng Mỹ thuật Đông Dương bán với mức cao nhất - 1,5 triệu HKD (4,5 tỷ đồng). Sơn mài gồm sáu tấm, mô tả phong cảnh làng quê Việt. Lấy con thuyền trên sông làm chủ đạo, xung quanh là những cây cối đặc trưng của Việt Nam như tre, chuối. Phía xa là những ngôi nhà trên mặt nước và đồi núi. Hình ảnh những cô thôn nữ dưới tán cây làm tăng vẻ nhẹ nhàng, nên thơ của cảnh vật. Theo nhà đấu giá, tranh là thành quả của các nghệ sĩ, sinh viên Cao đẳng Mỹ thuật Đông Dương (MBAI), dưới sự hướng của Nguyễn Gia Trí và Phạm Hậu. Chữ ký MBAI ở mặt sau khẳng định đây là tác phẩm của một tập thể. Tranh thể hiện sự hoàn hảo về tính thẩm mỹ và chủ đề được ưa chuộng trong sơn mài. Trong cuốn Cartographic Mapping Institute năm 1993, họa sĩ Trương Hạnh viết: \\"Mảng màu tối như bóng tối vào ban đêm, nhưng cũng sống động như màu của chiếc lá vàng dưới ánh mặt trời. Mảng màu vàng như bay lên tạo cho bức tranh sự cân bằng và thống nhất. Người ta có cảm giác như chạm vào nhung, satin, sứ và đá quý...\\". Bức sơn mài Cá của họa sĩ Nguyễn Khang được bán giá 1,26 triệu HKD (3,7 tỷ đồng), Mùa gặt của Phạm Hậu đạt mức 567.000 HKD (1,7 tỷ đồng). Ngoài ra, tác phẩm của Trần Phúc Duyên, Đinh Văn Dần... cũng bán với giá cao. Những tác phẩm sơn mài trong phiên đấu giá Cao đẳng Mỹ thuật Đông Dương được xem là cái nôi của nghệ thuật sơn mài Việt Nam, theo Sotheby's. Sơn mài xuất hiện tại Việt Nam từ thế kỷ thứ ba trước Công nguyên qua các việc sử dụng mủ cây sơn ta để làm thuyền, các vật dụng sơn son thếp vàng trong hoàng cung... Tuy nhiên, việc đưa sơn ta vào hội họa chuyên nghiệp thực sự bắt đầu qua khóa học của họa sĩ người Pháp Joseph Inguimberty tại Cao đẳng Mỹ thuật Đông Dương. Theo cuốn Các họa sĩ Cao đẳng Mỹ thuật Đông Dương, trong một buổi đi vẽ tại Văn Miếu Quốc Tử Giám, Joseph Inguimberty sửng sốt trước các bức hoành phi, câu đối, đồ thờ được sơn son thếp vàng lâu đời, với các gam màu phong phú tại đây. Ông đề xuất với hiệu trưởng Victor Tardieu đưa sơn ta vào chương trình nghiên cứu và học tập. Sau đó, trường mở xưởng kỹ thuật nghiên cứu sơn ta, đặt cơ sở hoàn thiện kỹ thuật và phát triển của tranh sơn mài. Đến năm 1938, sơn mài trở thành ngành giảng dạy chính. Trong tiểu luận Nền hội họa Pháp và ảnh hưởng tại Đông Dương, học giả người Pháp Claude Mahoudot viết: \\"Joseph Inguimberty thực sự đã tạo ra một phong trào hội họa và đưa sơn ta vào phục vụ họa sĩ. Chất sơn sau này có vị trí rất lớn trong lịch sử nghệ thuật Đông Dương\\". Những năm 1930-1940 được coi là thời kỳ hoàng kim của sơn mài Việt Nam với nhiều tên tuổi nổi tiếng như Phạm Hậu, Nguyễn Gia Trí, Nguyễn Văn Trung, Nguyễn Khang, Hoàng Tích Chù... Các họa sĩ liên tiếp cải tiến về kỹ thuật, màu sắc, tạo nên đặc trưng riêng biệt. Tác phẩm sơn mài Vườn xuân Trung Nam Bắc, Bình Phong của Nguyễn Gia Trí được công nhận là bảo vật quốc gia. Trong khi đó, Phạm Hậu có bốn bức sơn mài đạt mốc triệu USD, trong đó có tác phẩm Hoàng hôn vàng trên vịnh Hạ Long - từng thuộc bộ sưu tập của vua Bảo Đại - bán giá 1,24 triệu USD hồi cuối năm 2021. Hiểu Nhân","answer":"Tiêu đề: Tranh sơn mài phong cảnh Việt thời Đông Dương"},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut. Bilakah musim baru Are you the one dikeluarkan?","answer":"Tahun 2018"},{"question":"Kitap bağışı nasıl yapılıyor?","answer":"Bir koliye kitaplarınızı doldurup ağzını kapatmadan PTT Kargo ofisine (postahane değil) götürüyorsunuz, kontrol ediliyor. Kitap ayraçları ve kitap dışı şeyler kabul edilmiyor. Sonra koli bantlanarak tartılıyor, ölçülüyor ve ücretini ödüyorsunuz. 1-2 güne teslim ediliyor birçok yere."},{"question":"من اسماء الله الحسنى الآخر فما معناه؟","answer":"معنى الآخر : أي دائم البقاء، لا نهاية لوجوده"},{"question":"के तपाइँ खुम्बु क्षेत्रमा टेङ्बोचे मठ लगायतका जीवन्त गुम्बाहरूका लागि परिचित ट्रेकिङ गन्तव्य सिफारिस गर्न सक्नुहुन्छ?","answer":"खुम्बु क्षेत्रको सगरमाथा गुम्बा पदयात्रा यसका जीवन्त मठहरूका लागि परिचित छ, जसमा प्रतिष्ठित टेङ्बोचे गुम्बा पनि समावेश छ, जसले ट्रेकहरूलाई सांस्कृतिक अन्तरदृष्टि र आश्चर्यजनक दृश्यहरू प्रदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn ni àkókò yii?","answer":"Ògbéni Dapo Abiodun ni."},{"question":"لقب بأبو الأنبياء؟","answer":"الإجابة: هو سيدنا إبراهيم عليه السلام."},{"question":"Mene ne Wakilin Sunan Mallaka?","answer":"Wakilin suna ne da ya ke nuna mallaka. Sannan ya kasu gida biyu:Masu zaman kansu. Waɗannan wakilan suna suna ɗaukar jinsi. Namiji: nawa, naka, naku, nasu, naki, nata, namu. Mace: tawa, taka, taku, tasu, taki da kuma tata. Waɗannan a duk lokacin da ake rubutu, ba a haɗe su. Misali, wannan gidan nawa ne, da kuma waccar motar, tawa ce.Marasa zaman kansu. Maza na, nmu, nki, nta, nsu, nka da kuma nsa. Mace ta, rta, rmu, rki, rta, rsu, rsa, da kuma rka. Su kuma ba a raba su da suna, haɗe su ake yi a rubutu. Misali gidana, gidanku. Rigata, rigarku, da sauransu."},{"question":"ભારતીય સંસ્કૃતિમા કલા નો ઇતિહાસ જણાવો.","answer":"કલા શબ્દનો પ્રયોગ કદાચ સૌથી પહેલાં ભરતના \\"નાટ્યશાસ્ત્ર\\"માં જ થયો હોય એમ મળી આવે છે. પછીથી વાત્સ્યાયન અને ઉશનસ જેવા ઋષિઓએ ક્રમશ: પોતાના ગ્રંથ \\"કામસૂત્ર\\" તેમ જ \\"શુક્રનીતિ\\"માં કલાનું વર્ણન કર્યું હતું.\\"કામસૂત્ર\\", \\"શુક્રનીતિ\\", જૈન ગ્રંથ \\"પ્રબંધકોશ\\", \\"કલાવિલાસ\\", \\"લલિતવિસ્તર\\" ઇત્યાદિ બધા ભારતીય ગ્રંથોમાં કલાનું વર્ણન પ્રાપ્ત થાય છે. અધિકતર ગ્રંથોમાં કલાઓની સંખ્યા ૬૪ જેટલી છે એવું માનવામાં આવેલું છે. \\"પ્રબંધકોશ\\" ઇત્યાદિમાં ૭૨ કલાઓની સૂચી મળી આવે છે. \\"લલિતવિસ્તર\\"માં ૮૬ કલાઓનાં નામ ગણાવવામાં આવેલાં છે. પ્રસિદ્ધ કાશ્મીરી પંડિત ક્ષેમેંદ્રે પોતાના ગ્રંથ \\"કલાવિલાસ\\"માં સૌથી અધિક સંખ્યામાં કલાઓનું વર્ણન કર્યું છે. એમાં ૬૪ જનોપયોગી, ૩૨ ધર્મ, અર્થ, કામ, મોક્ષ, સંબંધી, ૩૨ માત્સર્ય-શીલ-પ્રભાવમાન સંબંધી, ૬૪ સ્વચ્છકારિતા સંબંધી, ૬૪ વેશ્યાઓ સંબંધી, ૧૦ ભેષજ, ૧૬ કાયસ્થ તથા ૧૦૦ સાર કલાઓની ચર્ચા છે. સૌથી અધિક પ્રમાણિક સૂચી \\"કામસૂત્ર\\"માં આપવામાં આવેલી છે.યુરોપીય સાહિત્યમાં પણ કલા શબ્દનો પ્રયોગ શારીરિક કે માનસિક કૌશલ માટે જ અધિકતર થયેલો જોવા મળે છે. ત્યાં આગળ પ્રકૃતિ અને કલાનું કાર્ય ભિન્ન છે એવું માનવામાં આવે છે. કલાનો અર્થ છે રચના કરવી અર્થાત્ રચના કૃત્રિમ હોય છે. પ્રાકૃતિક સૃષ્ટિ અને કલા બન્ને ભિન્ન વસ્તુઓ છે. કલા એવા કાર્યમાં હોય જે મનુષ્ય કરે છે. કલા અને વિજ્ઞાનમાં પણ અંતર રાખવામાં આવે છે. વિજ્ઞાનમાં જ્ઞાનનું પ્રાધાન્ય હોય છે, કલામાં કૌશલપૂર્ણ માનવીય કાર્યને કલાની સંજ્ઞા આપવામાં આવે છે. કૌશલવિહીન અથવા ખરાબ ઢંગથી કરવામાં આવેલા કાર્યોને કલામાં સ્થાન આપવામાં આવતું નથી."},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకి జవాబుని ఇవ్వండి: ‘ఇంక్విలాబ్ జిందాబాద్’ నినాదాన్ని ఎవరు ఇచ్చారు?","answer":" ‘ఇంక్విలాబ్ జిందాబాద్’ నినాదాన్ని భగత్ సింగ్ ఇచ్చారు."},{"question":"السؤال: كم يبلغ عدد أبناء الرسول صلَّى الله عليه وسلَّم؟","answer":"الجواب: 7 أبناء، وأسماؤهم هي: القاسم، عبد الله، إبراهيم، رقية، زينب، أم كلثوم، فاطمة."},{"question":"Qual filme escrito, dirigido e produzido por James Cameron se tornou o filme de maior bilheteria de sua época?","answer":"Titanic. Em 1998, tornou-se o primeiro filme a ultrapassar a bilheteria bruta mundial de US 1 bilhão."},{"question":"Алтай жөнүндө кыскача айтып берчи ?","answer":"Алтай – күчтүн жери  .Ал эми ар бир адам жок дегенде бир жолу барышы керек болгон Россиянын бир бурчу. Анда баары бар: карлуу чокулар, толкундуу дарыялар, чексиз түздүктөр, тунук көлдөр жана укмуштуудай кооз пейзаждар."},{"question":"Wangsulana pitakonan berdasarkan paragraf ing ngisor iki:Ing zaman mbiyen, kebo lan jalak kekancan. Kebo ngeroso pundake gatel-gatel. Nanging kebo ora iso ngukur awake dewe. Kebo njaluk tulung nang kanca kewan liyane. Dhilalah ora enek kewan sing gelem nulung kebo. Akhire kebo nelangsa. Bar kuwi, jalak teko. Jalak nakoni kebo sing nelangsa. Ngerti ceritone kebo, jalak nutuli gegere kebo ben ora gatel-gatel maneh. Ket dino kuwi, kebo lan jalak dadi kekancan.Pitakonan:Sapa sing akhire dadi kancane Kebo?Wangsulan:","answer":"Wangsulan: Jalak."},{"question":"Nombre algunas bandas de rock famosas de los años 60","answer":"En la década de 1960 hubo muchas bandas de rock famosas, incluyendo The Beatles, The Beach Boys, The Doors, The Rolling Stones, The Who, Led Zeppelin, The Grateful Dead y Pink Floyd, entre otras."},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:‘હું ચડિયાતો છું’ એનો મનોભાવ","answer":"ગુરુતાગ્રંથિ"},{"question":"Indil ma weer yi.","answer":"Fukk weer ak ñaar a àm:1. Tamxarit2. Diggi-gàmmu3. Gàmmu4. Rakk-i-gàmmu5. Rakkaat-i-gàmmu6. Maam-i-koor7. Nday-i-koor8. Bàraxlu9. Koor10. Kori11. Diggi-tëbaski12. TëbaskiWeer yii ci weer wi la ñu àju. Weer wi moo'y lees di séen ci asamaan si. Weer bi di diir bi ndox ci diggante ñaar i weer yu mat; man na a toll ci 29 walla 30 fan.Weer i tubaab ñoom ñoo àju ci jant bi.Wolof àm na ìtam ay weer i biir, ginnaaw dëluuñ ba nawet dugg. Weer u biir bu ne, da'y tektal aw dig wu nàwet gi toll. Weer yoo yu ñoo'y céebo yi, wàxset ak sattunbar.1. Céebo yi: juroom benn la'ñ   - Cang (13 fan)   - Dabraan (13 fan)   - Dékk (13 fan)   - Ànaata (13 fan)   - Yuuli-yuuli (7 fan)   - Sereyna (6 fan)2. Wàxset (40 fan)3. Sattunbar (40 fan)"},{"question":" Sheeg Xadka U Dhaxeeya Qaarada Afrika Iyo Qaarada Yurub?","answer":"Waa Badda Loo-Yaqaano Badda Cas (Red Sea)"},{"question":"Lazao ireo antony mahakanto ny hai-teny?","answer":"Lahateny nifaninanan’ny tovolahy sy ny tovovavy teo amin’ny fanehoana fahaizana mifehy ny fampiasana teny sy fanehoana-kevitra an-gola na teny an’ohatra ary famolahana ny tontolo manodidina ny hain-teny. Saika fanehoam-pitiavana no nanaovana izany."},{"question":"Continua la frase: - Ulteriori danni si sono avuto durante i bombardamenti alleati","answer":"della seconda guerra mondiale e a causa del terremoto dell'Irpinia del 1980. Nel 1992 la chiesa subì infine altri interventi di restauro grazie ai quali emerse l'affresco seicentesco di Aniello Falcone su \\"San Giorgio che uccide il drago\\" nella zona absidale."},{"question":"世界で最も北に野生のペンギンが生息している、エクアドルにある諸島群といえばどこでしょう？","answer":"ガラパゴス諸島です。"},{"question":"नेपालमा बन्जी जम्पिङ को बारेमा भन।","answer":" नेपालको पहिलो बन्जी जम्पिङ साइट १६० मिटरमा अवस्थित छ। भोटेकोशि खोलामा, तपाईंलाई यस अद्भुत ठाउँको वरपरको अन्तिम एड्रेनालाईन भीड अनुभव गर्न आमन्त्रित गर्दै। जम्प, १६० मि. मा, स्टाफ र व्यवसाय मा केहि सबैभन्दा अनुभवी जम्पमास्टरहरु द्वारा संचालित छ।"},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Srebrny medalista mistrzostw świata w 2018 i 2019; brązowy w 2010 i 2011. Ośmiokrotny medalista mistrzostw Europy, zwycięzca z 2010, 2011 i 2019. Trzeci na igrzyskach europejskich w 2015. Wicemistrz","answer":" uniwersjady w 2013. Drugi w Pucharze Świata w 2012 i 2018; trzeci w 2015 i 2017; ósmy w 2009. Mistrz świata juniorów z 2009 roku."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:येतां कृपेची निज उडी । विघ्नें कापती बापुडीं ।हो‍ऊन जाती देशधडी । नाममात्रें ॥ ४॥अर्थ:","answer":"गणेशाची कृपा झाली की विघ्ने चळचळा कापू लागतात. त्याच्या केवळ नामस्मरणानेही ती देशोधडीला लागतात. (४)"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira de Uganda.","answer":"A bandeira de Uganda é composta por seis faixas horizontais em preto, amarelo e vermelho, com o brasão de armas do país no canto superior esquerdo."},{"question":"नाम : भवानी भिक्षु ( भवानीप्रसाद गुप्ता)जन्म : विसं १९६६ साल जेठ २१ गर्तेजन्मस्थान : तौलिहवा, कपिलवस्तुमाता/पिता : यशोदादेवी/इन्द्रप्रसाद गृप्ताशिक्षा : हिन्दी साहित्य कुलमूषण षण परीक्षा उत्तीर्णभाषा ज्ञान : नेपाली, अवधि, हिन्दी, उर्दू, अङ्ग्रेजी, संस्कृत, बंगाली नेपालीसाहित्यमा प्रवेश : विसं १९९३ को शारदा पत्रिकामा प्रकाशित “वियोगरात्रि\\" शीर्षकको कविताछपाएरप्रकाशित कृतिहरू :कथासङ्गहः गुनकेशरी (२०१०), मैयाँ साहेब (२०१७), आवर्त (२०२४), अवान्तर (२०३४)उपन्यास : आगत (२०३२), पाइप नं. २ (२०३४), सुभद्रा बज्यै (२०१९)कवितासङ्गह : छाया (२०१७), प्रकाश (२०१७), परिष्कार (२०१७)सेवा : आजीवन सदस्य ,नेपाल राजकीय प्रज्ञाप्रतिष्ठानसम्मान/पुरस्कार : साझा पुरस्कार (२०३२), मदन पुरस्कार (२०३२), त्रिभुवन प्रज्ञा पुरस्कार(२०३६)निधन : विसं २०३८ वैशाख ४ गते, काठमाडौं ।प्रश्न : माथि दिएका बुदाका आधारमा जीवनी तयार पार्नुहोस्‌ :","answer":"उत्तर  :साहित्यकार भवानी भिक्षुभवानी भिक्षु नेपाली साहित्यमा घुपरिचित नाम हो । विशैषतः कथा, उपन्यास तथा कविताकाक्षेत्रमा उनले महत्वपूर्ण योगदान दिएका छन्‌ । भिक्षु उनको उपनाम हो । उनको वास्तविक नामभवानीप्रसाद गुप्ता हो । साहित्यकार भिक्षुको जन्म वि.सं. १९६६ साल जेठ २१ गते कपिलवस्तुजिल्लाको मासिहवामा भएको हो । उनका पिताको नाम इन्द्र्रसाद गुप्ला हो भने माताको नामयशोदादेवी हो । हिन्दी साहित्यमा साहित्य कुलभूषण परीक्षा गरेका भिक्षु अत्यन्तैप्रभावशाली व्यक्ति थिए |भिक्षुमा नेपाली, अवधि, हिन्दी, उर्दू, अङ्ग्रेजी, संस्कृत र बङ्गाली भाषाको रामो ज्ञान थियो ।उनको मातृभाषा चाहिँ अवधी हो। वि.सं. १९९३ मा 'शारदा' पत्रिकामा 'वियोगरात्रि' शीर्षककोकविता छपाएर भिक्षु नेपाली साहित्यमा प्रवेश गर्न पुगे । भिक्षु मुख्य रुपमा नेपाली कविता,उपन्यास र कथा साहित्यका त्रिवेणी छन्‌ | गुनकेशरी (२०१०), मैयाँ साहेब (२०१७), आवर्त(२०२४) र अवान्तर (२०३४) उनका कथा सङ्ग्रह हुन्‌ । त्यस्तै छाया (२०१७), प्रकाश (२०१७) रपरिष्कार (२०१७) कविता सङ्ग्रह पनि प्रकाशित छन्‌ । बहुमुखी प्रतिभाका धनी भिक्षुका प्रसिद्धउपन्यासहरू आगत (२०३२), पाइप नं. २ (२०३४) र सु बज्यै (२०१९) प्रकाशित भइसकेकाछन्‌।यसैगरी नेपाल राजकीय प्रज्ञा प्रतिष्ठानमा आजीवन सदस्य भएर नेपाली भाषा साहित्यमा सेवापुन्याएका भिक्षुलाई कदर गर्दै मदन पुरस्कार (२०३२), साझा पुरस्कार (२०३२) र त्रिभुवन प्रज्ञापुरस्कार (२०३६) दवारा सम्मान गरिएको थियो । नेपाली विशिष्ट योगदान पुयाउनेअनुकरणीय व्यक्तित्व भवानी मिले, पनि जन्मेपछि मर्नैपर्ने सत्यलाई स्विकार्दै वि.सं. २०३८वैशाख ४ गते काठमाडौंमा यस बिदा लिए। नेपाली साहित्यका एक साधकको अन्त्य हुँदासबैले नमिठो अनुभव गरे । उनी मरेर गए पनि उनका रचनाले उनलाई अमर बनाएको छ ।"},{"question":" Sheeg sadex kamida heesaha jiibta iyo jaanta leh ? ","answer":" Waxaa kamida dhaantada,shiribka iyo seylic. "},{"question":"Sparafrazuj tekst: Oddałem samochód do mechanika, ale od tej pory nadal nie dał znać co było zepsute.","answer":"Oto moja propozycja: Oddałem auto do mechanika, ale od tego czasu nadal nie powiedział mi co jest nie tak."},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan cara-cara memupuk amalan gaya hidup yang sihat. ","answer":"Mutakhir ini, isu kesihatan seringkali menjadi topik perbincangan di kaca televisyen dan dada-dada akhbar. Kebanyakan di antara masyarakat kita menghidap penyakit yang menjejaskan kesihatan mereka sehingga boleh meragut nyawa. Malah Tinjauan Kebangsaan Kesihatan dan Morbiditi (NHMS) tahun 2019 menyatakan bahawa peratusan penghidap obesiti dalam kalangan dewasa di Malaysia adalah tertinggi di rantau Asia Tenggara. Fakta yang menggerunkan ini perlu diubah dengan menggalakkan seluruh masyarakat di tanah air ini untuk mengamalkan gaya hidup sihat. Mekanisme ini bukan sahaja dapat mengurangkan risiko menghidap obesiti tetapi ia juga menyumbang kepda pengurangan risiko menghidapi penyakit berbahaya lain seperti penyakit jantung, obesiti, darah tinggi dan kencing manis. Oleh itu, penting untuk kita tahu apakah cara-cara memupuk amalan gaya hidup sihat dalam kalangan masyarakat di Malaysia?Langkah pertama untuk mengamalkan gaya hidup yang sihat adalah dengan menjaga kebersihan diri dan persekitaran. Perkara asas seperti mandi, menggosok gigi, memakai pakaian yang bersih dan kemas serta mendapatkan tidur atau rehat yang cukup adalah mustahak untuk diamalkan. Disiplin ini sedikit sebanyak dapat mendorong kita untuk melakukan aktiviti gaya hidup seihat yang lain. Tambahan pula, menjaga kebersihan persekitaran khususnya dikawasan tempat tinggal kita dapat menghindari daripada penyakit-penyakit berjangkit seperti denggi dan keracunan makanan. Sebagai contoh, sebelum menjamu selera, kita hendaklah mencuci tangan dengan bersih dan menutup makanan atau lauk-pauk dengan betul supaya tidak dihinggap lalat. Segelintir di antara ahli masyarakat bersikap sambil lewa apabila menjaga kebersihan sehingga membawa padah kepada diri dan juga masyarakat sekeliling. Tegasnya, menjaga kebersihan diri dan persekitaran adalah disiplin yang diperlukan untuk mengamalkan gaya hidup yang sihat.Inisiatif lain yang utama dalam mengamalkan gaya hidup sihat adalah dengan pemakanan yang seimbang. Semua sedia maklum bahawa makanan merupakan elemn penting dalam memastikan kesihatan kita berada di tahap yang terbaik. Berdasarkan piramid makanan yang disarankan oleh Kementerian Kesihatan Malaysia, kita digalakkan untuk memakan hidangan yang tinggi kandungan karbohirat, syaur-sayuran dan buah-buahan dengan banyak. Manakala makanan yang mempunyai protein daripada ikan, ayam, daging serta produk tenusu dalam pula diambil kadar sederhana. Makanan yang mengandungi lemak, minyak, gula dan garam yang tinggi hendaklah dikurangkan. Dengan pengambilan zat dan nutrien yang cukup, nescaya tubuh badan kita akan menjadi lebih sihat dan cergas. Masyarakat hari ini lebih gemar untuk memakan makanan restoran segera serta makanan yang telah diproses kerana menjimatkan masa, tenaga dan mendapat hidangan yang sedap. Tetapi jika dialakan dengan kerap, ia pasti menjejaskan kesihatan diri. Bak kata pepatah, turutkan rasa binasa, turutkan hati mati. Izharnya, pemakanan seimbang adalah ciri penting dalam amalan gaya hisup sihat.Pada masa yang sama, amalan gaya hidup sihat perlu dilengkapi dengan penyertaan dalam aktiviti sukan atau rekreasi. Apabila seseorang bersukan, ia dapat membantu individu tersebut membakar kalori dan lemak, mengeluarkan peluh atau toksin dari badan serta membina otot yang penting untuk pertumbuhan badan. Secara tidak langsung ia dapat meningkatkan imunisasi dan ketahanan diri. Setiap di antara kita hanya perlu meluangkan masa sekurang-kurangnya 30 minit sehari untuk beriadah atau bersukan. Pastikan anda melakukan aktiviti yang sesuai dengan kemampuan diri masing-masing di mana golongan warga emas boleh beriadah hanya dengan berjoging atau melakukan senam robik manakala golongan dewasa dan kanak-kanak boleh bersukan dan sebagainya. Jelas bahawa amalan gaya hidup sihat adalah penyertaan aktiviti sukan atau rekreasi yang memberikan pelbagai manfaat lain khususnya dari aspek kesihatan.Akhir sekali, kita digalakkan melakukan pemeriksaan kesihatan secara berkala sebagai amalan gaya hidup sihat. Umum mengetahui bahawa kita memiliki fasiliti kesihatan awam yang berpatutan dan wajar dimanfaatkan oleh semua lapisan masyarakat. Ibu dan bapa boleh membawa anak-anak untuk melakukan pemeriksaan kesihatan di klinik kesihatan yang dibina hampir di setiap daerah seluruh Malaysia. Pemeriksaan seperti tekanan darah, paras gula dalam darah dan tahap kolesterol serta pemeriksaan gigi boleh dilakukan enam bulan sekali atau dua kali setahun. Jika kita menghidapi penyakit tanpa sedar, tindakan ini dapat membantu kita untuk mengesan tanda-tanda awal dan merawatnya sebelum sakit yang lebih kronik menyerang. Persis kata peribahasa, ingat antara belum kena, hemat antara belum habis. Intihannya, melakukan pemeriksaan kesihatan adalah salah satu gaya hidup yang sihat.Kesimpulannya, banyak usaha dan cara untuk mengamalkan gaya hidup yang sihat oleh masyarakat pada hari ini. Kita perlu membuka mata dan melihat kepentingan dan kesan menjaga kesihatan kepada diri, keluarga, masyarakat dan juga negara. Sekiranya masyarakat berjaya mengamalkan gaya hidup sihat, pasti fasiliti kesihatan tidak dipenuhi pesakit sebaliknya fasiliti sukan dan rekreasi menjadi tumpuan dan pusat komuniti utama untuk negara. Selain itu, masyarakat yang sihat dari setiap aspek fizikal dan mental akan melahirkan individu yang berketrampilan tinggi dan disegani ramai. Hasilnya kelak, generasi masa hadapan kita mampu memacu negara ke arah yang lebih baik. Peribahasa melayu berkata, hendak seribu daya, tak hendak seribu dalih. Semoga setiap usaha untuk menjadikan amalan gaya hidup sihat sebagai satu rutin dalam diri setiap individu disokong dan memberikan hasil yang diingankan."},{"question":"புதுமைப்பித்தனின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"வகுப்பில் இரண்டு கெட்டிக்காரர்கள் இருந்தால், இரண்டு பேர்களுக்கும் நட்பு ஏற்படுவது இயற்கை; பகைமை ஏற்படுவதும் சகஜம். இவை இரண்டும் அற்று இருப்பது விதிக்கு விலக்கு"},{"question":"What is reinforcement learning?","answer":"Reinforcement learning is a type of machine learning where an agent learns to make decisions by taking actions in an environment to achieve some notion of cumulative reward."},{"question":"හිරැ අවරට යෑමෙන් පසු ආහාර අනුභවය සහදුර ගමනක් යන විට ගෙන යන්නා වූ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය බඩුබාහිරාදිය යන්නට යොදන තනි පද මොනවාද ?","answer":"මං දන්න තරමින් විකාල යන වචනයේ හිරු අවරට යෑමෙන් පසු යන අර්ථයක් නෑ. නො කල්හි යන්න තමයි ඊට සුදුසුම අර්ථය."},{"question":"Cad iad na príomhdhifríochtaí idir caipitíocht agus cumannachas? Cé acu an córas a bhí níos rathúla sa 20ú haois? ","answer":"Is córas polaitiúil agus eacnamaíoch é an chaipitíocht ina ndéantar infheistíochtaí, earraí a tháirgtear, agus seirbhísí a thairgtear, chun brabús a chruthú. I gcóras caipitliúil, tá gnólachtaí ag dul san iomaíocht lena chéile i margadh oscailte. Is córas polaitiúla agus eacnamaíochta é an cumannaíocht ina bhfuil gach maoin agus táirgeadh faoi úinéireacht an rialtais, agus déantar cinntí eacnamaíocha go daonlathach d'fhonn sochaí níos cothrom a chruthú. thar na 20 bliain anuas, tá sé coitianta a mheas go bhfuil daonlathas, margaí agus fiontar saor in aisce níos rathúla ó thaobh cobhsaíocht pholaitiúil agus eacnamaíochta, chomh maith le saoirse."},{"question":"« Nitaiza ny zandriko irery aho rehefa iny nindaosan’ny fahafatesana iny ny reninay. Tsy nanohy ny fianarako intsony aho fa dia ny asa hahavelona anay mirahalahy no notadiavina. Nahita asa aho tsara ihany aho ny farany na dia efa niovaova betsaka izany teo aloha. Taty aoriana, tafita ihany ny zandriko. »Iza  amin’ireto manaraka ireto no mety fiafaran’ny tantara :A. Nilaozan’ilay zandriko koa aho satria nahita asa tany am-pita izy ka hadinony na ny nanampy ahy aza.B. Na dia lasa tany am-pita aza ilay zandriko dia tsy mba hadinony ny mandefa vatsy isam-bolana ho ahy.","answer":"B no mety fiafaran’ny tantara."},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Nanao andro aman'alina izy mba hahatanteraka ny diany mandihy, ary tamin'ny farany dia nofantsihany izany.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Amin'ny alàlan'ny fanazaran-tena mitohy, dia nanatanteraka ny dihy tsy tapaka izy tamin'ny farany.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: \\"Η πιο διάσημη ελληνική αρχαιολογική ακρόπολη είναι η\\"","answer":"Απάντηση: \\"Ακρόπολη της Αθήνας\\""},{"question":"‘அகழாய்வு’ குறித்து பாடப்பகுதி கருத்துகளைக் கூறுக.","answer":"முன்னுரை:அகழாய்வு என்பது தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்ட நிலப்பகுதியில் செதுக்கிச் செதுக்கி ஆராய்தல் ஆகும். ஆய்வு என்பது அறிவின் வெளிப்பாடு. நமது முன்னோர்கள் வாழ்ந்து பெற்ற பட்டறிவை வகைப்படுத்தி தொகுத்துப் பார்ப்பதற்குத் தொல்லியல் ஆய்வே பெருங்கல்வியாக அமைகின்றது. பண்பாட்டு எச்சங்களாகத் திகழும் இவ்வகையான ஆய்வுகளைக் கண்டு பயனடையலாம்.கீழடி அகழாய்வு:மதுரை நகருக்கு அருகே உள்ள கீழடி என்னுமிடத்தில் நடத்தப்பட்ட அகழாய்வில் சுடுமண் பொருள்கள், உலோகப் பொருள்கள், முத்துகள், கிளிஞ்சல் பொருள்கள், மான்கொம்புகள், சோழிகள், கிண்ணங்கள், துளையிடப்பட்ட பாத்திரங்கள், இரத்தினக்கல் வகைகள், பழுப்பு, கறுப்பு, சிவப்பு-கறுப்புப் பானைகள், சதுரங்கக் காய்கள், தானியங்களைச் சேகரிக்கும் கலன்கள், செம்பு, சங்கு வளையல்கள், எலும்பினால் ஆன கூர்முனைகள், தமிழ் எழுத்துகள் பொறிக்கப்பட்ட பானை ஓடுகள், கற்கருவிகள், நீர் சேகரிக்கும் பெரிய மட்கலன்கள், சிறிய குடுவைகள், உறைக்கிணறுகள், சுடுமண் கூரை ஓடுகள் போன்ற பல்வேறு தொல்லியல் பொருள்கள் கிடைத்துள்ளன. மூன்று வெவ்வேறு காலகட்டங்களைச் சேர்ந்த இவற்றுள் தொன்மையானவை சுமார் இரண்டாயிரத்து முந்நூறு ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முற்பட்டவை எனக் கருதப்படுகின்றன.இதுவரை அகழாய்வு செய்யப்பட்ட பெரும்பான்மையான இடங்கள், இறப்புத் தொடர்பான தடயங்களை வெளிப்படுத்துவனவாக அமைந்துள்ளன. ஆனால், கீழடியில் கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ள முழுமையான வாழ்விடப்பகுதியும், செங்கல் கட்டுமானங்களும், இதரப் பொருள்களும் தமிழரின் உயரிய நாகரிகத்தைக் கண்முன் காட்டும் சாட்சிகளாய் அமைந்துள்ளன.பல்லாவரம் அகழாய்வு:நூற்றி ஐம்பது ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்னால் 1863ஆம் ஆண்டு இராபர்ட் புரூஸ்புட் என்னும் தொல்லியல் அறிஞர் சென்னைப் பல்லாவரம் செம்மண் மேட்டுப்பகுதியில் எலும்பையும் கற்கருவியையும் கண்டுபிடித்தார். இந்தக் கற்கருவிதான் இந்தியாவில் கண்டெடுக்கப்பட்ட முதல் கல்லாயுதம். இந்தக் கல்லாயுதம் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்படுவதற்கு முன்பே, ரோமானியர்களின் பழங்காசுகளைக் கோவையில் கண்டெடுத்தோம்.அரிக்கமேடு:அரிக்கமேடு அகழாய்வில் ரோமானிய மட்பாண்டங்கள் கிடைத்தன. அதனால், ரோமானியர்களுக்கும், நமக்கும் இருந்த வணிகத் தொடர்பு உறுதிப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.ஆதிச்சநல்லூர்:1914ஆம் ஆண்டு ஆதிச்சநல்லூரில் நடத்தப்பட்ட அகழாய்வில் ஏராளமான முதுமக்கள் தாழிகள் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டன. உள்ளங்கையில் உலகம் இருக்கிறது. மடிக்கணினி மலைக்க வைக்கிறது. நம் முன்னோர்கள் இரண்டாயிரம் ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பே, அறிவியல் அடிப்படையிலான பண்பாட்டு வாழ்க்கையை வாழ்ந்தவர்கள். தமிழர்களின் உணவு, உடை, வாழிடம் முதலியன இயற்கையைச் சிதைக்காத இயல்புகளைக் கொண்டவை என்பதற்கு அகழாய்வில் கண்ட சான்றுகளே ஆவணங்களாகத் திகழ்கின்றன.அகழாய்வின் பயனும் முடிவும்:அகழாய்வில் கிடைத்த ஆவணங்களோ அடுத்த தலைமுறைக்கு நம் பண்பாட்டின் மேன்மையைப் பறைசாற்றும். எனவே, அகழாய்வு என்பது நமக்கு மிகமிகத் தேவையான செயல்பாடு. அகழாய்வு தரும் சான்றுகளின் மூலம் நமது வளமான வரலாற்றையும் பண்பாட்டையும் அறிந்துகொண்டு வலிமையான எதிர்காலத்தை உருவாக்க முடியும். இயற்கையோடு இணைந்த பண்பாட்டு வாழ்க்கை நம்முடையது. மக்கள் அறிவியல் என்கிற மகத்தான சிந்தனையைப் புரிந்துகொள்வதற்கும் நமது பண்பாட்டின் மேன்மைகளை இன்றைய தலைமுறை எடுத்துக்கொண்டு சிறப்பாக வாழ்வதற்கும் அகழாய்வு துணைநிற்கின்றது."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 手などの消毒用アルコールの多くは、3年で使うことができなくなります。2020年に買ったものは、今年3年が過ぎます。捨てるときは注意が必要です。アルコールの濃さが60％以上あることが多くて燃えやすいためです。東京都は、消毒用のアルコールを台所などに流して捨てることはやめるように言っています。下水道で火事が起こる危険があります。東京の23区では、アルコールはまず布や新聞に捨てて、乾いてからごみに出します。新聞などに捨てるときは、近くに火がなくて十分に換気している場所で行います。薬の会社によると、入っているものがエタノールと水だけの場合は、台所で使う道具などの消毒にも使うことができます。しかし、手の消毒以外には使わないほうがいいものもあるため、会社のウェブサイトなどで確認してください。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。- 消毒: 1）薬や、熱などで、ばい菌を殺すこと。- 濃: 1）色や味などが強い。2）含まれているものの度合いが高い。3）びっしりとしている。すき間がない。4）ものごとの程度が強い。- 燃え: 1）火がついて、ほのおが上がる。2）燃えているようなようすになる。3）その気持ちが、さかんに起こる。- 流し: 1）液体などが低いほうへ動くようにする。2）水などにうかべて動かす。3）よごれを洗い落とす。4）うわさなどを広める。5）予定していたことを、取りやめる。6）そのことを気に留めない。- 下水道: 1）「下水」を流すためのみぞや管。- 起こる: 1）始まる。2）生じる。起きる。- 布: 1）糸で織った物。織物。きれ。- 換気: 1）よごれた空気を、きれいな空気と入れ換えること。- ウェブサイト: 1）インターネットで、ひとまとまりの情報が置かれている場所。サイト。ウェブ。- 確認: 1）十分に確かめること。"},{"question":"Kíni owó òṣìṣẹ́ ní orílè Jamaica ?","answer":"Jamaican dollar ni."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--एका मान्यात दोन तलवारी राहात नाहीत","answer":"दोन तेजस्वी माणसे गुण्या-गोविंदाने राहू शकत नाहीत."},{"question":"Δώσε την απάντηση στο: Γιατί πρέπει να συμπεριλαμβάνονται τα φυτά στις έρευνες για τον κύκλο του νερού; Διάλεξε από τα παρακάτω. --Τα φυτά επιταχύνουν τον κύκλο του νερού αφαιρώντας τον άνθρακα από τον αέρα. --Τα φυτά ξεκινούν τον κύκλο του νερού όταν παράγουν νερό στη φωτοσύνθεση. --Τα φυτά αποτελούν μέρος του κύκλου του νερού μέσω της διαδικασίας της διαπνοής. --Τα φυτά σταματούν τον κύκλο του νερού επειδή το απορροφούν και σταματούν τη ροή προς τα ρέματα.","answer":"Τα φυτά αποτελούν μέρος του κύκλου του νερού μέσω της διαδικασίας της διαπνοής."},{"question":"Buhari ki Joe Biden ku oriire, o ni o kaabọ sawujọ awọn aarẹ agbaye","answer":"Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari ti pẹlu awọn olori orilẹ-ede agbaye yooku ki Ọgbẹni Joe Biden, ku oriireLori ikanni abẹyẹfo rẹ ni Ọgbẹni Garba Shehu, to jẹ Oludamọran pataki lori eto iroyin kọ ọ si lorukọ Buhari, lo ti ki í kú oríire.O ni, “Mo ki Aarẹ tuntun tí wọn ṣẹṣẹ dibo yan ni ilẹ Amẹrika Joe Biden, ku oriire, paapaa lasiko ti gbogbo agbaye wa ninu ibẹru-bojo. Eto idibo to gbe e wọle yii tubọ fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ohun to dara ni eto ijọba dẹmokiresi.Ṣiwaju sí í, o ni irufẹ eto ijọba ọhun gan-an lo maa n fun awọn eeyan lanfaani lati dibo yan olori tuntun lọna alaafia ati irọrun."},{"question":"Apakah cara untuk menjaga kesihatan sendiri dan keluarga?","answer":"Kita boleh melakukan aktiviti riadah, mengamalkan pemakanan seimbang, menjaga kebersihan diri dan persekitaran, menjalani pemeriksaan kesihatan, dan mendapatkan rehat dan tidur yang cukup. "},{"question":"Deus que tenhamos compreendido o significado da palavra \\"Deus\\", sabemos, de imediato, que Deus existe. Com efeito, essa palavra designa uma coisa de tal ordem que não podemos conceber nada que lhe seja maior. Ora, o que existe na realidade e no pensamento é maior do que o que existe apenas no pensamento. Donde se segue que o objeto designado pela palavra \\"Deus\\", que existe no pensamento, desde que se entenda essa palavra, também existe na realidade. Por conseguinte, a existência de Deus é evidente.O texto apresenta uma elaboração teórica de Tomás de Aquino caracterizada por:a) reiterar a ortodoxia religiosa contra os heréticos.b) sustentar racionalmente doutrina alicerçada na fé.c) explicar as virtudes teologais pela demonstração.d) flexibilizar a interpretação oficial dos textos sagrados.e) justificar pragmaticamente a crença livre de dogmas.","answer":"b) sustentar racionalmente doutrina alicerçada na fé."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 鳥インフルエンザが広がって、今までに殺したにわとりは1200万羽以上になりました。このため卵が足りなくなっていないか、農林水産省がチェックしています。パックに入っている家庭で使う卵は、十分用意できていることがわかりました。しかし、卵を使って商品を作っている会社の中には、卵が足りなくなっている会社があります。コンビニのセブン‐イレブンは、1月31日から全部の店で、卵を使う15種類の商品を売るのを休んでいます。サラダやサンドイッチなど10種類の商品は、卵を少なくして、野菜やハムなどほかのものを多くして売っています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Xem video (theo VTVCab) Đội hình ra sân Hà Nội: Tấn Trường; Duy Mạnh, Thành Chung, Văn Hậu, Văn Toàn, Hùng Dũng, Văn Quyết, Văn Kiên, Tuấn Hải, Xuân Tú, Siladij. SLNA: Văn Hoàng, Bá Sang, Thế Nhật, Ngọc Hải, Xuân Tiến, Sỹ Hoàng, Xuân Mạnh, Đình Hoàng, Văn Đức, Oseni, Michael Olaha. Bàn thắng: Siladij 53' (pen), Thành Chung 76' - Olaha 4' Thẻ đỏ: Olaha 49'","answer":"Video bàn thắng Hà Nội 2-1 SLNA: Thành Chung tỏa sáng trong trận đấu"},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Thủ tướng Chính phủ Phạm Minh Chính vừa ký ban hành Công điện số 679/CĐ-TTg ngày 31/7/2022 về việc tăng cường các biện pháp quản lý, điều hành giá. Điều hành giá xăng dầu bám sát giá thị trường thế giớiPhó Thủ tướng Lê Minh Khái yêu cầu Bộ Công Thương và Bộ Tài chính phối hợp chặt chẽ điều hành giá xăng dầu; bảo đảm giá xăng dầu trong nước phản ánh, bám sát diễn biến giá thành phẩm xăng dầu thế giới. (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Công điện gửi Ban Chỉ đạo điều hành giá của Thủ tướng Chính phủ; các đồng chí Bộ trưởng, Thủ trưởng cơ quan ngang Bộ; Chủ tịch Ủy ban nhân dân các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương, nêu rõ: Trước diễn biến giá cả các hàng hóa, dịch vụ thiết yếu trong thời gian qua vẫn ở mức cao, Chính phủ, Ban Chỉ đạo điều hành giá đã triển khai nhiều giải pháp giữ ổn định giá hàng hóa, dịch vụ; kịp thời trình Ủy ban Thường vụ Quốc hội điều chỉnh giảm thuế bảo vệ môi trường để bình ổn, giảm giá mặt hàng xăng dầu trong nước. Nhằm tiếp tục đẩy mạnh công tác quản lý, điều hành giá, bình ổn giá các hàng hóa, dịch vụ thiết yếu có tác động đến chỉ số giá tiêu dùng và ảnh hưởng đến đời sống người dân, hoạt động sản xuất kinh doanh của tổ chức, cá nhân; nhất là việc kiểm soát giá các hàng hóa, dịch vụ sau khi giá xăng dầu giảm mạnh trong các kỳ điều hành vừa qua, Thủ tướng Chính phủ yêu cầu các Bộ trưởng, Thủ trưởng cơ quan ngang Bộ, Chủ tịch Ủy ban nhân dân các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc trung ương tiếp tục đẩy mạnh thực hiện các ý kiến chỉ đạo của Trưởng Ban Chỉ đạo điều hành giá; trong phạm vi, lĩnh vực, thẩm quyền quản lý đẩy mạnh tổ chức triển khai theo dõi sát diễn biến thị trường, kịp thời thực hiện giải pháp đảm bảo cân đối cung cầu trong nước, ổn định giá cả, không để xảy ra tình trạng thiếu hàng, găm hàng, đầu cơ, tăng giá bất hợp lý. Người tiêu dùng chọn mua hàng hóa tại một siêu thị. Ảnh: Thanh Liêm - TTXVN Đối với các mặt hàng chịu ảnh hưởng trực tiếp từ giá xăng dầu như dịch vụ vận tải hành khách, vận tải hàng hóa, logicstic: Bộ trưởng Bộ Giao thông vận tải phối hợp với Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương tăng cường tổ chức rà soát kê khai giá của doanh nghiệp để đánh giá việc điều chỉnh giá phù hợp với biến động của các yếu tố đầu vào, đặc biệt là chi phí xăng dầu trong yếu tố hình thành giá; trường hợp có thể giảm giá thì yêu cầu đơn vị thực hiện kê khai giảm giá kịp thời; tăng cường kiểm tra việc chấp hành niêm yết giá, thu tiền dịch vụ đúng giá niêm yết của các doanh nghiệp, xử lý nghiêm các hành vi lợi dụng tăng giá bất hợp lý, kết cấu đưa thêm những khoản thu ngoài giá để thu cao hơn mức giá kê khai, niêm yết. Đối với các hàng hóa, dịch vụ thiết yếu, chịu ảnh hưởng gián tiếp từ giá xăng dầu, có tác động đến chỉ số giá tiêu dùng và ảnh hưởng đến đời sống người dân, hoạt động sản xuất kinh doanh của doanh nghiệp: các Bộ trưởng, Thủ trưởng cơ quan ngang Bộ, Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương chỉ đạo theo dõi sát diễn biến giá cả thị trường, tổ chức nắm bắt tình hình thực hiện của các tổ chức, cá nhân kinh doanh để có các biện pháp điều hành, bình ổn giá phù hợp; tăng cường kiểm tra, kiểm soát việc chấp hành pháp luật về giá, các biện pháp kê khai, niêm yết giá, xử lý nghiêm các trường hợp lợi dụng để tăng giá bất hợp lý. Đồng thời chủ động kiểm tra yếu tố hình thành giá theo quy định tại Luật giá và theo thẩm quyền khi hàng hóa có biến động bất thường và xử lý các sai phạm theo quy định. Trong đó: Đối với giá lương thực, thực phẩm: Bộ trưởng Bộ Nông nghiệp và Phát triển nông thôn phối hợp với Bộ trưởng Bộ Công Thương chỉ đạo đánh giá kỹ tình hình sản xuất, điều hòa cung cầu các mặt hàng phục vụ nhu cầu trong nước, giữa các vùng, địa phương và nhu cầu xuất khẩu để ổn định giá cả thị trường. Đối với mặt hàng thịt lợn, thức ăn chăn nuôi: Bộ trưởng Bộ Nông nghiệp và Phát triển nông thôn chỉ đạo, hướng dẫn địa phương, các lực lượng chức năng, các tổ chức và cá nhân sản xuất chăn nuôi lợn tiếp tục tập trung thúc đẩy sản xuất, chăn nuôi, tái đàn, chế biến, điều hòa và đảm bảo nguồn cung để bình ổn giá thịt lợn; thực hiện công tác phòng, chống dịch; tổ chức tái đàn phù hợp, bền vững, chăn nuôi theo mô hình khép kín và an toàn sinh học; đẩy mạnh sản xuất con giống, bảo đảm tổng đàn lợn cả nước đáp ứng đủ nhu cầu trong nước trước mắt và lâu dài. Bộ trưởng Bộ Công Thương chủ trì phối hợp với Bộ trưởng Bộ Nông nghiệp và Phát triển nông thôn và Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương tăng cường kiểm tra, rà soát, đánh giá hệ thống kênh phân phối, cung ứng, lò mổ và đầu mối bán buôn, bán lẻ đối với mặt hàng thịt lợn tính từ cửa trại, cửa chuồng của doanh nghiệp, người chăn nuôi đến doanh nghiệp, siêu thị, người bán cuối cùng trực tiếp cung ứng cho người tiêu dùng; làm rõ các bất cập, hạn chế (nếu có) để đề xuất các giải pháp khắc phục đảm bảo giảm thiểu khâu trung gian đẩy chi phí lưu thông, tăng giá bán; tiến tới hoàn thiện hệ thống phân phối, bán buôn, bán lẻ tinh gọn, hiệu quả, có chi phí lưu thông hợp lý trong cơ cấu giá bán. Mua bán xăng dầu. Ảnh: Trần Việt/TTXVN Đối với vật liệu xây dựng: Bộ trưởng Bộ Tài nguyên và Môi trường, Bộ trưởng Bộ Xây dựng phối hợp với Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương quản lý hiệu quả nguồn cung; xử lý kịp thời các trường hợp găm hàng, giữ hàng, làm đứt gãy chuỗi cung ứng, đẩy giá tăng cao bất hợp lý ảnh hưởng đến tiến độ xây dựng của các công trình, dự án đầu tư, nhất là các dự án trọng điểm quốc gia. Bộ Xây dựng chỉ đạo các Sở Xây dựng đẩy mạnh công tác theo dõi, cập nhật biến động giá để kịp thời công bố giá vật liệu xây dựng; nghiên cứu rút ngắn chu kỳ công bố theo quy định. Đối với các dịch vụ lưu trú, du lịch: Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương tăng cường công tác kiểm tra việc chấp hành pháp luật về giá, niêm yết giá theo đúng quy định. Xử lý nghiêm các hành vi lợi dụng các dịp cao điểm, diễn biến giá xăng dầu để tăng giá bất hợp lý. Đối với thuốc, vật tư y tế: Bộ trưởng Bộ Y tế chỉ đạo tổ chức thực hiện bình ổn giá trang thiết bị theo quy định của pháp luật về giá, Nghị quyết số 12/2021/NQ-UBTVQH15 ngày 30 tháng 12 năm 2021 và Nghị định 98/2021/NĐ-CP ngày 08 tháng 11 năm 2021 về quản lý trang thiết bị y tế; tăng cường rà soát giá thuốc, vật tư y tế kê khai, theo quy định tại Luật Dược; theo dõi sát sao tình hình dịch bệnh để đảm bảo cung ứng đủ thuốc và vật tư y tế với giá hợp lý phục vụ nhu cầu khám bệnh, chữa bệnh và phòng, chống dịch bệnh. Đối với mặt hàng sách giáo khoa: Bộ trưởng Bộ Tài chính phối hợp với Bộ trưởng Bộ Giáo dục và Đào tạo chỉ đạo tiếp tục tiếp nhận, rà soát kê khai giá theo quy định của pháp luật; các đơn vị xuất bản tiếp tục rà soát và triển khai các biện pháp tiết giảm chi phí nhằm tiếp tục giảm giá, góp phần kiểm soát lạm phát, đảm bảo an sinh xã hội; chia sẻ với người dân. Đối với mặt hàng xăng dầu: Bộ trưởng Bộ Công Thương chỉ đạo tiếp tục theo dõi tình hình giá thế giới, sử dụng linh hoạt công cụ quỹ bình ổn giá xăng dầu để có phương án điều hành giá xăng dầu trong nước phù hợp, xử lý nghiêm các hành vi đầu cơ, găm hàng; Bộ trưởng Bộ Tài chính chỉ đạo chủ động nghiên cứu báo cáo Chính phủ phương án điều chỉnh thuế tiêu thụ đặc biệt, thuế giá trị gia tăng đối với xăng dầu. Đối với các hàng hóa, dịch vụ thuộc danh mục nhà nước định giá, các Bộ trưởng, Thủ trưởng cơ quan ngang Bộ, Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương tổ chức triển khai rà soát để chủ động có phương án điều chỉnh giá hoặc trình cấp có thẩm quyền xem xét điều chỉnh giá phù hợp với diễn biến, mặt bằng giá thị trường theo đúng quy định. Bộ trưởng Bộ Tài chính chủ trì phối hợp với Bộ trưởng Bộ Kế hoạch và Đầu tư, Thống đốc Ngân hàng Nhà nước Việt Nam tiếp tục đẩy mạnh triển khai công tác tổng hợp, phân tích, dự báo giá thị trường, cập nhật kịch bản điều hành giá chi tiết, kịp thời cho các tháng còn lại trong năm để tham mưu cho Chính phủ, Thủ tướng Chính phủ các biện pháp điều hành giá phù hợp nhằm kiểm soát lạm phát theo mục tiêu 4% đã đề ra. Đôn đốc, tổng hợp việc thực hiện công tác quản lý, điều hành giá của các Bộ, cơ quan ngang Bộ, UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương báo cáo Ban Chỉ đạo điều hành giá để báo cáo Thủ tướng Chính phủ. (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({}); Bộ trưởng Bộ Thông tin và Truyền thông phối hợp với các Bộ trưởng, Thủ trưởng cơ quan ngang Bộ, Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương tiếp tục chú trọng đẩy mạnh công tác thông tin, tuyên truyền, công khai minh bạch, trung thực thông tin về giá; xử lý nghiêm, quyết liệt theo pháp luật các trường hợp tung tin thất thiệt gây hoang mang cho người tiêu dùng, gây bất ổn thị trường để kiểm soát lạm phát kỳ vọng. Trong thời gian tới, áp lực lạm phát vẫn phụ thuộc vào diễn biến giá nguyên, nhiên, vật liệu, đặc biệt là mặt hàng xăng dầu hiện diễn biến khó lường, giá lương thực, thực phẩm, vậy tư nông nghiệp, vật liệu xây dựng, vận tải... đặt ra những thách thức cho công tác quản lý, điều hành giá từ nay đến cuối năm. Thủ tướng Chính phủ yêu cầu Bộ trưởng các Bộ, Thủ trưởng cơ quan ngang Bộ, Chủ tịch UBND các tỉnh, thành phố trực thuộc Trung ương theo chức năng, nhiệm vụ, thẩm quyền quản lý chỉ đạo các đơn vị trực thuộc triển khai quyết liệt các giải pháp đề ra tại Công điện này và các giải pháp của Chính phủ, ý kiến chỉ đạo của Thủ tướng Chính phủ, Trưởng Ban Chỉ đạo điều hành giá từ đầu năm và theo dõi sát, nắm chắc tình hình để chủ động xử lý theo thẩm quyền phù hợp, kịp thời, khoa học, hiệu quả, tuyệt đối không được chủ quan, lơ là, kiểm soát lạm phát theo mục tiêu đã đề ra đảm bảo đời sống người dân và hoạt động sản xuất kinh doanh, qua đó góp phần ổn định kinh tế vĩ mô, thúc đẩy tăng trưởng. TTXVN","answer":"Thủ tướng yêu cầu kiểm soát giá cả hàng hóa sau khi giá xăng dầu giảm mạnh"},{"question":"السؤال: من أول قاضي في الكوفة ؟","answer":"الإجابة : جبير بن القشعم ."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Évariste Galois para a matemática?","answer":"Évariste Galois foi um pioneiro na teoria dos grupos e álgebra abstrata. Suas contribuições incluem o desenvolvimento da teoria de Galois, que estabelece a relação entre raízes de equações polinomiais e simetrias de suas soluções. Galois também trabalhou com equações polinomiais de grau superior, proporcionando avanços cruciais na compreensão das soluções dessas equações."},{"question":"Escribe lo más importante de este texto: El coronel Piatyjin participó en la guerra soviético-finlandesa de 1939-1940 desde los primeros días. Durante la conducción de las hostilidades, su brigada, que formaba parte de la Fuerza Aérea del 13.° Ejército del Frente del Noroeste, realizó 1704 salidas de aviones de combate, pasando 7136 horas en el aire. Como resultado de las incursiones de la brigada en Víborg, Kexholm (actuak Priozersk), Sortavala y la base militar. en la isla de Valaam, el enemigo sufrió daños importantes. Iván Piatyjin dirigió personal y repetidamente a la brigada en la batalla, después de haber realizado 25 salidas durante la guerra. El 7 de abril de 1940, el coronel Iván Piatyjin recibió el título de Héroe de la Unión Soviética.","answer":"Lo más importante fue la guerra soviético-finlandesa"},{"question":"පීකි බ්ලයින්ඩර්ස් කතා මාලාවේ ශෙල්බි පවුලේ ව්‍යාපරවලදී නායකත්වය ගන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"ටොමී ෂෙල්බි"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air dicincang takkan putus\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya ialah pergaduhan antara adik-beradik tidak akan berterusan."},{"question":"Адам анын иштегенин каалайт. Бирок, иштеген кезде ачууланып өчүрүүгө шашылат бул эмне ?","answer":"Ойготкуч (будильник) саат ."},{"question":"२०१९ क्रिकेट विश्व कप में कितने टीमों ने हिस्सा लिया था और किस टीम ने यह जीत था ?","answer":"२०१९ क्रिकेट विश्व कप में दस टीमों ने हिस्सा लिया था। यह अंतर्राष्ट्रीय प्रतियोग्यता राउंड-रोबिन फॉर्मेट में था, जहां हर टीम एक दूसरे के साथ खेलती हैं। इस टूर्नामेंट का अंतिम राउंड न्यू ज़ीलैंड और इंग्लैंड के बीच में हुआ था । बाउंड्री काउंट के चलते यह टूर्नामेंट इंग्लैंड ने जीत लिया।यह इंग्लैंड की सबसे पहली ५० ओवर विश्व कप की जीत थी।  "},{"question":"અહીં ગુજરાતી નાટક ના કલાકારો વચ્ચેની વાતો નીચે મુજબ આપેલી છે:\\"કમા૦- શેઠ, હુમેરી ક્યા તકશીર? તુમેરા પાઊ દુખેગા ઓર મેં એકિલા તે કિતની ચંપી કરુંગા ?હજામ0 – સાળા, મુક્કિયો મારજેની. હું તો શરીર એમજ ચાંપું.નથ્થુ0 – બાવાડી ચસકી, વચમાં બકબક ન કર. એનું શરીર તો ચાંપાના છોડ જેવું છે.હજામ0 – બરાબર, કેમકે તેના પણ નશીબમાં ભમરનું સુખ નહિ લખેલું.નથ્થુ0 – એનું મ્હોં તો ગોળ લાડવોજ.હજામ0 – તારે બ્રાહ્મણને બહુ ભાવશે.નથ્થુ0 – અરે ! જુવાની તો વાડીની પેઠે ખીલી રહી છે!કમા૦- માલીકુ શિરપાવ દો. (ચંદા કહારની ગભરતી હતી તેની આંખમાં પાણી ભરાઈ આવે છે.) ઝુમ0 – બીન, બીન, ગાંડી ન થા . (ચ્હીડવાઈને) નથુશા, આ તમારા ઘરનો ઢંગ શો ? આ નીચ જાત તરકડાને અને ગાંયઝાને માથે શિદ ચ્હડાવી મ્હેલ્યાશે. હું કાંય મારી શોડીને ઠેકડી કરાવવા હિંયા નથી લાવ્યો.હજામ0 – ઠેકડી નહિ ઠઠ્ઠો.કમા૦- મ્હોં સમાલકર બોલ બે બકાલ ! અમકું નહિ પીછાનતા હૈ ? તેરા સીર તોડ ડાલુંગા.\\"આ કલાકારો ની આગળની વાતો શું હશે?","answer":"નથ્થુ0 – કમાલિયા ! કમાલિયા ! મત બોલ.ઝુમ0 – પીંજરડાને મીજાજ કેટલો છ !કમા૦- તેરા બાવા પીંજારા.નથ્થુ0 – અરે ! હં ! હં !ઝુમ0 – પીંજારડા, મને શુરતી દીઠો કે ? રોંડના તારૂં માથું જ ભાંજી નાખ્યો જો. ઓળખે છે મને.કમા૦- જા. જા. સાલ્લે , હીંગ તોલ, હીંગ તોલ.નથ્થુ૦ – (ચ્હીડીને) કમાલિયા ? મડવાનો થયોછ કે ?હજામ0 – કાકા , તમે પાછું તમારૂં કામ ચલાવો એટલે બધા ચૂપ રહેશે.નથ્થુ0 – રંગમાં ભંગ કરી નાંખ્યો. (પાછો ચંદા સામું જોવા લાગે છે.)ઝુમખશાહ, એના રૂપમાં તો કંઈ કસર નથી.કમા૦- (મનમાં) સાલે હીંગ તોલું અમ સિપાઈ બચ્ચેકું ગાલી બોલતા હૈ, જનમમેં કિસીકી ગાલી નહિ સુની હૈ.ઝુમ૦-મારે મ્હોડે શેઠ, વખાણ કરું તે શોભે નહિ, બાકી એવી ફુટડી શોડી અમારા આખા ગોમમાં કોય નથી.હજામ- ખરી કહોછો. અમારા આવા સુરતમાં કોઈ રામજણી પણ એવું રૂપ મ્હેં દીઠું નથી તો.નથ્થુ૦- ઝુમખશા, રૂપમાં કંઈ કસર નથી. લખ્યા કરતાં બેચંદા સરસ છે. એની કોટ કેવી છે ! પાની પીએ તો પણ દેખાય.ઝુમ૦- એતો શેઠ તમે ભૂલ્યા. તમારા શુરતી જેવા અમારા છોરૂ પોંગળાં નહિતો. એતો ધાબડધીંગા.નથ્થુ૦- અરે ઝુમખાંશાહ, હુંતો વખાણ કરૂં છું. અમારે ત્યાં કોઈ બૈરી ઘણી રૂપાળી હોય, ત્હારે તેને એમ કહેછે.કમા૦- સેઠ, એક મ્હેરી બાત સુન લો.ઝુમ૦- હુંઅ! વખાણ કરોછો ત્યારે તો ઠીક. પાણી પીએ ત્યારે પણ દેખાય છે, એ વાતતો ખરીછે.કમા૦- સેઠ, તુમ મેરી એક બાત સુનો. ક્યા દીવાના હોકર ઓ રંડીકી તારીફ.-નથ્થુ૦- કમ્બખત ! એને કંઈ કહેશે, તો તો હું કહાડીજ મુકીશ ને ચઢેલો પગારે નહિ આપું. કમા૦- સુનોતોસહી મેરી બાત. ઓ ગૂજરાતી બડા ચોર હૈં. તુમકું એ કમજાત ફિરેબ દેકર ફુસલાતા હૈં, એ લડકી તો મુંગી હૈં.નથ્થુ૦- હૈં !!હજામ-- અરેરે ! કહી દીધું કે!કમા૦- મ્હેં ઓ કમબખત કાફર કે મકાન પર ગયા થા, ઓ વખત ઈસકી સાથ ગાડીવાળા આયાથા ઈને અમકું કહ્યા, કે ઓ લડકી બોલ નહિ સકતી હૈ. મ્હેંને તઝવીઝ બોત કી આખર માલુમ પડા કે ઓ બાત સચહૈં. ફિર સાલેકી પાસ મ્હેં ગયા, ઓર પીછું બોલા કે તુમ ઐસેં દગા કરતેહો. ઓ બખત એ કમજાત બોલા કે \\"મિયાં શાહેબ, બોલશોમાં, બોલશોમાં, તમારો ગણ અમે નહિ વેસરિયે.\\"એસા બોલકર અમકુ પચીસ રૂપે દીએ.હજામ- કેમરે ભાયા ! આ વાત ખરી કે ?નથ્થુ૦- હેં ! આ સું ? એ બોલશે તોજ એની સાથે હું પહણીસ; નિકર એને નાંખો ઝાનમમાં!ઝુમ૦-ભાઈ સાહેબ, હું જૂઠું નથી બોલતો. એ શોડી જનમની તો મૂંગી નથી જો. મ્હારી આંખ્યોના સમ ! અંબાજીના સમ ! જો હું અશત બોલતો હોઊંતો.નથ્થુ૦- જોઊં કહાં બોલછ ? બોલાવોની.ઝુમ૦- શેઠ, જરા શોંસતા પડે, હું શુ કહુંશું તે તો કોંય શાંભલો, જનમને મુંગી નથી. હું ગોમ મ્હેલીને નેશર્યો, ત્યરની શોડી કુણ જાણે શું થયું બોલતી નથી. શેઠ, હું શોડી લઈને પાછો જાયો તેમાં તમારીને મારી બેઊની હોંશી થાશે. શોંસતા પડો. ધંતર મંતર કોંય કરીશું એટલે પરણ્યા પછે બે દનમાં શાજી થશે."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'memikul di bahu, menjunjung di kepala'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud melakukan kerja mengikut cara yang betul. Contoh ayat: Setiap kerja yang kita lakukan mestilah memikul di bahu, menjunjung di kepala barulah kerja itu mudah diselesaikan."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨੁ ਕਰਿ ਭਗਤ ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਏ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨਿ ਲਗਿ ਬੇਦ ਉਪਾਏ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨਿ ਭਏ ਸਿਧ ਜਤੀ ਦਾਤੇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨਿ ਨੀਚ ਚਹੁ ਕੁੰਟ ਜਾਤੇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨਿ ਧਾਰੀ ਸਭ ਧਰਨਾ ॥ਸਿਮਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਕਾਰਨ ਕਰਨਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨਿ ਕੀਓ ਸਗਲ ਅਕਾਰਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਮਹਿ ਆਪਿ ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰਾ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਜਿਸੁ ਆਪਿ ਬੁਝਾਇਆ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨੁ ਤਿਨਿ ਪਾਇਆ ॥੮॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 263 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਭਗਤ (ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ) ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਸਿਮਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਰਿਸ਼ੀਆਂ ਨੇ) ਵੇਦ (ਆਦਿਕ ਧਰਮ ਪੁਸਤਕ) ਰਚੇ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਿੱਧ ਬਣ ਗਏ, ਜਤੀ ਬਣ ਗਏ, ਦਾਤੇ ਬਣ ਗਏ;ਸਿਮਰਨ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਨੀਚ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਗਟ ਹੋ ਗਏ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਨੇ ਸਾਰੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਆਸਰਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ; ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਕਰਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਸਿਮਰ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੇ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ; ਜਿਥੇ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਹੈ ਓਥੇ ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰ ਆਪ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ (ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ) ਸਮਝ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ (ਦੀ ਦਾਤ) ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਈ ਹੈ ।੮।੧।\\""},{"question":"E-lista ang walo ka rarest minerals.","answer":"Ang walo ka rarest minerals kay Red Beryl, Paraiba Tourmaline, Alexandrite, Padparadscha Sapphire, Painite, Kashmir Sapphire, Red Diamond, og Jadeite."},{"question":"Кайда барба казандын кулагы бар. -дегенде эмнени түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Кайда барбагын эмгек кылсаң тиштейсиң, аракет жасасаң береке болот, жалкоо болсоң кайда барсаң да эки болбойсуң."},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto : Con la selección logró la medalla de plata en el Campeonato Mundial de Balonmano Masculino de 1967. Además, disputó los Juegos Olímpicos de Múnich 1972. Jugó en el Stadion IF.","answer":"El Campeonato Mundial de Balonmano Masculino de 1967. "},{"question":"cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuántos juegos de Call of Duty existen actualmente?","answer":"videojuegos"},{"question":"චලිත නියම තුන දියුණු කළ විද්‍යාඥයාගේ නම කුමක්ද?","answer":"චලිත නියම තුන දියුණු කළේ අයිසැක් නිව්ටන්ය"},{"question":"Ali menjual 253 bungkus nasi lemak dengan harga RM379.50. Berapakah harga satu bungkus nasi lemak? ","answer":"RM379.50/253 =RM1.50. Jadi, harga satu bungkus nasi lemak ialah RM1.50"},{"question":"Iya n run nimu awọn ileepo ti ko ba ta epo faraalu-Ogundoyin","answer":"O ṣee ṣe ki ijọba fiya jẹ awọn ileepo ti wọn ko ba ta bẹtiroolu fawọn araalu. Iyẹn bi wọn ba tẹle imọran ti Kọmiṣanna fọrọ iṣẹ ode ati eto irinna nipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ọjọgbọn Dauda Kẹhinde Ogundoyin, gba awọn DPP, iyẹn ajọ to n ri sì ìdíyelé epo bẹtiroolu nilẹ yii lati wa nnkan ṣe si ọrọ awọn ileepo ti wọn kọ láti ta epo.Nigba to n kopa lori eto ori redio aladaani kan nigboro Ibadan laaarọ ọjọ Ajé, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, Ọjọgbọn Ogundoyin sọ pe ijọba ko lọwọ si ọwọngogo epo bẹtiroolu tó wà níta bayii, awọn to n ta epo ni wọn kàn mọ-ọn-mọ tilẹkun mọ ọja wọn ti wọn si ṣe bẹẹ ko inira ba gbogbo araalu. Lati ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, lepo bẹtiroolu ti dọwọngogo pẹlu bi ọpọlọpọ ileepo ṣe kọ lati  taja fẹnikẹni nitori ti wọn ro pe epo maa gbowo lori latọdọ ijọba apapọ.Ero rẹpẹtẹ ati ọkẹ aimọye ohun irinṣẹ lo n to lati ra epo lawọn ileepo kọọkan ti wọn ba jaja ṣi ileetaja wọn, ti awọn eeyan si fẹẹ le maa lura wọn ki wọn too le ri epo ra titi dọsan ọjọ Mọnde ta a pari akojọ iroyin yii.Eyi lo fa a to jẹ pe ba a ṣe n wi yii, ohun gbogbo lo ti gbowo lori bayii pẹlu bi awọn ontaja ṣe n pariwo pe owo ti awọn fi wọ mọto lọọ raja ati eyi ti awọn fi ko o ki i ṣe kekere."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'manis seperti gula derawa'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud bersesuaian dalam semua hal (seperti suami isteri yang sama elok dan lain-lain)"},{"question":"Onye bụ Dora Akunyili?","answer":"Dora Nkem Akunyili  onye amụrụ ya na abali iri na anọ n'ọnwa asaa n'afọ 1954 – ya anwụọ n'abali asaa n'ọnwa isii na-afọ 2014 bụ onye Ntụziaka nke Ụlọ-ọru ndi (Director General) National Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control (NAFDAC) nile di na Naijiria. Bụkwara Onye isi Mgbasaozi nke ala Naijiria (Nigerian Minister of Information and Communications) site n'afọ 2008 ruo 2010. "},{"question":"Pergunta: quando é comemorado Australia Day? Resposta:","answer":"O feriado é comemorado no dia 26 de Janeiro"},{"question":"Bộ phận nào trên cơ thể giúp cho chúng ta có thể nghe thấy?A. MắtB. TaiC. MũiD. Miệng","answer":"Đáp án đúng: B"},{"question":"س212 - كم عدد الدول التي لها حق الفيتو في العالم ؟","answer":"ج212 - 5 دول"},{"question":"Wizkid, olorin taka-sufee, kan Aarẹ Buhari labuku","answer":"Afaimọ ki ọdọmọkunrin olorin taka-sufee nni, Ayọdeji Ibrahim Balogun, ẹni tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Wizkid ma wọ wahala ijọba pẹlu bo ṣe kan Aarẹ Muhammed Buhari labuku.Laipẹ yii ni arun Koronafairọọsi kọlu Aarẹ orilẹ-ede America, Donald Trump, ati iyawo ẹ, Melania, kaakiri agbaye si ni wọn ti n ki i, ti wọn n ṣadura fun un wi pe aisan ọhun ko ni i mọna ẹmi.Eyi naa ni Aarẹ Muhammed Buhari ṣe o, bo si ti gbe e sori ẹrọ abẹyẹfo rẹ, twitter, to ki Donald Trump, to si tun ṣadura fun un pe ki Ọlọrun tete mu un lara da, bẹẹ ni Wizkid naa gba ori ẹrọ abẹyẹfo rẹ, twitter lọ, nibẹ gan-an lo ti kan Aarẹ orilẹ-ede yii labuku. O kọ ọ sibẹ pe “Baba, ọrọ Donald Trump ko kan yin rara, awọn ọlọpaa atawọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ Sars ti wọn n pa awọn ọdọ ni Naijiria lojoojumọ ni kẹ ẹ ba wa mojuto, ko sohun to kan yin ninu ọrọ America, orilẹ-ede tiyin ni kẹ ẹ kọju mọ.”Bo ti ṣe kọ ọ niyẹn o, ohun tawọn eeyan si n sọ ni pe afaimọ ki ohun to ṣe yii ma di ọran si i lọrun, nitori ohun ti Buhari ṣe ki i ṣe ohun to buru rara. Wọn ni, kaakiri agbaye lawọn eeyan ti n ki Aarẹ Amẹrika, toun naa ba si ki i, eyi ko yẹ ko fa iru abuku bẹẹ.Bakan naa lawon mi-in sọ pe ko si wahala ninu ki eeyan sọ ero ọkan ẹ, ohun ti Wizkid ṣe, ero ọkan ẹ lo gbe jade. Ati pe ẹtọ ọmọniyan paapaa faaye gba a daadaa labẹ ofin."},{"question":"బెర్లిన్ వాల్ 1989 నవంబర్ 9న కూలిపోయిందిప్రచ్ఛన్న యుద్ధ సమయంలో కమ్యూనిస్టు ప్రాంతమైన తూర్పు యూరప్ నుంచి పశ్చిమ యూరప్‌లోకి ప్రజలు ప్రవేశించకుండా నిరోధిస్తూ నిర్మించిన బెర్లిన్ గోడ చరిత్రలో ప్రసిద్ధి చెందింది. మూడు దశాబ్దాల కిందట ఆ అడ్డుగోడను కూల్చివేశారు. ఆ చారిత్రక సందర్భాన్ని గుర్తు చేసుకుంటూ ప్రతి ఏటా సంబరాలు జరుపుకుంటుంటారు. కానీ బెర్లిన్ గోడను కూల్చివేసిన ముప్పై ఏళ్ల తర్వాత.. ఇప్పుడు యూరప్ ఖండమంతటా ప్రజలు స్వేచ్ఛగా సంచరించటాన్ని అడ్డుకుంటూ వందలాది కిలోమీటర్ల మేర కొత్తగా గోడలు నిర్మిస్తున్నారు. యూరప్ ఖండానికి వలసలతో ఉన్న క్లిష్టమైన సంబంధాలు దీనికి కేంద్ర బిందువు. ఈ అంశం.. ''విద్వేషపూరిత విధానాలు సాధారణంగా మారటానికి కారణమైంది.. ఆ విధానాల వల్ల సముద్రంలో ఎంతో మంది చనిపోయారు.. ఇంకెంతో మంది తీవ్ర కష్టాలపాలవుతున్నారు'' అని స్వచ్ఛంద వైద్య సేవా సంస్థ ఎంఎస్ఎఫ్ చెప్తోంది.కొన్ని యూరప్ దేశాలు వలసల విషయంలో మానవీయ కోణం కన్నా.. వాటి వల్ల తలెత్తే ఆర్థిక, రాజకీయ పర్యవసానాలకే అధిక ప్రాధాన్యమిస్తున్నట్లు కనిపిస్తోంది. అసలు వలసల పట్ల యూరప్ వైఖరులు ఎలా మారాయి? ఎందుకు మారాయి? బెర్లిన్ వాల్ ... Continue the article for another 4000 characters max:","answer":"చుట్టూ మందుపాతరలు, సాయుధ పహరా కూడా ఉండేదివిభజిత ఖండం రెండో ప్రపంచ యుద్ధం అనంతరం యూరప్ ఖండం.. కమ్యూనిస్టు (సామ్యవాద) తూర్పు ప్రాంతం - కాపిటలిస్ట్ (పెట్టుబడిదారీ) పశ్చిమ ప్రాంతంగా విడిపోయింది. తుర్పు ప్రాంతం (ఈస్ట్రన్ బ్లాక్)లో ప్రభుత్వాలు మరింత నిరంకుశంగా మారుతుంటే.. భారీ సంఖ్యలో ప్రజలు దానిని వ్యతిరేకిస్తూ పశ్చిమ ప్రాంతానికి వలస వచ్చారు. 1949 - 1961 మధ్య 27 లక్షల మంది తూర్పు జర్మనీ నుంచి పశ్చిమ జర్మనీకి వచ్చారు.సోవియట్ సారథ్యంలోని దేశాలు సరిహద్దు నియంత్రణను అత్యంత కఠినంగా మార్చాయి. విద్యుత్ కంచెలు వేయటం, మందుపాతరలు పాతటం, సాయుధ బలగాలను మోహరించటం వంటి చర్యలు చేపట్టాయి. ప్రజలు పశ్చిమ ప్రాంతానికి వెళ్లకుండా నిరోధించటానికి భీకరమైన బలప్రయోగం చేసేవి. ప్రచ్ఛన్న యుద్ధం ముగిసే సమయంలో బ్రిటన్ ప్రధానమంత్రిగా ఉన్న మార్గరెట్ థాచర్.. ఈస్ట్రన్ బ్లాక్ దేశాలు ''స్వేచ్ఛ, స్వాతంత్ర్యాలను నిరోధించటానికి క్రూరత్వాన్ని, ఆటవికత్వాన్ని ప్రదర్శించాయి'' అని వ్యాఖ్యానించారు. బెర్లిన్ గోడ నిర్మాణానికి కారణాలు ఏమిటి?ఆ చర్యల్లో అంత్యంత ప్రఖ్యాతి - లేదా అపఖ్యాతి - చెందినది బెర్లిన్ గోడ. జర్మనీ చరిత్రాత్మక రాజధానిని మధ్యకంటూ విభజిస్తూ 1961లో ఈ గోడను నిర్మించారు. ఈ గోడను దాటి వెళ్లటానికి ప్రయత్నిస్తూ 262 మంది చనిపోయారని బెర్లిన్ లోని ఫ్రీ యూనివర్సిటీ 2017లో నిర్వహించిన ఒక అధ్యయనం చెప్తోంది. బెర్లిన్ వాల్‌‌లో కొంత భాగం.. ఈ గోడను దాటే ప్రయత్నంలో చనిపోయిన వారికి స్మారక చిహ్నంగా మారిందిసాదర స్వాగతం తూర్పు ప్రాంతం నుంచి వలస వచ్చే వారిని పశ్చిమ ప్రాంత దేశాలు సాదరంగా ఆహ్వానించేవి. ప్రజల సంచారం మీద విధించిన ఆంక్షలను, వాటిని క్రూరంగా అమలు చేసే తీరును తీవ్రంగా ఖండించేవి. భారీ వలసలను నిరోధించే అడ్డుగోడలను, ఆంక్షలను వ్యతిరేకిస్తూ పశ్చిమ దేశాలు చేసిన వాదనలు, అనుసరించిన వైఖరులు.. చిరకాలం కొనసాగలేదు. ప్రచ్ఛన్న యుద్ధ దృక్కోణం నుంచి చూసినపుడు.. కమ్యూనిస్టు పాలనలో ఉన్న దేశాల ప్రజలు భారీ సంఖ్యలో తమ దేశాలను విడిచిపెట్టి.. తమకు సైద్ధాంతిక ప్రత్యర్థులైన ప్రభుత్వాల పాలనలోని దేశాలకు పారిపోవాలని భావించటం.. కమ్యూనిస్టు దేశాలకు రాజకీయంగా అవమానకరంగా ఉండింది. అదేసమయంలో పశ్చిమ యూరప్ ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థలు వేగంగా అభివృద్ధి చెందుతుండేవి. నిరుద్యోగిత స్థాయిలు అతి తక్కువగా ఉండేవి. ఆ దేశాల్లో కార్మికుల కొరతను.. ఈ వలసలు తీర్చేవి. "},{"question":"Pirmasis Lietuvos himno žodis yra \\"Lietuva\\". O koks yra paskutinis Lietuvos himno žodis?","answer":"Tebežydi (\\"Vardan tos Lietuvos vienybė težydi\\")."},{"question":"ஓர் ஒழுங்கு முறையில் தொகுக்கப்பட்ட ஒரே தொகை நூல் எது?","answer":"     எட்டுத் தொகை நூல்களுள் குறுந்தொகை, நற்றிணை, அகநானூறு, ஐங்குறுநூறு, கலித்தொகை ஆகிய ஐந்தும் அகம் பற்றியன. இவற்றுள் அகம் என்னும் சொல்லால் குறிக்கப்படுவது அகநானூறு மட்டுமே. அகத் த்தொகையுள் நீண்ட பாடல்களைக் கொண்டமையால் இதனை, 'நெடுந்தொகை' என்றும் கூறுவர்.     கடவுள் வாழ்த்துச் செய்யுளைத் தவிர்த்து இந்நூலில் 400 பாடல்கள் உள்ளன. இவை களிற்றியானை நிரை(1-120), மணி மிடை பவளம் (121-300), நித்திலக் கோவை (301-400) என மூன்று பெரும் பகுதிகளாகப் பிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. இதுவல்லாமல் பாடல்கள் அனைத்தும் தக்கதொரு நியமத்தைக் கொண்டமைந்துள்ளன. ஒற்றைப்பட எண்ணாலான பாடல்கள் 200-ம் பாலைத் திணையைச் சேர்ந்தவை. இரட்டைப்பட எண்களில் 2,8 எனப்படுபவை 80-ம் குறிஞ்சித் திணையைச் சேர்ந்தவை. இரட்டைப்பட எண்களில் 4 எனப்படுபவை 40-ம் முல்லைத் திணையைச் சேர்ந்தவை. இரட்டைபட எண்களில் 6 எனப்படுபவை 40-ம் மருதத் திணையைச் சேர்ந்தவை. இரட்டைப்பட எண்களில் 10 எனப்படுபவை 40-ம் நெய்தல் திணையைச் சேர்ந்தவை.     இத் தொகையைத் தொகுத்தவர் மதுரை உப்பூரிகுடி கிழார் மகனார் உருத்திரசன்மர். இதனைத் தொகுப்பித்த மன்னன் பாண்டியன் உக்கிரப் பெருவழுதியார். இத் தொகை பாடிய புலவர்கள் நூற்று நாற்பத்தைவர். அகநானூற்றுப் புலவர்கள் 146 பேர். அவர்களுள் 65 பேர் அகநானூற்றில் மட்டுமே பாடல் பாடியுள்ளார்கள். நாடாள்வோர், அந்தணர், இடையர், எயினர், பொற்கொல்லர், வணிகர், வேளாளர் எனப் பல தரப்பினர் புலவர்களாக இருந்த செய்தி அவர் தம் பெயர்களின் முன்னால் அமையும் அடைமொழிகளால் தெரிகிறது. மூன்று பாடல்களின் (114, 117, 165) ஆசிரியர் பெயர் காணப் பெறவில்லை.ஓர் ஒழுங்கு முறையில் தொகுக்கப்பட்ட ஒரே தொகை நூல் அகநானூறுஎன்று கூறுவர் .அகநானூறு எட்டுத்தொகை எனப்படும் சங்ககாலத்தமிழ் நூல் தொகுப்பில் உள்ள ஒரு நூலாகும். இந்நூல் அகத்திணை சார்ந்த நானூறு பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பாக விளங்குவதால் அகநானூறு என வழங்கப்படுகிறது. இதற்கு நெடுந்தொகை என்ற மற்றொரு பெயரும் உண்டு. இதில் அடங்கியுள்ள பாடல்கள் பல்வேறு காலங்களில் வாழ்ந்த பல்வேறு புலவர்கள் பாடிய பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பாகும். எட்டுத்தொகை நூல்களுள் குறுந்தொகை, நற்றிணை, அகநானூறு, ஐங்குறுநூறு, கலித்தொகை ஆகிய ஐந்தும் அகப்பொருள் பற்றியன. ஆயினும் அவற்றுள் அகம் என்னும் சொல்லால் குறிக்கப்படுவது அகநானூறு மட்டுமே. இந்நூல் 13 அடி சிற்றெல்லையும் 31 அடி பேரெல்லையும் கொண்ட நீண்ட பாடல்களைக் கொண்டிருப்பதால் இதனை, 'நெடுந்தொகை' (நெடுமை+தொகை, நெடிய அல்லது நீண்ட பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பு) என்றும் கூறுவர்."},{"question":"Gorfayn soo koobid.","answer":"GORFEYN/SOO KOOBID.Dhiganaha \\"Salaad baa I dhaaftay\\" oo uu Qoray qoraaga Carbeed  ee Islaam Jamaal uuna Turjumay mahadi ha ka gaadhee Cabdulxakiim Muxamad Obsiiye.Waxaan dhihi karaa  buugaagtii aan aqriye kii ugu qiimaaha badnaa buu ahaa, waana ku faa'idey waliba si baraatigaal ah,  waa buug  kugu saacidaayo waliba  qeyb weyn ka qaadanaayo u dhawaanshiyaha  Alle SWT. Saaladu waa camalka koowaad ee la iska xisaabin doono khiyaamah,  hadii ee salaadaada hagaagto waxaa hagaagi donaa dhaamaan aduunkagaa iyo Aaqiradaada,  Kaliya kama hadlaayo buugaan tukasha salaad ama ilaalinteeda Sidoo  kale waxa uu ka hadlaa waaqiciga  nolosha caadiga ah  waxaa uuna ku siinaa tabooyin/ dariiqyo kugu hagaayo inaad ahaato qof maareeya aduunkiisa kana faaideysto waqtiqiisa.Buuga salaad baa I dhaaftay waxa uu ka koobaan yahay  15  Cutub iyo 157 bog.Waxaan qof kasto u soo jeedin/ kula talin lahaa inuu buugaas aqristo waayo waa buug muhiim ah kaas oo lagu soo koobi karin qormooyin faa'iidada ku jirdha waxaan ku isku dayi doonaa inaa  qodobeeyo  oo ku soo  koobo ilaa 25 qodob waxyaabahii aan ka kororsaday dhiganahaan:-1.  In Dadka ilaasha saladaha oo ku tukada xiliyadeeda eena ka dhigneen in ee adiga kaa duwan yihiin ama ee leeyihiin hibo u gooni ah oo Alle siiye oo u fududeyneyso inee ilaashaan salaad ama ku tukadaan masaajida.2. In Dadka ilaasha saladaha eena kaa fursado badneyn,  oo qaarkooda laga yaabo inee habeenki dhan ama badankiisa  soo jeedeyn salaad subax na masjidka  yimadaaan.3. In oraahda aan nafteena badankeen ugu sheekeyno oo ah \\"Maalin Uun\\" waa yeeli doonaa  ee galaafan karto Aqiradeena iyo aduunkeen,  waayo naftu meelna ma jirto hadii aa tiraah MAALI UUN waa tukan doonaa ood dhimatay iyadoo la gaarin  xaalkaaga halkuu ku denbeyn doonaa!4.  Adeegso gefafkaaga! Wax ka baro gefafkaaga maalinlaha ah ee idin kala irdheeyay adiga iyo salaadaha. Furfur oo falanqee gefafkaaga kana dheerow in aad ku laabato mar kale.5. In Muuqaal ahaan salaadaha iney u ekayd mid lagu waajibiyay aadanaha, balse runtu waxey tahay waa hibo iyo hadiyada  cid wax jeceli siiso jaceylkeeda 6. In si aad u ilaaliso salaadaha, xirfadda ugu horreyso ee loo bahaanyahay ee tahay barshadda  ILAAHAY SWT weynidiisa, hadii aad barato isaga waa jecleyneysaa hadaa jecelaatana,   amarkiisa ayaad fulineysaa. jacaylka Alle waxa uu ku xidhan yahay jacaylka salaadaha markasto ood jecelaato salaadaha waa mar walba oo uu isgana ku jeclaado,   sidoo kale aad maalin walba 15- 30 dhageysato qof kaaga sheekeynaa Weynida Alle.7.  Inaad kaa faaideysato xasuusahaagi qurxoonaa ee Salaadaha, ka dibna kaga faa'ideyso xeelad aad ku bedesho hummaga xun ama waswaaska ku jira maskaaxdaada.8. In Xakameynta nafta ee asal u tahay ilaalinta salaadaha, xakameynta naftu waxa ay kaa dhigeysaa shaqsi jaad gooni ah,  xakameynta naftu; waa in aad ku qabato shaqada ku sugeyso waqtigeydii aad u astaysay jeclow ama ha jeclaanee.9. In aadan la tashan maankaaga marka aad maqasho eedanka salaaddda, garaadkaaga far in uu aamuso horena ka weysayso, ka dibna toos u tag masjidka.10.  Maree maalinkaaga!  in ee suurtagal aheyn  salaadda in aad u ilaaliso habka ugu wanaagsan, Haddii aad ka mid tahay dadka ku baraaruga eedanka, maaraynta wanaagsani waxa ay kaa caawinaysa ilaalinta salaadaha.11. In mar walba baahidaada u raadsato Ilaaha hodanka ah ee iska leh keydadka cirka iyo dhulalka, inta aad wax u raadsan leheyd ruux adiga kula mid ah, dhaqan ka dhigo inaad baahiyahaaga oo dhan u bandhigato Alle SWT. 12. In Alle yahay Falsame \\"xakiim\\" marka aad barido kuu dooraayo talada toosan, marna kaa hor istaagayo arin aan Dan kugu jirin lkn adiga aa wanaag u aragto.13. In badankeen salaadaha howl maalmeed noo noqotay oo aana ku bixinin dadaal dheeri ah , inagoo  la halgamin caqliyadeena ayaanu qorsheynaaya weysada ka dibna aadnaa salaad.   salaadu waxey u bahaan tahay maan iyo maskax xaadir ah!14. Hogasha salaada \\"khushuucdu\\" waxaa laga dhaxlaaa xasilooni kugu dhiirigelisa qofka inuu u boholyoobo tukashadeeda, haddaba maxaa kugu saacidaayo Hogashada:-Waxyaabaha keena Khushuucdu waxaa ka mid ah dhaqdhaqaaqa gacmaha oo la yareeyo laga bilaawo xidhashada salaada, AQRIS degan oo aad la timaado inta karaankaaga ah iyo dhuuxista macanaha Aayad Quraanka ah sidaa kale inaad ku xasisho Rukuucda iyo Sujuudda.15.  In marka aad tukaneee aad ka soo qaado ood sawirato  ina aad Allaha boqorka ah la faqeyso oo la sheekeysaneyso.16.   In kicida xili hore subaxdii \\"jarmaade\\" ee ku jirto sacaad ama laba saac oo mucjisa ah taas oysan  jirin wax loo dhigo ood ku qabsan karto howl kuu muhiim ah sidoo kale aad ku oogeyso salaada mucjisada  \\"salaada subax\\".  17. In aad horistaagto Allaha awooda badan adiga oo tukanaayo labada rakcadooda ee ka horreeya salaada subax taas oo ka wanaag badan waxa dunida ku dhex sugan oo dhan.    Sidoo kale Salaada Duxaada \\"Salaadtu altawaabiin\\" waxa ee ka mid tahay salaadaha Sunnada ah ee fadliga dheeraadka ku soo arooray, waxaa la tukadaa marka qoraxdu soo baxdo waran in la eg ilaa barqadi laga gaadho, ugu yaraan laba rakcadooda sida fadliga badan waa afar rakcadood.18.  Loolanka Gogosha, Dayax gacmeedka waxa uu adeegsadaa shidaal badan daqiiqda u horeyso duulimaadka sababato ah waxaa ku adkaanaayo cuf'isjiidka , sidaa waxaa la mid ah adiga markaa u kaceyso salaada subax!19. In Sababta ugu weyn ee keena salaad la'aanta ama dayacida waa qorsho la'aanta. qorshe la'aantu, nafta iyo sheydaanka ayay sisaa fursad ay kugu soo galaan; salaadahana waa aad dib dhigidooontaa! 20.  In aad naftaada u sheegto waqtigani in uu tagaayo  hadii aad wahsato salaada subax waqtiga joogsaneen oodan sii jiifeyn hurdadaas yar ee macaan dhamaaneyso oo kaceyso ugu danbeyn.21.  In ku Ilaalinta salaadaha waqtigooda,  ama shey kale in ee fududeyn bilwoga hore sidoo kale ee culus tahay inaad sii joogteyso. 22. In Weysada  uu jirka ka helo caafimaad.  waqtiga weysada, isbedelo weyn ayaa ku dhaca jidhka xiliga ay biyaha qabow xubnaha jirka garaan waxaan yaaraada dhiigga dhexmara xubnaha waayo heerkulkaaga ayaa hoos u dhaca hadda  si uu iskugu dheelitirmo heer-kulka guud ee jidhka waxaa xoogeysto dhiiga ku qulqulaayo xubnaha, waxaa aanay dareemtaa firfircooni dheeri ah.  23. In Tegista Masjidka,Rukuucda iyo Sujuuda  jirka waxa uu kala helaa dhaqdhaqaaq murqaha aha  ama jimicsi kaas  oo ilaalinaayo caafimaadkaaga.24. Salaadaha sunada.  maalinkii iyo habeenkii qofka tukada 12 rakacadood oo aan waajib aheyn, guri ayaa looga dhisaa Jannada  dhexdeeda,   Salaadah sunada laga ma dhisto guri aadduun laakiin waxaa lagu dhaxlaa mid ku yaala jannada!25.  Ku Joogteynta salaadaha waqtigooda waxey u baahantahay dhabar adeeg iyo inaad ku fara adeygto korkeeda,adkaysigu waa xeer gun- dhig u ah guusha."},{"question":" Дүйнөдөгү эң узак жашаган адам ким? ","answer":"Жанна Калмент"},{"question":"வினா: வயது வந்த மனிதனுக்கு எத்தனை எலும்புகள் உள்ளன?","answer":"விடை: 206"},{"question":"Rangarira ndima iri pasi apa uye ipapo pindura mubvunzo gare gare mumutauro mumwe chetewo sechikamu:  Passage: Kukwanisa kuenda kuFIFA Women's World Cup 2007 kwakaratidza kuti zvikwata zvipi gumi neshanu zvakabatana neChina, varidzi vemakwikwi e2007, kuti vatambe muFIFA Women's World Cup. Europe yakanga ine nzvimbo 5 dzakakodzera, Asia 3.5 nzvimbo (kusanganisira vanogamuchira), North neCentral America 2.5 nzvimbo, Africa 2 nzvimbo, South America 2 nzvimbo uye Oceania 1 nzvimbo. Nzvimbo yechi16 yakasarudzwa kuburikidza nemutambo wekutamba pakati pezvikwata zvechitatu-zvakaiswa muNorth / Central America neAsia.  Mubvunzo: Africa yaiva nenzvimbo dzakakodzera dzakawanda sei?","answer":"Mundima iyi, zvinonzi Africa yaive nzvimbo mbiri dzakakodzera kupinda mumakwikwi eFIFA Women’s World Cup 2007. Izvi zvinoreva kuti zvikwata zviviri zvemuAfrica zvaikodzera kupinda mumakwikwi aya. Ndima iyi inopa ruzivo pamusoro pehuwandu hwenzvimbo dziripo dzezvikwata kubva kumatunhu akasiyana, uye panguva iyi, Africa yakapihwa nzvimbo mbiri zvichienderana negwara rekuti vakwanise kukwikwidza."},{"question":"Kedu egwuregwu eji mara Patience Okoro?","answer":"Patience Okoro (amụrụ na 10 Julaị 1984) bụ nwaanyi onye ọsọ egwurewgu. Ọ nọchiri Naijiria na asompi ụlọ ma na mba ọzọ. Ọ meriri ola edo na egwuregu nke 2008 Afrika emere na Addis Ababa, Ethiopia."},{"question":"ගතානුගතික යුදෙව් ආගම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"යුදෙව්වන්ගේ සම්ප්‍රදායික ආගම යුදෙව් ආගමයි. නූතන යුදෙව් ආගම ඇදහිලිවලට වඩා ජීවන රටාව සහ වටිනාකම් අවධාරණය කරන ආගමකි, එබැවින් ධර්මය හැසිරීම තරම්ම අවධාරණය නොකෙරේ. බොහෝ යුදෙව්වන් ධර්මශාලාවකට (සිනගෝගයකට) ඔවුන්ගේ සම්බන්ධතාවය පවත්වා ගෙන යන අතර ඇතැම් යුදෙව් පිළිවෙත් සහ සම්ප්‍රදායන් දිගටම නිරීක්ෂණය කරන අතරම ඔවුන්ගේ විශේෂිත යුදෙව් ආගමේ ඉගැන්විය හැකි බොහෝ මූලධර්ම ප්‍රතික්ෂේප කරති.සාධාර්මික (ඕතඩොක්ස්) යුදෙව් ආගම යුදෙව් ආගමේ එකම ස්වරූපය වූ කාලයක් තිබුණි. අද යුදෙව් ආගමට ප්‍රධාන “ශාඛා” තුනක් ඇත: සාධාර්මික (ඕතඩොක්ස්) (ඉතා සම්ප්‍රදායික), ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණ (ලිබරල් හෝ ප්‍රගතිශීලී ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ) සහ ගාතානුගතික, අනෙක් දෙක අතර මැද මාවතක් ගනී. ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, ප්‍රධාන ශාඛා තුන අතර ශාඛා, වෙනස්කම් සහ දෙමුහුන් පවා ඇත. බොහෝ ධර්මශාලා (සිනගෝග) තමන්ව ශාඛා තුනෙන් එකක් ලෙස නම් කරයි, එය සභාවක් නිකාය නාමයක් භාවිතා කරන ආකාරය හා සමානයි.ගතානුගතිකයින් එක් අතකින් සම්ප්‍රදාය සමතුලිත කිරීමට උත්සාහ කරන අතර අනෙක් පැත්තෙන් නවෝත්පාදනයන් වෙනස් කරයි. මෙය තරමක් අපැහැදිලි සම්මතයකි, එබැවින් දේවධර්මවාදී විශ්වාසයන් සහ භාවිතයන් ගතානුගතිකවරුන් අතර පුළුල් ලෙස වෙනස් වේ. ඇත්ත වශයෙන්ම, බහුත්වවාදය ඉහළ අගයක් ගන්නා බැවින් සහ ප්‍රබලවාදයෙන් වැළකී සිටින බැවින්, දේවධර්ම එකඟතාවය අවශ්‍ය නොවේ. ගතානුගතිකයින් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් දෙවියන්වහන්සේගේ මැවුම්කරු සහ ලෝකයට මග පෙන්වන්නා ලෙස තරමක් සාමාන්‍ය ධර්මයක් දරයි, නමුත් ඉන් ඔබ්බට නොවේ.කලක් එක්සත් ජනපදයේ යුදෙව් ආගමේ විශාලතම ශාඛාව වූ ගතානුගතික යුදෙව් ආගම එක්සත් ජනපදයේ පිරිහෙමින් පවතින නමුත් යුරෝපයේ වැඩිවෙමින් පවතී. එය ශීඝ්‍රයෙන් යල්පැනෙමින් පවතින බව ඇතැම් විචාරකයෝ පවසති. එය අධිකාරියට තොල් සැපයුවද, එය සංස්කෘතියේ වෙනස්වන සුළඟට ඉඩ සලසයි."},{"question":"ஆண் தன் குட்டிகளைப் பெற்றெடுக்கும் ஒரே விலங்கு எது?","answer":"விடை: கடல் குதிரைகள்"},{"question":"గౌతమీపుత్ర శాతకర్ణి గొప్పతనాన్ని అంచనా వేయండి.","answer":"శాతవాహన పాలకులలో గౌతమీపుత్ర శాతకర్ణి (క్రీ.శ. 78-102) 23వ వాడు. ఇతని తల్లి గౌతమీ బాలశ్రీ వేయించిన నాసిక్ శాసనం వలన ఇతని ఘనతను తెలుసుకోవచ్చు. ఈ శాసనం వలన ఇతడు శక, యవన, పహ్లవ, క్షహరాట వంశాలను నాశనం చేశాడని, శాతవాహన వంశ ప్రతిష్టను పునరుద్ధరించాడని తెలుస్తున్నది. గౌతమీ బాలశ్రీ మరొక నాసిక్ శాసనంలో తాను గొప్ప చక్రవర్తికి తల్లినని, మరొక రాజుకు “మహారాజ పితామహి”నని చెప్పుకుంది. దీనిని బట్టి శాతకర్ణి గొప్ప యుద్ధవీరుడని తెలుస్తున్నది. ఇతడు అనేక క్షత్రియ రాజవంశాలను జయించి “క్షత్రియ దర్పమానమర్ధన” అనే బిరుదు ధరించాడు. మూడు సముద్రాల మధ్య ప్రాంతాన్ని జయించి “త్రిసముద్రతోయ పీతవాహన” అను బిరుదును ధరించాడు. మహారాష్ట్ర, ఉత్తర కొంకణ, సౌరాష్ట్ర, మాళవ, విదర్భ రాజ్యాలు ఇతని ఆధీనంలో ఉన్నాయి. నాసిక్ శాసనాల వలన గౌతమీపుత్ర శాతకర్ణి ప్రజల కష్టసుఖాలను తెలుసుకొని న్యాయబద్ధంగా పన్నులు విధించేవాడని, పేదవారికి, బ్రాహ్మణులకు భూదానాలు చేసేవాడని తెలుస్తున్నది. ఈ శాసనాలే గౌతమీపుత్ర శాతకర్ణికి వర్ణవ్యవస్థ మీద ప్రగాఢమైన నమ్మకముందని, బ్రాహ్మణ కులాన్ని వర్ణసంకరం కాకుండా రక్షించాడని, “ఏకబ్రాహ్మణుడు” అనే బిరుదు ధరించాడని పేర్కొన్నాయి. ఇతడికి ఉన్న “ఆగమనిలయ” అను బిరుదు వల్ల ఇతనికి ఆగమశాస్త్రాలపై అవగాహన ఉన్నట్లు తెలుస్తున్నది. ఈ కారణాల వలన గౌతమీపుత్ర శాతకర్ణి శాతవాహనుల్లో గొప్పవాడని చెప్పవచ్చు."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Ny teny toy ny voantsilo tsy afa-day: ...............................................  \\" ","answer":"\\" Ny teny toy ny voantsilo tsy afa-day: mamy fa sarotra entina \\""},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළේ  තේරුම කුමක්ද?සෙක්කුවේ බැන්ද හරකා වගේ.","answer":"විවේකයක් නොගෙන එකදිගටම වැඩ කිරීම. එකම රටාවකට ජිවත්වන පුද්ගලයන් සදහා මෙම ප්‍රස්ථාව පිරුල භාවිත් කෙරේ."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Samoa?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Samoa mu ngi tudd Apia."},{"question":"句子1: 压力往往通过一个小的导管从上游 (被保护的系统) 供应到圆顶. 句子2:从上游 (供应系统) 到圆顶的压力通常由一个小的导管保护. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"මැටිවලට සමාන පදයක් දෙන්න පුලුවන් ද?","answer":"මෘච්ඡ"},{"question":"Kañ la Federb faatu ?","answer":"28 sattumbar 1889."},{"question":"नेवार महिलाहरुको परम्परागत पहिरनमा \\"हर\\" र \\"पाटुका\\" गहनाको महत्व वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"हर एक परम्परागत हार हो, र पटुका कम्मरपट्टी हो, दुबै नेवार महिलाहरु को परम्परागत पोशाक को एक महत्वपूर्ण घटक को रूप मा लगाइन्छ।"},{"question":"චේ ගුවේරා  කවුද?","answer":"චේගුවේරා ආර්ජන්ටිනාවේ මාක්ස්වාදී විප්ලවවාදියෙක්, වෛද්‍යවරයෙක්, ලේඛකයෙක්, ගරිල්ලා නායකයෙක්, රාජ්‍ය තාන්ත්‍රිකයෙක් සහ හමුදා න්‍යායාචාර්යවරයෙක් විය. ඔහු කියුබානු විප්ලවයේ ප්‍රධාන භූමිකාවක් ඉටු කළේය.1928 ජුනි මස 14 වන දින ආජන්ටිනාවේ රෝසරියෝ නගරයේ උපත ලද චේ හට කුඩා කල පටන් ඇදුම රෝගයෙන් පීඩා විඳීමට සිදු විය. වසර නවයක් ගතවනතුරු පාසල් යාමට නොහැකි වීමට ඔහුගේ රෝගී තත්වය හේතු විය. නමුත් ඉන් කිසි විටෙක පසුබට නොවූ චේ රෝගී තත්වය පසෙකලා පාසල් වියේදී පාපන්දු, ගොල්ෆ්, රගර් මෙන්ම චෙස් ක්‍රීඩාවෙන් ද දක්ෂතා පෑවේය. "},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fiteny fandaharana?","answer":"Ny fiteny fandaharana dia andiana fitsipika sy marika ampiasaina hanoratana toromarika izay ho adikan'ny solosaina iray hanao asa na programa."},{"question":"Калдвел жөнүндө эмне айта аласыз?","answer":"Калдвелл механик катары квалификациядан өткөндөн кийин Макларенге 1967 - жылы Италиянын Улуу Премиясына катышкан. Кийинчерээк ал команданын техникалык жетекчиси болуп дайындалган. Анын айдоочулары Эмерсон Фиттипальди, Джеймс Хант жана Джохен Масс. Ал унаалардын дизайнына, өндүрүшүнө жана жарышка даярдалышына катышкан жана унааларды жеңилдетүү үчүн аба стартердин ойлоп табуучусу болгон, ошондой эле алтынчы ылдамдыкты киргизген, төмөнкү күчтү жана команданын формаларын көбөйтүү үчүн, буга чейин кийген комбинезондордун жана башка кийимдердин ордун толтуруу үчүн."},{"question":"Босого деген эмне ?","answer":"Босого - эшиктин кире бериш жерин \\"Босого\\" деп коюшат.  Кыргыз элинде босогого отурба, босогону аттаба деген сөздөр бар. "},{"question":"उत्तर पूर्व भारतातील सर्वात मोठे तलाव ‘लोकताक’ कोणत्या राज्यात आहे?(A) मेघालय(B) त्रिपुरा(C) मणिपूर(D) मिझोरम=>","answer":" (C) मणिपूर"},{"question":"தெய்வநாயகத்திற்கு உலகத்தமிழ் ஆராய்ச்சிக் கழகம் கொடுத்த பட்டம் எது?","answer":"தெய்வநாயகத்திற்கு உலகத்தமிழ் ஆராய்ச்சிக் கழகம் கொடுத்த பட்டம் தமிழ் மணி."},{"question":"Ta lo f’ọbẹ dúḿbú Oluwatoyin niluu Okuku, awọn ọlọpaa bẹrẹ iwadii nla","answer":"Wọn kan ba a ninu ọgbara ẹjẹ ninu ile rẹ ni. Oluwatoyin Afọlabi! Wọn ti dumbu ẹ bii ẹran. Ko si ẹni to mọ ẹni to ṣe bẹẹ fun un.Ṣugbon alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ni ipinlẹ Ọṣun, ASP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, ti sọ fun Alaroye pe iwadii ti bẹrẹ lori iku to pa Oluwatoyin, ẹni ọdun marunlelaaadọta, yii niluu Okuku, nijọba ibilẹ Odo-Ọtin.Gẹgẹ bi Ọpalọla ṣe wi, aarọ ana, Wẹsidee, ni ọkunrin kan, Adejimi Abiọdun, lọ si agọ ọlọpaa ilu naa lati fi to wọn leti nipa iku abami to pa obinrin ọhun.O ni niṣe ni wọn ṣaa deede ba Oluwatoyin ninu agbara ẹjẹ pẹlu ọrun rẹ ti wọn dunbu bii ẹwurẹ nile rẹ to wa lagbegbe Aro Oyebọde niluu Okuku.Nigba ti awọn ọlọpaa debẹ, wọn gbe oku obinrin naa lọ sile igbokuupamọsi ni ọsibitu Ọlanrewaju Medical Center niluu ọhun.Ko si ẹnikẹni ti wọn ti i mu gẹgẹ bii afurasi lori ọrọ yii, ṣugbọn kọmisanna ọlọpaa, Undie J Adie, ti paṣẹ pe ki awọn ẹka to n ṣewadii iwa ọdaran bẹrẹ iṣẹ lori ẹ."},{"question":"Determine if the following statement expresses happiness, sadness, anger, or fear.Statement: “I broke my phone ;(”","answer":"The previous statement indicates sadness. You are sad that your phone is not working!"},{"question":"Wọn tun fi diẹ silẹ ninu awọn ọmọleewe Baptist ti wọn ji ko, wọn lawọn n reti owo awọn  to ku","answer":"Binu obi awọn ọmọleewe kan ṣe n dun, ti wọn n ki ara wọn ku ewu bii aja to re’le ẹkun to bọ, bẹẹ lawọn obi mi-in n wa ẹkun mu nipinlẹ Kaduna lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, latari pe awọn ọmọ wọn ṣi wa ninu igbekun awọn janduku agbebọn, wọn o tu wọn silẹ.Ọsan ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹjọ yii, lawọn afẹmiṣofo naa yọnda mejidinlọgbọn ninu awọn ọmọleewe Bethel Baptist to wa lagbegbe ijọba ibilẹ Chikun, nipinlẹ Kaduna, lẹyin ti wọn ti wa nigbekun wọn fun ọjọ mejilelaaadọta gbako.Taara ni wọn ko awọn ọmọ naa lọ sileewe ọhun, nibi ti wọn ti ni kawọn obi wọn wọn waa pade ọmọ kaluku.Tẹkun-tomije lawọn obi naa fi n ki awọn ọmọ wọn kaabọ, bi wọn ṣe n dupẹ pe iku aitọjọ re awọn ọmọ naa kete, bẹẹ ni wọn n kẹdun latari ohun tawọn majeṣin wọnyi foju wina rẹ lakata awọn agbebọn laarin oṣu meji o di ọsẹ kan ti wọn ti wa nibẹ.Ọjọ karun-un, oṣu keje, ọdun yii, lawọn agbebọn naa ya bo ileewe awọn ọmọ naa, ti wọn si fipa ji okanlelọgọfa (121) gbe sa lọ ninu wọn. Wọn fi mejidinlọgbọn lara awọn ọmọ naa silẹ lọjọ kẹẹẹdọgbọn, oṣu keje, lẹyin ti wọn ti gba owo rẹpẹtẹ lọwọ awọn obi wọnWọn tun da awọn mẹẹẹdogun mi-in silẹ lọsẹ to kọja, ko too kan awọn ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ fi silẹ yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe niṣe lawọn kan lara awọn obi awọn ọmọleewe naa lọọ ta ilẹ, oko ati ile wọn ki wọn le rowo tawọn ajinigbe naa n beere fun san tori ọmọ wọn, bẹẹ lawọn obi ti agbara wọn ko gbe e lati san owo itusilẹ bu sẹkun tori wọn lawọn o mọ’na abayọ si riri ọmọ tiwọn naa gba pada."},{"question":"Em qual jogo oficial do Sonic você pode jogar como Knuckles e foi desenvolvido por desenvolvedores que eram antigos fãs?","answer":" Sonic Mania"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mabuk kerana beruk berayun'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud asyik memerhatikan sesuatu yang tidak berguna dengan menghabiskan masa"},{"question":"4 సం||ల క్రితం నా వయస్సు, 5 సం||ల తరువాత నా వయస్సుల మొత్తం 36 సం||. “ప్రస్తుతం నా వయస్సు x సం||.”పై సమాచారాన్ని సూచించే రేఖీయ సమీకరణాన్ని రాయండి.","answer":"(x – 4) + (x + 5) = 36∴ 2x + 1 = 36 ⇒ 2x – 35 = 0"},{"question":"Ọláídé Ọláògún ","answer":"Ọláídé Ọláògún tí a tún mọ̀ sí Ọláídé Omololá Ọláògún Emmanuel tí wọ́n bí lọ́jọ́ kẹsàn-án oṣù kẹfà ọdún 1986,(July 9, 1986) jẹ́ Òṣèrébìnrin, Afẹ́wà-ṣojú àti Atọ́kùn ètò ọmọ Nàìjíríà. Ó ti fìgbà kan jẹ́ Afẹ́wà-ṣojú oṣẹ LuWọ́n bí Ọláídé Ọláògún ní ìlú Èkó lọ́jọ́ kẹsàn-án oṣù kẹfà ọdún 1986. Ó kàwé ní African Church Model College. Bẹ́ẹ̀ náà ló kàwé gboyè nínú èdè Òyìnbó ní University of Lagos.Ó di gbajúmọ̀ òṣèré ní Nàìjíríà àti Ghana nígbà tí ó kópa nínú eré kan tí Wale Adenuga gbé jáde lórí tẹlifíṣàn, ti àkọlé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ \\"Soul Sisters\\" and she was also in the Yoruba series Super Story.Lọ́dún 2007, ó gba ipò Genevieve Nnaji gẹ́gẹ́ bí afoge-ṣojú nínú ìpolówó-ọjà ọṣẹ Lux and continued in this role until 2009. Bẹ́ẹ̀ náà ló jẹ́ afoge-ṣojú ilé iṣẹ́ aṣerunlóge, Diva hair extension, Fuman juice àti Ilé-ìfowópamọ́ United Bank for Africa (UBA).Ọláídé fẹ́ Babátúndé Ọ̀jọrá Emmanuel lọ́kọ lọ́dún 2015 wọ́n sìn bímọ kan péré fún ara wọn lọ́dún 2016. She was married to Babatunde Ojora in 2019."},{"question":"ደቡብ ሱዳን ነጻ ሀገር ለመሆን ሕዝበ ውሳኔ የተሰጠው መቼ ነበር?","answer":"እ.ኤ.አ. በጃኑዋሪ 2011 ።"},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın: Hunger Ward, Skye Fitzgerald ve Michael Shueuerman tarafından yönetilmiş 2020 yapımı Amerikan belgesel filmidir. Film, Yemen'de devam eden kıtlığı ve neticesinde ortaya çıkan çocukların eksik beslenmesiyle mücadele eden iki hastanenin çabalarını konu alıyor. 93. Akademi Ödülleri'nde","answer":"En iyi kısa belgesel dalında Akademi Ödülü'ne aday gösterildi."},{"question":"மயிலை சீனி. வேங்கடசாமியின் படைப்புகள் குறித்து எழுதுக.","answer":"• ஆசிரியர் பயிற்சி பெற்றுத் தொடக்கப் பள்ளியில் 25 ஆண்டுகள் ஆசிரியராகப் பணியாற்றினார். பாடம் கற்பிக்கும் நேரத்தைத் தவிர மற்ற நேரங்களில் அவர் வளாகம் சாராத ஆய்வாளராகத் தம்மை உருவாக்கிக் கொண்டார்.• கட்டுரையோ, நூலோ எழுதும் முன் தரவுகளைச் சேகரித்துத் தமது ஆய்வுக்கு ஏற்றதை ஒப்பிட்டுஐயமிருப்பின் மற்றவர்களைக் கேட்டுத் தெளிந்த பிறகே வெளியிடுவார். • மயிலை சீனி. ஒரு தமிழ்த் தேனீ. அறிவின் வாயில்களை நோக்கியே அவர் கால்கள் நடந்தன. நூலகங்களே அவரது தாயகங்களாயின. அறிவை விரிவு செய்து அல்லும் பகலும் ஆய்வில் மூழ்கிக் கருத்து முத்துக்களைத் தமிழ்நாட்டிற்கு வழங்கினார்.• புதிய செய்தி தருதல், புது விளக்கமளித்தல், இருண்ட பக்கங்களுக்கு ஒளியூட்டுதல், தவறுகளை மறுத்து உண்மையை எடுத்துரைத்தல் என்பவற்றை ஆய்வு அணுகு முறைகளாகக் கொண்டார்.மயிலை சீனி. வேங்கடசாமியின் படைப்புகள்:• விபுலானந்த அடிகள்…… இதழ்களில் வெளியாகின.• பௌத்தமும் தமிழும், சமணமும் தமிழும்• களப்பிரர் ஆட்சியில் தமிழகம்• தமிழர் வளர்த்த அழகுக் கலைகள்• தமிழ்நாட்டு வரலாறு• சாசனச் செய்யுள் மஞ்சரி• மறைந்து போன தமிழ் நூல்கள்"},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity : \\" Ny mijekijeky ro _\\".","answer":"\\"Ny mijekijeky ro avy lavitsa.\\" "},{"question":"බන්කියාඕ වේල්ල බිඳවැටීම සම්බන්ධව සිද්ධි අධ්‍යයනයක් ලබාදෙන්න .","answer":"Banqiao වේල්ල, Shimantan වේල්ල ලෙසද හැඳින්වේ, චීනයේ Henan පළාතේ පිහිටි විශාල පස් වේල්ලකි. එය 1950 ගණන්වල කහ ගඟ දිගේ ගංවතුර පාලනය කිරීමේ විශාල උත්සාහයක කොටසක් ලෙස ඉදිකරන ලද්දකි. එය ඉදිකරන විට එය ලෝකයේ විශාලතම වේල්ල වූ අතර එහි උස මීටර් 125 ක් සහ දිග මීටර් 7,000 කි.1975 අගෝස්තු මාසයේදී, බැන්කියාඕ වේල්ලට නීනා ටයිෆූන් පහර දුන් අතර, එය අධික වර්ෂාපතනයක් ගෙන දුන් අතර කලාපය පුරා දැඩි ගංවතුරක් ඇති කළේය. වේල්ල සහ පහළ කුඩා වේලි පීඩනයට ඔරොත්තු නොදෙන අතර, දින කිහිපයක් පුරා, වේල්ල මුදුනේ සිට මීටර් 3 කට වඩා වැඩි ජල මට්ටමක් දක්වා ඉහළ ගියේය.අගෝස්තු 8 වන දින වේල්ල අසාර්ථක වීමට පටන් ගත් අතර විශාල කඩඉම් කිහිපයක් හරහා ජලය ගලා ගියේය. ඉන් පසුව ඇති වූ ගංවතුර ව්‍යසනකාරී වූ අතර ඇස්තමේන්තුගත පුද්ගලයන් 26,000 ක් මිය ගිය අතර තවත් 145,000 ක් අතුරුදහන් වී හෝ මිය ගොස් ඇතැයි අනුමාන කෙරේ. මෙම ව්‍යසනය නිසා මාර්ග, පාලම්, ගොඩනැගිලි ඇතුළු යටිතල පහසුකම්වලට ද පුලුල් ලෙස හානි සිදු විය.Banqiao වේල්ල අසාර්ථක වීමෙන් පසුව, චීන රජය වේලි ආරක්ෂාව සහ ගංවතුර පාලන පියවරයන් වැඩිදියුණු කිරීම සඳහා මහා පරිමාණ උත්සාහයක් දියත් කළේය. දරුණු කාලගුණික තත්ත්වයන්ට වඩා හොඳින් ඔරොත්තු දිය හැකි කුඩා, විමධ්‍යගත වේලි ඉදිකිරීම මෙයට ඇතුළත් විය. වේලි කළමනාකරණයේ වැඩි විනිවිදභාවයක් සහ වගවීමක අවශ්‍යතාවය සහ තීරණ ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලීන් සඳහා ප්‍රාදේශීය ප්‍රජාවන් සම්බන්ධ කර ගැනීමේ වැදගත්කම ද මෙම ව්‍යසනය මගින් පෙන්වා දී ඇත.Banqiao වේල්ල බිඳවැටීම ඉතිහාසයේ දරුණුතම වේලි ව්‍යසනයක් ලෙස පවතින අතර, මහා පරිමාණ යටිතල පහසුකම් ව්‍යාපෘතිවල ඇති විය හැකි අවදානම් සහ ප්‍රතිවිපාක පිළිබඳ අනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ කතාවකි."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa ti tu aṣiri awọn to waa jo ile Sunday Igboho","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ ti sọrọ lori ijamba ina to waye laaarọ ọkọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii, n’Ibadan, nile Sunday Adeyẹmọ, tawọn eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, wọn ni awọn janduku kan ni wọn ṣiṣẹ buruku ọhun loru, mọto meji kan ni wọn gbe wa.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Alukoro ọlọpaa ipinlẹ naa, Ọgbẹni Gbenga Fadeyi, fi lede lori iṣẹlẹ ọhun, o ni ọkọ Hummer ati Micra ni wọn gun wa ni nnkan bii aago mẹta kọja iṣẹju diẹ loru, ti wọn bẹrẹ si i yinbọn soke, ki wọn too sọna sile naa, ti wọn si ba tiwọn lọ.Gbenga ni gbara ti DPO Sanyo ti gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ yii lo ti sare tẹ ileeṣẹ panapana laago, oju ẹsẹ loun funra ẹ si ti lọ sibi iṣẹlẹ naa pẹlu awọn ọlọpaa meloo kan.O lawọn panapana tete pa ina naa, yara igbalejo to wa nisalẹ lo jona gidi, pẹlu awọn dukia ti wọn o ti i le diwọn iye owo wọn. O ni iwadii ti bẹrẹ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, awọn si ti n tọpasẹ awọn janduku naa lọ, o lo daju pe ko sẹnikan to lọwọ ninu ijamba yii ti ko ni i fimu kata ofin.Bakan naa ni Ọgbẹni Ismail Adeleke to jẹ darẹkitọ ileeṣẹ panapana ipinlẹ Ọyọ sọ fun Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN), pe awọn ti bẹrẹ iwadii lati mọ hulẹhulẹ ohun to ṣokunfa ina ojiji yii, awọn si maa jẹ karaye mọ okodoro otitọ nipa ẹ."},{"question":"為什麼要舉辦奧林匹克運動會？","answer":"　　顧拜旦籌辦奧運會的時候沒有想那么多吧，他喜歡運動，他喜歡競技體育，然後他為此奮鬥半生．後來大家發現奧運會可以交朋友，增進各國之間的文化交流，及展示各國的科技實力，被大家都歡迎。　　現代奧林匹克運動不論從發展規模，還是從發展水平上來看，都已為舉世所矚目。奧林匹克精神得到了廣泛傳播。人們看到，作為一種文化現象，奧林匹克主義以競技的形式，將不同膚色、不同文化背景的民族緊密聯繫在一起，對人類的社會活動，對人類的文明產生了深刻的影響。　　作為一種體育現象，奧運會是人類探索體能極限的最引人入勝的賽場，奧運會紀錄、獎牌成為運動員追求的崇高目標，奧林匹克運動已成為參與國家和地區眾多、具有巨大吸引力、穿透力和凝聚力的一項全球性活動。　　1893年，根據\\"奧運之父\\"顧拜旦的建議，在巴黎舉行了討論復興奧運會問題的國際性體育會議。　　1894年1月，顧拜旦草擬了復興奧運會的具體步驟和需要探討的10個問題，致函各國體育組織和團體。6月16日，\\"國際體育運動代表大會\\"在巴黎索邦神學院開幕，到會代表79人，代表著12個國家的49個體育組織。有2000人參加了開幕式。大會通過了《復興奧林匹克運動》的決議。　　6月23日成立了國際奧林匹克委員會。國際奧林匹克委員會的成立，標誌著奧林匹克運動的誕生"},{"question":"இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-compress","answer":"அழுத்து/அமுக்குசிறிதாக்கு (in software, to make small)"},{"question":"ప్రశ్న మీకు ఏ రకమైన ప్రభుత్వం ఇష్టం? ఎందుకు?","answer":"నాకు ప్రజాస్వామ్య ప్రభుత్వం ఇష్టం. ఎందుకంటే ప్రజాస్వామ్య ప్రభుత్వం ప్రజలచే ఎన్నుకొనబడుతుంది. ప్రజల సంక్షేమం కొరకు కృషి చేస్తుంది."},{"question":"De onde obtemos o enxofre?","answer":"O enxofre ou súlfur é um elemento químico de símbolo S, com número atômico 16 e massa atômica 32 u. À temperatura ambiente, o enxofre encontra-se no estado sólido. O enxofre é o 16º elemento em ordem de abundância, constituindo 0,034% em peso na crosta terrestre, é encontrado em grandes quantidades na forma de sulfetos (galena) e de sulfatos (gesso). É extraído normalmente pelo processo Frasch, processo responsável por 23% da produção, que consiste em injetar vapor d'água superaquecido para fundir o enxofre, que posteriormente é bombeado para o exterior utilizando-se ar comprimido. O maior produtor mundial de enxofre em 2023 é a China."},{"question":"સાર્વનામિક વિશેષણ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"સાર્વનામિક વિશેષણ: જ્યા નામ વિશેષણ તરીકે પ્રયોજાયું હોય તેને સાર્વનામિક વિશેષણ કહે છે.સાર્વનામિક વિશેષણના ઉદાહરણ:આ સાંભળીને ખલીફાને એ લોભી દરબારીઓ વિશે દુઃખ થયું.આ કોઈ શાણો માણસ જણાય છે.હું કશી આજ્ઞા કરવા માંગતો નથી.એવો તે શો ધડાકો ભયંકર હતો.મને તે સારો ના લાગ્યો.ઉદાહરણ: આ, હું, અમે, તમે, તેઓને, તે, તેણી, તેઓ, વગેરે, સાર્વનામિક વિશેષણ સૂચવે છે."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Tesla yêu cầu một khách hàng trả 4.500 USD để mở dung lượng pin, tương đương 129 km phạm vi hoạt động của xe bị khoá bằng phần mềm. Câu chuyện được Jason Hughes, một hacker khét tiếng được biết đến về dịch vụ kích hoạt tính năng bị khóa trong xe Tesla kể lại. Khách hàng mua lại một chiếc Tesla Model S 60 (pin bị khóa ở mức 60 kWh), nhưng từng được Tesla bảo hành, thay pin và mở dung lượng 90 kWh rồi trả cho khách. Bởi các dòng xe Tesla cũ chỉ có kết nối 3G, khách hàng này đã đến trung tâm bảo hành của Tesla để được cập nhật phần mềm nhằm đảm bảo xe có thể kết nối Internet. Sau khi đưa xe đến Tesla bảo hành, vị khách đã nhận được cuộc gọi từ trung tâm sửa chữa, nói rằng họ đã tìm thấy lỗi trong hệ thống và họ sẽ tiến hành \\"sửa chữa lại\\" chiếc xe. \\"Bản vá lỗi\\" của Tesla đã đưa chiếc xe của vị khách ngược trở lại cấu hình ban đầu, giống như Model S 60, giảm khoảng 129 km phạm vi hoạt động của xe với cho dù vị khách đã nâng cấp pin. Cho dù vị khách cố gắng giải thích mình mua lại khi xe đang là mẫu Model S 90 và yêu cầu công ty kích hoạt lại phạm vi bị khóa, Tesla vẫn yêu cầu người này phải trả 4.500 USD để mở khóa phạm vi mở rộng. Hughes nhận ra rằng tuy có thể sử dụng bản hack phần mềm để khôi phục lại phạm vi hoạt động, việc này sẽ yêu cầu xe ngắt kết nối hoàn toàn khỏi các dịch vụ của Tesla, ngược lại mục đích ban đầu của vị khách hàng. Vì vậy, thay vì hack vào hệ thống phần mềm của xe, người này đã quyết định đăng tải vấn đề mà mình đang gặp phải lên MXH Twitter. Ngay lập tức, câu chuyện nhận được nhiều phản ứng của cộng đồng mạng. Nhận thấy sự ảnh hưởng quá manh mẽ, hãng xe điện cuối cùng đã nhượng bộ với người dùng. Tesla đã liên hệ với Hughes và thông báo rằng họ 'sẽ xử lý vấn đề ngay lập tức'. Trước đó, Tesla từng bán xe Model S với dung lượng pin khác nhau cùng viên pin bị khóa bằng phần mềm. Phiên bản Tesla Model S 40 mà hãng ra mắt thực tế là Model S với viên pin 60 kWh bị khóa bằng phần mềm, khiến pin của xe chỉ vận hành ở mức công suất 40 kWh. Đây là cách công ty sử dụng để cung cấp nhiều tùy chọn phạm vi khác nhau cho người dùng mà không khiến công đoạn sản xuất bị phức tạp lên với các viên pin khác nhau. Sau khi xe đến tay khách hàng, Tesla bắt đầu cung cấp cho chủ sở hữu tùy chọn mở khóa hoàn toàn dung lượng pin với một khoản phí bổ sung. Tuy đã loại bỏ mô hình kinh doanh từ nhiều năm qua, công ty vẫn sử dụng các bộ pin bị khóa phần mềm khi thực hiện thay thế hay bảo hành cho các mẫu xe nhất định mà hãng không sản xuất nữa. Tham khảo: Electrek","answer":"Chơi chiêu như Tesla: Khóa dung lượng pin xe điện, người dùng phải trả 4.500 USD mới được mở khóa tính năng"},{"question":"Ajàkálẹ̀-àrùn COVID-19 ní Sierra Leone","answer":"Ajàkálẹ̀-àrùn COVID-19 tàn kálẹ̀ dé Orílẹ̀-èdè ní orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone ní ọjọ́ kọkanlélọ́gbòn oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020.Ní ọjọ́ Kejìlá oṣù Kíní ọdún 2020, Àjọ ìṣọ̀kan tí ó ń rí sí ìlera ní àgbáyé fìdí àrùn Kòrónà tí a tún ń pè ní Kofid-19 ní orílẹ̀-m àgbáyé ní ọjọ́ Kejìlá oṣù Kínní ní ọdún 2020. Tí wọ́n sì fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ wípé àrùn yí bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní ìlú kan tí wọ́n ń pè ní Wuhan, ní ẹkùn Hubei ní orílẹ̀-èdè China. Àmọ́ ó tó ọjọ́ Kẹtalélọ́gbọ̀n oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2019 kí wọ́n tó fi tó àjọ ìṣòkan àgbáyé létí On 12 January 2020. Wọ́n tún fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ siwájú si wípé bí àrùn yí bá ti mú ènìyàn, oun ni ó ń fa ìfúnpinpin ní ní inú káà ọ̀fun ati àyà, tí ó sì ma ń fa kàtá tàbí kí ènìyàn ó ma wú ikọ́ tàbí sín léra léra. Iye ìjàmbá tí àrùn Kòrónà ti fà lágbáyé kéré sí iye ìjàmbá tí àìsàn àrùn ọ̀fun SARS ti fà láti ọdún 2003. Àmọ́ iye àwọn ènìyàn tí wọ́n tó àrùn Kòrónà látàrí ríràn tí ó ń ràn kálẹ̀ ti.pọ̀ ju ti SARS lọ, bí ó ti lẹ̀ jẹ́ wípé ìtànkálé àrùn COVID-19 ń gbópọn si lójojúmọ́ tí ó sì ti ṣekú pa ọ̀pọ̀lọpò ènìyàn lágbáyé.Oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020Ààrẹ orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone ọ̀gbẹ́ni Julius Maada Bio, kéde ìtánká arùn Kòrónà tí ó wọ orílẹ̀-èdè wọn ní ọjọ́ kọkanlélọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kẹ́ta ọdún 2020 lára arákùnrin kan tí ó jẹ́ ẹni ọdún mẹ́tàdínlógójì tí ó ń darí ìrìn-àjò bọ̀ láti ìlú Faransé ní ọjọ́ kẹrìndínlógún oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020, amọ́ tí wọ́n ti fi sí iyará àdágbé láti ìgbà náà. This single case remained active at the end of the month.Oṣù kẹrin ọdún 2020Ní ọjọ́ Kíní oṣù kẹ́rin ọdún 2020, orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone ní akọsílẹ̀ àrùn Kòrónà ìkejì lára 3nìkan tí ó ṣèrín ajò pẹ́lú 3ni akọ́kọ́ tí ó ti kọ́kọ́ ní arùn náà. The government announced a 3-day lockdown starting on 5 April.Wọ́n tún ní akọsílẹ̀ méjì méjì ní ọjọ́ kẹrin àti ìkarùún oṣù kẹrin, tí ó mú kí iye àwọn aláàrẹ̀ COVID-9 jẹ́ mẹ́fa. Ní ọjọ́ kẹsàán oṣù kẹrin, lẹ́yìn ìsénimọ́lé ọlọjọ́ mẹ́ta, ìjọba kéde àwọn ìgbésẹ̀ míràn. Wọ́n ṣòfin kónílé-ó-gbélé tí àwọn ènìyàn yóò ní ànfaní láti rìn láti agogo mẹ́sàán àrọ̀ sí agogo mẹ́fà ìrọ̀lẹ́, àwọn òsìṣẹ́ ìjọba tí iṣẹ́ wọn ṣe pàtàkì jùlọ ni wọ́n ní ànfaní láti ma jáde. Òfin yí wà bẹ́ẹ̀ fún odidi ọjọ́ mẹ́rìnlá gbáko. Wíwọ ìbòjú ní àkókò àtànkálẹ̀ àrùn kòrónà di dan dan fún ẹnìkan tí ó bá fẹ́ jáde lọ sí àárín ọ̀pọ̀ èrò.Ní ọjọ́ Kejìlá oṣù kẹrin, ìjọba fi àtẹ̀jáde kan léde tí ó sọ wípé àwọn ènìyàn mẹ́ta lára àwọn mẹ́wá kan tí wọ́n fara kó àrùn COVID-9 ti wà ní iyará àdágbé, tí àwọn mẹ́wéwá sì wà ní abẹ́ ìtọ́jú àwọn ilé ìwòsàn ìjọba. Ìjọba ti kó ọ̀gọ̀rọ̀ àwọn ènìyàn tí ó tó ẹgbẹ̀rún kan ó lé ọgọ́rùún mẹ́ta ai àádọ́ta ó lé mẹ́rin, ni wọ́n ti wà ní iyará àdágbé fún ọ̀sẹ̀ méjì, nígbà tí wọ́n ti dá àwọn ọgọ́rùún méje àti mẹ́rìndínlógójì ti pada sí ilé wọn láyọ̀ àti alàáfía.Ní ọjọ́ kọkàndínlógún oṣù kẹrin, wọ́n ní akọsílẹ̀ àwọn ènìyàn mẹ́fà akọ́kọ́ tí wọ́n sí ìwòsàn gbà.Wọ́n kéde rẹ̀ wípé Ààrẹ orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone ọ̀gbẹ́ni Julius Maada Bio náà ti wọn iyará àdágbé látàrí bí ó ṣe fara kásá àìsàn àrùn COVID-9 ní ọjọ́ kọkànlélógún oṣù kẹrin ọdún 2020. Ní ọjọ́ Kẹtalélógún oṣù kẹrin, wọ́n ní akọsílẹ̀ ẹnìkan tí ó pàdánù ẹ̀mí rẹ̀ sí ọwọ́ àrùn Kòrónà. Ẹni náà jẹ́ ẹni ọdún mẹ́rìndínlọ́gọ́rin. Ẹnìkejì tí lú ni ó jẹ́ ẹni ọdún mọ́kandínlógóje tí wọ́n sì fìdí àìsàn Kòrónà múlẹ lára wọn lẹ́yin tí wọ́n ti gbé gùru-gaja.Wọ́n kéde ikú ọkùnrin tí ọjọ́ orí rẹ̀ jẹ́ mẹ́tàdínlógójì tí ó jẹ́ ẹnìkẹta ní ọjọ́ Kẹrìnlélógún oṣù kẹrin ọdún 2020.Nígbà tí oṣù kẹrin yóò fi tẹnu bepo, àwọn ènìyàn ọgọ́rùún ni wọ́n ti lu gúdẹ àrùn yí nígbà tí àwọn méje gbẹ́mí mì. Àwọn mọ́kanlélógún ni wọ́n rí ìwòsàn gbà tí wọ́n sì padà lọ sílẹ́ wọn, ó wá ku àwọn mẹ́rìndínlọ́gọ́rùún tí wọ́n sì ń bá àìsàn náà jà.Oṣù Karùún ọdún 2020Ìjọba ṣòfin kónílé-ó-gbélé ọlọ́jọ mẹ́ta tí ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní ọjọ́ kẹta oṣù Karùún. Nígbà tí yóò fi di ọjọ́ yìí, iye àwọn tí wọ́n ti wà ní iyará àdágbé ti tó ẹgbẹ̀rún kan ati ọgọ́rùún mẹ́ta ó lé mọ́kànlélógójì ènìyàn, àwọn mọ́kandínlọ́gbọ̀n ni wọ́n rí ìwòsàn gbà tí wọ́n sì lọ sílé wọn.Ní inú oṣù Karùún, wọ́n rí akọsílẹ̀ tuntun tí ó tó ogóje ó lé mẹ́tàdínlógójì tí ó mú kí gbogbo akọsílẹ̀ àwọn aláàrẹ̀ àrùn Kòrónà lápapọ̀ jẹ́ 9gọ́jọ àti mọ́kanlé ọgọ́ta. Àwọn tí wọ́n kú jẹ́ mẹ́rìndín láàdọ́ta. Àwọn tí wọ́n gbádùn jẹ́ ọgọ́rùún mẹ́rin àti mẹ́rìndínlọ́góta ní ìparí oṣù Karùún.Oṣù Kẹfà ọdún 2020Láti ọ́jọ́ kíní oṣù Kẹfà, wọ́n ṣe wí From 1 June, wearing of face masks became compulsory. Also on this day, frontline workers declared a strike because of unpaid salaries. Nígbà tí yóò gi di ọjọ́ kẹrin oṣù Kẹfà, àwọn ènìyàn tí wọ́n tó ẹgbẹ̀rún mẹ́rin àti àádọ́rin ó lé mẹ́tadínlógún tí wọ́n ti ṣàyẹ̀wò ẹ̀jẹ̀ fún tí ọgọ́rin léní mẹ́jìdínláàdóje jẹ́ obìnrin nígbà tí àwọn ẹgbẹ̀rún mẹ́rin ó lé mẹ́rìndíláàdọ́ta jẹ́ ọkùnrin.Ní ìparí oṣù Kẹfà, iye àwọn ènìyàn tí wọ́n ṣàyẹ̀wò fún tí ayẹ̀wọ̀ sì fìdí arùn yí múlẹ̀ lára wọn jẹ́ ọgọ́rùú mẹfa ó lé mẹ́ta ènìyàn, àwọn ọgọ́ta ènìyàn ṣaláìsí, nígbà tí àwọn tí ara wọ́n yá jẹ́ ọgọ́ta lápapọ̀.Oṣù keje ọdún 2020Ní ọjọ́ kejì oṣù keje, ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone fagilé ìrìnà ọkọ̀ òfurufú àti lílọ-bíbọ̀ àwọn ènìyàn nípa lílo ọkọ̀ òfurufú tí tí di ọjọ́ kẹẹ̀ẹ́dógún oṣù keje. Ní ọjọ́ Kẹwàá oṣù keje, Ààrẹ orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone pàṣẹ pé kí wọ́n ṣí àwọn ilé-ìjọsìn ati àwọn pápákọ̀ òfurufú gbogbo pátá padà ní ọjọ́ kẹtàlá oṣù keje.Àwọn ènìyàn tí wọ́n tó ọgọ́rùún mẹ́ta àti mọ́kalélọ́gọ́ta tí wọ́n ní àrùn COVID-19 ni wọ́n tún rí tí ó mú kí àpapọ̀ iye àwọn tí wọ́n ní arùn COVID-9 ní orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone jẹ́ ẹgbẹ̀rún kan àti àádọ́rin ó lé mètàlélógún tí àwọn mẹ́tadínlógóje papò dà nígbà tí àwọn ènìyàn ẹgbẹ̀rún kan ati ọgọ́rùún mẹ́ta ó lé méjìlélọ́gọ́ta rí ìwòsàn tí wọ́n sì gbádùn. Àwọn kòkú-kòyè jẹ́ ọgọ́rùún mẹ́ta àti mẹ́rìnléláàzdọ́sàán.Ní ọjọ́ karùndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kẹta, ṣáájú kí wọ́n tó ní akọsílẹ̀ akọ́kọ́, ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone ti kéde ìṣèjọba ti pàjáwìrì tí yóò ṣíṣe fún oṣù méjìlá gbáko tíń ṣe odidi ọdún kan gbáko. Wọ́n fagilé ètò ìrìnà gbogbo, wọ́n sì fagilé àwọn ilé-ìjọsìn gbogbo pẹ̀lú. Wọ́n tún kéde kónílé-ó-gbélé ọlọ́jọ́ méta tí ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ ní 9jọ́ Karùún oṣù Kẹrin.Ilé ìfowó-pamọ́ agbáyé kéde owó ìrànwọ́ tí ó tó mílíọ́nù méje àbọ̀ dọ́là fún orílẹ̀-èdè Sierra Leone kí wọ́n fi kojú Ìbúrẹ́kẹ́ ajàkálẹ̀ àrùn COVID-9"},{"question":"Em bị cận mỗi bên 3-4 độ, sinh hoạt và học tập, thể thao rất bất tiện. Em muốn mổ nhưng được tư vấn một số phương pháp, mọi người nói là can thiệp mổ cận sẽ ảnh hưởng trực tiếp đến lớp giác mạc, làm mỏng giác mạc đi, mà lớp đó là quý giá nhất, không nên can thiệp vào. Xin tư vấn giải pháp?","answer":"Khi mổ cận, bác sĩ sẽ lấy một phần trên lớp nhu mô giác mạc, nên giác phải phải đủ độ dày cho phép nhằm đảm bảo sau mổ không làm biến dạng cấu trúc giác mạc. Nhiều nghiên cứu theo dõi mắt sau mổ 10-20 năm và cho thấy các kỹ thuật đảm bảo an toàn cho người bệnh. Hiện tại, có một số phương pháp đang được áp dụng rộng rãi và an toàn cho bệnh nhân như Relex Smile, Smart Surface, Femto-Lasik. Bạn có thể chọn một trong 3 phương pháp này để đảm bảo kết quả mổ tốt."},{"question":"ਮੁੰਡੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਉਂਗਲਾਂ ਛਿੱਲੜ ਵਰਗੀਆਂ ਹੋ ਗਈਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਦੇਰ ਤਕ ਸ਼ਾਵਰ ਲਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਸਾਬਣ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੱਥਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਝੱਗ ਕੀਤੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਦੇਰ ਤਕ ਸ਼ਾਵਰ ਲਿਆ।"},{"question":"வினா : பாலை நிலக் கடவுள் யார் ? ","answer":"விடை : கொற்றவை"},{"question":"Bãi biển nào dưới đây không thuộc Đà Nẵng?Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi trên trong những câu sau:A. Non NướcB. Mỹ KhêC. Thuận An","answer":"Câu trả lời đúng: C. Thuận AnThuận An là bãi biển thuộc tỉnh Thừa Thiên Huế, còn thành phố Đà Nẵng có đường bờ biển dài 92 km, nổi tiếng với nhiều bãi biển đẹp như Non Nước, Mỹ Khê, Thanh Khê, Làng Vân... Biển Đà Nẵng có độ sóng nhỏ, nước êm, trong xanh, độ mặn khoảng 60%. Các bãi tắm ở bán đảo Sơn Trà còn có nhiều san hô, nguồn động thực vật ven bờ và dưới biển phong phú. Khoảng cách từ trung tâm thành phố tới các bãi tắm đều rất gần, nên Đà Nẵng luôn là điểm đến thu hút nhiều du khách."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : కింది కథనం ఆధారంగా సమాచార హక్కు చట్టం నేపథ్యంలో వివిధ ప్రభుత్వ శాఖల, పౌరుల పాత్రలను వివరించండి. సమాచార హక్కు చట్టం వల్ల ప్రభుత్వ పని మరింత పారదర్శకంగా ఎలా అవుతుందో రాయండి. కింద పేర్కొన్న ఘటన మెదక్ జిల్లాలోని చిన్న శంకరం పేటలో జరిగింది. స్వయం సహాయక బృందాల సభ్యులు రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వ గ్రామీణ అభివృద్ధి మంత్రిత్వశాఖ పథకాలైన అభయహస్తం, ఆమ్ ఆద్మీలలో చేరారు. ఈ పథకం కింద 9 నుంచి 12 తరగతులు చదువుతున్న పిల్లలకు 1200 రూపాయల స్కాలర్షిప్ పొందడానికి అర్హత ఉంది. అయితే 2008-11 మధ్య మూడు సంవత్సరాల పాటు విద్యార్థులకు స్కాలర్షిప్ మొత్తం అందలేదు. విద్యార్థులు ఇందిరా క్రాంతి పథకం కార్యాలయానికి వెళ్లి అడిగారు. కానీ అక్కడి అధికారులు వాళ్లను పట్టించుకోలేదు.ఇది స్థానిక దినపత్రికల దృష్టికి వచ్చింది. ఆమోదించిన స్కాలర్షిప్పుల వివరాలు ఇవ్వమంటూ వాళ్లు సంబంధిత అధికారుల వద్ద దరఖాస్తు చేశారు. 2008-09, 2009-10, 2010-11 సంవత్సరాలలో లబ్ధిదారుల సంఖ్య, మంజూరు చేసిన మొత్తం ఎంత అని అడిగారు. వాళ్లకు ఒక వారంలోపు సమాచారం వచ్చింది. మొత్తం ఏడు లక్షల రూపాయలు మంజూరయ్యాయి. సమాచార హక్కు ద్వారా అందిన వివరాలను బట్టి డబ్బు మంజూరయ్యింది కానీ, దానిని పంచలేదని తెలిసింది. ఈ విషయం వార్తాపత్రికలలో ప్రచురితం కాగానే 15 రోజుల లోపు 1167 విద్యార్థులకు స్కాలర్షిప్ అందజేశారు.","answer":"సమాచార హక్కు చట్టం ప్రయోజనాలు ప్రజలకు అందాలంటే రెండు పాత్రలు తమ విధులను సక్రమంగా నిర్వర్తించాలి.ప్రభుత్వ శాఖలు పౌరులు ఏ ప్రజాస్వామిక వ్యవస్థలోనైనా ప్రభుత్వాలు ప్రజలకు బాధ్యత వహించి వారికి జవాబుదారీగా ఉండాలి.1) ప్రభుత్వశాఖల పాత్ర :పై ఘటనలో ఉన్న ప్రభుత్వ శాఖలు – రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వ గ్రామీణ అభివృద్ధి మంత్రిత్వశాఖ పథకాలైన అభయహస్తం, ఆమ్ ఆద్మీ, ఇందిరా క్రాంతి పథం. ఈ సంస్థలు వాటి యొక్క విధులను సక్రమంగా నిర్వర్తించాలి. అంటే 9 నుండి 12 తరగతులు చదువుతున్న విద్యార్థులకు 1200 రూపాయల స్కాలర్షిప్ అందజేయాలి. కాని 2008-11 మధ్య మూడు సంవత్సరాలపాటు పిల్లలకు స్కాలర్షిప్ అందచేయలేదు. ఆ విషయాలు పట్టించుకోలేదు. చివరికి విద్యార్థులే సమాచారహక్కును ఉపయోగించి వివరాలు కనుక్కోవలసి వచ్చింది. ఈ విషయమంతా వార్తాపత్రికలలో కూడా వచ్చింది. దీనితో 15 రోజులలోపు 1167 మంది విద్యార్థులకు స్కాలర్షిప్ అందచేశారు. అయితే ఈ సంస్థల నిర్లక్ష్యం, జాప్యం అనేవి ప్రజలు, వార్తాపత్రికల దృష్టికి వెళ్ళింది. ప్రభుత్వ సంస్థలు సక్రమంగా పనిచేయట్లేదంటూ మాట్లాడారు. కావున ప్రభుత్వ సంస్థలు నిరంతరం మెలకువతో ఉండి, తమ వద్ద ఏ ఫైల్ను ఆపకుండా సకాలంలో పనిచేయాలి.2) పౌరుల పాత్ర :అభయహస్తం, ఆమ్ ఆద్మీ, ఇందిరా క్రాంతి పథం వంటి సంస్థలు వాటి విధులు మరిచిపోయాయి. కాని విద్యార్థులు వదలకుండా సమాచార హక్కు చట్టంను ఉపయోగించి వాస్తవాలు తెలుసుకున్నారు. ఈలోగా ఈ విషయాలన్నీ వార్తాపత్రికలో వచ్చాయి. అప్పుడు హడావుడిగా ఆ సంస్థలు విద్యార్థులకు డబ్బును అందించారు. ఇందులో పౌరులు వారి విధులను సక్రమంగా నిర్వర్తించినారని తెలుస్తుంది."},{"question":"ഭൂമിയിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ സമുദ്രം ഏതാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: പസഫിക്"},{"question":"సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వాన్ని ఎలా అర్థం చేసుకొంటావు ?","answer":"“జాతీయ సమైక్యత, ప్రాంతీయ విభాగాల హక్కులను సమన్వయపరచే రాజకీయ సాధనమే సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వం” అని ఎ.వి.డైసీ పేర్కొన్నాడు. సమాఖ్య ప్రభుత్వానికి ప్రధానంగా మూడు లక్షణాలుంటాయని ఎ.వి.డైసీ పేర్కొన్నాడు.కేంద్ర – రాష్ట్ర ప్రభుత్వాల మధ్య స్పష్టమైన, నిర్దిష్టమైన అధికారాల పంపిణీ.లిఖిత, దృఢ, ఉన్నత రాజ్యాంగంస్వతంత్ర ప్రతిపత్తి కల్గిన న్యాయవ్యవస్థ."},{"question":" Escribe la continuación de este texto : El 16 de octubre en el episodio número 1000 de SmackDown, Miz derrotó a Rusev gracias a una interferencia de Aiden English para clasificar al torneo por la Copa Mundial de WWE para determinar al mejor luchador del mundo en el evento Crown Jewel. En el evento, Miz derrotó a Jeff Hardy y Rey Mysterio para avanzar a la final contra Dolph Ziggler, pero se lesionó la rodilla antes de la lucha, lo que le impidió competir. El comisionado de SmackDown, Shane McMahon, lo reemplazó y derrotó a Ziggler, ganando el torneo y la Copa Mundial de WWE. En el episodio del 6 de noviembre de SmackDown, después de que Daniel Bryan fuera nombrado capitán del Team SmackDown para el Traditional Survivor Series Men's match en Survivor Series, Miz interrumpiría y exigiría ser capitán en su lugar debido a su éxito en el torneo por la Copa Mundial de WWE. Más tarde, Shane McMahon se rendiría ante Miz, y le otorgaría los deberes de co-capitán del equipo, con Miz y Bryan trabajando a regañadientes para formar su equipo. Sin embargo, la semana siguiente, la gerente general Paige sacó a Bryan del combate y lo reemplazó con Jeff Hardy, dejando a Miz como el único capitán del Team SmackDown para el evento. el evento, Team SmackDown perdió ante Team Raw. Durante las siguientes semanas, Miz comenzó a convertirse lentamente en \\"\\" al tratar de persuadir a Shane McMahon para que formara un equipo con él, refiriéndose a ellos como \\"Co-Besties\\", ya que para Miz ambos ganaron la Copa Mundial de WWE. En el episodio del 25 de diciembre de SmackDown, McMahon apareció como invitado en \\"Miz TV\\" y aceptó formar el equipo.... ","answer":"De Crown Jewel. "},{"question":"\\"Чапса чабылбайт,Кессе кесилбейт\\".-табышмактын жандырмагы кандай?","answer":"Табышмактын жандырмагы -(көлөкө)"},{"question":"Pirmasis šių filmų sukurtas 2004 m., antrasis – 2009 m. Abu filmai vadinasi beveik taip pat, tik antrojo filmo pavadinime dar yra minimi ir metai – 2009. Pirmasis filmas yra istorinis, režisuotas Algimanto Puipos, jo veiksmas vyksta Vilniuje II pasaulinio karo metais, antrasis – dokumentinis, režisuotas Andriaus Lelkaičio, pasakoja apie Vilniaus romų taboro gyvenimą. Parašykite pirmojo filmo pavadinimą.","answer":"Pirmasis filmas vadinasi: Vilniaus Getas. 2004 m. pasirodęs Algimanto Puipos režisuotas filmas. Veiksmas vyksta Vilniaus gete Antrojo pasaulinio karo metais (1942–1943 m.). Nacių karininkas Kitelis, pats buvęs aktorius ir džiazo muzikantas, įsimyli žydaitę dainininkę Chają ir dėl jos gete padeda įkurti teatrą.Antrasis filmas: 2009 m. pasirodęs Audriaus Lelkaičio filmas vadinasi \\"Vilniaus getas 2009\\"."},{"question":"ਆਦਮੀ ਨੇ ਪੌੜੀ ਤੋਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਸੰਤੁਲਨ ਗੁਆ ਦਿੱਤਾ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਪੌੜੀ ’ਤੇ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਗਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਪੌੜੀ ਤੋਂ ਡਿੱਗ ਗਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਪੌੜੀ ਤੋਂ ਡਿੱਗ ਗਿਆ।"},{"question":"Hãy trình bày nguyên nhân, diễn biến, hậu quả, tính chất, bài học ý nghĩa của cuộc chiến tranh Thế Giới thứ nhất","answer":"Chiến tranh thế giới thứ nhấta. Nguyên nhân* Nguyên nhân sâu xa:- Sự phát triển không đều của chủ nghĩa tư bản vào cuối thế kỉ XIX - đầu thế kỉ XX làm thay đổi sâu sắc so sánh lực lượng giữa các nước đế quốc.- Mâu thuẫn giữa các nước đế quốc về vấn đề thuộc địa ngày càng gay gắt là nguyên nhân cơ bản dẫn đến chiến tranh.* Nguyên nhân trực tiếp:- Sự hình thành hai khối quân sự đối lập, kình địch nhau: khối Liên minh (Đức, Áo - Hung, I-ta-li-a) và khối Hiệp ước (Anh, Pháp, Nga).- Duyên cớ: Ngày 28-6-1914, Thái tử Áo-Hung bị một phần tử khủng bố ở Xéc-bi ám sát. Quân phiệt Đức, Áo-Hung chớp lấy cơ hội này để gây chiến tranh.b. Diễn biến*Giai đoạn thứ nhất (1914- 1916)- 28/6/1914 Thái tử Áo - Hung bị 1 người  Xéc-bi ám sát. Áo - Hung tấn công Xécbi- 1/8, Đức tuyên chiến Nga- 3/8, Đức tuyên chiến Pháp- 4/8, Anh tuyên chiến với Đức- Chiến tranh nhanh chóng lan rộng ra khắp thế giới- Từ 1916, chiến tranh chuyển sang thế cầm cự đối với cả hai phe.- Cả hai phe đều lôi kéo nhiều nước tham gia.- Sử dụng nhiều loại vũ khí hiện đại, đã giết hại và làm bị thương hàng triệu người.*Giai đoạn thứ hai (1917 - 1918).- 1917 Mĩ nhảy vào tham chiến và đứng về phe Hiệp ước.- Từ cuối năm 1917, phe Hiệp ước liên tiếp mở các cuộc tấn công làm cho đồng minh của Đức lần lượt đầu hàng.- 11/11/1918, Đức đầu hàng đồng minh vô điều kiện. CTTG1 kết thúc với sự thất bại của phe Liên minh.c. Kết cục của chiến tranh thế giới- Chiến tranh gây nhiều thảm họa cho nhân loại:+ 10 triệu người chết, 20 triệu người bị thương+  Cơ sở vật chất bị tàn phá, số tiền chi phí lên tới 85 tỷ đô la...- Chiến tranh đem lại lợi ích cho các nước thắng trận, Đức mất hết thuộc địa.*Tính chất: đây là cuộc chiến tranh đế quốc phi nghĩa"},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Đoàn xe tăng Nga di chuyển tại một khu vực không xác định ở Ukraine. Báo Anh Guardian ngày 31.7 dẫn lời ông Skibitsky cho biết, Nga đang huy động một lượng lớn binh sĩ tới vùng phía nam Ukraine, đối phó đợt phản công của quân đội Ukraine ở tỉnh Kherson. \\"Nếu Nga chiến thắng, họ sẽ tiếp tục tiến công nhằm giành thêm nhiều khu vực lãnh thổ\\", ông Skibitsky nói về kịch bản sau khi Nga chặn đứng đợt phản công của quân đội Ukraine ở Kherson. \\"Họ đang gia tăng số lượng binh sĩ, đối phó với đợt phản công của chúng tôi và có lẽ họ cũng chuẩn bị cho đợt tấn công mới. Miền nam Ukraine có ý nghĩa cực kỳ quan trọng với họ vì khu vực này giáp với bán đảo Crimea\\". \\"Nga đang thành lập các mũi nhọn mới với nòng cốt là quân dự bị thuộc các quân khu và quân đoàn số 3 đóng quân ở quân khu phía Tây\\", ông Skibitsky nói, cho rằng đơn vị mới này sẽ có nhiệm vụ dẫn đầu mũi tiến công của Nga nếu cục diện ở Kherson vẫn được giữ vững. Việc đào tạo và trang bị cho mũi nhọn mới đã được bắt đầu dưới sự giám sát trực tiếp của Bộ trưởng và Thứ trưởng Bộ Quốc phòng Nga. Lực lượng mới được triển khai ở đâu sẽ còn tùy thuộc vào tình hình ở miền nam và đông Ukraine, theo ông Skibitsky. Ông Skibitsky nói ưu thế của quân đội Nga hiện nay là khả năng điều động lực lượng và vận chuyển","answer":"trang thiết bị quân sự một cách nhanh chóng. Theo ông Skibitsky, Nga đã rút các nhóm tác chiến thuộc lực lượng đổ bộ đường không khỏi Donbass và tăng cường đến vùng Kherson. Đây là một trong những cánh quân chủ lực của Nga, từng tham gia tấn công thành phố Sloviansk ở Donetsk. Tuy vậy, ông Skibitsky nói Nga sẽ vẫn duy trì tiến công ở vùng Donbass, với tần suất và mức độ sẽ giảm bớt. Ở tỉnh Kharkiv, ông Skibitsky nói Nga đang tập trung phòng thủ, ngăn chặn các lực lượng Ukraine tiến sát đến biên giới. Ông Skibitsky nói quân đội Ukraine cần thêm nhiều vũ khí, cũng như các binh sĩ cần được tham gia các khóa huấn luyện cấp tốc ở nước ngoài. Phó cục trưởng cục tình báo quân đội Ukraine nói Nga đang cấp tốc tăng tốc sản xuất tên lửa và đạn dược phục vụ chiến tranh. Đầu tháng 7, quốc hội Nga đã thông qua các biện pháp kinh tế thời chiến. Các doanh nghiệp cung cấp hàng hóa và vật tư cho quân đội được yêu cầu tăng tốc sản xuất, luân phiên cho công nhân làm thêm giờ, theo Guardian."},{"question":"ෆෝමියුලා වන් තරඟයක් ජයග්‍රහණය කිරීමට පෙර වැඩිම තරඟ ප්‍රමාණයකට සහභාගී වූ ධාවකයා කවුද?","answer":"මෙක්සිකන් ජාතික ස'ජියෝ පේරෙස්"},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Жарым миллион кеп билген, Жалпы дүйнө боюнча Жаттагандай төп билген. Жалгыз сенсиң оюмча,  Саякбайга арналган бул саптардын автору- төкмө акын ким болгон?а) К. Акиев б) Барпыв) Алымкул г) Ы. Борончиев","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Туура жообу:г) Ы. Борончиев"},{"question":"Maxaa qalinku sheekiyo?","answer":"Hadraawi:\\"Maxaa qalinku sheekiyoQubanaha dharaartiyoKolba qodob la yaabliyoMahadhooyin qorayaa!   (Quduro,1980)."},{"question":"Tìm số nguyên x, biết:a) 4 . x + 15 = – 5; b) (– 270) : x – 20 = 70.","answer":"Lời giải:a) 4 . x + 15 = – 5     4 . x         = (– 5) – 15    4 . x         = – 20          x         = (– 20) : 4           x        = – 5Vậy x = – 5. b) (– 270) : x – 20 = 70   (– 270) : x            = 70 + 20    (– 270) : x           = 90                   x          = (– 270) : 90                  x          = – 3Vậy x = – 3. "},{"question":"Khẳng định nào sau đây là sai?A. 0 và 1 không phải là số nguyên tố cũng không phải là hợp số.B. Cho số a > 1, a có 2 ước thì a là hợp số.C. 2 là số nguyên tố chẵn duy nhất.D. Số nguyên tố là số tự nhiên lớn hơn 1 mà chỉ có hai ước 1 và chính nó.","answer":"Chọn đáp án B.Số a phải là số tự nhiên lớn hơn 1 và có nhiều hơn 2 ước thì a mới là hợp số.Nên đáp án B sai."},{"question":"Firy taona no azo lazaina hoe ampy taona ?","answer":"Valo ambin'ny folo(18) taona no azo atao hoe ampy taona."},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ 日本摂食障害学会のグループは、食事を食べることができなくなる「拒食症」と呼ばれる病気について調べました。この病気の治療をしている病院にアンケートを行って、28の病院が答えました。その結果、初めて病院に来た人の中で「拒食症」だった人は、2019年に400人いました。新型コロナウイルスが広がった2020年は480人になりました。2021年は610人で、約1.5倍になりました。特に10歳から19歳の若い人が増えています。2021年は347人で、2019年の約1.7倍になりました。グループは、新型コロナウイルスで学校が休みになったり、お金の心配をしたりして、ストレスが増えたことが原因だろうと考えています。専門家は「話を聞いて、気持ちをわかってあげることが大事です」と話しています。","answer":"食事が食べられない「拒食症」　特に若い人が増えている"},{"question":"Kurio iš dešimties didžiausių Lietuvos miestų pavadinimas yra kildinamas iš vienuolių ordino pavadinimo?","answer":"Marijampolės."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة هجاء من بحر الطويل. ساعدني؟","answer":"وَفى بِمَواعيدِ الخَليطِ وَأَخلَفووَكَم وَعَدوا القَلبَ المُعَنّى وَلَم يَفواوَما ضَرَّهُم أَن لَم يَجودوا بِمُقنِعٍمِنَ النَيلِ إِذ مَنَّوا قَليلاً وَسَوَّفواأَفي كُلِّ يَومٍ لَفتَةٌ ثُمَّ عَبرَةٌعَلى رَسمِ دارٍ أَو مَطيٌّ مُوَقَّفُوَرَكبٍ عَلى الأَكوارِ يَثني رِقابَهُملِداعي الصِبا عَهدٌ قَديمٌ وَمَألَفُفَمِن واجِدٍ قَد أَلزَمَ القَلبَ كَفَّهُوَمِن طَرَبٍ يَعلو اليَفاعَ وَيُشرِفُوَمُستَعبِرٍ قَد أَتبَعَ الدَمعَ زَفرَةًتَكادُ لَها عوجُ الضُلوعِ تَثَقَّفُقَضى ما قَضى مِن أَنَّةِ الشَوقِ وَاِنثَنىبِدارِ الجَوى وَالقَلبُ يَهفو وَيَرجُفُوَلَم تُغنِ حَتّى زايَلَ البُعدُ بَينَناوَحَتّى رَمانا الأَزلَمُ المُتَغَطرِفُكَأَنَّ اللَيالي كُنَّ آلَينَ حَلفَةًبِأَن لا يُرى فيهِنَّ شَملٌ مُؤَلَّفُأَلَمَّ خَيالُ العامِريَّةِ بَعدَماتَبَطَّنَنا جَفنٌ مِنَ اللَيلِ أَوطَفُيُحَيِّي طِلاحاً حينَ هَمّوا بِوَقعَةٍتَهاوَوا عَلى الأَذقانِ مِمّا تَعَسَّفواوَقيذينَ قَد مالَ النُعاسُ بِهامِهِمكَما أَرعَشَت أَيدي المُعاطينَ قَرقَفُأَعاريبَ لا يَدرونَ ما الريفُ بِالفَلاوَلا يَغبِطونَ القَومَ إِمّا تَرَيَّفوارَذايا هَوىً إِن عَنَّ بَرقٌ تَطاوَلواوَإِن عارَضوا الطَيرَ الغَوادي تَعَيَّفواتَوارِكَ لِلشَقِّ الَّذي هُوَ آمِنٌنَوازِلَ بِالأَرضِ الَّتي هِيَ أَخوَفُأَيا وَقفَةَ التَوديعِ هَل فيكِ راجِعٌإِشارَتَهُ ذاكَ البَنانُ المُطَرَّفُوَهَل مُطمِعي ذاكَ الغَزالُ بِلَفتَةٍوَإِن ثَوَّرَ الرَكبُ العِجالَ وَأَوجَفواعَشيَّةَ لا يَنفَكُّ لَحظٌ مُبَهَّتٌمُراقَبَةً مِنّا وَدَمعٌ مُكَفكَفُفَلِلَّهِ مَن غَنّى الحُداةُ وَراءَهُوَلِلَّهِ ما وارى العَبيطُ المُسَجَّفُوَسائِلَةٍ عَنّي كَأَنِّيَ لَم أَلِجحِمى قَومِها وَاليَومُ بِالنَقعِ مُسدِفُلَئِن كُنتُ مَجهولاً بِذُلِّيَ في الهَوىفَإِنّي بِعِزّي عِندَ غَيرِكِ أَعرَفُفَلا تَعجَبي أَنّي تَعَرَّقَني الضَنىفَإِنَّ الهَوى يَقوى عَلَيَّ وَأَضعُفُيُقَرَّعُ بِاِسمي الجَيشُ ثُمَّ يَرُدُّنيإِلى طاعَةِ الحَسناءِ قَلبٌ مُكَلَّفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَنغَلُّ في لَهَواتِهاوَفَحلُ الرَدى دوني بِنابَيهِ يَصرُفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَحمِل عَلى الضيمِ ساعِديوَقَد ثُلِمَ الماضي وَرُضَّ المُثَقَّفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَثنِ الأَعِنَّةَ ظافِراًتُحَدِّثُ عَن يَومي نِزارٌ وَخِندِفُوَحَيٍّ تَخَطَّت بي أَعَزَّ بُيوتِهِصُدورُ المَواضي وَالوَشيجُ المُرَعَّفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَصبِر عَلى الظَمءِ بَعدَماهَوى بِالمَهاري نَفنَفٌ ثُمَّ نَفنَفُوَكُلُّ غُلامٍ مِلءُ دِرعَيهِ نَجدَةٌوَلَوثَةُ أَعرابيَّةٍ وَتَغَطرُفُعَلى كُلِّ طاوٍ فيهِ جَدٌّ وَمَيعَةٌوَطاوِيَةٍ فيها هِبابٌ وَعَجرَفُوَقَد أُتبِعَت سُمرُ العَوالي زِجاجَهاوَحَنَّ مِنَ الإِنباضِ جَزعٌ مُعَطَّفُفَإِن تَسمَعوا صَوتَ المُرِنّاتِ تَعلَموابِمَن جَعَلَت تَدعو النَواعي وَتَهتُفُلَنا الدَولَةُ الغَرّاءُ ما زالَ عِندَهامِنَ الجَورِ واقٍ أَو مِنَ الظُلمِ مُنصِفُبَعيدَةُ صَوتٍ في العُلى غَيرُ رافِعٍبِها صَوتَهُ المَظلومُ وَالمُتَحَيَّفُوَنَحنُ أَعَزُّ الناسِ شَرقاً وَمَغرِباًوَأَكرَمُ أَبصارٍ عَلى الأَرضِ تَطرِفُبَنو كُلِّ فَيّاضِ اليَدَينِ مِنَ النَدىإِذا جادَ أَلغى ما يَقولُ المُعَنِّفُوَكُلِّ مُحَيّاً بِالسَلامِ مُعَظَّمٍكَثيرٍ إِلَيهِ الناظِرُ المُتَشَوِّفُوَأَبيَضَ بَسّامٍ كَأَنَّ جَبينَهُسَنا قَمَرٍ أَو بارِقٌ مُتَكَشِّفُحَيِيٌّ فَإِن سيمَ الهَوانَ رَأَيتَهُيَشُدُّ وَلا ماضي الغِرارَينِ مُرهَفُلَنا الجَبَهاتُ المُستَنيراتُ في العُلىإِذا اِلتَثَمَ الأَقوامُ ذُلّاً وَأَغدَفواأَبونا الَّذي أَبدى بِصِفّينَ سَيفَهُضُغاءَ اِبنِ هِندٍ وَالقَنا يَتَقَصَّفُوَمِن قَبلِ ما أَبلى بِبَدرٍ وَغَيرَهاوَلا مَوقِفٍ إِلّا لَهُ فيهِ مَوقِفُوَرِثنا رَسولَ اللَهِ عُلويَّ مَجدِهِوَمُعظَمُ ما ضَمَّ الصَفا وَالمُعَرَّفُوَعِندَ رِجالٍ أَنَّ جُلَّ تُراثِهِقَضيبٌ مُحَلّىً أَو رِداءٌ مُفَوَّفُيُريدونَ أَن نُلقي إِلَيهِم أَكُفَّناوَمِن دَمِنا أَيديهِمُ الدَهرَ تَنطِفُفَلِلَّهِ ما أَقسى ضَمائِرَ قَومِنالَقَد جاوَزوا حَدَّ العُقوقِ وَأَسرَفوايَضَنّونَ أَن نُعطى نَصيباً مِنَ العُلاوَقَد عالَجوا دَينَ العُلى وَتَسَلَّفواوَهَذا أَبي الأَدنى الَّذي تَعرِفونَهُمُقَدَّمُ مَجدٍ أَوَّلٌ وَمُخَلَّفُمُؤَلِّفُ ما بَينَ المُلوكِ إِذا هَفَواوَأَشفَوا عَلى حَزِّ الرِقابِ وَأَشرَفواإِذا قالَ رُدّوا غارِبَ الحِلمِ راجَعواوَإِن قالَ مَهلاً بَعضَ ذا الجَدِّ وَقَّفواوَبِالأَمسِ لَمّا صالَ قادِرُ مُلكِهِموَأَعرَضَ مِنهُ الجانِبُ المُتَخَوَّفُتَلافاهُ حَتّى سامَحَ الضَغنَ قَلبُهُوَأَسمَحَ لَمّا قيلَ لا يَتَأَلَّفُوَكانَ وَليُّ العَقدِ وَالعَهدِ بَينَهُوَبَينَ بَهاءِ المُلكِ يَسعى وَيَلطُفُوَلَمّا اِلتَقى نَجوى عُقَيلٍ لِنَبوَةٍوَمَدَّ لَهُم حَبلاً مِنَ الغَدرِ مُحصَفُلَوى عِطفَهُ لَيَّ القَنيِّ رِقابَهُموَلَو لِسِواهُ اِستَعطَفوا ما تَعَطَّفواوَسَل مُضَراً لَمّا سَما لِدِيارِهافَهَبَّ وَنامَ العاجِزُ المُتَضَعَّفُتَوَلَّجَها كَالسَيلِ صُلحاً وَعَنوَةًفَأَبقى وَرَدَّ البيضَ ظَمأى تَلَهَّفُلَهُ وَقَفاتٌ بَالحَجيجِ شُهودُهاإِلى عَقِبِ الدُنيا مِنىً وَالمُخَيَّفُوَمِن مَأثُراتٍ غَيرَ هاتيكَ لَم تَزَللَها عُنُقٌ عالٍ عَلى الناسِ مُشرِفُحَمى فاهُ عَن بُسطِ المُلوكِ وَقَد كَبَتعَلَيها جِباهٌ مِن رِجالٍ وَآنُفُزِمامُ عُلاً لَو غَيرُهُ رامَ جَرَّهُلَساقَ بِهِ حادٍ مِنَ الذُلِّ مُعنِفُجَرى ما جَرى قَبلي وَها أَنا خَلفَهُإِلى الأَمَدِ الأَقصى أُغِذُّ وَأوجِفُوَلَولا مُراعاةُ الأُبوَّةِ جُزتُهُوَلَكِن لِغَيرِ العَجزِ ما أَتَوَقَّفُحَذَفتُ فُضولَ العَيشِ حَتّى رَدَدتُهاإِلى دونِ ما يَرضى بِهِ المُتَعَفِّفُوَأَمَّلتُ أَن أَجري خَفيفاً إِلى العُلىإِذا شِئتُمُ أَن تَلحَقوا فَتَخَفَّفواحَلَفتُ بِرَبِّ البُدنِ تَدمى نُحورُهاوَبِالنَفَرِ الأَطوارِ لَبّوا وَعَرَّفوالَأَبتَذِلَنَّ النَفسَ حَتّى أَصونَهاوَغَيرِيَ في قَيدٍ مِنَ الذُلِّ يَرسُفُفَقَد طالَما ضَيَّعتُ في العَيشِ فُرصَةًوَهَل يَنفَعُ المَلهوفُ ما يَتَلَهَّفُوَإِنَّ قَوافي الشِعرِ ما لَم أَكُن لَهامُسَفسَفَةٌ فيها عَتيقٌ وَمُقرِفُأَنا الفارِسُ الوَثّابُ في صَهَواتِهاوَكُلُّ مُجيدٍ جاءَ بَعدِيَ مُردَفُ"},{"question":"Sheeg Nabi Cismaaciil Cs Meesha Uu Ku Aasan Yahay ?","answer":"Magaalada Makkah."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Vẽ bậy, bôi bẩn ở cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 mới khánh thành cách đây chưa lâu","answer":"Theo ghi nhận chiều 30.7, tại hai nhánh cầu qua quận 1 đã xuất hiện hàng chục những hình vẽ chằng chịt. Nét vẽ bằng sơn xịt màu đỏ và đen, mang bóng dáng của graffiti (nghệ thuật vẽ tranh tường) - thuộc nhóm các loại hình nghệ thuật đường phố. Tại vị trí lối cầu thang bộ lên xuống cầu cũng có hình vẽ kỳ dị màu trắng tựa mặt người và nhiều nét chữ nguệch ngoạc. Tình trạng bôi bẩn, vẽ bậy lên cầu khiến nhiều người dân bức xúc. Chị Phan Tố Nga (38 tuổi, ngụ Q.4) chia sẻ: \\"Khách du lịch nước ngoài đến đây tham quan, chụp hình kỷ niệm rất nhiều. Những hình vẽ như vậy sẽ làm xấu đi hình ảnh của Việt Nam trong mắt du khách quốc tế. Tôi thật sự không hiểu những người vẽ bậy đó họ suy nghĩ thế nào mà lại có hành động vô ý thức như vậy.\\" Bạn Trần Thị Mỹ Anh (18 tuổi, ngụ Q.3) bày tỏ: \\"Để làm nên một công trình đẹp như thế này cần sự cố gắng của rất nhiều người, vậy mà một hành động vô ý thức đã phá bỏ đi tất cả. Những hành vi đó cần bị lên án, phê bình. Mình cũng mong cơ quan chức năng sẽ có những hình thức quản lý, giám sát kỹ hơn cũng như những biện pháp xử phạt thích đáng những hành vi như vậy.\\" Cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 được xem là biểu tượng mới vừa được TP.HCM khánh thành thông xe cách đây không lâu. Cây cầu dây văng với kiến trúc đẹp được đầu tư với 3.100 tỷ đồng, dài gần 1,5 km với 6 làn xe, là điểm kết nối giao lộ Tôn Đức Thắng - Lê Duẩn (Q.1) với Đại lộ Vòng cung trong Khu đô thị mới Thủ Thiêm (TP.Thủ Đức). Sau khi đưa vào hoạt động đã thu hút được nhiều người dân đến tham quan, check-in. Được biết, đây không phải lần đầu tình trạng bôi bẩn, vẽ bậy lên các công trình công cộng khiến dư luận bức xúc. Vào cuối năm 2017, khi tuyến tàu sắt Cát Linh - Hà Đông đang dần hoàn thiện, những hình ảnh graffiti đã xuất hiện trên thân tàu. Hay vào giữa tháng 6.2022, 2 trong tổng số 17 toa tàu thuộc tuyến metro số 1 (Bến Thành - Suối Tiên) đặt tại depot Long Bình, TP.Thủ Đức cũng xảy ra tình trạng tương tự. Tình trạng mất mỹ quan đô thị tại cầu Thủ Thiêm 2 không chỉ dừng lại ở những nét viết, vẽ bậy tuỳ tiện. Theo ghi nhận, dưới chân cầu, rác và phế thải chất đống hàng loạt. Một số người dân còn \\"trưng dụng\\" các dải phân cách để nằm ngủ, thậm chí còn mắc cả võng để nằm. Ngoài ra, nhiều thanh thiếu niên đã biến một khu vực tại đây trở thành nơi trượt ván, trượt patin, khiến nhiều cột đèn công cộng bị đổ ngã."},{"question":"பின்வரும் சொற்றொடரை முடிக்கவும்: இவரது தந்தை இமான் அலிகான் மற்றும் இவரது மாவட்டத்தைச் சேர்ந்த பலரைப் போலவே, இவரும் இந்தியத் தரைப்படையில் பணியாற்றினார். இவர் 1950இல் கவசப் படையின் 18வது குதிரைப் படைப்பிரிவில் சேர்ந்து பல பதவிகளை வகித்தார். ","answer":"இந்திய-பாகிஸ்தான் போரின் போது சியால்கோட் பகுதியில் இவரது வீரத்திற்காக வீர சக்ரா விருது  பாக்கிஸ்தான் அரசால் வழங்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":" Sheeg qofka aan hooyo mooyaane aan aabo laheyn?","answer":" Waa Nebi Ciise (C.S)"},{"question":"தோசை இச்சொல்லின் ஒலிப்புடன் தொடர்பில்லாத சொல் எது? _________ஆசைமேசைபூசைஇசை","answer":"விடை : தோசை இச்சொல்லின் ஒலிப்புடன் தொடர்பில்லாத சொல் எது? __இசை___"},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa Asxaabigii geridiisa uu u luxmay Carshiga Alle","answer":" Wuxuu ahaa Sacad binu Mucaad al-Ansaariyi (RC)S38aad: Waxaad sheegtaa Sir-hayihii (xog-hayihii), Nebigaﷺ"},{"question":"Ija Nnamdi Azikiwe pẹlu ajọ FEDECO to n ṣeto ibo lọdun 1979","answer":"Ko si tabi ṣugbọn kan nibẹ pe ọgbọn oloṣelu ni Oloye Nnamdi Azikiwe fẹẹ lo fun awọn ti wọn n ṣeto idibo, o si fẹẹ fi juujuu bo gbogbo eeyan loju ni. Ofin eto idibo ti la ọrọ naa kalẹ, ohun ti ofin naa si sọ ni pe ki gbogbo eeyan to ba mọ pe oun yoo du ipo aarẹ orilẹ-ede Naijiria ri i pe awọn san owo-ori awọn pe perepere. Wọn ni ki i ṣe pe ki tọhun ṣẹṣẹ lọọ sare san owo-ori ẹ lẹyin ti eto idibo ti bẹrẹ, to jẹ pe tọhun yoo ti mọ pe oun fẹẹ dupo, nitori ẹ lo si ṣe lọọ sanwo ori. Wọn ni ẹnikẹni to ba ṣe eleyii, wọn yoo ka a kun ẹni ti ko sanwo ori ni, nitori ko yẹ ko jẹ nigba ti aṣaaju ba ni nnkan kan lati gba lọwọ araalu tabi ijọba ni yoo maa sare lọọ sawo-ori, ojuṣe to yẹ ki gbogbo aṣaaju maa ṣe ni. Ohun to jẹ ki Azikiwe ni iṣoro niwaju ajọ FEDECO to n ṣeto idibo nigba naa ree, nitori awọn yẹn ni awọn ko ni i gba orukọ ẹ wọle.Ni ọjọ kẹẹẹdọgbọn, oṣu kẹrin 1979, Azikiwe ko gbogbo awọn oniroyin jọ. Awọn oniroyin Naijiria lo pọ ju, ṣugbọn awọn aṣoju ileeṣẹ iroyin ilẹ okeere naa wa nibẹ, o ni nitori ọrọ ti oun fẹẹ sọ, ọrọ agbaye ni. Ọrọ agbaye kẹ! Eyi lo jẹ ki awọn oniroyin maa ṣubu lu ara wọn, wọn si jokoo wọọrọ sibi ti Azikiwe pepade si, wọn ni awọn ṣetan lati gbọrọ lẹnu ọmọwe oloṣelu to gboyinbo bii awọn araalu ọba. Ṣugbọn nigba ti Azikiwe de, o ni aaye oyinbo rẹpẹtẹ paapaa ko si, ohun ti oun pe wọn fun ni pe oun waa tun ọmọluabi oun ṣe ni. “Gẹgẹ bi orukọ mi, ati ipo pataki ti mo ti di mu ni Naijiria yii, gẹgẹ bii olori orilẹ-ede yii lẹẹkan ri, mo fẹẹ sọ fun gbogbo ẹyin oniroyin tiẹ duro yii pe irọ buruku ni Oloye Michael Ani ti i ṣe alaga ajọ to n ṣẹto idibo ilẹ wa, FEDECO, pa mọ mi.“Ẹyin naa ti gbọ ti ọkunrin naa n ke tantan pe Azikiwe ko sanwo-ori, Azikiwe ko sanwo-ori! Ọrọ to n sọ yii ko ri bẹẹ, nitori emi sanwo-ori ni temi o. Mo sanwo-ori mi ni ọdun 1976 si 1977, mo san ti 1977 si 1978, mo si ti san ti 1978 si 1979. Ohun ti ọkunrin olori FEDECO yii wa n sọ ko ye mi, idi ti mo si fi jade si gbangba ree, ko too di pe mọ gba ile-ẹjo lọ, nitori bi wọn ba sọ ọrọ naa ti ko tẹ mi lọrun, ile-ẹjọ ni yoo ba wa yanju ẹ. Ẹgbẹrun mẹta Naira o le (N3,062.75) ni owo ti mo san lọdun 1976 si 1977 yẹn o, o kan jẹ pe ninu awọn ipin idokoowo ti mo ni ni wọn ti yọ owo naa ni. Ohun ti ko ye Ani naa ree, kaka ko si pe mi jokoo ki n ṣalaye ọrọ fun un, o sare gbe atẹjade sita pe Azikiwe ko sanwo-ori. Nibo ni wọn ti n ṣe iru iyẹn, bawo ni yoo ṣe ṣe iyẹn fun mi laarin gbogbo awa ti a jọ fẹẹ du ipo aarẹ!”Ṣugbọn ọrọ ti Azikiwe sọ pẹlu awọn oniroyin yii tubọ bi Michael Ani ninu ni, n loun naa ba jade, o loun ko laiki bi Azikiwe ti sọrọ laali oun ni gbangba, oun ko fẹ iru ọrọ bẹẹ rara, nitori agbalagba ni Azikiwe, ko si yẹ ki wọn ba a nibi ti yoo ti maa jo langbalangba kikri. Oun naa ba awọn oniroyin Daily Times sọrọ lọjọ kan naa ti Azikiwe sọ ọrọ tirẹ, ohun to si wi ni pe ko si ihalẹ ti eeyan yoo ṣe fun onigẹgẹ ti yoo pọ ti ọfun rẹ silẹ o, ohun ti oun sọ nipa Azikiwe, ododo ọrọ gbaa ni. Baba yii ko sanwo-ori, o kan fẹẹ fi ṣakara pe oniroyin ati oloṣelu loun bo nnkan mọlẹ ni. “Ẹ wo o, ọrọ ti mo n sọ yii, emi mọ ohun ti mo n wi o!”, Michael Ani lo n sọrọ yẹn o, ọga awọn FEDECO. “Ṣe ẹ ri i, Ki ọrọ too di gbangba bayii, Oloye Azikiwe ti kọwe si mi, to ni ki n fọwọ sowọ pọ pẹlu oun, o ni ki n ṣe oun daadaa, itumọ ohun to si n wi ko ye mi.“Ṣe ki n fọwọsọwọpọ pẹlu ẹ ki n waa parọ fun awọn araalu ni, abi iru ifọwọsọwọ wo lo n beere lọwọ mi. Ọrọ yii o ruju rara, ki Azikiwe ko risiiti to fi sanwo-ori ẹ wa, risiiti yii naa ṣaa la fi n ṣe akọsilẹ ohun ti a n ṣe. Emi kọ ni mo ni risiiti, emi kọ ni mo n wa a, n ko si mọgba ti Azikiwe gba risiiti ẹ, risiiti to ti ko fun lemi fi n ṣe ohun tijọba ni ka ṣẹ. Ninu risiiti yii naa lo ti han pe Oloye Azikiwe ko sanwo ori ẹ nigba to yẹ ko san an. Ko san owo-ori ọdun 1976 si 1977 lọdun yẹn rara. O san diẹ ninu owo-ori ti 1976 si1977 yii lasiko to n san ninu owo-ori ti 1977 si 1978. Ẹẹmẹta lo sanwo ori 1977 si 1978, bẹẹ ni ki i ṣe ọdun yẹn tabi igba to yẹ ko san an lo san an, o san gbogbo ẹ pọ lasiko to n sanwo-ori 1978 si 1979 ni, iyẹn lẹyin ti awa ti kọwe si wọn lati FEDECO nibi pe ki wọn ko iwe ori wọn jade. Ninu oṣu keji la kọwe si wọn, oṣu kẹta ni Azikiwe sanwo-ori ẹ. Ki waa lo n sọ pe Michael Ani ko mọ ohun to n sọ si!”Aṣiri buruku ti Ani tu yii ka awọn ẹgbẹ NPP lara gan-an ni, iyẹn awọn ẹgbẹ Azikiwe, ẹgbẹ to ti fa a kalẹ lati dupo aarẹ lorukọ wọn. Ohun to si n dun wọn ni pe ọrọ naa ti n di yẹyẹ laarin awọn ẹgbẹ oṣelu to ku, pe ẹni ti ẹgbẹ NPP fa kalẹ, Azikiwe bo ṣe lagbara to, ko ni iwe ori, bẹẹ lo n kọwe si awọn ti wọn n ṣeto idibo pe ki wọn fọwọ sowọ pọ pẹlu oun. N lawọn naa ba binu, Paul Nnongo ti i ṣe akọwe ẹgbẹ naa si ni ọrọ ti doju ẹ, awọn yoo kuku gbe iwe ti Azikiwe kọ si Michael Ani jade, ko fi le mọ pe ko si awo kan ninu awo ẹwa, ko si igba kan ti Azikiwe beere awọn ohun ti ko ṣee ṣe tabi ti ko dara lọwọ ‘Ani. Ni Nnongo ba gbe iwe naa jade, ohun ti Azikiwe si kọ sibẹ ni pe awọn akauntanti oun, iyẹn awon aṣiro-owo to wa nidii eto owo-ori oun ṣe awọn aṣiṣe kan, ati pe ko si alaga ẹgbẹ awọn nile, nitori ẹ lo ṣe jẹ oun funra oun loun kọwe si Ani. O si ki i pe o ṣeun bo ṣe n fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu oun.Ṣugbọn pẹlu gbogbo eleyii naa, ohun ti Ani ṣaa n wi ni pe Azikiwe ko san owo-ori, bẹẹ ni Azikiwe n pariwo kiri pe oun san owo-ori. Nigba tọrọ naa fẹẹ burẹkẹ, ẹni kan to jẹ agbalagba ninu ẹgbẹ NPP, ẹni to mọ bi Azikiwe ṣe denu ẹgbẹ naa, to si di oludije ipo aarẹ lorukọ ẹgbẹ wọn, iyẹn Oloye Adeniran Ogunsanya, ko agbada rẹ kọrun nijọ kan, iyẹn lọjọ kẹta, oṣu karun-un, ọdun 1979, o gba ileeṣẹ awọn FEDECO lọ, ni Sẹkiteeria ijọba l’Ekoo. Ogunsanya ko wa ẹni meji lọ, Michael Ani lo tori ẹ lọ, ohun to si ba lọ naa ni bi ọrọ to wa nilẹ naa ko ṣe ni i dele-ẹjọ, o ni ki ọkunrin olori awọn FEDECO naa wo nnkan ṣe fun Azikiwe, ko si ma ṣẹ jẹ ki ọrọ ti awọn mejeeji ba n fa di ohun tawọn oniroyin yoo maa gbe kiri, nitori bi ọwọ awọn oniroyin ba ti tẹ ọrọ kan, wọn yoo fọ ọ bii aṣọ titi ti yoo fi gbo ni.Ṣugbọn pẹlu abẹwo yii naa, Ani ni oun ko ti i mọ bi oun ṣe le ran Azikiwe ati ẹgbẹ oṣelu rẹ lọwọ, nitori ofin ti sọ pe ẹni ti ko ba sanwo-ori ko le du ipo aarẹ, bẹẹ lofin sọ pe ẹni ti ko ba san owo naa ni asiko to yẹ ko san an, ki wọn ka a si ẹni ti ko sanwo-ori ni. Ki waa ni toun ninu ọrọ yii. Oun ko ṣaa ni i yi ofin pada nitori oludije kan ṣoṣo, pe ohun kan naa to le mu nnkan rọgbọ fun Azikiwe ni ko wa iwe to fi sanwo ori ni 1976 si 1977 jade. Azikiwe mọ pe nnkan fẹẹ daru ree, nitori awọn kan ti n kun hunrunhunrun ninu ẹgbẹ NPP pe ti awọn FEDECO ba lọọ ja a bọ silẹ, yoo pẹ fun ẹgbẹ awọn ki awọn too le ri ẹlomi-in gbe dide o. Wọn ni ki wọn tete yọ Azikiwe ki wọn fi ẹlomi-in rọpo ẹ, ko too di pe yoo ba ọrukọ ẹgbẹ awọn jẹ. Azikiwe mọ pe ipo aarẹ fẹẹ bọ ree, ati pe bi oun ko ba tete, orukọ oun yoo tun bajẹ pẹlu ẹ ni.Nidii eyi, bi iṣẹ ko pẹ ni, ẹni kan ki i pẹṣe. Azikiwe bẹ lọọya rẹ lọwẹ, o ni ko niṣo nile-ẹjọ. Ni wọn ba sare pe ẹjọ o, wọn ni FEDECO fẹẹ fiya jẹ Azikiwe, wọn ko fẹ ko du ipo aarẹ lorilẹ-ede baba rẹ, wọn fẹẹ fọwọ ọla gba a loju."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Turquia?","answer":"Ancara."},{"question":"Iza amin'ireo sehatra indostrialy no miasa amin'ny fanangonana sy famakafakana angona ara-bola?1-Sehatra teknolojia2-Sehatra ara-bola3-Seha-pampianarana","answer":"Valiny: 2. Sehatra ara-bola"},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri kanun labarai dan wannan labari mai zuwa: Miliyoyin Musulmai na yin ibadar azumin Ramadan a faɗin duniya a yanzu haka. Sai dai wasu masallatai a Birtaniya na hana mata shiga domin yin sallah, yayin da a gefe guda kuma wasu ke cewa lokaci ya yi da za a samu sauyi. Da kyar Almas ke samun lokacin yin ibada. Bazawara ce mai 'ya'ya uku kuma tana karatun digiri a jami'a. Dalilin da ya sa kenan take kallon Ramadan a matsayin wata dama ta musamman. \\"Na yi ta hanƙoron fara sallar Tarawihi musamman a ƙarshen mako, lokacin da muke da isasshen lokaci,\\" a cewarta. \\"Sai dai da na tuntuɓi masallacin unguwarmu sai suka ce 'ban da tsofaffi, ban da yara, ban da mata'.\\" Ba Almas kaɗai ba, sauran masallatai da yawa a faɗin Birtaniya sun yanke shawarar hana mata shiga a wannan watan. Akasari sukan ce saboda annobar korona. Mata irinsu Almas ba wai sallar Tarawihi kaɗai suke gaza yi ba, wadda nafila ce da ake yi a watan Ramadan, da yawa ba sa iya yin ibadar ma gaba ɗaya a masallatai, ciki har da Juma'a. 'Marasa gata' Yayin da iyalai da dama ke yin sallarsu a gida, da alama ibada a masallatai na ta'allaƙa ne da jinsin mutum, inda mutane da yawa ke ganin cewa hakan yana ba da damar natsuwa wajen gudanar da ibadar ga maza. Wani lokaci mata kan yi sallah a bayan maza a wuri ɗaya. Sai dai akasari akan samar da ɗaki biyu ne na maza daban na mata daban, yayin da maza ke yin sallah a ainahin masallacin su kuma mata a keɓaɓɓen wuri kuma ƙarami. Amma ba duka masallatai ne ke ware wurin mata ba. Fiye da ɗaya cikin huɗu na masallatai a Birtaniya ba su da ɓangaren mata. A wuraren da babu ɓangaren mata, akasari girman wurin yana bambanta. Anita Nayyar, wadda ke fafutikar Open My Mosque don nema wa mata 'yancin addini, ta ce da yawa ana bai wa mata \\"kujerar baya\\" ne. ta ce ɓangarensu ya yi ƙanƙanta, inda ake ba su wurare kamar gidan ƙasa ko kullellun ɗakuna ko kuma fili fetal. Ita ma annobar korona ta ta'azzara lamarin. \\"A lokacin dokar kulle, mun samu rahotanni cewa masallatan da mata ke zuwa sun hana su shiga, ko dai don su bi dokokin bayar da tazara ga maza ko kuma dai ba za su iya tabbatar da dokar ba a ɓangaren matan,\\" in ji ta. BBC ta tuntuɓi manyan masallatai guda 29 a Birtaniya domin jin tsare-tsarensu na watan Ramadan. Biyar dagaa ciki ba su da ɓangaren mata, yayin da shida suka ce ba za su iya barin mata ba saboda kariya daga annobar korona. Guda 12 sun bar mata, amma bakwai daga ciki ba su ba mu amsa ba. Daga cikin masallatan akwai Greenwich Islamic Centre da Baitul Futuh na Landan da  Jamia Al-Akbaria da ke Luton Masallacin Lanarkshire da ke Scotland. Masallacin su Almas mai suna  Milton Keynes Islamic Centre bai amsa buƙatar BBC ba da farko, amma daga baya ya ce ya hana mata da yara da tsofaffi shiga yayin wani \\"matakin gwaji\\". \\"Abin haushi shi ne akwai ɓangaren mata da kuma manyan ɗakuna uku a ƙasa,\\" Almas ta bayyana. \\"Akwai matan da na sani a masallacin waɗanda zawararwa ne da ba sa tare da yaransu da kuma masu fama da lalurar ƙwaƙwalwa. \\"Yadda abin ke damuna, ina mamakin yadda zai dami sauran waɗannan matan su ma.\\" \\"Abu ne da za a iya yi\\" Julie Siddiqi, wata mata mai fafutikar sama wa mata masallatai a Birtaniya, ta wallafa wani bidiyo a shafinta na Instagram tana kokawa kan yadda masallacin unguwarsu Jamia Masjid and Islamic Centre suka ƙi barin mata shiga a Ramadan ɗin nan. Ɗaruruwan mata a Birtaniya sun tura mata saƙon cewa su ma suna fuskantar irin wannan halin. \\"Na fahimci cewa akwai maganar kiwon lafiya,\\" in ji ta. \\"Amma masallacinmu na da girma sosai. Abu ne mai yiwuwa a masallacin. Magana ta gaskiya wannan abin ya fi ƙarfin korona. Da gangan ne kawai, aƙida ce cewa maza ne za su yanke hukuncin ko mata za su iya zuwa masallaci ko a'a.\\" Masallacin nata sun faɗa wa BBC cewa sun ɗaukji matakin ne bayan sun tuntuɓi wasu mata 'yan sa-kai \\"waɗnda ke da burin haɓaka harkokin mata\\". Ya ce ba zai so ya saka masu fafutikar cikin haɗari ba. Masallacin Baitul Futuh da ke Landan ya ce ba \\"wajibi ba ne a Musulunci mata su yi sallar jam'i a masallaci, wajibin na maza ne\\". Musulunci ya sharɗanta cewa sallar jam'i dole ce maza, amma ba dole ba ce kan mata waɗanda za su iya yin ta a gida. \\"Da zarar an cire dokokin kulle mata za su ci gaba da zuwa masallaci don gudanar da ibadu,\\" a cewar masallacin cikin wata sanarwa. Sheikh Ibrahim Mogra, wani limami a Leicester, ya ce \\"ya kamata a bai wa maza da mata damar shiga masallaci\\", yana mai cewa: \\"Wasu malaman sun ce zai fi kyau mata su yi sallah a gida fiye da masallaci, saboda haka akwai saɓani.\\" Wasu masallatan sun sauya shawara. Da farko Masallacin Hounslow Jamia Masjid and Islamic Centre ya tsara maza ne kawai za su yi sallah, amma ya sauya bayan an fara tattauna matsalar rashin zuwan mata masallataia a intanet a farkon Ramadan. Zara Mohammed, shugabar ƙungiyar Musulmai ta Birtaniya, ta ce kiran da suke yi shi ne a bai maza da mata damar amfani da masallaci - \\"a watan Ramadan ko kuma wajensa\\". \\"Dole ne a saka mata cikin shirin tafiyar da masallatai kuma muna ƙarfafa gwiwar ci gaba da tattaunawa mai amfani domin samar wa mata ƙarin damarmaki.\\"","answer":"Tabbas, ga kanun labarai don rubutun da aka bayar - Coronavirus: Me ya sa wasu masallatai ke hana mata ibada a watan Ramadan?"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو سبب نزول الآية: ” وَلَا تَنكِحُوا الْمُشْرِكَاتِ حَتَّىٰ يُؤْمِنَّ ۚ وَلَأَمَةٌ مُّؤْمِنَةٌ خَيْرٌ مِّن مُّشْرِكَةٍ وَلَوْ أَعْجَبَتْكُمْ” ؟","answer":"الإجابة: أحد المسلمين أراد نكاح مشركة وعلق نكاحه على موافقة النبي صلى الله عليه وسلم وعندما أخبره نزلت الآية"},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Bernhard Riemann para a matemática?","answer":"Bernhard Riemann teve um impacto profundo na análise matemática, especialmente na teoria dos números e na geometria diferencial. Ele formulou a hipótese de Riemann, influenciou o desenvolvimento da teoria dos números complexos e contribuiu para a geometria diferencial, introduzindo a métrica que leva seu nome, a métrica de Riemann."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? \\"Lâu nay, các dự án dọc bãi biển Nha Trang (phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng) rất được người dân và du khách quan tâm, bởi đây được xem là \\"linh hồn\\" của du lịch TP biển Nha Trang. Nhưng suốt thời gian dài, khá nhiều công trình chắn biển Nha Trang đua nhau mọc lên ở khu vực này Tháng 6.2022, UBND tỉnh Khánh Hòa đã có yêu cầu Công ty TNHH Sovico Khánh Hòa dừng hoạt động lưu trú tại khu nghỉ dưỡng Ana Mandara Nha Trang (dọc bãi biển Nha Trang, rộng gần 2 ha); đồng thời tháo bỏ hàng rào, tạo thông thoáng và mỹ quan khu vực. Sau đó, tỉnh Khánh Hòa tiếp tục có động thái để thu hồi phần diện tích 21.722 m2 tại dự án công viên Phù Đổng do Công ty TNHH Invest Park Nha Trang làm chủ đầu tư. Việc tháo dỡ, phá bỏ các kiến trúc công trình chắn biển không sử dụng nguồn ngân sách. Hai dự án này được biết đến là có \\"thâm niên\\" chắn biển, có dự án tồn tại hàng chục năm. Sau khi tỉnh Khánh Hòa có động thái trên, dư luận tiếp tục băn khoăn đến \\"số phận\\" của nhiều dự án chắn biển khác dọc bãi biển Nha Trang. Trong đó có 2 nhà hàng nổi tiếng là Sailing Club và Lousiane, sẽ như thế nào? Do Công ty CP quốc tế Biển Xanh làm chủ đầu tư và có diện tích hơn 4.800 m2, nhà hàng Lousiane có thời hạn hoạt động là 40 năm kể từ tháng 1.2004. Còn nhà hàng Sailing Club do Công ty TNHH Eco và Công ty CP Hòn Tằm biển Nha Trang làm chủ đầu tư, được cấp giấy chứng nhận đầu tư lần đầu vào tháng 9.2003, có diện tích hơn 2.000 m2; thời hạn hoạt động của dự án là 20 năm. Cả 2 nhà hàng này nổi tiếng đối với du khách từng đến Nha Trang, nhưng cả hai đều được xây dựng ngay chính diện mặt biển, khiến một khoảng lớn bờ biển bị chắn. Vì thế, cử tri nhiều lần phản ánh nên di dời các nhà hàng này, trả lại không gian biển công cộng cho người dân. Tuy nhiên, đến nay vẫn chưa có quyết định cụ thể nào. Trước đó, khi góp ý về việc lập điều chỉnh quy hoạch phân khu của khu vực phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng (trong đó tỉnh Khánh Hòa có đề xuất xây dựng xen kẽ các công trình dịch vụ trong các khu công viên, theo hướng mở, hài hòa cho các hoạt động cộng đồng…), thì Bộ VH-TT-DL không thống nhất với đề xuất này. Theo đó, UBND tỉnh Khánh Hòa cũng báo cáo xin ý kiến Tỉnh ủy Khánh Hòa về việc chấm dứt thực hiện lập điều chỉnh quy hoạch phân khu của khu vực phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng. Lý do là nếu tiếp tục triển khai đồ án này sẽ bị kéo dài và không tuân thủ theo mục tiêu, tính chất, quy mô thiết kế, nội dung định hướng ban đầu của đồ án theo nhiệm vụ quy hoạch được duyệt và các nội dung chỉ đạo triển khai liên quan của Tỉnh ủy, UBND tỉnh (do các nội dung liên quan mục tiêu, tính chất, định hướng quy hoạch chính của đồ án không được Bộ VH-TT-DL thống nhất). Mới đây, Ban Cán sự Đảng UBND tỉnh Khánh Hòa đã có báo cáo, xin ý kiến Ban Thường vụ Tỉnh ủy về việc xử lý, di dời một số công trình phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng; đồng thời đề xuất lập đồ án thiết kế đô thị đối với khu vực phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng (phía bờ biển Nha Trang). Theo đó, đối với 3 công trình (dự án Ana Mandara Nha Trang, nhà hàng và dịch vụ giải trí Louisiane, nhà hàng Sailing Club), UBND tỉnh Khánh Hòa xin ý kiến thống nhất theo hướng cho phép gia hạn thời gian tháo dỡ, di dời dự án Ana Mandara Nha Trang cho đến khi hoàn thành giai đoạn 1 dự án Ana Mandara tại khu du lịch bắc bán đảo Cam Ranh (dự kiến tháng 8.2022); cho phép nhà hàng Louisiane và Sailing Club được tiếp tục hoạt động cho đến khi Quy hoạch phân khu khu dân cư các phường Tân Lập - Lộc Thọ - Phước Tiến do UBND TP.Nha Trang đang triển khai, hoặc đồ án thiết kế đô thị riêng liên quan được phê duyệt. Đồ án thiết kế đô thị riêng này do Công ty CP tập đoàn đầu tư địa ốc No Va tài trợ kinh phí thực hiện. Theo UBND tỉnh Khánh Hòa, khu vực dọc theo phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng là khu vực có giá trị cao, đặc thù về cảnh quan và có vai trò quan trọng trong tổng thể phát triển của TP.Nha Trang nói riêng và tỉnh Khánh Hòa nói chung. Việc tồn tại các điểm dịch vụ công cộng trong phạm vi dải công viên bờ biển này cần được xem xét, vì sẽ góp phần nâng cao chất lượng không gian và cảnh quan khu vực này, thuận lợi cho các sinh hoạt công cộng của người dân và du khách; phát huy giá trị của khu vực để trở thành động lực phát triển kinh tế - xã hội địa phương. Trả lời Thanh Niên, ông Nguyễn Tấn Tuân, Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh Khánh Hòa, cho biết quan điểm của tỉnh không phải là xóa trắng các dự án dọc công viên bờ biển. Theo quy định của pháp luật, mật độ xây dựng tại khu vực này không quá 5%; tại đây sẽ có những điểm nhấn để làm nơi dừng chân cho người dân, du khách. Ngày 27.7 vừa qua, Tỉnh ủy Khánh Hòa đã có kết luận đồng ý việc đề xuất lập đồ án thiết kế đô thị đối với khu vực phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng theo định hướng phục vụ mục đích công cộng kết hợp với dịch vụ, nhưng ưu tiên phục vụ công cộng là chính. Ngoài ra, chỉ đạo rà soát toàn bộ các công trình, dự án của các nhà đầu tư (kể cả của nhà nước, tư nhân) đang hoạt động, khai thác ở khu vực phía đông đường Trần Phú - Phạm Văn Đồng. Đối với các dự án chưa hết thời hạn cho thuê đất, Tỉnh ủy Khánh Hòa đề nghị rà soát lại các thủ tục cho thuê đất trước đây để xử lý theo đúng quy định. Đối với các dự án đã hết thời hạn cho thuê đất, Tỉnh ủy Khánh Hòa đề nghị có phương án xử lý từng trường hợp cụ thể.\\"","answer":"Rà soát công trình chắn biển Nha Trang để có phương án xử lý từng trường hợp cụ thể"},{"question":"Title: ఉపగ్రహ చిత్రాలు: భారత్‌లో గాలి ఎందుకిలా మారింది?","answer":"వాతావరణంలోని ఫార్మాల్డిహైడ్ వాయువు స్థాయిని చూపే చిత్రం.ఉపగ్రహం ద్వారా సేకరించిన పై చిత్రాన్ని చూస్తే ఆ తేడా స్పష్టంగా కనిపిస్తోంది.ఇది వాతావరణంలో ఫార్మాల్డిహైడ్(CH₂O) అనే వర్ణరహిత వాయువు పరిమాణాన్ని సూచిస్తోంది.ఉత్తర భారతంలోని మైదాన ప్రాంతాల నుంచి కాలుష్య కారక వాయువులు ఉత్తరం దిశగా వెళ్లకుండా హిమాలయ పర్వతాలు ఎలా అడ్డుపడుతున్నాయో కూడా పై ఉపగ్రహ చిత్రంలో చూడొచ్చు. ఫార్మాల్డిహైడ్ వాయువు సహజంగా మొక్కలు, జంతువుల నుంచి విడుదలవుతుంది. అలాగే కాలుష్యాన్ని వెదజల్లే యంత్రాలు, కర్మాగారాల నుంచి కూడా వెలువడుతుంది.    ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా గాలి నాణ్యతను పరిశీలించేందుకు 'సెంటినల్-5పీ' అనే ఉపగ్రహాన్ని యూరోపియన్ స్పేస్ ఏజెన్సీ 2017 అక్టోబర్‌లో అంతరిక్షంలోకి పంపింది. భారత్‌తో పాటు మరికొన్ని దేశాల మీద కమ్మేసిన CH₂O గాఢతను ఆ ఉపగ్రహం గుర్తించింది. సాధారణంగా వాతావరణంలో అధికంగా ఉండే నైట్రోజన్, ఆక్సీజన్‌ వాయువులతో పోల్చితే ఫార్మాల్డిహైడ్ చాలా తక్కువ పరిమాణంలో ఉంటుంది. కొన్ని వందల కోట్ల వాయు అణువుల్లో CH₂O అణువులు కొన్ని మాత్రమే ఉంటాయి. గాలిలో దీని మోతాదును బట్టి కాలుష్య తీవ్రతను అంచనా వేయవచ్చని పరిశోధకులు చెబుతున్నారు. విభిన్న రకాల అస్థిర కర్బన సమ్మేళనాలతో ఫార్మాల్డిహైడ్ ఏర్పడుతుంది. అది సజహంగా మొక్కలు, జంతువుల నుంచి విడుదల అవుతుంది.అలాగే, మంట పెట్టినప్పుడు, కాలుష్యాన్ని విడుదల చేసే యంత్రాల నుంచి కూడా ఫార్మాల్డిహైడ్ వెలువడుతుంది. అందుకే వాతావరణంలో దాని పరిమాణం ఒక్కో ప్రాంతంలో ఒక్కో విధంగా ఉంటుంది.బొగ్గును మండించే కర్మాగారాలు, అడవుల్లో కార్చిచ్చు వల్ల ఇది ఎక్కువగా విడుదలవుతుంది. అయితే భారత దేశం విషయానికొస్తే, వ్యవసాయ భూముల్లో పంట కోతలు పూర్తయ్యాక వ్యర్థాలను తగలబెట్టడం కూడా మరో కారణంగా చెప్పొచ్చని బెల్జియన్ ఇన్‌స్టిట్యూట్ ఫర్ స్పేస్ ఏరోనమీ సంస్థకు చెందిన పరిశోధకురాలు ఇసాబెల్లె అన్నారు. అస్థిర కర్బన సమ్మేళనాలు, నైట్రోజన్ డయాక్సైడ్ (ఇంధనం మండించడం ద్వారా వెలువడే NO₂), సూర్యరశ్మితో కలిసి చర్యనొందినప్పుడు భూతలానికి సమీపంలో ఓజోన్ (ట్రోపోస్పియరిక్ ఓజోన్) ఏర్పుడుతుంది. అది తీవ్రమైన ఆరోగ్య సమస్యలకు దారితీస్తుంది. దానితో ఇతర జీవజాతులకూ, పంట చేలకు కూడా ప్రమాదమే.  బాగ్ధాద్, టెహ్రాన్, కువైట్ నగరాల్లో..రాజస్థాన్‌లో ఎడారి ప్రాంతాల్లో ఫార్మాల్డిహైడ్ తీవ్రత చాలా తక్కువగా ఉన్నట్టు తేలింది. అందుకు కారణం ఏమిటో కూడా స్పష్టంగా..."},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Demokrasi merupakan sistem politik di mana kekuasaan berada di tangan rakyat.","answer":"Démokrasi nyaéta sistem pulitik di mana kakawasaan aya dina leungeun rahayat."},{"question":"தவறு செய்தவர்களை என்ன செய்யலாம்? திருத்தலாமா? அப்படியே விட்டுவிடலாமா?","answer":"தவறு செய்வது மனித இயல்பு. தவறே செய்யாத மனிதர்கள் இல்லை. ஆனால் தவறு, சிறிய தவறு, பெரிய தவறு என்று இருவகைகளில் அமைகிறது. சிறிய தவறு செய்தால் அவர்களை திருத்த முயற்சி செய்யலாம். ஆனால், பெரிய தவறு செய்தவர்களுக்குக் கட்டாயம் தண்டனை கொடுத்தாக வேண்டும். அப்படியே விட்டுவிடக்கூடாது. இல்லையென்றால் மனித சமுதாயத்தைக் காப்பாற்ற முடியாமல் போய்விடும். தண்டனை கூட திருந்துவதற்கு வாய்ப்பாக அமையும்.இந்த மூன்று புள்ளிகள் பட்டியலிடப்பட்டு ஒரு முடிவு எடுக்கப்பட்டது:\\"1. தகவல் ஏற்கனவே பரவலாக அறியப்பட்டதா? அப்படியானால், அது பல முக்கிய செய்தி ஆதாரங்களில் தோன்றியிருந்தால், அது கட்டுரையில் சேர்க்க மிகவும் பொருத்தமானது. தகவல் ஒரு சில டேப்லாய்டு ஆதாரங்களில் மட்டுமே வெளிவந்திருந்தால், உள்ளூர் செய்தித்தாள்கள் , அல்லது சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான தரமான வலைத்தளங்கள், பின்னர் அதை சேர்ப்பது பொருத்தமானது அல்ல.\\"2. தகவல் உறுதியானதா மற்றும் உண்மையா? விக்கிப்பீடியா ஊகங்கள் அல்லது சந்தேகத்திற்கிடமான குற்றச்சாட்டுகளை வெளியிடும் வணிகத்தில் இல்லை, இது போன்ற குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் தங்களுக்குள் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கவை. குறிப்பாக, ஒரு நபரின் உயிருக்கு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் தவறான குற்றச்சாட்டுகள் தவிர்க்கப்பட வேண்டும்\\"3. பாடத்தின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க தன்மைக்கு தகவல் இன்றியமையாததா? திருமதி புஷ் ஒரு பதவியில் இருக்கும் அரச தலைவரின் மகளாக குறிப்பிடத்தக்கவர் என்றாலும், அவரைச் சுற்றியுள்ள ஊடகங்களில் பெரும்பாலானவை தனிநபராக சிறுவயதில் மது அருந்திய சம்பவத்தை மையமாகக் கொண்டுள்ளன. எனவே, தகவல் கட்டுரைக்கு இன்றியமையாததாகக் காணலாம்.\\"இவை அனைத்தும் பொருந்தினால், தகவல் சேர்க்கப்படுவது நியாயமானது. அவற்றில் எதுவுமே பொருந்தவில்லை என்றால், அது அகற்றப்பட வேண்டும் அல்லது பொதுவான சொற்களில் மட்டுமே சேர்க்கப்பட வேண்டும்.\\"ஆனால், இது தெளிவாக இல்லை: மூன்றும் பொருந்தினால், தகவல் சேர்க்கப்பட வேண்டும்; இல்லை என்றால், அது அகற்றப்பட வேண்டும். முதலாவதாக, \\"பொதுவான சொற்களில் மட்டும் சேர்க்கப்பட்டுள்ளது\\" என்பது தெளிவான வழிகாட்டுதல் அல்ல, ஆனால் பட்டியலில் உள்ள இரண்டாவது உருப்படியை மறந்து விடுங்கள் -- முதல் அல்லது மூன்றாவது பொருந்தும் ஆனால் இரண்டும் பொருந்தவில்லையா? இந்த வழிகாட்டுதல் மூன்றும் பொருந்தும் அல்லது மூன்றில் எதுவுமே இல்லாதது போன்ற நிகழ்வுகளுக்கு குறைந்தபட்சம் வரக்கூடும் என்று தோன்றுவதற்கு உதவாது.இரண்டாவதைப் பொறுத்தவரை, மற்ற இரண்டில் ஏதேனும் ஒன்று இல்லாதது தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் ஒன்றைத் தவிர்க்க அல்லது நீக்க போதுமான காரணமாக செயல்படவில்லை என்றால், அது மற்ற இரண்டில் இருந்து பிரிக்கப்பட வேண்டும் மற்றும் ஒரு அளவுகோலை உருவாக்க வேண்டும். என்சைக்ளோபீடியாவில் உள்ள அனைத்தும் \\"உறுதியான மற்றும் உண்மையாக\\" இருக்க வேண்டும், அதைக் கண்டறிய கடினமாக இருந்தாலும் கூட. மற்ற இரண்டு அளவுகோல்கள் இருந்தபோதிலும், உயிருள்ள ஒரு நபரின் நற்பெயருக்கு ஏதாவது தீங்கு விளைவிக்கும் என்றால், இந்த அளவுகோல் முடிந்தவரை முழுமையானதாக இருப்பது இரட்டிப்பாகும்."},{"question":"Inona ilay kilalao malagasy malaza fahiny mampiasa vatokely ankoatra ny fanorona?","answer":"Katro ilay kilalao malagasy malaza fahiny mampiasa vatokely ankoatra ny fanorona ."},{"question":"निम्नलिखित चुटकुले का उत्तर दें :चार पैर और सिर जब मैं काम करता हूँ, पानी में घुस जाता हूँ तो छोटा हो जाता हूँ। क्या हूँ मैं?","answer":"उत्तर: मेंढ़क"},{"question":"સોયદોરો કાવ્ય નું વર્ણન કરો.","answer":"સોયદોરોસોયદોરો ગામડો,અને તેના ગામડાઓ,હરિયાળી ધરતી,અને ગોરી ગોરી ટેકરીઓ.સોયદોરો લોકો,અને તેમની લોકવાણી,સરળતા અને નિર્દોષતા,અને તેમની ખુશી.સોયદોરો સંસ્કૃતિ,અને તેની સમૃદ્ધિ,પરંપરાઓ અને રિવાજો,અને તેમની અનોખી ઓળખ.સોયદોરો સંગીત,અને તેની ગૂંજ,ગીતો અને તાલ,અને તેમની આકર્ષકતા.સોયદોરો ભાષા,અને તેની ઝણકાર,શબ્દો અને વાક્યો,અને તેમની શક્તિ.સોયદોરો પ્રેમ,અને તેની ગરમી,હૃદયો અને શરીરો,અને તેમની ઉત્તેજના.સોયદોરો આશા,અને તેની ચમક,ભવિષ્ય અને સપના,અને તેમની સુંદરતા.સોયદોરો ગામડો,અને તેના ગામડાઓ,એક સુંદર સ્વપ્ન છે,જે હંમેશા જીવંત રહેશે.આ કાવ્ય સોયદોરો ગામડાની સુંદરતા અને સમૃદ્ધિને વર્ણવે છે. કાવ્યમાં ગામડાની લોકો, તેમની લોકવાણી, સંસ્કૃતિ, સંગીત, ભાષા અને પ્રેમનો પણ ઉલ્લેખ કરવામાં આવ્યો છે. કાવ્યના અંતે, ગામડાની આશા અને સુંદરતાને પ્રતિબિંબિત કરવામાં આવ્યું છે."},{"question":" தண்டோரா என்பதன் பொருள் தராத சொல் எது? கீழே உள்ள நான்கு விருப்பங்களிலிருந்து மிகவும் பொருத்தமான பதிலைத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கவும்:அ) முரசு அறிவித்தல்ஆ) தெரிவித்தல்இ) கூறுதல்ஈ) எழுதுதல்","answer":"விடை: ஈ) எழுதுதல்தண்டோரா என்பதன் மற்றொரு பொருள் பறை சாற்றல் ஆகும். இசை / ஓசை எழுப்பி தகவல் கூறும் முறை பறை சாற்றல் ஆகும். கொடுக்கப்பட்ட விருப்பங்களிலிருந்து தொடர்புடைய சொற்கள் முரசு அறிவித்தல், தெரிவித்தல், கூறுதல் ஆகும். அதனால், தண்டோரா என்பதன் பொருள் தராத சொல் எழுதுதல் ஆகும்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'salah urat'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud terseliuh atau terpelecok. Contoh ayat: Dia salah urat semasa mengadakan latihan lompat tinggi semalam."},{"question":"मैडम क्युरी","answer":"मैडम क्युरी, जसलाई मारी क्युरी पनि भनिन्छ, एक अग्रगामी भौतिकशास्त्री र रसायनशास्त्री थिइन्। उनी नोबेल पुरस्कार जित्ने पहिलो महिला थिइन् र दुई फरक वैज्ञानिक क्षेत्रहरूमा नोबेल पुरस्कार जित्ने एक मात्र व्यक्ति रहिन् (१९०३ मा भौतिकशास्त्र र १९११ मा रसायनशास्त्र)। उनी पोलोनियम र रेडियम तत्वहरूको खोजका लागि प्रख्यात छन्। म्याडम क्युरीको कामले परमाणुको बुझाइमा क्रान्ति ल्यायो र विज्ञान र चिकित्साको क्षेत्रमा गहिरो प्रभाव पार्यो।"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta tamanin da takwas a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 88"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο: Διοργάνωσε αρκετούς από τους αγώνες του Παγκοσμίου Πρωταθλήματος ","answer":"Καλαθοσφαίρισης Ανδρών Κ-19 2019."},{"question":"Welke vruchten en groenten worden geteeld in de laaggelegen gebieden van Kenia?","answer":"Dit zijn de volgende vruchten en groenten: Kokosnoten, ananassen en maïs."},{"question":"சு. தியோடர் பாஸ்கரன் அவர்களின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"இன்று உணவுக்காக நாம் சாகுபடி செய்யும் எல்லாத் தாவரங்களும், நம்முடன் வாழும் செல்லப்பிராணிகள், கால்நடைகள் எல்லாமே காட்டுயிரிலிருந்து வந்தவைதான்."},{"question":"හොරණෑව යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"හොරණෑවක් යනු පිත්තල වලින් සාදන ලද අං සහිත උපකරණයකි. එය ශාස්ත්‍රීය සංගීතයේ භාවිතා වන අතර එය ජෑස් වලද බහුලව දක්නට ලැබේ. ඔබට පිකෝලෝ වැනි ඉතා ඉහළ ශබ්දයක් ඇති හොරණෑ සහ ඉතා අඩු ශබ්දයක් ඇති බේස් හොරණෑවක් තිබේ. හොරණෑ තනි තනිව හෝ වෙනත් සංගීත භාණ්ඩ සමඟ කණ්ඩායමක් ලෙස වාදනය කළ හැකිය."},{"question":"\\"Кызыл болот желегим, Алмамбет — Каңгайдан келген белегим, кысталыш жерде керегим, өйдө чыкса — өбөгүм, өлбөй кантип турамын, кайран Алмам — жөлөгүм,  алтын айдар, чок белбоо, арстаным Алмам, ала жат, кол кармашып кеткенге, кокуй күн, Алмам, ала жат\\",- деп ким арманын айткан?","answer":"\\"Чоң казатта\\" Алмамбет ке Шыпшайдардын огу тийип, каза болот. Ошондо кан досунан, жан досунан ажыраган, тоодой болгон алп Манас кумурскадай кунсуз болуп: \\"Кызыл болот желегим, Алмамбет — Каңгайдан келген белегим, кысталыш жерде керегим, өйдө чыкса — өбөгүм, өлбөй кантип турамын, кайран Алмам — жөлөгүм, алтын айдар, чок белбоо, арстаным Алмам, ала жат, кол кармашып кеткенге, кокуй күн, Алмам, ала жат\\",- деп жер муштап арманын төгөт.Алмамбеттин керээзи жана анын сөөгүнүн коюлушу. Алмамбет керээз кылгандай, анын сөөгү Катагандын кан Кошой жердеген Ат-Башынын Чеч-Дөбөсүнө коюлат."},{"question":"Theo em, vì sao chúng ta luôn nghĩ về những người thân yêu trong gia đình mỗi khi xa nhà hoặc gặp khó khăn?","answer":"- Chúng ta luôn nghĩ về những người thân yêu trong gia đình mỗi khi xa nhà hoặc gặp khó khăn bởi gia đình là điểm tựa tinh thần của mỗi người, là nơi chúng ta gắn bó, trưởng thành. Mỗi thành viên trong gia đình đều yêu thương, đùm bọc, chia sẻ mọi buồn vui với nhau, khi xa nhau luôn nghĩ về để mong muốn được an ủi động viên, mong muốn được chia sẻ để vượt qua mọi khó khan thử thách."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kasih bapa sepanjang jalan, kasih anak sepanjang penggalan'?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud kasih sayang bapa kepada anak jauh lebih besar daripada anak kepada bapanya."},{"question":"Créez un modèle d'e-mail de remerciement à envoyer après l'entretien.","answer":"Objet : Merci pour l'opportunité d'entretienCher [Nom de l'intervieweur],J'espère que cet e-mail vous trouvera bien. Je voulais prendre un moment pour exprimer ma sincère gratitude pour l'opportunité de passer un entretien pour le poste de [Titre du poste] chez [Nom de l'entreprise] le [Date de l'entretien]. Ce fut vraiment un plaisir d'en apprendre davantage sur l'équipe, la mission de l'entreprise et les projets passionnants sur lesquels vous travaillez.J'ai été très impressionné par la conversation perspicace que nous avons eue concernant le rôle et la manière dont mes compétences correspondent aux besoins de l'équipe. Les informations que vous avez fournies sur [un projet spécifique, un défi ou un aspect abordé lors de l'entretien] m'ont particulièrement touché, et je suis enthousiasmé par la perspective de contribuer à des initiatives aussi percutantes.J'apprécie le temps que vous et le reste de l'équipe avez pris pour me rencontrer et me donner un aperçu complet du poste. Notre discussion a encore solidifié mon enthousiasme à l’idée de rejoindre [Nom de l’entreprise]. Je suis convaincu que mon expérience dans [mentionner les compétences ou expériences pertinentes discutées] me permettra d'apporter une contribution positive et significative à l'équipe.Si vous avez besoin de documents ou de références supplémentaires, n'hésitez pas à me le faire savoir. Je serai plus qu’heureux de vous fournir toute information complémentaire susceptible de vous aider dans votre processus de prise de décision.Merci encore d'avoir pensé à moi pour le rôle de [Titre du poste]. J'attends avec impatience l'opportunité de potentiellement rejoindre l'équipe et de contribuer au succès continu de [Nom de l'entreprise]. N'hésitez pas à me contacter si vous avez d'autres questions ou si vous avez besoin de plus d'informations.Je vous souhaite une semaine productive à venir et j'espère avoir de vos nouvelles bientôt.Cordialement,[Ton nom complet][Vos coordonnées]"},{"question":"QR කේතය සහිතව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිකුත් කළ පළමු මුද්දරය කුමක්ද?","answer":"QR කේතය සහිතව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිකුත් කළ පළමු මුද්දරය රුපියල් 25 මුද්දරය වේ."},{"question":"waxaad Sheegtaa Magaca Iyo Wadanka Uu U Dhashay Xog-Hayihi Ugu Horeyey Qaramada Midoway(UNO)?","answer":"Magaciisa Wuxu Ahaa Trygare Lie, Wuxuuna U Dhashay Wadanka Norway."},{"question":"پروژه څه شی ده ؟","answer":"هدف لرونکي فعاليتونه چي د بوديجې ، تشکيل ، کاري پلان او مشخصي مودې لرونکي او د ټاکلو پایلو لرونکي وي . یا په بل عبارت اهدافو ته د رسېدو لپاره له پلانګذاري او طرح شويو فعالیتونو څخه عبارت ده . په پروژه کي د فعالیتونو شروع او ختم او بوديجه مشخصه وي ."},{"question":"web framework တွေရဲ့ Backbone Components တွေအကြောင်း ပြောပြပေးနိုင်မလား","answer":"Web Framework တခုရဲ့ architecture ကို High level ကြည့်မယ်ဆိုရင် Orchestrator, Request/Response Model, Routing System, Handler, Middleware ဆိုပြီး အဓိက ၅ ခု ရှိပါတယ်။Orchestrator ရဲ့ တာဝန်က request-response cycle တခုလုံးကို စီမံ manage လုပ်ပေးဖို့ဖြစ်တယ်။Request နဲ့ Response Model တွေက raw http တွေကို Web Program က နားလည်မယ့် object တွေအဖြစ် ပြောင်းယူထားတဲ့ model တွေဖြစ်ပါတယ်။ ပြောင်းလိုက်တဲ့ Request Object မှာ မူလ raw http ထဲပါလာတဲ့ header, body စတာတွေကို state အနေနဲ့ ပြန်ရယူနိုင်သလို လိုအပ်တဲ့ behavior တွေကိုပါ တပါတည်း ထည့်ဆောက်ပေးလိုက်ပါတယ်။Handler တွေက business logic နဲ့ဆက်နွယ်တဲ့ လုပ်ဆောင်ချက်တွေကို ကိုင်ထားပြီး Middlware တွေကတော့ business logic နဲ့ တိုက်ရိုက် မပတ်သက်တဲ့ လုပ်ဆောင်ချက်တွေကို တာဝန်ယူကြတယ်။ Shopping mall တခုအနေနဲ့ တွေးကြည့်မယ်ဆိုရင် ပစ္စည်းတင်တဲ့စင်၊ စျေးခြင်း၊ ငွေရှင်းကောင်တာ၊ အရောင်းဝန်ထမ်း စတာတွေက business logic တွေဖြစ်ပြီး ဝင်ပေါက်မှာ လုံခြုံရေး စစ်တာနဲ့ mall ထဲက cctv တွေကိုတော့ စျေးဝယ်ရာမှာ တိုက်ရိုက်မပတ်သက်တဲ့ middleware တွေလို့ တွေးကြည့်နိုင်ပါတယ်။ client ဆီက Request ရောက်လာတဲ့အခါ ဘယ် url နဲ့ ဘယ်အခြေအနေတွေမှာဆိုရင် အဲဒီ Request ကို ဘယ် Handler ဒါမှမဟုတ် ဘယ် Middleware တွေက process လုပ်စေချင်သလဲဆိုတာကိုတော့ Routing system မှာ သတ်မှတ်ထားရပါတယ်။"},{"question":"Wat is de glenea mimoscalaris?","answer":"De glenea mimoscalaris is een keversoort uit de familie van de boktorren (Cerambycidae). De wetenschappelijke naam van de soort werd voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1969 door Breuning."},{"question":"فصل دراسي يبلغ عدد الطلاب فيه 25 طالب، رسب منهم 40%، احسب عدد الطلاب الناجحين في هذا الفصل؟","answer":"عدد طلاب الفصل الراسبين في الفصل يساوي = [(25×40) ÷ 100] يساوى عددهم 10 طلاب.عدد طلاب الفصل الناجحين يساوي = 25- 10 يساوي= 15 طالب."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Norvège","answer":"Péeyum réwum Norvège mu ngi tudu Oslo"},{"question":"ലോകത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും ഉയരം കൂടിയ പർവ്വതം ഏതാണ്?","answer":"ലോകത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും ഉയരം കൂടിയ പർവ്വതം എവറസ്റ്റ് കൊടുമുടിയാണ്."},{"question":"उपन्यास","answer":"उपन्यास कथाको एक अपेक्षाकृत लामो लेख हो। सामान्यतया अनौपचारिक रूपमा लेखिने यसमा व्याकरणलाई भन्दा पनि कथाको प्रवाहलाई प्रथमिकता दिइन्छ।"},{"question":"انګېزه څه شی ده ؟","answer":" سبب ، باعث ، علت ، هغه څه چي یو څوک یو کار ته وپاروي "},{"question":"මිනිසකුගේ සාමාන්‍ය ශ්වසන වේගය වනුයේ කොපමණද?","answer":"මිනිසකුගේ සාමාන්‍ය ශ්වසන වේගය වනුයේ විනාඩියකට වාර දහසයකි. (16) වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාවේදී ඉතා අවශ්‍ය වන ඔක්සිජන් වායුව අතිරේක හා රෝගීන්ගේ ශ්වසන අවශ්‍යතා සැපරීමට භාවිතාවේ. ඔක්සිජන් මුහුණු ආවරණ හා නාසික ආධාරක (nasal cannels) ආධාරයෙන්, නියුමෝනියා, එම්පිසිමා හා හදවත් රෝග වැනි අපහසුතා මඟ හරවා ගැනීමට ඔක්සිජන් වායුව අතිරේක ලෙස භාවිත කරයි."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hujan berbalik ke langit'? Nyatakan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud perihal orang yang lebih (kuat, pandai, dan lain-lain) meminta tolong kepada orang yang kurang (lemah, bodoh, dan lain-lain). Contoh ayat ialah \\"Walaupun Pak Abu seorang yang kaya, tetapi dia masih meminta pertolongan daripada orang miskin di kampungnya."},{"question":"Marik'andro malagasy amin'ny enin'ora maraina dia antsoina hoe:...?\\t1- Mifoha olona\\t2- Mazava ratsy\\t3- Mivoaka goaika\\t4- Miran'andro","answer":"\\tsafidy 3: Miran'andro no iantsona nu marik'andro malagasy amin'ny enin'ora maraina."},{"question":"waa maxay jiifto?","answer":"Jiifto : jiiftada waa nooc kamid ah maansadda waxaana la tiriyaa xilliga guubaabada iyo waanada,waana tiirka saddexaad ee maansadda.Tusaale:Haddii dunida lagu waarayooy daayin noqoneysoWaxaan laga dileen nebiyadii laysu soo dirayeeAsxaabihii baan degeen daahirka ahaayeFaadumo iyo dirked ayaan dumug yidhaahdeene                                                                "},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Ankehitriny, halako ny manodidina ahy ! Maharikoriko ahy ny salovantava rehetra mifanehatra amiko. »","answer":"Maneho atezerana io fanambarana io. Tsy ampiononina ny fo, ka lasa izay mampionona dia mahatezitra."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: I samband med Tysklands delning kom universitetet att befinna sig i den sovjetiska ockupationssektorn i Östberlin. Undervisningen började åter i januari 1946, nu underställd den sovjetiska militärförvaltningen av Östberlin. Fram till 1948 kom universitetet gradvis att anpassas till officiell sovjetisk doktrin, och ideologiska föreläsningar organiserade av kommunistpartiet SED gjordes till en obligatorisk del av undervisningen. Studentprotester under åren 1946-1948 ledde till att flera studenter tillhörande CDU och Junge Union dömdes till långa fängelsestraff i arbetsläger, och enstaka medlemmar av proteströrelsen avrättades i Sovjetunionen. Som en reaktion på dessa händelser och SED-ledningens vägran att anta studenter som ansågs politiskt oppositionella, grundades på studentoppositionens begäran Freie Universität Berlin 1948, med understöd av Västberlins regerande borgmästare Ernst Reuter och den amerikanska ockupationsmakten. Freie Universität förlade sin verksamhet till förorten Dahlem i Västberlin. Samma år inleddes","answer":"Berlinblockaden och förbindelserna mellan Östberlin och Västberlin skars av."},{"question":"अलबर्ट आइंस्टीन की सापेक्षता सिद्धांत क्या है?","answer":"अलबर्ट आइंस्टीन के सापेक्षता सिद्धांत के अनुसार, समय और स्थान एक ही तत्त्व के रूप में जुड़े होते हैं।"},{"question":"සිංහල අක්ෂර මාලාවේ දැනට භාවිතා නොවන අක්ෂර මොනවාද?","answer":"සිංහල අක්ෂර මාලාවේ ඇති 'ඏ', 'ඐ' යන අක්ෂර නූතන ව්‍යවහාරයේ දී යොදා නොගනී."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini? Mula-mula saya hijau, lama jadi kuning, akhir jadi kering, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah daun kerana daun berubah warna, bermula dengan hijau semasa muda dan segar, menjadi kuning apabila mula tua, dan akhirnya kering dan gugur."},{"question":"Dalam se _______ ayat yang kakak tulis terdapat kira-kira lapan _______ perkataan.","answer":"baris....patah"},{"question":"Dado el título y el resumen de un artículo a continuación, genere un artículo breve o el comienzo de un artículo largo para acompañarlos (máximo 500 caracteres). Título: Cuáles son los teléfonos inteligentes más veloces del mercado.Resumen: Apple no estaba bromeando cuando se jactó de la velocidad y el nuevo chip A9 de su  iPhone 6s . Al menos, eso es lo que revelan las últimas cifras de An Tu Tu Benchmark, una herramienta que analiza la potencia de los teléfonos inteligentes.","answer":"En la carrera por la supremacía en el mundo de los dispositivos móviles, la velocidad se ha convertido en un factor crucial y en este aspecto, Apple parece estar liderando el camino con su iPhone 6s y su potente chip A9. Los resultados recientes de An Tu Tu Benchmark, una herramienta confiable para evaluar la potencia de los teléfonos inteligentes, respaldan las afirmaciones de Apple. Estas cifras, no solo subrayan la competencia en el mercado, sino que también plantean la pregunta: ¿cuáles son los otros contendientes en esta carrera de velocidad?"},{"question":"Si Ann ay may pitong kendi. Binigyan siya ni Lucy ng pitong kendi pa. Ilang candies ang mayroon si Ann?","answer":"Mayroong 7 + 7 = 14 na kendi si Ann."},{"question":"اكمل النص التالي: في أوائل خمسينيات القرن العشرين أتبعت أودلا للحكم الأردني بين حربي 1948","answer":"و1967، وكان عدد سكانها آنذاك حوالي 179 نسمة عام 1961، وكانت تتبع إدارياً إلى لواء نابلس."},{"question":"nhận định về tác phẩm “Vợ chồng A Phủ” - Tô Hoài","answer":"Bàn về kết thúc đoạn trích Vợ chồng A Phủ của Tô Hoài, có ý kiến cho rằng: “ Hành động cắt đứt dây mây cởi trói cứu A Phủ rồi chạy theo A Phủ của nhân vật Mị thật bất ngờ, đột ngột, không thể dự đoán trước.”, lại có người khẳng định: “Đó là một kết thúc tự nhiên, tất yếu.”"},{"question":"What is the Oxford comma, and when should it be used?","answer":"The Oxford comma is a comma placed before the conjunction in a list of items. Its use is a matter of style, but it helps clarify the meaning of a sentence."},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Surabi nyaéta kadaharan tina tipung béas nu dicampur kalapa jeung bumbu séjénna, nu diasupkeun kana citakan tina taneuh nu dipanaskeun maké suluh.","answer":"Terjemahan: Surabi merupakan makanan yang terbuat dari tepung beras yang dicampur dengan kelapa dan bumbu lainnya, yang dimasukkan ke dalam cetakan tanah yang dipanaskan menggunakan kayu bakar."},{"question":"青楼有哪些著名的人物？","answer":"答：历史上，青楼出过很多著名的人物，如杜十娘、李师师、董小宛等。"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: XSMN 1/8 - Xổ số miền Nam hôm nay - SXMN 1/8/2022 - Kết quả xổ số ngày 1 tháng 8","answer":"XSMN. Xổ số hôm nay. Xổ số miền Nam. SXMN. XSMN . Kết quả xổ số. XSMN 01/8/2022. Xổ số hôm nay ngày 01 tháng 8. Xo so hom nay. Xo so mien Nam. KQXS hom nay. KQXSMN. XSKG 31/7 - Xổ số Kiên Giang hôm nay 31/7/2022 - Kết quả xổ số ngày 31 tháng 7XSKG. Xổ số Kiên Giang. XSKG 31/7. Kết quả xổ số hôm nay 31/7/2022. Xổ số Kiên Giang ngày 31 háng 7. XSKG hôm nay. Xo so Kien Giang, XS KG. XSMN, Xổ số miền Nam, SXMN. (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});  XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam hôm nay:    XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam ngày 30/7/2022:   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});  Trực tiếp xổ số hôm nay 30/7/2022:   XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam ngày 29/7/2022:   XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam ngày 28/7/2022:   XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam ngày 27/7/2022:   XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam ngày 26/7/2022:   XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam ngày 25/7/2022:   XSMN - SXMN - Xổ số miền Nam ngày 24/7/2022:   Các từ khoá tra cứu: xsmn 1/8, xsmn 1/8/2022, xổ số miền nam ngày 1 tháng 8, xsmn thứ Hai, xsmn, xổ số, xo so, so xo, sxmn, xổ số miền nam, xổ số hôm nay, xsmn hôm nay, sxmn hôm nay, số miền nam, xsmn hom nay, sxmn hom nay, xo so mien nam, so xo mien nam, kqxsmn, kqxs miền nam, xs hom nay, xổ số miền nam hôm nay, kết quả xổ số, kết quả xổ số hôm nay, kết quả xổ số miền nam, kết quả xổ số miền nam hôm nay, xổ số miền nam hôm qua, xổ số kiến thiết miền nam, trực tiếp xổ số miền nam, truc tiep xsmn, xổ số miền nam trực tiếp.  "},{"question":"من قصد خرید یک آپارتمان از خانه‌های مسکن مهر فلان شهر را دارم آیا چنین معامله‌ای صحیح است؟ چه شرایطی را باید رعایت کنم تا با مشکل قانونی مواجه نشوم؟","answer":"ازنظر قانون مدنی با وقوع عقد بیع مالکیت کاشانه از فروشنده به خریدار منتقل می‌شود. در خصوص خانه‌های مسکن مهر چون غالباً اسناد مالکیت صادر نشده ازاین‌جهت مشکلاتی برای انتقال رسمی ملک وجود دارد. که توصیه می‌کنیم اولاً قبل از انجام معامله به شرکت قانونی مربوطه که خانه موضوع معامله متعلق به اعضای آن است مراجعه کنید و مالکیت فروشنده را نسبت به آن کاشانه احراز کنید. سپس جویا شوید که قرارداد یا شرطی مبنی بر منع نقل‌وانتقال وجود نداشته و قبلاً هم به کسی واگذار نشده باشد و همچنین اینکه بدهی احتمالی فروشنده به‌عنوان سهامدار چه میزان است و متراژ دقیق و امکانات آن را از مدیرعامل یا نماینده او بپرسید. پس از حصول اطمینان اولیه اقدام به تنظیم مبایعه‌نامه کنید و متعاقباً به دفترخانه اسناد رسمی بروید و یک صلح‌نامه با موضوع صلح حقوق ناشی از عضویت در شرکت تعاونی مسکن فلان را از فروشنده با کلیه اختیارات بعلاوه یک وکالت تام بلاعزل با حق توکیل به غیر با تمام اختیارات دریافت کنید.فروشنده باید در مبایعه‌نامه شرط کند پس از تاریخ قرارداد مسئولیت هرگونه بدهی، وام، مالکیت و سایر هزینه‌ها بر عهده خریدار است و در صورت عدم پرداخت آن عواقب احتمالی آن ازهرجهت بر عهده خریدار می‌باشد و فروشنده هیچ‌گونه مسئولیتی ندارد.ضمناً دو طرف پس از اقدامات فوق باید به دفتر شرکت تعاونی مسکن مراجعه کنند و کپی برابر اصل وکالت‌نامه، صلح‌نامه و مبایعه‌نامه را به شرکت تحویل بدهند و مقابل نام فروشنده، نام خریدار درج شود تا مسئولین شرکت متوجه انتقال سهم عضو قبلی بشوند و نامه‌ها و ابلاغیه‌های بعدی را به خریدار تسلیم کنند."},{"question":"Complétez la phrase suivante :  En , dans une tribune parue sur le site Internet du quotidien \\"Le Monde\\" et intitulée « En invitant Netanyahou, Emmanuel Macron instrumentalise l’histoire de France », Suzanne Citron critique ce qu'elle juge comme une instrumentalisation de l'histoire de France par Emmanuel Macron, coupable, à ses yeux, d'alimenter une confusion sur l’histoire de France en invitant le premier ministre israélien à la commémoration de la","answer":"rafle du Vél’ d’Hiv."},{"question":"Dyana Gaye","answer":"Dyana Gaye (tí wọ́n bí ní ọdún 1975) jẹ́ olùdarí eré ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Fráǹsì àti Sẹ́nẹ́gàlWọ́n bí Gaye ní ìlú Paris, orílẹ̀-èdè Fráǹsì ní ọdún 1975. Ó jẹ́ ọmọ àwọn òbí tí wọ́n ti orílẹ̀-èdè ṣẹ́nẹ́gàl wá sí Fráǹsì. Gaye kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ìmọ̀ fíìmù ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga University of Paris 8 Vincennes-Saint-Denis. Ó gba ẹ̀bùn ìrànlọ́wọ́ kan láti ọwọ́ Louis Lumière - Villa Médicis ní ọdún 1999 fún ìtàn-eré rẹ̀ tí ó kọ táa pe àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ní Une femme pour Souleymane. Gaye náà ló ṣe adarí nígbà tí wọ́n fi n ṣiṣẹ́ láti gbé eré náà jáde ní ọdún 2000, eré náà síì gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ níbi ayẹyẹ Dakar Film Festival. Ní ọdún 2004, ó kópa níbi àṣekágbá ti ètò Rolex Mentor and Protégé Arts Initiative. Gaye darí fíìmù oníṣókí kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ J'ai deux amours ní ìlànà pẹ̀lú iṣẹ́ àkànṣe kan tí wọ́n pẹ̀ ní Paris la métisse ní ọdún 2005. Ní ọdún tí ó tẹ̀le, ó ṣe adarí fún ti eré Ousmane, èyítí wọ́n ṣe ní àṣeyege. Wọ́n yaan eré náà fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ eré oníṣókí tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ César Awards. Ní ọdún 2009, Gaye tún ṣe olùgbéréjáde àti olùdarí eré aláwàdà kan tí a pe àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ní Saint Louis Blues. Wọ́n tún yaan eré ọ̀ún náà fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ eré oníṣókí tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ César Awards bákan náà. Ààjọ kan tí wọ́n pè ní Focus Features Africa ni ó ṣe onígbọ̀wọ́ ètó náà.Ó gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti Gan Foundation Creation Prize ní ọdún 2012. Gaye darí fíìmù Under the Starry Sky ní ọdún 2013, tó sì di àkọ́kọ́ fíìmù gígùn tí wọ́n gbéṣe ní ìlú Dakar, Turin, àti New York. Fíìmù náà jẹ́ wíwò níbi ayẹyẹ Toronto International Film Festival, ó sì tún gba àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ méjì kan níbi ayẹyẹ Premiers Plans Angers Festival. Gaye ṣàpèjúwe fíìmù náà gẹ́gẹ́bi ìtẹ̀síwájú àwọn fíìmù oníṣókí tí òún ti ṣe tẹ́lẹ̀.Gaye jẹ́ ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ Collectif 50/50, ẹgbẹ́ kan tí ó fẹ́ láti ri dájú wípé ìdọ́gba wà láàrin àwọn ọkùnrin àti obìnrin ní agbo òṣèré fíìmù."},{"question":"கேள்வி :  ஒலிம்பிக்கில் பதக்கம் வென்ற முதல் இந்தியப்  பெண்மணி  யார்?","answer":"பதில் :  பி.டி. உஷா       பி. டி. உஷா (பிறப்பு சூன் 27, 1964) என பரவலாக அறியப்படும் உஷா கேரளாவைச் சேர்ந்த ஓர் இந்திய தடகள விளையாட்டாளர் ஆவார். 1979ஆம் ஆண்டிலிருந்து இந்திய தடகள விளையாட்டுத் துறையில் பங்கெடுத்து வருகிறார். இந்தியத் தடகள விளையாட்டுக்களில் மாபெரும் சாதனையாளர்களில் ஒருவராகக் கருதப்படும் உஷா பலநேரங்களில் \\"இந்தியத் தட களங்களின் அரசி\\"எனக் குறிப்பிடப்படுகிறார்.    இவர் பய்யோலி எக்சுபிரசு என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். தற்போது கேரளத்தின் கொயிலாண்டியில் உஷா தடகளப் பயிற்சிப் பள்ளியை நடத்தி வருகிறார். 1985இலும் 1986இலும் உலகத் தடகள விளையாட்டுக்களில் முதல் பத்து பெண் விளையாட்டாளர்களில் ஒருவராக விளங்கினார். இவருக்கு முன்பும் பின்பும் இந்தப் பட்டியலில் வேறெந்த இந்தியரும் இடம் பெறவில்லை என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது. இவர் 2022 திசம்பர் 10 ஆம் நாள் அன்று இந்திய ஒலிம்பிக் சங்கத்தின் தலைவராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ளார்.    இவருக்கு கேரளா மாநிலம், கோழிக்கூடு பல்கலைக்கழகம் சார்பில் சனவரி 29, 2018 ஆம் ஆண்டு இவருக்கு கவுரவ டாக்டர் பட்டம் வழங்கியது"},{"question":"Sino ang nag-imbento ng gamot na pennicilin?","answer":"Si Alexander Fleming ay isang Scottish na manggagamot at siyentista na kinilala sa pagtuklas ng penicillin."},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 国民生活センターによると、うそのウェブサイトで買い物をしてしまった人からの相談が増えています。「買った物が届かない」とか「偽物が届く」という相談です。4月から10月の終わりまでに2500ぐらいあって、去年の同じときの2.7倍ぐらいになりました。この中には、13万円のパソコンを1万円で買ったり、3万円の靴を7000円で買ったりして、品物が届かなかった人がいました。うそのウェブサイトは、本当の会社のウェブサイトのように見えて、品物がとても安くなっています。インターネットやSNSに出ている広告などを見て、買い物した人が多いようです。専門家は「うそのウェブサイトはたくさんあります。クリスマスのセールだと言って、とても安く売っていることがあるので、気をつけてほしいです」と話しています。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。"},{"question":"Bhala okuqhubekayo kwalesi sigaba Ngemva kokuba i-Italy ingenele iMpi Yezwe II ngoJune 1940, \\"iTrento\\" yabhekana nempi enkulu oLwandle iMedithera, kuhlanganise nasezimpi zaseCalabria, eCape Spartivento naseCape Matapan","answer":"ngoJulayi nangoNovemba 1940 nangoMashi 1941, ngokulandelana. Wayekhona futhi ngesikhathi seMpi Yokuqala neyesiBili yaseSirte, futhi kulokhu kamuva walimaza kakhulu umkhumbi waseBrithani. I- \\"Trento\\" yayiphinde inikezwe umsebenzi wokuhambisa ama-convoy ukuhlinzeka amabutho ase-Italy eNyakatho Afrika kanye nokuvimbela ama-convoy aseBrithani eMalta. Phakathi nenye yezinhlelo zokugcina zokuhlasela iBritish Operation Harpoon convoy ngoJuni 1942, i \\"Trento\\" yahlaselwa ngama-torpedo kabili, okokuqala yi-Bristol Beaufighter torpedo bomber bese icwiliswa yisubmarine ngokulahlekelwa okukhulu kakhulu kwempilo."},{"question":"السؤال: بصمات أي حيوان يشبه البشر إلى حد بعيد؟","answer":"الإجابة: كوالا"},{"question":"Crie um verso contendo a palavra: Recomeço","answer":"Verso: Cada dia é um recomeço, uma nova jornada,Com coragem e esperança, seguimos a caminhada."},{"question":"actress played Mary Poppins in the 1964 film Mary Poppins?","answer":" Andrews"},{"question":"Di manakah terletaknya Perlis? ","answer":"Perlis merupakan sebuah negeri yang terletak di utara Semenanjung Malaysia bersempadan dengan negara Thailand di utara, negeri Kedah di selatan dan Selat Melaka di barat. Perlis mempunyai keluasan sebanyak 819 kilometer persegi menjadikannya sebagai negeri terkecil di Malaysia."},{"question":"ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਐਸ਼ਵਰਿਆ ਰਾਏ ਬੱਚਨ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ ?","answer":"ਐਸ਼ਵਰਿਆ ਰਾਏ (ਜਨਮ 1 ਨਵੰਬਰ 1973) ਜਾਂ ਐਸ਼ਵਰਿਆ ਰਾਏ ਬੱਚਨ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਫਿਲਮ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਡਲ ਹੈ। 1994 ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਮਿਸ ਇੰਡਿਆ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਉਪਵਿਜੇਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਮਿਸ ਵਰਲਡ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਦੇ ਜੇਤੂ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰਮੁੱਖ ਸਮਕਾਲੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਸਨੇ ਬਾਲੀਵੁਡ ਦੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਲਈ ਦੋ ​​ਫਿਲਮਫੇਇਰ ਇਨਾਮ, ਦੋ ਸਕਰੀਨ ਇਨਾਮ, ਅਤੇ ਦੋ ਆਈਫਾ ਇਨਾਮ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਰਾਏ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀਆਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਹਰਮਨ ਪਿਆਰੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਹਸਤੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਮੀਡਿਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਕਸਰ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖੂਬਸੂਰਤ ਔਰਤ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ, ਰਾਏ ਨੇ ਕੁਝ ਮਾਡਲਿੰਗ ਦੀਆਂ ਨੌਕਰੀਆਂ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ। ਕਈ ਟੈਲੀਵਿਜ਼ਨ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹੋਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ, ਉਹ ਮਿਸ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਪੇਜੈਂਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋ ਗਈ,  ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਦੂਜਾ ਸਥਾਨ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤਾ। ਫਿਰ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਸ ਵਰਲਡ 1994 ਦਾ ਤਾਜ ਪਹਿਨਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ, ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਕਰਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ਾਂ ਮਿਲਣੀਆਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋ ਗਈਆਂ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਮਨੀ ਰਤਨਮ ਦੀ 1997 ਦੀ ਤਾਮਿਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ \\"ਇਰੂਵਰ\\" ਤੋਂ ਅਭਿਨੈ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸੇ ਸਾਲ \\"ਔਰ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ\\" ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਤਮਿਲ ਰੋਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਡਰਾਮਾ \\"ਜੀਨਸ\\" (1998) ਸੀ, ਜੋ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਣੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਮਹਿੰਗੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਵਧੇਰੇ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ \\"ਹਮ ਦਿਲ ਦੇ ਚੁਕੇ ਸਨਮ\\" (1999) ਅਤੇ \\"ਦੇਵਦਾਸ\\" (2002) ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਅਦਾਕਾਰੀ ਲਈ ਫਿਲਮਫੇਅਰ ਵਿਖੇ ਦੋ ਸਰਬੋਤਮ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਪੁਰਸਕਾਰ ਜਿੱਤੇ।ਰਾਏ ਨੇ ਤਾਮਿਲ ਰੋਮਾਂਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ \\"ਕੰਦੁਕੋਂਦਿਨ ਕੰਦੁਕੋਂਦਿਨ\\" (2000), ਬੰਗਾਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਚੋਖਰ ਬਾਲੀ (2003) ਵਿੱਚ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ, ਬਿਨੋਦਿਨੀ, ਰੇਨਕੋਟ (2004) ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਦੁੱਖੀ ਔਰਤ,  ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਨਾਟਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ \\"ਪ੍ਰੋਵੋਕਡ\\" ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਰਨਜੀਤ ਆਹਲੂਵਾਲੀਆ ਅਤੇ ਡਰਾਮਾ ਗੂਜਾਰਿਸ਼ (2010)ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਨਰਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਵੁਕ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਚਿੱਤਰਣ ਲਈ ਅਲੋਚਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ। ਰਾਏ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਰੋਮਾਂਸ \\"ਮੁਹੱਬਤੇਂ\\" (2000), ਐਡਵੈਂਚਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ \\"ਧੂਮ 2\\" (2006), ਇਤਿਹਾਸਕ ਰੋਮਾਂਸ ਗੁਰੂ (2007) ਅਤੇ ਜੋਧਾ ਅਕਬਰ (2008), ਵਿਗਿਆਨ ਕਲਪਨਾ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ \\"ਐਂਥੀਰਨ\\" (2010) ਅਤੇ ਰੋਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਨਾਟਕ \\"ਐ ਦਿਲ ਹੈ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲ\\" (2016) ਰਹੀਆਂ।ਰਾਏ ਨੇ 2007 ਵਿੱਚ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਅਭਿਸ਼ੇਕ ਬੱਚਨ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ; ਇਸ ਜੋੜੇ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਧੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਆਫ-ਸਕ੍ਰੀਨ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਈ ਚੈਰਿਟੀ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਮੁਹਿੰਮਾਂ ਲਈ ਬ੍ਰਾਂਡ ਅੰਬੈਸਡਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਡਿਊਟੀਆਂ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ। ਉਹ ਏਡਜ਼ (UNAIDS) ਦੇ ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਦੇ ਸੰਯੁਕਤ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਦੇ ਸਦਭਾਵਨਾ ਰਾਜਦੂਤ ਹੈ। 2003 ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਹ ਕਾਨ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਫੈਸਟੀਵਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿਊਰੀ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਬਣਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਸੀ।== ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਰਾਏ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 1 ਨਵੰਬਰ 1973 ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨਾਟਕ ਦੇ ਮੰਗਲੋਰੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਲੂ-ਭਾਸ਼ੀ ਬੰਟ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ, ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਰਾਜ, ਜਿਸ ਦੀ 18 ਮਾਰਚ 2017 ਨੂੰ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਆਰਮੀ ਜੀਵ ਵਿਗਿਆਨੀ ਸੀ, ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ, ਵਰਿੰਦਾ, ਇੱਕ ਘਰੇਲੂ ਔਰਤ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡਾ ਭਰਾ ਆਦਿੱਤਿਆ ਰਾਏ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਨੇਵੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੰਜੀਨੀਅਰ ਹੈ। ਰਾਏ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ \\"ਦਿਲ ਕਾ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ\\" (2003) ਉਸ ਦੇ ਭਰਾ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਹਿ-ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਾਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਹਿ-ਲਿਖਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ਇਹ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਚਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਰਾਏ ਨੇ ਆਰੀਆ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਮੰਦਰ ਹਾਈ ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ। ਰਾਏ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਸਾਲ ਜੈ ਜੈ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੰਟਰਮੀਡੀਏਟ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ, ਅਤੇ ਫਿਰ ਮਟੁੰਗਾ ਦੇ ਡੀਜੀ ਰੁਪਾਰੈਲ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਿਲਾ ਲਿਆ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਐਚ.ਐਸ.ਸੀ. ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰੀਖਿਆਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ 90 ਪ੍ਰਤੀਸ਼ਤ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੇ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਜਵਾਨੀ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਪੰਜ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਲਈ ਕਲਾਸੀਕਲ ਡਾਂਸ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਦੀ ਸਿਖਲਾਈ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸ ਦਾ ਮਨਪਸੰਦ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਜੀਵ-ਵਿਗਿਆਨ ਸੀ, ਇਸ ਲਈ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਵਾਈ ਦੇ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਨੂੰ ਮੰਨਿਆ। ਫਿਰ ਇੱਕ ਆਰਕੀਟੈਕਟ ਬਣਨ ਦੀ ਯੋਜਨਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਰਚਨਾ ਸੰਸਦ ਅਕਾਦਮੀ ਦੀ ਆਰਕੀਟੈਕਚਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲਾ ਲਿਆ, ਪਰ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਮਾਡਲਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਕੈਰੀਅਰ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਛੱਡ ਦਿੱਤੀ।== ਨਿੱਜੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ==1999 ਵਿੱਚ, ਰਾਏ ਨੇ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ ਸਲਮਾਨ ਖਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਡੇਟ ਕਰਨਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ; ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਕਸਰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਜਦੋਂ ਤੱਕ ਇਹ ਜੋੜਾ 2002 ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਜੋੜਾ ਵੱਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਰਾਏ ਨੇ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਦੀ ਬਦਸਲੂਕੀ (ਜ਼ਬਾਨੀ, ਸਰੀਰਕ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਵਨਾਤਮਕ), ਬੇਵਫ਼ਾਈ ਅਤੇ ਗੁੱਸਾ, ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਦੱਸੇ ਸਨ। ਫਿਰ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ ਵਿਵੇਕ ਓਬਰਾਏ ਨਾਲ 2005 ਵਿੱਚ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਟੁੱਟਣ ਤੱਕ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਸੰਬੰਧ ਸਨ।ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ \\"ਢਾਈ ਅਕਸ਼ਰ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਕੇ\\" (ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ-ਲੰਬ ਚਿਰੇ ਬੁਆਏਫਰੈਂਡ, ਸਲਮਾਨ ਖਾਨ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਛੋਟਾ ਜਿਹਾ ਕੈਮਿਓ ਸੀ) ਅਤੇ \\"ਕੁਛ ਨਾ ਕਹੋ\\" ਵਿੱਚ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਏ ਸਨ। ਅਭਿਸ਼ੇਕ ਬੱਚਨ ਨੂੰ ਧੂਮ 2 ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਰਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।  ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕੁੜਮਾਈ ਦੀ ਘੋਸ਼ਣਾ 14 ਜਨਵਰੀ 2007 ਨੂੰ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਅਮਿਤਾਭ ਬੱਚਨ ਨੇ ਇਸਦੀ ਪੁਸ਼ਟੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਜੋੜੇ ਨੇ 20 ਅਪ੍ਰੈਲ 2007 ਨੂੰ ਬੰਟ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਦੇ ਰਵਾਇਤੀ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਸੰਸਕਾਰਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਆਹ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਸੰਬੰਧਤ ਹਨ। ਉੱਤਰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਬੰਗਾਲੀ ਸਮਾਰੋਹ ਵੀ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ। ਵਿਆਹ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਦੇ ਜੁਹੂ ਵਿੱਚ, ਬੱਚਨ ਨਿਵਾਸ, \\"ਪ੍ਰਤੀਕਸ਼ਾ\\" ਵਿਖੇ ਇੱਕ ਨਿਜੀ ਸਮਾਰੋਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੁਪਰਕਪਲ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਰਾਏ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਬਹੁਤ ਨਜ਼ਦੀਕ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਤੱਕ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਦੇ ਬਾਂਦਰਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਸੀ। ਰਾਏ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਅਤੇ ਗਹਿਰੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਹਨ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਅੰਤਰਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਮੌਜੂਦਗੀ ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਗਰਮਾ ਗਈ ਜਦੋਂ ਅਭਿਸ਼ੇਕ ਬੱਚਨ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਤੋਂ ਥੋੜ੍ਹੀ ਦੇਰ ਬਾਅਦ ਕਾਨ ਫਿਲਮ ਫੈਸਟੀਵਲ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਓਪਰਾ ਵਿਨਫਰੇ ਸ਼ੋਅ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਈ, ਜੋ 28 ਸਤੰਬਰ 2009 ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਿਤ ਹੋਏ ਸਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬ੍ਰੈਂਜਲੀਨਾ ਨਾਲ਼ੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਜੋਡ਼ੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਵਧੇਰਾ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ । ਰਾਏ ਨੇ 16 ਨਵੰਬਰ, 2011 ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਲੜਕੀ, ਆਰਾਧਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਰਾਏ ਨੂੰ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਦੁਆਰਾ \\"ਐਸ਼\\" ਉਪਨਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਣਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਇਹ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਬੁਲਾਇਆ ਜਾਣ ਨੂੰ ਨਾਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ \\"ਐਸ਼ਵਰਿਆ\\" ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨਾਵਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਕਰ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਮਨਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ \\"ਉਸਦੇ ਚੰਗੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਗਾੜਨਾ\\" ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ। 12 ਜੁਲਾਈ 2020 ਨੂੰ, ਰਾਏ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਧੀ ਦਾ COVID-19 ਲਈ ਸਕਾਰਾਤਮਕ ਟੈਸਟ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਖਬਰ ਮਿਲੀ ਸੀ। 17 ਜੁਲਾਈ ਨੂੰ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਰਤੀ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਮਿਲੀ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Instagram 10 bin takipçi olunca ne oluyor?","answer":"Ama en genel hatlarıyla Instagramda Para Kazanmak İçin Kaç Takipçi Gerekir sorusuna cevap olarak , ilk aşamada 10.000 takipçi sayısını hedeflemelisiniz diyebiliriz. 10.000 takipçi sayısına ulaşan kişiler ilk olarak swipe-up özelliğine sahip olmanızı sağlar. Bu özellikle takipçilerinizle bağlantılar paylaşabilirsiniz."},{"question":"రెండు వరుస తరగతుల ఆరోహణా సంచిత పౌనఃపున్యాలు వరుసగా 72, 83 అయిన రెండవ తరగతి యొక్క పౌనఃపున్యము ఎంత ?","answer":"ఆ.రెండవ తరగతి పౌనఃపున్యము = 83-72 = 9"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Szczęsny gjorde sin debut i Polens seniorlandslag mot Kanada den 18 november 2009, när han i den 46:e minuten byttes in mot Tomasz Kuszczak. Han var uttagen i Polens trupp vid","answer":"fotbolls-EM 2012."},{"question":"આ એક લોકગીત \\"વહુએ વગોવ્યા મોટા ખોરડાં રે લોલ\\" છે, એના પહેલા ચાર ફકરા નીચે મુજબ છે. ગામમાં સાસરિયું ને ગામમાં પિયરયું રે લોલકહેજો દીકરી સખદખની વાત જોકવળાં સાસરિયામાં જીવવું રે લોલહરખના દાડા તો માતા વહી ગયા રે લોલદખનાં ઉગ્યાં છે ઝીણા ઝાડ જોકવળાં સાસરિયામાં જીવવું રે લોલપછવાડે ઊભેલ નણંદ સાંભળે રે લોલવહુ કરે છે આપણા ઘરની વાત જોવહુએ વગોવ્યાં મોટાં ખોરડાં રે લોલનણંદીએ જઈ સાસુને સંભળાવિયું રે લોલવહુ કરે છે આપણા ઘરની વાત જોવહુએ વગોવ્યાં મોટાં ખોરડાં રે લોલઆગળ ના ચાર ફકરા લખો.","answer":"સાસુએ જઈ સસરાને સંભળાવિયું રે લોલવહુ કરે છે આપણા ઘરની વાત જોવહુએ વગોવ્યાં મોટાં ખોરડાં રે લોલસસરાએ જઈ જેઠને સંભળાવિયું રે લોલવહુ કરે છે આપણા ઘરની વાત જોવહુએ વગોવ્યાં મોટાં ખોરડાં રે લોલજેઠે જઈ પરણ્યાને સંભળાવિયું રે લોલવહુ કરે છે આપણા ઘરની વાત જોવહુએ વગોવ્યાં મોટાં ખોરડાં રે લોલપરણ્યે જઈને તેજી ઘોડો હાંકિયો રે લોલજઈ ઝૂકાડ્યો ગાંધીડાને હાટ જોવહુએ વગોવ્યાં મોટાં ખોરડાં રે લોલ"},{"question":"Mi o fẹ irọ tawọn ọlọpaa n pa yii o, awọn Fulani ko maaluu wọ ile mi – Wọle Ṣoyinka","answer":"Gbajugbaja onkọtan ati ọmọwe ilẹ wa nni, Ọjọgbọn Wọle Ṣoyinka, ti fẹsun kan ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa pe ko sootọ ninu ọrọ ti wọn sọ nipa iṣẹlẹ awọn darandaran to ṣakọlu si ile rẹ lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, to kọja yii, o ni irọ lawọn ọlọpaa n pa, oun o si nifẹẹ siru irọ bẹẹ.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Ṣoyinka funra rẹ buwọ lu l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii, o ṣalaye bi iṣẹlẹ naa ṣe waye gan-an. O ni ọrọ naa ki i ṣe pe ẹyọ maaluu kan tabi meji kan ṣirin wọ ọdọ oun, odidi agbo maaluu rẹpẹtẹ ni wọn ya bo ọgba ile toun n gbe.Ṣoyinka ni, “Tori awọn ti wọn fẹẹ mọ ootọ bọrọ ṣe jẹ gan-an nipa iṣẹlẹ to waye ni Ijẹgba, mo n fidi ẹ mulẹ bayii pe ko sẹnikẹni to kọ lu emi funra mi o, nnkan kan o ṣe mi lagoọ ara, emi naa o si kọ lu maaluu kankan. Ṣugbọn awọn maaluu atawọn darandaran kọ lu ile mi, wọn kọlu ọgba mi, ki i si i ṣe igba akọkọ pẹlu.“Bawo lawọn ọlọpaa ṣe maa pa iru irọ bẹẹ yẹn pe ko si maaluu to ṣakọlu si ile mi? Wọn ṣakọlu daadaa. Ọpẹlọpẹ awọn to n ba mi ṣiṣẹ ti wọn ti mọ nipa wọn, awọn ni wọn ṣakitiyan lati le wọn bọ sita. Ọlọrun si ṣe e, emi ti wa ninu mọto, mo n jade lọ tẹlẹ ni tiṣẹlẹ naa fi waye, niṣe ni mo n fi ọwọ kan wakọ, ti mo si n fi ọwọ kan le awọn maaluu, titi ti mo fi dọgbọn wa ara mi kuro laarin wọn.“Igba ti mo de ita, mo bọọlẹ, mo si wawọ sawọn darandaran naa pe ki wọn sun mọ mi. Wọn kọkọ ṣe bii ẹni pe awọn o gbọ ohun ti mo wi, ṣugbọn nigba ti mo n rin lọ sọdọ wọn, wọn bẹ sinu igbo, wọn fi maaluu wọn silẹ, wọn sa lọ. La ba da maaluu wọn duro soju-kan nibẹ, mo si ran oṣiṣẹ mi kan, Taiwo, pe ko lọọ ba mi pe awọn ọlọpaa wa.“Igba tawọn ọlọpaa o tete de, emi funra mi bọ si mọto, mo fẹẹ lọọ ba wọn, ṣugbọn niṣẹ ni mo pade ̄mọto wọn lọna, a si jọ debi iṣẹlẹ naa. Awọn ọlọpaa fẹẹ maa wa awọn darandaran to sa lọ naa ninu igbo, ṣugbọn mo ni ko niidi, niṣe ni ki wọn ko maaluu wọn pamọ, to ba ya, ẹni to ni maaluu aa yọju. Igba to si ya loootọ, onimaaluu naa yọju.Inu mi o dun rara si ọrọ tawọn ọlọpaa n sọ yẹn pe maaluu ko wọle mi, ile ki i ṣe ogiri ati yara nikan, apakan ile mi ni gbogbo ọgba ati ayika mi kẹ! Awọn ọlọpaa tun parọ pe maaluu kan si meji lo kan ya bara, irọ niyẹn, gbogbo agbo ẹran ni, a ya fọto wọn, a tun fidio wọn pẹlu, ki ni wọn waa n parọ fun? Ko sidii to fi yẹ ki wọn ṣe yẹn, ko si ba iwa agbofinro gidi mu, koda ọrọ ti wọn sọ naa mu ifura dani, boya wọn ti gbabọde pẹlu. Tawọn ọlọpaa ba ni ki n mu ẹri wa, ẹ jẹ ki n sọ ọ kedere pe tawọn maaluu ba tun ya inu ọgba mi bẹẹ yẹn nigba mi-in, ma a ranṣẹ pe wọn pe ki wọn waa ba wa jẹ suya, igba yẹn ni wọn aa too mọ pe ṣereṣere kọ.”"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga : \\" Mpivaro-tantely : nilela-tanana, mpandrafitra : nindran-tseza, ka _ \\"","answer":"Toy izao ny tohin'ny fanambarana: \\" voatondro molotra akaiky. \\""},{"question":"Кыргыз макал-лакап, учкул сөздөрүнө мисал келтир.","answer":"Агасын чапса балаңыз, атасын урам дегени.Эжесин чапса балаңыз, энесин урам дегени."},{"question":"ਮਿਨਾਲ ਦਖਵੇ ਭੋਸਲੇ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਕੰਮ ਇੱਕ “ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੂਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ\\"।ਕੋਰੋਨਾਵਾਇਰਸ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਜਾਂਚ, ਇੱਥੇ ਵੱਡੀ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਦਾ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਬਣੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਸਥਿਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਹੁਣ ਬਦਲਣ ਦੀ ਤਿਆਰੀ ਹੈ।ਇਸ ਦਾ ਸਿਹਰਾ ਇੱਕ ਗਰਭਵਤੀ ਵਿਸ਼ਾਣੂ-ਵਿਗਿਆਨੀ (ਵਾਇਰੌਲੋਜਿਸਟ) ਮਿਨਾਲ ਦਖਵੇ ਭੋਂਸਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਬੱਚੇ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਮ ਦੇਣ ਤੋਂ ਕੁਝ ਘੰਟੇ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਿਆਰ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਕੋਵਿਡ-19 ਟੈਸਟ ਕਿੱਟ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਪੂਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ।ਇਹ ਵੀ ਪੜ੍ਹੋ:ਵੀਰਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਕਸਿਤ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਕੋਵਿਡ-19 ਜਾਂਚ ਕਿੱਟ ਬਜ਼ਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਤਾਰੀ ਗਈ। ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਮੀਦ ਬੱਝੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਫਲੂ ਦੇ ਲੱਛਣਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਰੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਮਹਾਂਮਾਰੀ ਲਈ ਟੈਸਟ ਸੰਭਵ ਹੋ ਸਕੇਗਾ।ਹੁਣ 1200 ਰੁਪਏ 'ਚ ਕਿੱਟ ਤਿਆਰ।ਇਹ ਕਿੱਟ ਪੂਣੇ ਦੀ ਮੇਲੈਬ ਡਿਸਕਵਰੀ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਫ਼ਰਮ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਕਿੱਟਜ਼ ਤਿਆਰ ਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਵੇਚਣ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨਗੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ।150 ਕਿੱਟਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਖੇਪ ਕੰਪਨੀ ਨੇ ਪੂਣੇ, ਮੁੰਬਈ ਦਿੱਲੀ, ਗੋਆ ਤੇ ਬੈਂਗਲੂਰੂ ਦੀਆਂ ਲੈਬੋਰਟਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੇਜੀ ਹੈ।ਹਰੇਕ ਕਿੱਟ 100 ਨਮੂਨਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੀ ਕੀਮਤ 1200 ਰੁਪਏ ਹੈ। ਭਾਰਤ ਬਾਹਰੋਂ ਜੋ ਕਿੱਟ ਮੰਗਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਲਗਭਗ 4500 ਰੁਪਏ ਦੀ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਟੈਸਟਾਂ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਵਧਣ ਨਾਲ ਪੌਜ਼ੀਟਿਵ ਆਏ ਮਰੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲਣਾ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੀ ਚੁਣੌਤੀ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।ਮੇਲੈਬ ਦੇ ਮੈਡੀਕਲ ਅਫੇਅਰਜ਼ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਡਾ਼ ਗੌਤਮ ਵਾਨਖੇੜੇ ਨੇ ਸ਼ੁੱਕਰਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ, “ਸਾਡੀ ਮੈਨੂਫ਼ੈਕਚਰਿੰਗ ਇਕਾਈ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਦੇ ਅਖ਼ੀਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦੂਜੀ ਖੇਪ ਸੋਮਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਭੇਜ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ।ਇਹ ਫ਼ਰਮ ਐੱਚਆਈਵੀ, ਹੈਪੇਟਾਈਟਸ-ਬੀ ਤੇ ਸੀ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਹੋਰ ਵੀ ਬੀਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਲਈ ਟੈਸਟਿੰਗ ਕਿੱਟਾਂ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਰਮ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਲੱਖ ਕਿੱਟਾਂ ਬਣਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਇਹ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਦੋ ਲੱਖ ਵੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ।ਮੇਲੈਬ ਦੇ ਖੋਜ ਤੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਦੀ ਮੁਖੀ ਵਿਸ਼ਾਣੂ-ਵਿਗਿਆਨੀ ਮਿਨਾਲ ਦਖਵੇ ਭੋਂਸਲੇ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ, “ਸਾਡੀ ਕਿੱਟ ਢਾਈ ਘੰਟਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਤੀਜਾ ਦੇ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ। ਜਦਕਿ ਦੂਜੀ ਕਿੱਟ 6-7 ਘੰਟੇ ਲੈ ਲੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ।”ਇਹ ਵੀ ਪੜ੍ਹੋ:ਕਿੱਟ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਕਸਿਤ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਟੀਮ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਮਿਨਾਲ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਕੰਮ ਇੱਕ “ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੂਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਚਾਰ ਮਹੀਨਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਛੇ ਹਫ਼ਤਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ।”ਸਾਇੰਸਦਾਨ ਕੋਲ ਆਪਣੀ ਵੀ ਡੈਡਲਾਈਨ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਕਰਨਾ ਪੈ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਪਿਛਲੇ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਬੇਟੀ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਗਰਭ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਲ ਕਾਰਨ ਅਰਾਮ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਫ਼ਰਵਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰੋਜੈਕਟ ਉੱਪਰ ਕੰਮ ਸ਼ੂਰੂ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ।","answer":"ਕੋਰੋਨਾਵਾਇਰਸ: ਇਸ ਸਾਇੰਸਦਾਨ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕੋਵਿਡ-19 ਜਾਂਚ ਕਿੱਟ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਪੂਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ, ਫ਼ਿਰ ਬੱਚੇ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ।"},{"question":"Ọpẹ o, awọn Fulani ti tu Basit, ọmọ Damilọla olorin Islam silẹ o","answer":"Aṣaalẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii lawọn olorin Musulumi bẹrẹ si i pin iroyin ọhun laarin ara wọn pe Ọlọrun ti ṣe e, awọn janduku ajinigbe Fulani ti tu Basit ọmọ Damilọla olorin silẹ.Ọgbọn miliọnu naira ni wọn ni ki ọkunrin olorin yii lọọ mu wa ni kete ti wọn ti pe e lẹyin bii wakati meloo kan ti ọmọ ẹ ti ko ju ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogun lọ ti wa lahaamọ wọn.Ni gbogbo ọsan ana lawọn olorin ẹgbẹ ẹ ṣi ṣe fidio kan ti wọn fi n bẹbẹ pe ki awọn ajinigbe yii ṣaanu ọkunrin naa nitori owo ti wọn n beere fun yẹn ti pọ ju.Aṣaalẹ ana ni iroyin mi-in gba igboro pe wọn ti tu u silẹ, lẹyin ti wọn gba owo lọwọ awọn obi ẹ, ti Abdul-Basit, ọmọ Poli Kwara, si ti wa nile bayii.Ninu ọrọ ti Damilọla, ba ALAROYE sọ, o ni awọn ajinigbe ọhun gba owo to pọ ki wọn too le tu ọmọ oun silẹ, bẹẹ lo fi kun un pe awọn ti sin iyawo aburo oun tawọn eeyan buruku yii pa lasiko ikọlu ọhun.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, opin ọsẹ to kọja yii ni wọn kọ lu mọlẹbi Damilọla olorin Islam tawọn eeyan tun mọ si Ẹsin-o-gba-mi-laye, ile aburo ẹ to wa ni Gaa Saka ni wọn sọ pe awọn Fulani kan wọ lọ, wọn pa iyawo aburọ ẹ to wa ninu oyun, bẹẹ ni wọn ji Basit, ọmọ ẹ to n gbe pẹlu wọn lọ."},{"question":"السؤال: في أي عام دخل الانجليز فلسطين ؟","answer":"الإجابة: عام 1917 م"},{"question":"जयन्ति ते सुकृतिनो रससिद्धाः कवीश्वराः ।नास्ति येषां यशःकाये जरामरणजं भयम् ॥","answer":"श्रेष्ठ कवी (कवींमधले ईश्वर) आपल्या चांगल्या कृतींनीच जिंकतात, अमर होतात, त्यांना शरीराच्या जरामरणाची भीती असत नाही."},{"question":" شنو الاسم ديال النبيان اللي رفعهم الله للسما ؟","answer":"سيدنا عيسى وإدريس عليهما السلام"},{"question":"Lee el siguiente texto y escribe un buen título: La muerte del joven desencadenó fuertes disturbios en Ferguson, que provocaron saqueos y destrozos. Durante las manifestaciones en Minneapolis, una mujer fue atropelleda por un auto. \\"The Star Tribune\\" informó que el conductor del automóvil tocó la bocina a los manifestantes antes de golpear a varias personas y aparentemente pasar con su vehículo sobre las piernas de la mujer, quien fue hospitalizada por \\"heridas menores\\".","answer":"\\"170 ciudades de Estados Unidos registran protestas por caso Michael Brown\\"."},{"question":"සිග්මන්ඩ් ෆ්‍රොයිඩ් යනු කවුරුන් ද?","answer":"සිග්මන්ඩ් ෆ්‍රොයිඩ් ඔස්ට්‍රියානු ජාතික ස්නායු විශේෂඥයෙක් වන අතර, එතුමා මනෝ විශ්ලේෂණයේ නිර්මාතෘවරයා ලෙස සැළකේ. අවිඥානික මනස, ලිංගික ආශාව සහ පෞරුෂ වර්ධනය කෙරෙහි අවධානය යොමු කළ ෆ්‍රොයිඩ්ගේ න්‍යායන් මනෝවිද්‍යාව සහ මානව ශාස්ත්‍ර කෙරෙහි ප්‍රබල බලපෑමක් ඇති කර ඇත. ෆ්‍රොයිඩ් ආවේනික මනස සහ අවරෝධනය සඳහා ආරක්ෂණ යාන්ත්‍ර සඳහා වන න්‍යායන්වලට ප්‍රසිද්ධියක් උසුලයි."},{"question":"Adalar Hangisi daha güzel?","answer":"Büyükada, Rumca adıyla Prinkipo; Prens Adalarının en büyüğü ve en güzelidir. Birçok insanın ziyaret ederek gezip gördüğü tek ada budur ve en gözde yazlık mekanlardan biridir. 5,4 km2'lik yüzölçümüyle Büyükada, diğer üç ana adanın toplamından daha büyüktür."},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර යුක්ති අධිකරණයේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ කොහේද?","answer":"ජාත්‍යන්තර අධිකරණය (ICJ) මූලස්ථානය නෙදර්ලන්තයේ හේග් හි සාම මන්දිරයේ පිහිටා  ඇත. ලෝක අධිකරණය ලෙසද හැඳින්වෙන ICJ යනු එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ ප්‍රධාන අධිකරණ ආයතනය වන අතර රාජ්‍යයන් අතර නීතිමය ආරවුල් නිරාකරණය කිරීමේදී සහ බලයලත් ජාත්‍යන්තර ආයතන සහ නියෝජිතායතන විසින් යොමු කරනු ලබන නීතිමය ප්‍රශ්න පිළිබඳව උපදේශන අදහස් ලබා දීමේදී තීරණාත්මක කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කරයි. සාම මාලිගයේ ICJ පමණක් නොව අනෙකුත් ජාත්‍යන්තර අධිකරණ ආයතන ද ඇත."},{"question":"Fammi un esempio di quiz in questa categoria: \\"Videogiochi\\".","answer":"The Legend of Zelda è uscito prima del 1988? Sì."},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"Antes tarde do que nunca\\"?","answer":"Também dada como uma mensagem de sabedoria, esse ditado é, além de conformista, uma forma de otimismo. Para que reclamar de algo que demorou para acontecer? Ao menos aconteceu!Exemplo: “Finalmente passei naquele exame, pessoal. Antes tarde do que nunca!”"},{"question":"Hain nagapuyo ang Presidente sa Pilipinas kasamtangan sa iyang termino?","answer":"Malacañang Palace"},{"question":"వృద్ధులపట్ల పిల్లలు ఆదరాభిమానాలు చూపాలనే ఆలోచనను కల్గించే విధంగా చైతన్యాన్ని పెంపొందించాలని కోరుతూ పత్రికా – సంపాదకునికి లేఖ","answer":"విజయవాడ,xxxxxxxగౌరవనీయులైనప్రతికా సంపాదకునికి,‘ఆంధ్రజ్యోతి’ కార్యాలయం,విజయవాడ.అయ్యా,‘ఈనాటి సమాజంలో ఎంతోమంది వృద్ధులు నిరాదరణకు గురవుతున్నారు. వివిధ కారణాలతో వృద్ధాశ్రమాల్లో చేరుతున్నారు. ఇది విచారింపదగిన విషయం.పిల్లలు తమ తల్లిదండ్రులపట్ల, తాతయ్య, నాయనమ్మ, అమ్మమ్మలపట్ల ఆధారం చూపాలి. వారికి అవసరమైన సపర్యలు చేయాలి. మానవీయ విలువలను కాపాడాలి. ఈతరం విద్యార్థుల్లో వృద్ధులపట్ల ఆదరం చూపించాల్సిన బాధ్యతను పెంపొందించాల్సి ఉంది. ఉపాధ్యాయులు, పెద్దలు, విద్యార్థుల్లో పరివర్తనను సాధించాలి. మీ పత్రిక ద్వారా నేటి యువతలో వృద్ధులపట్ల సేవాదృక్పధం అలవడే విధంగా ప్రయత్నం చేయాలని కోరుతున్నాను.ఇట్లు,మీ విధేయుడు,పి. మల్లికార్జునరావు.చిరునామా :గౌ|| పత్రికా సంపాదకుడు,‘ఆంధ్రజ్యోతి’ కార్యాలయం,విజయవాడ."},{"question":"ලෝක ඒඩ්ස් දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"ලෝක ඒඩ්ස් දිනය දෙසැම්බර් 01 වන දිනට යෙදී තිබේ."},{"question":"Gwa m gbasara Imo steeti","answer":"Ọ̀hà Ímò (nà bèkeè: Imo State) bú òtú state no n'ime ala Naigeria. Ya na Imo State bu ebe ndi Igbo na kpo obi wo, ebe Obi Ala ndi Igbo (bekee:Heart of Igboland).Isi obodo Imo steeti bụ Owerri. Emepụtara ya n'abalị atọ nke ọnwa Febrụwarị 1976. A họọrọ ya dịka steeti iri na atọ kacha nwee mmadụ na Naịjirịa."},{"question":"නිරුත්සාහය යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"නිරුත්සාහය යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය උත්සාහය වේ. "},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع غينيا؟","answer":"تقع غينيا في قارة إفريقيا."},{"question":"Quelle est une astuce pour mieux dormir la nuit ?","answer":"Ajuster le thermostat! La température idéale pour dormir se situe entre 18°C et 22°C. Et mange pas trop avant dormir. "},{"question":"ኢትዮጵያ በቶኪዮ ኦሎምፒክ በወርልድ ቴኳንዶ በምን ምድብ ተወዳደረች?","answer":"በ58 ኪ.ግ"},{"question":" السؤال: ما هو أوّل مذهبٍ ديني ظهر في الإسلام؟","answer":"الجواب: المذهب الحنفي."},{"question":"आत्म-सम्मान निर्माणमा सकारात्मक आत्म-वार्ताको भूमिकाबारे छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"सकारात्मक आत्म-वार्ता आत्म-सम्मान निर्माणको एक प्रमुख घटक हो। नकारात्मक विचारहरूलाई पुष्टि र प्रोत्साहनजनक कथनहरूको साथ प्रतिस्थापन गरेर, व्यक्तिहरूले सकारात्मक आत्म-छविलाई पोषण गर्न र आत्म-मूल्यको बलियो भावना विकास गर्न सक्छन्।"},{"question":"கேள்வி : முக்காலக் கல்வியறிவு குறித்து எழுதுக.","answer":"பதில் : முந்தைய கல்வியறிவு :ஒரு காலத்தில் வாழ்க்கையில் முன்னேறுவதற்கு எழுதப் படிக்கத் தெரிந்த கல்வியறிவே போதுமானதாக இருந்தது. ஆனால் இன்று, கல்வியறிவுடன் மின்னணுக் கல்வியறிவையும் மின்னணுச் சந்தைப்படுத்துதலையும் அறிந்திருத்தல் வேண்டும். இது வாழ்க்கையை எளிதாக்கவும் வணிகத்தில் வெற்றியடையவும் உதவுகிறது.எதிர்காலக் கல்வியறிவு :எதிர்காலத்தில் செயற்கை நுண்ணறிவு பற்றிய அறிவும் நான்காவது தொழிற் புரட்சியின் தொழில் நுட்பங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தும் அறிவுமே நம்மை வளப்படுத்தும்."},{"question":"Giải thích khái niệm về nhân số học","answer":"Nhân số học hay Thần số học (Numerology) là một phương pháp dự đoán tính cách và định hướng phát triển của con người thông qua mã hoá ngày tháng năm sinh, và tên gọi thành các con số và giải thích ý nghĩa của các con số đó. Bộ môn khoa học này nghiên cứu về những con số và các tác động sóng rung của những con số đó đối với đời sống của mỗi con người.Có thể coi Nhân số học như một cách đọc, giải mã những tín hiệu mà cuộc sống đã gửi đến đối với từng người trong đời sống này. Đồng thời, với nhiều điểm tương đồng với Phật học, bộ môn Thần số học được thầy Louis Nguyễn đánh giá sẽ mang đến nhiều giá trị tốt đẹp cho đời sống con người."},{"question":"Waa maxay lo?","answer":"Lo waa xayawan lamasho la hlibkisna la cuno."},{"question":"ක්‍රෙඩිට් කාඩ්පතක් යනු කුමක්ද සහ එය ක්‍රියා කරන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"ක්‍රෙඩිට් කාඩ්පතක් යනු කුඩා ප්ලාස්ටික් කාඩ්පතක් වන අතර එය කාඩ්පත් හිමියාට භාණ්ඩ හෝ සේවා ගිණුමකට අය කිරීමට බලය පවරන අතර, බිල්පත කාලානුරූපව කාඩ්පත් හිමියා වෙත යවනු ලැබේ. එහි සාමාන්‍යයෙන් අත්සනක් හෝ පින්තූරයක් වැනි හඳුනාගැනීමේ මාධ්‍ය අඩංගු වේ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud peribahasa \\"bagai rupa tungkahan\\"?","answer":"Ianya bermaksud muka orang yang sangat buruk."},{"question":"\\"અંકિત ત્રિવેદી\\" ની કવિતા લખો.","answer":"આકાશે ધોધમાર બંધાતા રોજતોય ઈચ્છા વિનાના સાવ પાંગળા,આપનો સબંધ જાણેવરસ્યા વિનાના રહ્યાં વાદળા.કોડિયામાં પ્રગટેલા અજવાળા જેમએકબીજામાં ઝળહળતા આપણે.અજવાળું ઓલવીને કેમ કરી મોકલેલુંશરતોનું સરનામું પાંપણે.શમણાના તૂટવામાં એવું લાગે કે જાણેહાથમાંથી છૂટાં પડ્યા આંગળા.અંતરથી અંતર જો માપો તો આમઅમે પાસે ને આમ દૂર દૂર,કિનારે પહોચેલાં મોજાની જેમ અમેદરિયાથી છૂટવા આતુર.ચહેરાના ભાવ બધા વાંચી શકાયેતોયે આંખોને લાગે કે આંધળા.નાછૂટકે લેવાતા શ્વાસોમાં વર્તાતીસંગાથે જીવ્યાની ભૂલ,આપણા જ ક્યારામાં આપને જ વાવેલુંસુગંધ વિનાનું એક ફૂલ.સાથે રહ્યાની વાત ભૂલી જઈનેઆજ છૂટાં પડવાને ઉતાવળા."},{"question":"வினா : தமிழ்நாட்டின் மதுரை நகரில் உருவான பிரபலமான உணவுப் பொருள் எது?","answer":"விடை : மதுரை மீனாட்சி சுந்தரேஸ்வரர் இட்லி."},{"question":"Бучкак дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"1. Теринин шыйрак жаккы ичке бөлүкчөлөрү; булгаарынын, теринин, ушундай бөлүкчөлөрдөн түшкөн майда кесиндилери. ...Үстүндө түлкүнүн бучкагынан курап, көк ноотудан тыштап жасалган ичик (Жантөшев).2. Жоон сандан төмөн тизеге чейинки аралык. Бучкагынан аккан тер көбүктөнүп, атандын тостойгон көзү жашылданып калган экен (Убукеев). [Назгүлдүн].. көмүрдөй кара чачы эки бөлөк өрүлүп, кош мүрүсүнөн бучкагына чейин эңилип турду (Бейшеналиев).3. Кийимдин этек жаккы бөлүгү. [Кементайдын].. бучкактарынан сарыккан жаандын суусу тамчылап турат (Байтемиров).Бучкагына / шыйрагына теңебөөТеңсинбөө, теңине албоо, тоготпоо, жеңил, оңой-олтоң катары эсептөө, кенебөө. Зың-зың этип кенебей, Алышар баатыр Коңурду, бучкагына теңебей («Манас»). Аларды апамдын бучкагына теңебеймин («Советтик Кыргызстан»). Менин айткан сөзүмө болбой койгон кенебей, боздоп айткан кебимди бучкагына теңебей («Сейтек»).Жылаңач төөнү бучкакка чапкандайЭч токтоосуз, буйдалабастан, шыдыр, шар.Жылаңач төөнү бучкакка чапкандай сүйлөдү."},{"question":"\\"නබෝමිණි\\" යනු කුමක්ද?යෙදුම: නබෝමිණි වළා රැලි","answer":"'නබෝ' හෙවත් නුබ යනු අහසයි. මිණ යනු මැණිකයි. 'නබෝමිණ' අහසෙහි දිලෙන මැණිකයි. එනම් සූර්යයා යි."},{"question":"Theo luật, quân tốt trong cờ vua không thể phong cấp thành quân nào?","answer":"Thông thường tốt được phong cấp thành hậu bởi đó là quân mạnh nhất. Tuy nhiên cũng có những thế cờ, phong hậu không phải phương án tối ưu nhất, thường để tránh việc đối thủ được rơi vào thế hòa vì hết nước đi. Tốt khi xuống đến hàng 8 với Trắng, hoặc hàng 1 với Đen, buộc phải phong cấp thành một trong bốn quân gồm hậu, xe, tượng hoặc mã ở vị trí đó. Do không giới hạn số quân trên bàn cờ, mỗi bên có thể có tối đa 9 hậu hoặc 10 xe, 10 tượng hay 10 mã. Tốt không được phong thành vua, cũng không thể giữ nguyên là tốt."},{"question":"வினா: காஸ்டிக் சோடா எனப்படுவது என்ன ?1.சோடியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு2.மெக்னீசியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு3.பொட்டாசியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு4.ஜிப்சம்","answer":"விடை: 1.சோடியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு"},{"question":" Sheg Meeshay Eheed Meeshii Ay Aayada Quraanka Ugu Horeesay Ku Soo Degtay?","answer":"Meeshii Ugu Horeesay Ay Aayada Quraanka Ku Soo Degto Waxay Eheed Xiraa"},{"question":"Zer da geografia fisikoa, eta nola aztertzen du lurrazalaren egitura eta prozesuak?","answer":"Geografia fisikoa da lurrazalaren egitura, prozesu eta fenomenoak aztertzen duen geografiaren adar bat. Lurrazalaren egitura eta prozesuak aztertzeko, geografia fisikoa erakusten du nola lurrazalaren elementuak elkarrekin interaktuan dute."},{"question":"ਟੋਸਟਰ ਦੀ ਦੇਖਭਾਲ ਤੇ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਕਰੀਦੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਦੇਖਭਾਲ ਤੇ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ-    ਟੋਸਟ ਨੂੰ ਕੱਢਣ ਲਈ ਕਦੇ ਵੀ ਚਾਕੂ ਜਾਂ ਕਾਂਟੇ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਐਲੀਮੈਂਟ ਦੀ ਤਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।    ਹਰ ਵਾਰ ਟੋਸਟਰ ਨੂੰ ਵਰਤਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ, ਟੋਸਟਰ ਨੂੰ ਉਲਟਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਡਬਲਰੋਟੀ ਦੇ ਟੁਕੜਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੱਢਣ ਲਈ ਟੋਸਟਰ ਨੂੰ ਹੱਥ ਨਾਲ ਹਲਕਾ ਥਪਥਪਾ ਦਿਉ ।    ਵਰਤਣ ਲੱਗਿਆਂ ਟੋਸਟਰ ਨੂੰ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਤਾਰੋਧਕ ਅਤੇ ਬਿਜਲੀ ਦੇ ਕੁਚਾਲਕ ਥਾਂ ਤੇ ਹੀ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।    ਕੰਮ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਟੋਸਟਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਿਜਲੀ ਦੇ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਤੋਂ ਅਲੱਗ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਠੰਡਾ ਹੋਣ ਦਿਉ ਫਿਰ ਤਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਆਸੇ-ਪਾਸੇ ਲਪੇਟ ਕੇ ਰੱਖ ਲਉ ।"},{"question":" Em que ano os navegadores portugueses chegaram ao Brasil pela primeira vez?","answer":"O beija-flor. A velocidade com que bate as asas garante estabilidade e o permite ficar parado no ar."},{"question":"ਜਦੋਂ ਵੱਖਰੇ ਵਿਅਕਤਿਤਵ ਵਾਲੇ ਦੋ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ‘ਚ ਬਹਿ ਕੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਵਰਗੇ ਅਟੁੱਟ ਬੰਧਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੱਝਦੇ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਈ ਨਹੀਂ ਟਿਕਟਾ। ਇਸੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਊਣਾ ਸਿਖਾਉਣ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਬਿਹਤਰੀਨ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ‘ਚ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਤੇ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਉੱਥੇ ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਬਤਰਾ ਦੀ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਵਜੋਂ ਇਹ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਇੱਕ ਡੱਬੂ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੇ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਆਰਕੀਟੇਕਟ ਰਾਹੁਲ (ਇਮਰਾਨ ਖ਼ਾਨ) ਤੇ ਹੇਅਰ ਸਟਾਈਲਿਸਟ ਕ੍ਰਿਸਚੀਅਨ ਕੁੜੀ, ਰਿਆਨਾ ਬ੍ਰਿਗੇਂਜ਼ਾ (ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ) ਦੇ ਆਲੇ-ਦੁਆਲੇ ਘੁੰਮਦੀ ਹੈ। ਰਾਹੁਲ ਦਾ ਪਾਲਣ-ਪੋਸ਼ਣ ਇੱਕ ਅਲੱਗ ਹੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਾਹੌਲ ‘ਚ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਾਂ-ਬਾਪ ਦੇ ਦਬਾਅ ਹੇਠ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਾਂ-ਬਾਪ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਲਏ ਗਏ ਹਨ, ਚਾਹੇ ਉਹ ਕਰੀਅਰ ਦਾ ਸਵਾਲ ਹੋਵੇ, ਖਾਣ-ਪੀਣ ਦਾ ਜਾਂ ਕੱਪੜਾ ਪਹਿਨਣ ਦਾ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕਦੋਂ ਕੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ? ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਨੀ ਹੈ? ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਾਂ-ਬਾਪ ਹੀ ਤੈਅ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਵਿਚਾਰਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀ ਲੜਕੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੇ ਮਾਅਨੇ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਜਿਊਣੀ ਹੈ। ਲਾਸ ਵੇਗਾਸ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰ ‘ਚ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਅਜੀਬੋ-ਗ਼ਰੀਬ ਮਾਹੌਲ ‘ਚ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਤੇ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਦੀ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਜੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ‘ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੇਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਸ਼ਾਇਦ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਕਦੇ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲ ਨਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਪਰ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਹੀ ਕੁਝ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦਾ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਸਿਲਸਿਲਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਸ਼ਰਾਬ ਪੀਣ ਬੈਠ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ। ਦਸ ਬਾਰਾਂ ਪੈੱਗ ਪੀ ਜਾਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਸਾਰੀ ਰਾਤ ਨਸ਼ੇ ‘ਚ ਗੁਜ਼ਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਸਵੇਰੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਨਸ਼ਾ ਉਤਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਤਲਾਕ ਲਈ ਅਦਾਲਤ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਤਲਾਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਤਲਾਕ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਬਾਵਜੂਦ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਤੇ ਰਿਆਨਾ ਦੀ ਦੋਸਤੀ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤਾਂ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਰਹਿੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਨਵੇਂ ਰਿਸ਼ਤੇ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਰਿਆਨਾ, ਰਾਹੁਲ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਜਿਊਣਾ ਸਿਖਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਵਿਅਕਤਿਤਵ ‘ਚ ਭਾਰੀ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਲਿਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ।। ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਵੂਡੀ ਏਲਨ ਦੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੈਲੀ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਿਤ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਬਤਰਾ ਨੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਤਜਰਬੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ। ਉਹ ਵੂਡੀ ਏਲਨ ਦੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਸ਼ੈਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਅਪਨਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।। ਹਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਈ ਰੁਮਾਂਟਿਕ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਚ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਚ ਕੈਮਰਾ ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਨਾਲ ਚੱਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਹੀ ਦੇਖਣ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲੇਗਾ।ਕੁਛ-ਕੁਛ ਹੋਤਾ ਹੈ, ਕਭੀ-ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਕਭੀ ਗ਼ਮ, ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਹੋ ਨਾ ਹੋ, ‘ਵੇਕ ਅੱਪ ਸਿਡ’ ਅਤੇ ਮਾਈ ਨੇਮ ਇਜ਼ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਜਿਹੀਆਂ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਪਰੰਪਰਾਗਤ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਿਤਾਰਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਵੀ ਚਰਚਾ ‘ਚ ਹੈ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਇਮਾਰਨ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸੋਚ ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਜੋੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਦੇ ‘ਤੇ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਢੁਕਵਾਂ ਹੈ। ਅਸੀਂ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਲਿਆਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਅਸਲੀਅਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਵੱਖਰੇ ਹੋਣ। ਸ਼ਕੁਨ, ਇਮਰਾਨ ਦੇ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਕਰੀਬ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦੋਸਤੀ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ  ‘ਵੇਕ ਅੱਪ ਸਿਡ’ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਣਬੀਰ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਕੋਕਨਾ ਸੇਨ ਦੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਤਜਰਬਾ ਕਰ ਚੱਕੇ ਸਨ। ਕਦੇ-ਕਦੇ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਅਨੋਖੀ ਜੋੜੀ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਦੇ ‘ਤੇ ਦੇਖਣਾ ਮਜ਼ੇਦਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਬਤਰਾ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਇੱਕ-ਦੋ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ‘ਚ ਛੋਟੇ ਜਿਹੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ। ਸਹਾਇਕ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ‘ਚ ਉਹ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਬਤੌਰ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਇਹ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਸ਼ਕੁਨ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਇਨ ਹਾਊਸ ਹੀਰੋ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਤਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਸਵਾਲ ਹੈ, ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਨਾ ਕੋਈ ਸੰਦੇਸ਼ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਦੇਵੇਗੀ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਅਸੀਂ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਮਾਤਾ-ਪਿਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਹਰ ਚੀਜ਼ ਜਾਂ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਤੇ ਥੋਪਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ, ਬਲਕਿ ਬੱਚੇ ਦੀ ਰੁਚੀ ਨੂੰ ਧਿਆਨ ‘ਚ ਰੱਖ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਤ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।ਇਮਰਾਨ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਜੇ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਪੀੜ੍ਹੀ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਸਬਕ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਵਧੀਆ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਮੇਰਾ ਮੰਨਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਦੇਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਜਾਗਰੂਕਤਾ ਲਿਆਉਣਾ ਹੈ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਮੇਰਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਜਬ ਵੂਈ ਸੈੱਟ ਦੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲਦਾ-ਜੁਲਦਾ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਬੇਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਕੁੜੀ ਦਾ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹਾਂ, ਜੋ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨੂੰ ਹਰ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਮਾਨਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਵੇਗੀ। ਇਮਰਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਰੀ ਕੈਮਿਸਟਰੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਸ਼ਕੁਨ, ਕਰਨ, ਇਮਰਾਨ ਤੇ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਮੌਲਿਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ‘ਚ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਵੱਟ ਹੈਪਨ ਇਨ ਲਾੱਸ ਵੇਗਾਸ’ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਚਰਚੇ ਹਨ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਲੈਣ ਦੀ ਸਲਾਹ ਵੀ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ। ਇਮਰਾਨ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਬਚਪਨ ਤੋਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਦੀਵਾਨੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਕਰੀਨਾ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ‘ਚੋਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖੂਬਸੂਰਤ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਰਫਿਊਜੀ ‘ਚ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਦੀਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਖਿੱਚ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਹਿਸਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੇੜੇ ਤੋਂ ਜਾਣਨ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਮੈਂ ਕਰੀਨਾ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਤਸਵੀਰਾਂ ਵੀ ਲਈਆਂ। ਕਰੀਨਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਹਤਰ ਇਹ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਸੀ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਕਰਨ ਜੌਹਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਸੋ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ‘ਕੁਛ-ਕੁਛ ਹੋਤਾ ਹੈ’, ‘ਕਭੀ-ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਕਭੀ ਗ਼ਮ’, ‘ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਹੋ ਨਾ ਹੋ’, ‘ਬੇਕ ਅੱਪ ਸਿਡ’, ‘ਮਾਈ ਨੇਮ ਇਜ਼ ਖ਼ਾਨ’, ਅਤੇ ‘ਏਕ ਮੈਂ ਔਰ ਏਕ ਤੂ’।"},{"question":"మామూలు వాక్యాలు కూడా సరైన పదాలు జోడించి అందంగా వివరిస్తూ రాస్తే వర్ణనాత్మక వాక్యాలు అవుతాయి కదా! అలాగే మీరు కూడా మంచి పదాలతో మీకు నచ్చిన ఒక కథను వర్ణిస్తూ రాయండి.","answer":"వర్ణనాత్మక కథ :ప్రేమే పరమాన్నంఆప్యాయతతో ఆదరించిన వారింట పచ్చడన్నం తిన్నా తృప్తిగా ఉంటుంది. అదే ప్రేమ నటిస్తూ పంచభక్ష్య పరమాన్నాలు పెట్టినా ఆ భోజనం రుచించదు. అంటే నిజమైన రుచి వంటకంలో లేదు. వండి వడ్డించిన వారి మనసులో ఉంది. దానికి ఉదాహరణే ఈ కథ.పాండవులు పాచికల ఆటలో మోసపోయి 12 యేండ్లు అడవుల్లో, ఒక యేడాది మారువేషాల్లో బతికి అరణ్య, అజ్ఞాత వాసాలు పూర్తి చేసుకొన్నారు. తిరిగి రాజ్యాన్ని అప్పగించమంటూ కృష్ణుడి ద్వారా కౌరవులకు రాయబారం పంపారు పాండవులు. అప్పుడు కృష్ణుడు హస్తినాపురానికి వెళ్ళగా, దుర్యోధనుడు శ్రీకృష్ణుణ్ణి మచ్చిక చేసుకొని, తనవైపు తిప్పుకోవాలని ప్రయత్నించి, కపట ప్రేమను ఒలకబోస్తాడు. కానీ కృష్ణుడు తాను కౌరవుల అతిథిగా రాలేదని, పాండవుల రాయబారిగా వచ్చానని చెబుతాడు. ఆ రాత్రి బసకు ధృతరాష్ట్రుని మంత్రి విదురుని ఇంటికి వెళతాడు. ఆయన భోగభాగ్యాల లాలస లేక నిరాడంబర జీవితాన్ని గడుపుతుంటాడు. తన ఇంటి తలుపు తట్టిన కృష్ణుని చూసి నివ్వెరపోయాడు. అంతులేని ఆనందంతో చేతులు జోడించాడు. అపరిమితమైన ప్రేమతో స్వాగతం పలికాడు.శ్రీకృష్ణునికి పాదపూజ చేస్తాడు. ఆకలిగా ఉందన్న ఆయనకు అరిటాకు వేసి, ఇంటిలో ఉన్న కొన్ని అరటిపళ్ళు పెడతాడు విదురుడు. శ్రీకృష్ణునికి భక్తిపూర్వక నైవేద్యంగా ప్రేమతో వడ్డించింది ఆ ఇంటి ఇల్లాలు. విదురుడు వింజామరతో విసురుతున్నాడు. వారి ఆదరాభిమానాలకు వాసుదేవుడు కరిగిపోయాడు. ఆ దంపతులు భక్తి పారవశ్యంలో కృష్ణుణ్ణి చూస్తూ అరటిపండ్లు ఒలిచి పండును పక్కన పెట్టి తొక్కను ఇస్తుంటే వాటినే ఆరగించాడు ఆ పరమాత్మ. తర్వాత గమనించిన దంపతులు తేరుకొని మన్నించమని ప్రార్థిస్తారు. భక్తులకు తాను దాసుణ్ణని, వారు మనసు పెట్టి సమర్పించింది ఏదైనా సరే స్వీకరిస్తానని చెప్తాడు.ఎదుటి వారికి ఇచ్చేది ఏదైనా సరే అణకువతో ఇవ్వాలి. అహంకారం లేని సమర్షణను ఆనందంగా స్వీకరించడానికి భగవంతుడైనా నిరుపేద ముంగిటికి వస్తాడు. తన భక్తులు తనకేమిచ్చారో చూడకుండా ఎలా ఇచ్చారన్న దానికే పెద్దపీట వేస్తాడు."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Laget spelade sin första match den 14 mars","answer":"2011, då man utklassade Irland med 23-0 i Sofia under en match i världsmästerskapets Division V."},{"question":"Délé Giwa ","answer":"Dele Giwa tí abísọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Sùmọ́nù Ọládélé Baines Giwa jẹ́ ọmọ prílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà tí won bí ní ọjọ́ kẹrìndínlógún oṣù Ẹrẹ́nà l, ọdún 1947, tí ó sì papò dà ní ọjọ́ kọkàndínlógún oṣù Ọ̀wàwà ọdún 1986. (16 March 1947 – 19 October 1986) jẹ́ oníṣẹ́ ìwé ìròyìn àti olóòtú ìwé ìròyìn ọlọ́sọ̀ọ̀sẹ̀ Newswatch.Sùmọ́nù Ọládélé Baines Giwa won bí ní ọjọ́ kẹrìndínlógún oṣù kẹta ọdún 1947, tí ó sì papò dà ní ọjọ́ kọkàndínlógún oṣù kẹwá ọdún 1986. (16 March 1947 ) ni wọ́n bí sínú ẹbí ìkan nínú àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ l'áàfin Ọba Adesoji Aderemi nígbà ayé rẹ̀.Délé l9 sí ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ L.A tí ó wà ní Làgèrè ní ìlú Ilé-Ifẹ̀. Ó sì wọ ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ ti Odùduwà College ní Ilé-Ifẹ̀ nígbà tí bàbá rẹ̀ ríṣẹ́ sí ibẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí alágbàfọ̀. Délé tún lọ sílé ẹ̀kọ́ àgbà ní ìlú Amẹ́ríkà tí ó sì kẹ́kọ́ gboyè BA nínú ìmọ̀ èdè Gẹ̀ẹ́sì ní ulé-ẹ̀kọ́ Brooklyn College ní ọdún 1977. Ó tún sì tún lọ sílé ẹ̀kọ́ Fordham University láti kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyè siwájú si. Ó ṣiṣẹ́ ní ilé-iṣẹ́ ìwé ìròyìn ilẹ̀ Amerika tí orúkọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ The New York Times gẹ́gẹ́ bí amúgbá-lẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ olóòtú ìwé ìròyìn náà fún odidi ọdún mẹ́rin gbáko ṣáájú kí ó tó padà sí orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà láti sìṣẹ́ nílé iṣẹ́ ìwé ìròyìn Daily Times tí ó wà ní ìlú Èkó.Délé Gíwá, Ray Ekpu, Dan Agbese ati Yakubu Mohammed ni wọ́n jọ pawọ́pọ̀ dá ilé-iṣẹ́ ìwé ìròyìn Newswatch ní ọdún 1984, wọ́n sì gbé àpilẹ̀kọ akọ́kọ́ jáde ní ọjọ́ kejìdínlógún oṣù kíní ọdún 1985, tí wọ́n sì bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ń pin ká ní oṣù kíní. Délé gbé iṣẹ́ ìmọ̀ ìròyìn àti ìkóroyìn jọ jáde ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà pẹ̀lú ṣíṣàfikún ìgboyà àti ìtọpinpin nínú iṣẹ́ ìròyìn nígbà ayé rẹ̀. Ní àsìkò ìjọba Ààrẹ apàṣẹ wàá lábẹ́ ìjọba ológun Ibrahim Babangida tí ó gba ìjọba ní inú oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 1985. Délé gbé àwòrán ojú Ààrẹ náà sí ojú ewé akọ́kọ́ ìwé ìròyìn náà ní ẹ̀mẹ́rin tí ó sì tún ń fẹnu àbùkù sọ tẹni bá ro wípé òun yóò ma da ìjọba Ààrẹ Babangida rà. Nígbẹ̀yìn, ìwé ìròyìn Newswatch gbójú agan sí Ààrẹ náà lásìkò ìjọba rẹ̀.Délé Gíwá fẹ́ ìyàwó rẹ̀ àkọ́kọ́ ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà tí ó jẹ́ oníṣẹ́ ìlera ní ọdún 1974. Ó fẹ́ ìyàwó kejì tí orúkọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Florence Ita Giwa, amọ́ ìgbéyàwó wọn kò ju lò ju oṣù mẹ́wá lọ kí ó tó túká. Lẹ́yìn náà ó tún ṣe ìgbéyàwó pẹ̀lú arabìnrin Olufunmilayo Olaniyan ní ọjọ́ kẹwá oṣù keje ọdún 1984, tí wọ́n sì jọ wà papọ̀ títí di àsìkò ikú rẹ̀ ní ọdún 1986. Ìyá rẹ̀ tó bi àti ọmọ rẹ̀ ni wọ́n gbẹ̀yìn rẹ̀."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి పర్యాయ పదాలని ఇవ్వండి: కరుణ","answer":"దయ, కృప, కనికరము"},{"question":"கேள்வி : தந்தை பெரியாரின் கல்வி தொடர்பான கூற்றுக்கள் யாவை? ","answer":"பதில்  :கல்விகல்வி என்பது ஒரு மனிதனுக்கு கற்பிக்கப்பட வேண்டிய அவசியமெல்லாம், அவன் தன் வாழ்நாளில் சுதந்திரத்தோடு வாழ்வதற்கு தகுதிப்படுத்தவே!.கல்வி அறிவும், சுயமரியாதை எண்ணமும், பகுத்தறிவு தன்மையுமே தாழ்ந்து கிடக்கும் மக்களை உயர்த்தும்.கல்வியானது அறிவு வளர்ச்சிக்கும், புலமைக்குமே தவிர, மதப்பிரச்சாரத்துக்கு அல்ல என்பது கல்வியின் அடிப்படை தத்துவமாக இருக்க வேண்டும்.பகுத்தறிவுக்கு மாறானதும், மூட நம்பிக்கையை வளர்ப்பதுமான எந்த செய்தியும் கல்வியில் பாடமாக கற்பிக்கக் கூடாது.எவ்வளவு பெரிய கல்வியும், ஒரு கலையாகவும் தொழிலாகவும் போய்விட்டதேயல்லாமல் பகுத்தறிவுக்கு ஒரு சிறிதும் பயன்படுவதாக இல்லை.தேசம் மக்களாலும், மக்கள் ஆசிரியர்களாலும் உருப்பட வேண்டி இருக்கிறது.ஆசிரியர்கள் முதலில் மக்களுக்குச் சுயமரியாதை இன்னதென்பதைக் கற்றுக் கொடுக்க வேண்டும்.அறிவு முற்றும் வரையில் கற்பதிலேயே மாணவர்கள் மனத்தைச் செலுத்த ஆசிரியர்கள் அறிவுறுத்த வேண்டும்.நமக்கு வேண்டியதெல்லாம் கோவிலல்ல; பள்ளிக்கூடம்தான்.மாணவர்கள்"},{"question":"Lực là gì?","answer":"tác dụng đẩy, kéo của vật này lên vật khác.- Lực là đại lượng vecto.- Khi có lực tác dụng, mọi vật không thể thay đổi vận tốc đột ngột được vì có quán tính.- Lực tác dụng lên vật có thể làm biến đổi chuyển động của vật hoặc làm nó biến dạng.- Hai lực cân bằng:+ Cùng cường độ.+ Cùng phương.+ Ngược chiều."},{"question":"Rubuta 10 a rubutan ce.","answer":"Goma"},{"question":"Chii chinonzi pH yemushonga ine hydrogen ion concentration [H⁺] ye1.0 x 10⁻⁵ M?","answer":"pH inoverengwa uchishandisa fomula: pH = -log[H⁺].pH = -log(1.0 x 10⁻⁵) ≈ -(-5) ≈ 5Saka, iyo pH yemhinduro inenge 5."},{"question":"Wie waren de kinderen van Jaehaerys I Targaryen?","answer":"De kinderen waren Prins Aegon, Prinses Daenerys, Prins Aemon, Prins Baelon, Prinses Alyssa, Septa Maegelle, Aartsmaester Vaegon, Prinses Daella, Prinses Saera, Prinses Viserra, Prins Gaemon, Prins Valerion, Prinses Gael"},{"question":"Завершите параграф: Раскольников не привык к толпе и, как уже сказано, бежал всякого общества, особенно в последнее время. Но теперь его вдруг что-то потянуло к людям. Что-то совершалось в нем как бы новое, и вместе с тем ощутилась какая-то жажда людей.","answer":"Он так устал от целого месяца этой сосредоточенной тоски своей и мрачного возбуждения, что хотя одну минуту хотелось ему вздохнуть в другом мире, хоть бы в каком бы то ни было, и, несмотря на всю грязь обстановки, он с удовольствием оставался теперь в распивочной."},{"question":"Are there any superstitions or beliefs unique to Sri Lankan culture?","answer":"Yes, Sri Lankan culture, rich and diverse due to its history and geographic location, encompasses a variety of superstitions and beliefs, many of which are influenced by the island's major religions, including Buddhism, Hinduism, Islam, and Christianity, as well as by local traditions and folklore. Here are some examples:Evil Eye (Drishti): Similar to many other cultures, Sri Lankans believe in the concept of the \\"evil eye,\\" which can bring bad luck or harm to a person. Amulets, charms, or rituals are often used to ward off the evil eye.Astrology: Astrology plays a significant role in Sri Lankan life. Many people consult astrologers for various aspects of life such as marriage, starting a new business, or even naming a newborn. The auspicious times (nakath) determined by astrological readings are considered important for starting any significant task.New Year Rituals: The Sinhala and Tamil New Year, a major festival in April, is surrounded by numerous rituals and beliefs. These include specific auspicious times for lighting the hearth, eating the first meal, and starting work, based on astrology.Lime and Chillies to Ward Off Evil: Hanging a combination of lime and chillies in vehicles or outside homes is believed to ward off evil spirits and bring good luck.Protection from the Supernatural: Many Sri Lankans believe in the presence of supernatural beings and spirits. Various rituals and amulets are used for protection against them.Beliefs Around Pregnancy and Childbirth: There are numerous beliefs and rituals associated with pregnancy and childbirth intended to protect the mother and child. These may include restrictions on certain activities or foods for pregnant women.Rituals for the Deceased: Sri Lankan Buddhists often observe specific rituals after the death of a person, such as almsgiving at set intervals after death, which are believed to aid in the deceased’s journey in the afterlife.Dream Interpretation: Dreams are often given much importance in Sri Lankan culture, with people seeking interpretations of dreams, believing they can contain messages or premonitions.'Kapuwa' or Traditional Shaman: In rural areas, people might still consult a 'kapuwa' or traditional shaman for various issues, from health problems to personal issues, believing in their power to connect with the spiritual realm or to use traditional herbal medicines.Beliefs around Trees and Nature: Certain trees and locations are considered sacred or are believed to be inhabited by spirits. Respecting these places and entities is an important aspect of local beliefs.These beliefs and superstitions are deeply embedded in Sri Lankan culture and are a significant part of the social and cultural fabric of the country. They also reflect the blend of various cultural influences that have shaped Sri Lanka over its history."},{"question":"كم وردة كلمة(شفاء) في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"4مرات"},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Keji)","answer":"Ibeere pataki ni. Pe irọ wo lo ku ti Sanwo-Olu tun fẹẹ pa? Ọga awọn ṣọja to wa ni Bonny Camp, ti jade wa, Ahmed Taiwo lorukọ ẹ, o ni Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu, lo pe awọn, ati pe inu awọn ko dun rara pe Sanwo-Olu jade lati maa sọ pe oun ko pe awọn. Ṣe ẹ ri i, bi ọrọ ba da bayii, ti ijangbọn tabi rogbodiyan ba de si aarin ilu, ojuṣe gomina ibẹ ni lati wa gbogbo ọna ti iru rogbodiyan bẹẹ yoo fi lọ. Nigba mi-in, o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ awọn ọlọpaa ni wọn yoo ranṣẹ si lati gba wọn, igba mi-in, o si ṣee ṣe pe awọn ṣọja ni wọn yoo bẹ lọwẹ. Ṣugbọn gomina ti yoo ṣe bẹẹ, ti yo pe ọlọpaa tabi ṣọja lati ba a pana rogbodiyan araalu, o gbọdọ jẹ gomina to mọ ohun to n ṣe, to mọ ohun to n lọ, to si mọ idi to fi pe awọn agbofinro yii pe ki wọn waa gba oun. Ṣugbọn Sanwo-Olu ṣe aṣiṣe nla, nitori bi ọrọ ba ri bo ti ri yii, ki i ṣe awọn ṣọja ni wọn n pe, wọn maa n lọọ ba awọn to n ṣewọde yii sọrọ ni, wọn yoo si wa ọna lati ri awọn to dari eto naa, ki wọn le pẹtu si wọn ninu, ki wọn si tu wọn ka. Bi eleyii ko ba ṣe, wọn yo lọọ ko awọn ọlọpaa wa, awọn ọlọpaa yii ko ni i yinbọn, tajutaju lasan ti to lati tu awọn ọdọ ti ko gbebọn, ti wọn ko mu ada tabi ohun ija kankan lọwọ yii. Ko si bi wọn ti le pọ to ti tajutaju ati ibọn onirọba ko ni i le wọn lọ. Ṣugbọn aṣilo agbara lo mu Gomina Sanwo-Olu, ohun to si jẹ ko ro pe ṣọja lo le yanju ọrọ to wa nile naa niyi. Ni oun ba fi ranṣẹ si wọn. Ṣugbọn ṣọja ki i lọ si ode alaafia, ohun to yẹ ki gomina yii ti mọ niyi, ode yoowu ti wọn ba lọ, ode ijangbọn ni. Ode iku! Iru ẹ naa lo si ṣẹlẹ yii. Eyi to waa buru ninu gbogbo ọrọ yii ni irọ ti Gomina yii n pa. O ti ṣe e, o ti ṣe e na, ọrọ si ti ja si ibi ti oun paapaa ko ro, ko si si ohun meji to le ṣe lẹyin ẹ mọ ju ko ba araalu sọrọ, ko si tuuba lọ, ko si jẹ ki wọn mọ pe oun ṣe aṣiṣe ni ọọkan ibẹ yẹn, ati pe iru aṣiṣe bẹẹ ko ni i waye mọ. Sanwo-Olu ko ṣe eleyii, kaka bẹẹ, o n puro mọ irọ ni. Irọ naa lo ja bayii o. Nitori ẹ naa la ṣe n beere: Irọ ewo lo waa ku ti Sanwo-Olu fẹẹ pa o. Ko sirọ kan ti yoo pa ti yoo niyi mọ. Ohun to yẹ bayii naa ni ko jade sita, ko sọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an fun gbogbo ilu, ko si tuuba, ki gbogbo ilu si fori ji gomina wọn. O ya, Sanwo-Olu, gbogbo aye n reti rẹ o!Owo tawọn gomina to ti fẹyin ti n gba, ijẹkujẹ niOhun kan ti Gomina Sanwo-Olu fẹẹ ṣe to dara gan-an, ti awọn aṣofin Eko naa si gbọdọ fọwọ si i, ni lati gbegi le owo-oṣu ati awọn ajẹmọnu ọran ti awọn gomina to ti fẹyinti n gba ni ipinlẹ wọn. Owo naa ko daa rara, awọn ohun tawọn si sọ pe ki wọn maa ṣe fun wọn ki i ṣe ohun to ṣee gbọ seti. Bi eeyan kan ba ti jẹ gomina tan, wọn ni wọn yoo maa ra mọto tuntun meji meji fun un lọdun mẹta mẹta, wọn yoo maa ran an lọ siluu oyinbo ko lọọ gba itọju lọdọọdun, wọn yoo kọle fun un l’Abuja ati l’Ekoo, wọn yoo ko awọn ọlọpaa fun un, wọn yoo maa sanwo gbogbo awọn oṣiṣẹ to ba wa nile ẹ, wọn yoo si jẹ ko maa ko awọn ọlọpaa to n lo lọ. Ijọba ni yoo si maa sanwo gbogbo eleyii o, bẹẹ lo jẹ owo-oṣu ti gomina to ba wa lori oye ba n gba lawọn naa yoo maa gba. Nitori pe wọn ṣe gomina fọdun mẹjo! Bẹẹ ni ko si iru anfaani bayii fun awọn oṣiṣẹ to fi ọdun marundinlogoji wa nibẹ, to jẹ ati gba owo ifẹyinti wọn gan-an, wahala ni. Ki waa ni gomina yoo maa gba iru owo buruku bayii lọwọ ipinlẹ kọọkan bayii. Bi Eko ti ṣe naa ni awọn ipinlẹ mi-in tẹle e, o kan jẹ Bọla Tinubu lo ṣaaju lasiko naa ni. Nitori naa lo ṣe yẹ ki eeyan ki Tinubu naa, nitori o ti sọ pe oun naa fara mọ ki ijọba Eko gbegi le owo ifẹyinti yii. Tinubu naa ti jade, o si ti ri i pe ohun tawọn ṣe ko dara, iwa irẹjẹ ati ika lo jẹ fun awọn araalu. Ṣugbọn bo ṣe ẹlomi-in naa ni, yoo tubọ maa ṣe agidi ni, yoo ni owo awọn ni, awọn aṣofin ọjọsi si kuku ti fọwọ si i. Nigba ti Tinubu waa sọ pe oun ti fara mọ ọn yii, ko si aṣofin kan to gbọdọ ni oun ko ni i fọwọ si i. Afi ki wọn fọwọ si i, ki irẹjẹ owo ti awọn gomina atijọ yii n gba lọwọ araalu si dopin kia. Ki gbogbo eto naa kari ilẹ Yoruba pata paapaa, nitori gbogbo wọn ni wọn ni owo ọran bayii ti wọn n gba lọwọ ijọba. Sanwoolu ṣe eleyii daadaa o, ki gbogbo gomina to ku yaa sare tẹle e.Bẹẹ ki i ṣe Fayoṣe ni yoo ba tawọn PDP yii jẹ ṣaaAwọn aṣaaju ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP ti ilẹ Yoruba nibi ṣepade wọn lọsẹ to kọja niluu Ibadan, labẹ Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde to yẹ ko jẹ olori pata fun ẹkun yii, gẹgẹ bi gomina ẹyo kan naa to wa nibẹ. Nibẹ ni wọn ti yan Ọlagunsoye Oyinnlọla bii alaga igbimọ ti wọn ni ko pari ija to wa laarin awọn aṣaaju ati awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ naa kaakiri ilẹ Yoruba yii. Amọ bi awọn ti ṣepade tiwọn, ki wọn too kuro naa ni Ayọdele Fayoṣe ti i ṣe gomina ipinlẹ Ekiti tẹlẹ naa gbe igbimọ tirẹ mi-in dide, o ni ipade awọn aṣaaju PDP niyi. Nibi ipade tiwọn yii, ko si gomina PDP kan, ko si awọn aṣofin, oun naa kan ko awọn kan jọ, o ni awọn ni aṣaaju ẹgbẹ naa. Awọn iwa ti Fayoṣe n hu ninu ẹgbẹ yii lati ọjọ yii ko fi i han bii aṣaaju daadaa fun ẹgbẹ wọn, iwa awọn eeyan ti wọn n pe ni pọn-tan-o-rudo ni, nitori oun ti pọn omi tirẹ tan, o si bẹrẹ si i da odo ru fun awon mi-in ti wọn fẹẹ pọnmi. Fayoṣe ti ṣejọba, nigba to si n ṣe gomina, oun ni olori ẹgbẹ wọn, tori oun nikan naa ni gomina PDP. Lati igba to ti waa kuro nijọba ni wahala ti bẹrẹ. Akọkọ ni pe ko fi ori fun ẹni to yẹ ko jẹ olori ẹgbẹ naa ni ipinlẹ tirẹ gan-an, iyẹn obinrin kan sṣoṣo to jẹ sẹneto lati ọdọ wọn, Abiọdun Olujimi. Ẹẹkeji ni pe ko gba fun awọn ti wọn jẹ olori ẹgbẹ naa ni agbegbe ilẹ Yoruba. Gbogbo ibo ti wọn di kọja lorukọ ẹgbẹ naa, ko yọju sibẹ, ko si ṣe atilẹyin kankan fun wọn. Lati waa gbe igbimọ mi-in kalẹ yatọ si eyi ti awọn ti wọn jẹ olori ẹgbẹ naa gbe dide, ọna lati ba ẹgbẹ naa jẹ pata ni. Idi ti Fayọṣe si ṣe n ṣe eleyii, oun nikan lo ye. Bi ohun yoowu ba wa laarin wọn to jẹ ede-aiyede, ko si ohun to buru ki Fayoṣe sun mọ awọn to ku ki wọn si yanju ẹ, nitori bi ẹgbẹ naa ba fọ, ko ṣe ẹnikẹni lanfaani ninu wọn. Ati pe ko ṣe apọnle foun naa, nitori wọn yoo ri i bii ọbayejẹ, adanikanjẹ, ati agufọn lasan. Bẹẹ, ẹgbẹ PDP ṣe pataki nilẹ Yoruba gẹgẹ bii ẹgbẹ alatako, nitori ko si ibi ti ẹgbẹ oloṣelu kan ṣoṣo ba ti n ṣejọba ki i dara. Bi APC ba wa nibẹ, ti wọn n ṣejọba lọ, ti ijọba wọn ko tẹ araalu lọrun mọ, o yẹ ki ẹgbẹ mi-in wa ti araalu yoo le dibo wọn fun. Ati pe bi APC naa ba mọ pe PDP wa nipo alatako awọn, wọn yoo ṣe ijọba daadaa. Ki waa ni Fayoṣe yoo da ẹgbe naa ru si! Kin ni Fayoṣe n fẹ gan-an! Eyi to n ṣe yii ko le fun un lorukọ rere, nitori bo ti n ṣe yii, afaimọ ko maa ba ti PDP jẹ nilẹ Yoruba patapata.Ki Ọlọrun fun Dapọ Abiọdun ṣeỌkan ninu awọn ironu to daa gan-an, ti yoo ti ọdọ Ọmọọba Dapọ Abiọdun, Gomina ipinlẹ Ogun, ati awọn ti wọn jọ n ṣejọba rẹ jade ni pe ki wọn sọ aṣọ adirẹ di aṣọ ti awọn ọmọ ileewe yoo maa wọ ni ipinlẹ naa, jake-jado. Eyi ni pe aṣọ awọn ọmọleewe yoo kuro ni Kaki, yoo si di aṣọ adirẹ. Nigba ti ipinlẹ kan ba mọ ohun ti oun ni, ti oun le fi ṣe owo, ohun to dara ju ni ko lo ọna naa, nitori eyi ti gomina naa ṣe yii yoo mu owo nla wa fun ipinlẹ rẹ, owo naa yoo si ya oun paapaa lẹnu. Nigba ti adirẹ ba di ohun ti awọn ọmọleewe n wọ, awọn olowo ati ọlọla naa yoo wa oju adirẹ mi-in ti wọn yoo maa wọ. Awọn ti wọn si nile aṣọ adirẹ yii yoo pọ si i. Bi awọn ti wọn nile aṣọ adirẹ yii ba ti n pọ si i, bẹẹ ni awọn ti wọn n ṣe yoo si maa pọ si i, awọn mi-in yoo si da ileeṣẹ adirẹ silẹl lọpọ yanturu. Ọna owo nla kan ni funjọba, nitori ko ni i yaayan lẹnu bi awọn ara ilẹ okeere ba n wa lati waa ra aṣọ naa lọ sọdọ wọn. Ki Gomina Abiọdun ma duro sidii eyi nikan o, ko tubọ pa a laṣẹ ki awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba ati awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba naa maa lo adirẹ, paapaa wa sibi iṣẹ wọn. Ki awọn ti wọn fẹẹ fi da ṣẹẹti fi da a, ki awọn ti wọn si fẹẹ fi da buba fi da a, ko ṣaa ti jẹ aṣọ to ba ibi iṣẹ mu. Lara ohun ti wọn n sọ fawọn gomina gbogbo ree, pe inu ile wọn ni ki wọn wo, ki wọn wo ohun to wa ni ipinlẹ wọn ti awọn naa le ṣe, eyi yoo mu owo irọrun wa fun wọn, yoo si mu nnkan rọrun fawọn eeyan wọn naa, gbogbo ilu yoo si maa gbadun labẹ ijọba wọn. Eyi ti Dapọ Abiọdun fẹẹ ṣe yii daa o, ki gbogbo ọmọ ipinlẹ Ogun dide ran an lọwọ, ki oriire to wa nibẹ le jẹ ti gbogbo wa.Dangote lo ku ti yoo jogun Naijiria, abi?Ni ọsẹ to kọja yii, ijọba orilẹ-ede wa, labẹ alaṣẹ Muhammadu Buhari, faaye gba ileeṣẹ Dangote pe ki wọn maa ko ọja wọn lọ si awọn ibi yoowu ti wọn ba ti fẹẹ ta a kaakiri orilẹ-ede Afrika, paapaa ni Nijee (Niger Republic) ati Togo. Ibeere to wa ninu igbesẹ yii ni pe ki lo de ti ijọba Buhari fẹẹ sọ gbogbo Naijiria di ti ileeṣẹ Dangote nikan. Ki lo de ti ijọba Naijiria n mu awọn onileeṣẹ ati awọn olokoowo to ku lọwọ dani ki ileeṣẹ Dangote le kọja, ko si jere ju awọn to ku lọ. Ki lo de ti ijọba Buhari n pa awọn ileeṣẹ to ku ni Naijiria nitori lati gbe Dangote ga. Nigba ti korona wa nita, ti ijọba ṣe ofin konilegbele, Dangote nikan lawọn Buhari fun laaye pe kawọn mọto ẹ maa rin lọ, ki wọn maa rin bọ, ki wọn maa ba iṣẹ tiwọn lọ. Awọn onileeṣẹ nla nla mi-in wa nibẹ, awọn bii Lever Brothers, UAC, Cadbury, Nestle, Guiness, Nigerian Breweries ati awọn ileeṣẹ bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ wa niluu, awọn naa n ṣowo, awọn mi-in si wa to jẹ ounjẹ jijẹ to wulo fun gbogbo ilu nikan ni iṣẹ tiwọn. Ṣugbọn awọn Buhari ko fun wọn laaye lati rin loju titi, afi Dangote nikan. O ti le lọdun kan sẹyin ti ijọba Naijiria ti ti gbogbo ẹnubode orilẹ-ede yii pa, ti wọn ko si jẹ ki ọja kankan wọle tabi jade, paapaa lati awọn ilu to ja si ilẹ Yoruba ati ilẹ Ibo. Titi di asiko yii, wọn ko ti i ṣi bọda naa. Ṣugbọn lọsẹ to kọja ni ijọba ṣe ofin yii pe ki Dangote maa lọ ko maa bọ lawọn bọda ti wọn ti ti pa yii, ko maa ko ọja wọle ko maa ko ọja jade. Ṣe iru eleyii daa ni. Nigba ti gbogbo aye pariwo, awọn Buhari tun fun ẹlomi-in laaye, ọmo Hausa kan to ni ileeṣe BUA, wọn ni koun naa maa ko ọja rẹ jade lẹnubode bii ti Dangote, ki gbogbo aye le mọ pe ki i ṣe Dangote nikan lawọn ṣe bẹẹ fun. Ati Dangote ati BUA, ọmọ Kano, nilẹ Hausa, lawọn mejeeji! Aṣe pe ko si oniṣowo ati awọn ti wọn ni ileeṣẹ nilẹ Yoruba ati ilẹ Ibo bi? Ki lo de ti Buhari n ṣe bayii! Ki lo de ti awọn eeyan yii n fi ẹlẹyamẹya ṣejọba, tabi wọn ti ro pe ileejọba yii lawọn yoo ku si ni! Eleyii o daa! Irẹjẹ yii ṣẹ n pọ ju, ohun ti yoo ti ẹyin rẹ jade ko le daa o! Ẹni to ba leti ko yaa gbọ."},{"question":"Viết bài văn với đề bài sau: Hãy đóng vai nhạc sĩ Văn Cao, viết bài văn kể lại sự ra đời của bài hát “Tiến quân ca”.","answer":"Tuổi thanh niên là tuổi của ước mơ, của hoài bão khát vọng. Ấy vậy mà tôi lúc ấy không còn khát vọng, ước mơ của tuổi thanh niên, buồn chán và thất vọng bủa vây cuộc đời tôi. Đúng lúc tuyệt vọng nhất tôi gặp được Vũ Quý thông qua người bạn thân Ph.D. Khi gặp Vũ Quý tôi mong muốn được tham gia chiến khu cùng các anh em cầm súng giết giặc. Nhưng có lẽ Vũ Quý theo dõi sự nghiệp sáng tác nghệ thuật của tôi nên giao cho tôi sáng tác nghệ thuật để cổ vũ tinh thần cho quân đội cách mạng.Khi bắt tay viết bài hát Tiến quân ca, tôi chưa được cầm một khẩu súng, chưa được gia nhập đội vũ trang nào; tôi chưa được ra chiến khu, và cũng chưa từng gặp chiến sĩ cách mạng trong khóa quân chính ấy. Nhưng tại căn gác nhỏ ở phố Nguyễn Thượng Hiền, tôi lại hình dung đó là chiến khu, là khu rừng nào đó trên Việt Bắc, và cứ thế lời ca ra đời, con chữ tự nhiên hiện ra dưới ngòi bút. Tại căn gác nhỏ đó Ph.D đã chứng kiến sự ra đời của Tiến quân ca, và Vũ Quý là người đầu tiên biết đến bài hát này.Bài hát Tiến quân ca ra đời được chào đón rất nồng nhiệt. Bài hát được công bố lần đầu trong ngày 17-8-1945, khi diễn ra cuộc mít tinh của công chức Hà Nội. Tại đây bài hát Tiến quân ca được hàng ngàn người hoà nhịp cất cao tiếng hát trước Quảng trường Nhà hát Lớn. Tại buổi hôm đó bài hát đã nổ ra như một trái bom. Nước mắt tôi trào ra. Xung quanh tôi hang ngàn giọng hát cất vang theo những đoạn sôi nổi. Trong một lúc những tờ truyền đơn in Tiến quân ca được phát cho từng người trong hàng ngũ các công chức dự mít tinh. Lúc này anh bạn Ph.D của tôi đã buông lá cờ đỏ sao vàng trên kia xuống và cướp loa phóng thanh hát vang Tiến quân ca. Con người trầm lặng ấy đã có sức hát hấp dẫn hang vạn quần chúng ngày hôm đó, cũng là người hát trước quần chúng lần đầu tiên và cũng là một lần duy nhất. Lần thứ hai bài hát Tiến quân ca của tôi xuất hiện là trong cuộc mít tinh vào ngày 19-8, hàng ngàn người và các em thiếu nhi cùng cất lời ca, thét lên tiếng căm thù vào mặt bọn đế quốc với sự hào hùng chiến thắng của cách mạng. Bài hát Tiến quân ca của tôi đã ra đời như thế đấy. Sau đó, bài hát được chọn làm Quốc ca Việt Nam cho đến ngày nay. Bài hát là niềm tự hào không phải của riêng tôi mà là của cả dân tộc Việt Nam. "},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Thực tế, có những người đã đi làm tới cả chục năm rồi nhưng vẫn không có tiền tiết kiệm hoặc số tiền này quá ít, chẳng đủ để làm gì dù thu nhập hàng tháng không hề ít. Cũng có những người chỉ vừa mới đi làm được 1, 2 năm đã có khoản để dành. Sự khác biệt này cho thấy, rõ ràng 1 phần nguyên nhân tới từ cách quản lý tài chính cũng như chi tiêu hoặc chưa thật sự hiểu hết vai trò và giá trị của tiết kiệm. Dưới đây là những sai lầm phổ biến khi quản lý tài chính mà mọi người nên tránh: 1. Tiết kiệm tiền sau khi chi tiêu Có không ít người nghĩ rằng hàng tháng cứ để dành được 1 khoản là được, không cần biết số tiền đó được trích ra trước hay sau khi chi tiêu. Đây là suy nghĩ thông thường về khái niệm tiết kiệm mà những người mới bắt đầu mắc phải. Tuy vậy, bạn cần biết rằng, có thể trong 1-2 tháng đầu mới thực hiện và khi tài chính của bạn vẫn đang dư dả thì sự sai lầm sẽ không được thể hiện rõ ràng. Nhưng hãy thử nghĩ xem, nếu 1 tháng nào đó không đạt KPIs và lương của bạn bị giảm trừ, trong khi đó lại có 1 số khoản phát sinh thì liệu bạn có chắc mình còn để tiết kiệm nữa hay không? Theo đó, nếu muốn tiết kiệm thì bằng mọi giá, hãy tiết kiệm xong rồi chi tiêu phần còn lại. 2. Không kiểm soát chặt chẽ dòng tiền Với những ai đang làm freelancer hoặc làm 1 lúc nhiều công việc thì kiểm soát dòng tiền thực sự khó, đây có lẽ cũng là lý do khiến nhiều người thấy chán nản trong công cuộc này. Tuy vậy, bạn cần biết rằng, càng nhỏ lẻ thì bạn càng cần quản lý chặt chẽ. Có thể nhiều người sẽ nghĩ, khoản được ít thì cứ tiêu đi. Nhưng thực ra, những đồng tiền lẻ đó nếu được tích cóp lại sẽ không hề ít chút nào. Hãy học cách duy trì thói quen kiểm soát những dòng tiền có thể đổ về trong tháng và cân nhắc xem nên được dùng vào khoản nào để đưa ra cách quản lý cũng như chi tiêu phù hợp, tránh lãng phí. 3. Bỏ qua bước lập kế hoạch chi tiêu Lập kế hoạch chi tiêu trong ngày hay tháng vốn dĩ không hề tốn thời gian của mọi người. Nhưng hầu hết chúng ta đều cảm thấy lười biếng mỗi khi nghĩ tới việc này. Song, có 1 điều mà chúng ta cần biết là, những bản kế hoạch đóng vai trò đặc biệt quan trọng trước khi bắt đầu điều gì đó. Kế hoạch chi tiêu không chỉ cho phép bạn ước tính cách tiêu tiền trước, thay vì tiêu tiền theo cảm tính mà còn giúp bạn xác định và đạt được mục tiêu 1 cách dễ dàng, nhanh chóng hơn. Từ đó giúp đem lại cảm giác yên tâm trước khi chi tiêu. 4. Tìm cách tiết kiệm bằng mọi giá nhưng lại không thực sự biết cách chi tiêu, dễ sa đà vào \\"bẫy\\" mua sắm Điều này nghe có vẻ hơi mơ hồ nhưng các bạn cần biết như thế này: Việc bạn nắm chắc cách chi tiêu đúng ảnh hưởng","answer":"rất nhiều tới túi tiền của bạn. Nhiều người vẫn thường tiết kiệm không dám tiêu tiền, hoặc chỉ bỏ tiền để mua các món đồ rẻ tiền/giảm giá... Hầu hết mọi người vẫn nghĩ bằng cách này sẽ giúp tiết kiệm chi tiêu. Nhưng chưa chắc đâu nhé! Ví dụ như thế này, khi đi siêu thị, bạn thấy sữa tươi đang được bày bán với quảng cáo khuyến mãi mua 2 tặng 1. Tuy nhiên, đi cùng với nó là hạn sử dụng rất ngắn. Vậy là để được hời, bạn lựa chọn mua cố thêm 1 thùng mà không tính toán đến việc liệu có sử dụng hết hay không. Sau đó, rất có thể bạn sẽ phải vứt bỏ tới hơn 2 thùng sữa vì quá hạn sử dụng. Hoặc giả, bạn nghĩ rằng mình chỉ cần mua 1 đôi giày giá rẻ, chất lượng bình dân để đi chạy bộ hàng ngày thôi nhưng sử dụng được 1 tháng đã hỏng và bạn tiếp tục phải mua 1 đôi khác. Trong khi 1 đôi giày xịn, giá chỉ chừng 1 triệu đồng lại dùng được 1 năm. So sánh như vậy để thấy, bạn cần tính toán thật kĩ trước mỗi quyết định chi tiêu. Mua được hàng rẻ chưa chắc đã tiết kiệm. Và tiết kiệm được là tốt, nhưng cũng đừng để bản thân bị tiền bạc chi phối quá nhiều, ảnh hưởng đến chất lượng cuộc sống và cả túi tiền của bạn. Trân trọng đồng tiền là việc bạn cần làm nhưng hãy tìm cách tận dụng thật tốt để mọi thứ đều phát huy được hết giá trị của nó. 5. Chăm chăm tìm cách tạo ra lợi nhuận, nhưng không quan tâm đến việc quản lý rủi ro 1 điểm khác biệt rõ rệt của các bạn trẻ hiện nay đối với thế hệ trước chính là tư duy cải thiện kinh tế thay vì tìm cách tiết kiệm bằng mọi giá. Chính từ suy nghĩ này, những người trẻ cũng tìm ra rất nhiều cơ hội để tạo ra lợi nhuận. Song, lợi nhuận luôn đi cùng với rủi ro, nên nếu không biết cách quản lý điều đó, mọi thứ gần như trở nên vô nghĩa. Trên đây là những sai lầm khi quản lý tài chính mà không ít người mắc phải. Hy vọng với những gợi ý này, mọi người có thể nhìn lại và tìm ra cách quản lý tài chính đúng đắn, giúp cải thiện tiền bạc."},{"question":"Tuliskan sebuah karangan yang bertajuk \\"Kepentingan Industri Kecil dan Sederhana\\".","answer":"Mutakhir ini, arus globalisasi yang menerjah dunia telah memberi impak dan perubahan yang besar kepada negara sama ada dari segi politik, ekonomi dan sosial. Dalam menongkah dan mengejar arus modenisasi ini, kerajaan kita telah menggagaskan konsep 1 Malaysia yang berpaksikan slogan  “Rakyat Didahulukan, Pencapaian Diutamakan”. Hal ini juga merupakan rentetan kepada Dasar Ekonomi Baru supaya semua lapisan masyarakat dapat menikmati kemakmuran negara secara adil dan saksama. Menyedari hakikat inilah kerajaan telah memperuntukkan sejumlah dana yang besar bagi memajukan Industri Kecil dan Sederhana (IKS). Hal ini bertepatan dengan peribahasa Melayu hati kuman sama di cecah, hati gajah sama dilapah. IKS  telah dibangunkan dengan pesatnya umpama cendawan tumbuh selepas hujan. Contoh Industri Kecil dan Sederhana (IKS) ialah kilang kraf tangan, kilang keropok, perusahaan batik, kilang mi dan lain-lain lagi. Terdapat banyak kepentingan IKS kepada masyarakat dan negara.Salah satu kepentingan IKS ialah dapat meningkatkan ekonomi masyarakat terutamanya penduduk di luar bandar.  Kita sedia maklum bahawa industri ini banyak didirikan di kawasan luar bandar selaras dengan konsep ‘Satu Kampung Satu Produk’.  Sebagai contoh  kilang membuat kerepek, kilang membuat sos tomato, kilang kraf tangan  dan lain-lain lagi.  Pengusaha kilang dapat menjual hasil keluaran mereka kepada penduduk-penduduk kampung serta pengunjung-pengunjung yang lain. Selain itu, mereka juga boleh memasarkan hasil IKS ini di pasar malam, pasar tani serta di karnival-karnival jualan. Meskipun keuntungan penjualannya tidaklah seberapa, namun sikap gigih dan istiqamah pengusaha IKS menyebabkan produk mereka akhirnya mendapat perhatian para pengguna. Dalam usaha untuk mempromosi produk IKS ini, peribahasa yang pipih tidak datang melayang, yang bulat tidak datang bergolek haruslah dijadikan pegangan. Prinsip membujur lalu, melintang patah iaitu berani menghadapi cabaran dan dugaan dalam perniagaan merupakan resipi kejayaan ramai pengusaha IKS pada hari ini.  Oleh hal yang demikian, jelaslah bahawa IKS ini sangat penting untuk meningkatkan pendapatan penduduk di luar bandar dan seterusnya meningkatkan ekonomi negara.               Selain itu, IKS juga dapat membuka dan memberi peluang pekerjaan kepada masyarakat terutamanya penduduk kampung. Kita sedia maklum bahawa untuk menjana dan meningkatkan hasil pengeluarannya pengusaha IKS ini memerlukan pekerja yang ramai. Sebagai contoh, kilang membuat kerepek memerlukan pekerja untuk menyediakan bahan, memasak, membungkus serta memasarkan produk mereka. Sekurang-kurangnya kilang IKS tersebut memerlukan antara 15 hingga 20 orang pekerja untuk menjalankan operasinya. Dalam usaha untuk meminimumkan kos serta meningkatkan produktiviti, sudah tentu pengusaha IKS akan memilih para pekerja dalam kalangan masyarakat setempat . Hal ini telah akan membuka peluang kepada suri rumah, ibu tunggal atau orang kurang upaya (OKU) untuk bekerja di situ. Sikap pengusaha IKS yang prihatin serta mengutamakan khidmat sosial kepada masyarakat setempat, akan mewujudkan perasaan kekitaan terhadap IKS yang diwujudkan di sesuatu kawasan itu. Peribahasa Melayu ada mengatakan orang berbudi kita berbahasa, orang memberi kita merasa, ironinya, para pekerja tersebut akan berusaha dengan gigih untuk meningkatkan mutu serta kualiti produk kilang tersebut. Jelaslah bahawa IKS ini bukan sahaja dapat membuka peluang pekerjaan kepada penduduk kampung malah dapat membantu negara mengurangkan masalah pengangguran.Di samping itu, pembinaan IKS di kawasan-kawasan luar bandar juga dapat membantu meningkatkan sektor pertanian dan perikanan. Kita sedia maklum bahawa IKS memerlukan bahan-bahan mentah untuk proses pengeluaran kilang mereka. Biasanya bahan-bahan mentah ini adalah daripada hasil  pertanian, perikanan atau perhutanan. Tamsilnya kilang membuat keropok memerlukan hasil tangkapan laut, manakala kilang kerepek pula memerlukan hasil pertanian seperti ubi, keladi, pisang, jagung dan lain-lain. Secara tidak langsung aktiviti pertanian dan  perikanan turut meningkat di kawasan tersebut. Hasil pertanian sara diri penduduk kampung yang selama ini sukar untuk dipasarkan, kini telah menjadi rebutan para pengusaha IKS. Hukum ekonomi menjelaskan bahawa kadar permintaan mempengaruhi penawaran dan harga barangan. Implikasinya harga barang mentah pertanian seperti ubi, pisang, keledek, keladi akan meningkat. Secara   tidak langsung sektor pertanian akan meningkat. Hal ini, diperkukuhkan lagi dengan dasar kerajaan yang memberi perhatian serius untuk membantu meningkatkan pendapatan petani dan nelayan. Oleh hal yang demikian, dalam usaha memenuhi permintaan IKS terhadap bahan mentah yang semakin  meningkat kerajaan melalui agensi-agensi pertanian seperti FAMA, MARDI, PELADANG dan sebagainya telah memberi khidmat kepakaran dan subsidi kewangan kepada para petani dan nelayan. Tuntasnya, IKS ini merupakan serampang dua mata kerana  kewujudannya bukan sahaja dapat meningkatkan ekonomi malahan dapat membasmi kadar kemiskinan  rakyat di negara kita yang tercinta ini.Ada pendapat yang mengatakan bahawa melancong ke Malaysia umpama telah melancong ke separuh dunia. Hal ini kerana, di Malaysia terdapat pelbagai kesenian dan budaya daripada penduduk pelbagai bangsa dan agama. Apakah kaitan penyataan ini dengan IKS? Kolerasinya ialah kewujudan IKS dapat meningkatkan sektor pelancongan di negara kita. Kita sedia maklum bahawa para pelancong suka membeli  kraftangan untuk dibawa pulang. Sebenarnya di Malaysia terdapat banyak barangan kraftangan daripada pelbagai etnik dan kaum yang menjadi warganegara Malaysia. Sebagai contoh perusahaan membuat tembikar, pasu bunga, ukiran, labu sayong, batik, songket, tikar, bakul barangan hutan dan lain-lain lagi. Hasil kraf tangan melambangkan identiti serta jati diri negara. Para pelancong membelanjakan berjuta-juta ringgit untuk  membeli kraftangan ini sebagai cenderamata kenang-kenangan atau hadiah  kepada rakan-rakan apabila pulang kelak. Dalam hal ini peribahasa Melayu ada menyebut bahawa “tak tumbuh, tak melata, tak sungguh orang tak kata”. Hal ini menjelaskan bahawa kualiti serta keunikan kraftangan Malaysia  akan menarik lebih ramai pelancong ke negara kita. Ironinya perkara ini bukan sahaja akan meningkatkan imej Malaysia sebagai negara berbilang bangsa malahan dapat meningkatkan ekonomi negara menerusi sektor pelancongan.Konklusinya,  terdapat banyak kemaslahatan Indutri Kecil dan Sederhana (IKS) kepada masyarakat dan negara kita. Sebagai rakyat Malaysia kita tidak seharusnya membiarkan peluang ini berlalu begitu sahaja. Kita perlu gigih meningkatkan kualiti IKS kerana industri ini sebenarnya merupakan sebahagian daripada barangan keluaran tempatan yang berperanan meningkatkan imej negara di mata dunia. Apabila masyarakat sama ada di dalam atau di luar negara menggunakan sahaja barangan IKS, maka secara tidak langsung jati diri negara telah terserlah.  Oleh hal yang demikian, semua pihak iaitu pihak kerajaan, swasta, masyarakat serta individu perlulah bekerjasama untuk meningkatkan industri ini. Dana yang besar telah diperuntukkan oleh kerajaan perlu digunakan sebaik-baiknya bagi tujuan memajukan IKS.  Diharapkan barangan keluaran IKS mampu bersaing dalam pasaran  di peringkat tempatan dan juga persada antarabangsa. Hal ini juga selaras dengan gagasan 1 Malaysia iaitu, Rakyat didahulukan, Pencapaian diutamakan."},{"question":"\\"Tamin'ny akora vaovao sy ny fomba fahandro manokana, nanomana ny sakafo sinoa ho an'ny sakafo hariva aho:\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha:A. Indrisy fa nodorako ilay vilany teo am-panendasana azy.B. Ny vahiny rehetra dia nidera ny tsirony miavaka amin'ny sakafo.","answer":"B. no fiafarana azo inoana indrindra ho an'ny tantara."},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianao: \\"LAOLA\\".Inona no teny marina mifanaraka amin'io teny mikorontana io?","answer":"Ny teny marina mifanaraka amin'io teny mikorontana io dia \\"LALAO\\"."},{"question":"waxaad sheegtaa abwaan hadraawi AUN magaciisa oo sedexan ?","answer":"Waa maxamed ibraahim warsame . "},{"question":"40. O que é um contrato de trabalho intermitente?","answer":"O contrato de trabalho intermitente é aquele em que o empregado presta serviços de forma não contínua, sendo convocado pelo empregador apenas quando há demanda. Nesse tipo de contrato, o empregado tem direito a receber pelas horas efetivamente trabalhadas, com registro na carteira de trabalho."},{"question":"Yakha inguqulo eyinkimbinkimbi yalesi sigwebo Okuwukuphela kokungena ngaphandle kweRawson Rd. Ihlanganiswe yiWoodville Rd, Water Supply Pipeline kanye neBarbers Rd. Le nkundla yegalofu enezimbobo ezingu18 enezifundo / imitholampilo yegalofu.","answer":"Yiqiniso, inguqulo eyinkimbinkimbi yomusho ithi \\"Kungeniswa kuphela ngaphandle kweRawson Rd. Ihlanganiswe yiWoodville Rd, Water Supply Pipeline kanye neBarbers Rd. Le nkundla yegalofu enemigodi engu18 enamakilasi / imitholampilo yegalofu nayo yayiyingxenye yeJohn Thomas Campbells Land Grant ka1000."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta: ¿Qué dramaturgo ha ganado la mayor cantidad de Premios Pulitzer?","answer":"El ganador de más premios es Eugene O'Neil. "},{"question":"पौधों में विभाजन तय करने के मानदंड जानवरों के बीच उपसमूह तय करने के मानदंड से कैसे भिन्न हैं?","answer":"पौधों में शरीर की मूल संरचना एक प्रमुख मानदंड है जिसके आधार पर थैलोफाइट्स ब्रायोफाइट्स से भिन्न होते हैं। इसके अलावा बीजों की अनुपस्थिति या उपस्थिति एक अन्य महत्वपूर्ण मानदंड है। जिम्नोस्पर्म और एंजियोस्पर्म को इस आधार पर अलग किया जाता है कि बीज ढके हुए हैं या नहीं। स्पष्ट है कि रूपात्मक लक्षण ही पौधों के वर्गीकरण का आधार बनता है।जानवरों में वर्गीकरण अधिक सूक्ष्म संरचनात्मक विविधताओं पर आधारित होता है। अतः आकृति विज्ञान के स्थान पर कोशिका विज्ञान आधार बनता है। जानवरों को कोशिकाओं की परतों, कोइलोम की उपस्थिति या अनुपस्थिति के आधार पर वर्गीकृत किया जाता है। इसके अलावा उच्चतर पदानुक्रम में जानवरों को छोटी विशेषताओं की उपस्थिति या अनुपस्थिति के आधार पर वर्गीकृत किया जाता है, जैसे चार पैरों की उपस्थिति या अनुपस्थिति।"},{"question":"பொதுவுடைமைக் கொள்கையின் முன்னோடிகளில் ஒருவர்?","answer":"ஜீவானந்தம்,பொதுவுடைமைக் கொள்கையின் முன்னோடிகளில் ஒருவர் ஆவார்."},{"question":"Responda: Qual é a capital do estado de Amazonas?","answer":"Manaus é um município brasileiro, capital do estado do Amazonas e principal centro financeiro, corporativo e mercantil da Região Norte do Brasil. É a cidade mais populosa do Amazonas, da Região Norte e de toda a Amazônia Brasileira, com mais de 2 milhões de habitantes em 2022. Localizada no centro da maior floresta tropical do mundo, Manaus é um dos maiores destinos turísticos no Brasil e também a cidade mais influente da Amazônia Ocidental, onde exerce um impacto significativo sobre o comércio, educação, finanças, indústria, mídia, pesquisas, poder militar, tecnologia e entretenimento de toda a região, recebendo a classificação de metrópole regional, por parte do Instituto Brasileiro de Geografia e Estatística (IBGE)."},{"question":"Content: Uma cooperativa de comunidades quilombolas conseguiu reunir 10 toneladas de alimentos para doar a famílias pobresTudo começou com a pandemia de covid-19. Com o isolamento social, a maior parte da produção agrícola de 16 comunidades quilombolas do Vale do Ribeira corria o risco de estragar. Antes da quarentena, mais de 95% dos alimentos eram vendidos a municípios do entorno por meio de um programa de compra de merenda para escolas públicas.Esses produtos, cultivados em pequena escala na roça, representam boa parte da renda dos quilombolas da região. As comunidades ficam em áreas isoladas e, em boa parte, são cobertas pela mata atlântica remanescente. \\"Com a quarentena, as escolas fecharam e as cidades deixaram de comprar os produtos. Eles ficam acumulados, e a gente iria perder tudo\\", explica Rosana de Almeida, diretora financeira da Cooperativa dos Agricultores Quilombolas do Vale do Ribeira (Cooperquivale).Fim do Talvez também te interesseEntão, o que fazer com toneladas de mais de 20 tipos de alimentos, como banana, arroz, feijão, inhame, cará, abóbora, batata, laranja, tomate e rapadura? Mais de 20 produtos fizeram parte da cesta de alimentos doadas a moradores da Brasilândia\\"A interrupção unilateral da compra pelas cidades gerou muita apreensão e insegurança. Além da produção que poderia se perder, as pessoas precisavam de renda para sobreviver\\", diz Maurício Biesek, agrônomo e assessor técnico do Instituto Sócioambiental (ISA), ONG que há anos atua com quilombolas da região. Foi então que surgiu a ideia de comprar os alimentos e doá-los a comunidades pobres do Estado atingidas pela covid-19. Mas retirar 14 toneladas de alimentos de áreas isoladas não é tarefa fácil nem barata. Junto ao ISA, formou-se uma espécie de consórcio de doação com outras duas entidades não-governamentais: os institutos Linha D'Água e Brasil a Gosto. Elas criaram uma campanha de arrecadação de recursos com o apoio da loja de departamento Magazine Luiza, e de organizações internacionais, como a União EuropeiaComo esse texto acima pode ser resumido?","answer":"Mais de 250 quilômetros separam duas regiões pobres de São Paulo: o Vale do Ribeira, ao sul do Estado, e a Vila Brasilândia, na zona norte da capital, uma das áreas mais atingidas pelo novo coronavírus. Mas, nas últimas semanas, uma rede de doação de alimentos conectou os dois territórios."},{"question":"Quem escreveu os contos de Sherlock Holmes?","answer":"Foi Arthur Ignatius Conan Doyle, escritor e médico escocês, mundialmente famoso por suas 60 histórias sobre o detetive Sherlock Holmes, consideradas uma grande inovação no campo da literatura criminal"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Staden har historiskt tillhört det tyska hertigdömet Braunschweig samt dess föregångare och efterföljare. Efter fristaten","answer":"Braunschweigs upplösning vid andra världskrigets slut tillföll orten det västtyska förbundslandet Niedersachsen. Orten blev då en gränsort på västra sidan om Inomtyska gränsen, vilket den förblev fram till Tysklands återförening 1990."},{"question":"ఏకదళ బీజకాండం అడ్డుకోతను వివరించండి.","answer":"ఏకదళ బీజకాండం అడ్డుకోతలో 4 భాగాలను గుర్తిస్తారు. అవి 1) బాహ్యచర్మము, 2) అధశ్చర్మము, 3) సంధాయక కణజాలము, 4) నాళికా పుంజాలు.1. బాహ్యచర్మం :ఇది వెలుపలి పొర. దీనిలో దీర్ఘచతురస్రాకార లేదా చదునైన సజీవ మృదుకణాలు దగ్గరదగ్గరగా ఒకే వరుసలో, దట్టంగా, కణాంతరావకాశాలు లేకుండా అమరి ఉంటాయి. కణాల్లో రిక్తికాయుతమైన కణద్రవ్యం ఉంటుంది. కణాల్లో హరితరేణువులుండవు. ఒకే స్పష్టమైన కేంద్రకం చిన్నదిగా ఉంటుంది. బాహ్యచర్మంలో పత్రరంధ్రాలుంటాయి. బాహ్యచర్మాన్ని కప్పుతూ, అవభాసిని పొర ఉంటుంది. బాహ్యచర్మం మీద కేశాలుండవు. బాహ్యచర్మం లోపలి కణజాలాలకు రక్షణనిస్తుంది, బాష్పోత్సేకాన్ని నిరోధిస్తుంది. నీరు ఆవిరి కాకుండా నిరోధిస్తుంది. పత్ర రంధ్రాల ద్వారా వాయువుల వినిమయంలో. తోడ్పడుతుంది.2. అథఃశ్చర్మం :బాహ్య చర్మం క్రింద 3-4 వరుసలలో దృఢకణజాలంతో ఉంటుంది. ఈ కణాలు మందంగా లిగ్నిన్పరిత కవచాలను కలిగి, దట్టంగా అమరి ఉంటాయి. ఇది కాండానికి యాంత్రిక బలాన్నిస్తుంది.3. సంధాయక కణజాలము :కాండంలో ఎక్కువ భాగము విశాలమైన, మృదువైన సజీవ కణజాలముతో ఉంటుంది. దీనిని సంధాయక కణజాలము అంటారు. పరిధీయంగా ఉన్న కణాలు చిన్నవిగాను, లోపలి కణాలు పెద్దవిగాను ఉంటాయి. పరిధీయ కణాలు హరిత రేణువులను కలిగి, ఆహార పదార్థాల సంశ్లేషణలో పాల్గొంటాయి. లోపలి కణాలు ఆహార పదార్థాలను నిల్వ చేస్తాయి.4. నాళికా పుంజాలు :సంధాయక కణజాలంలో అనేక నాళికా పుంజాలు చెల్లాచెదురుగా అమరి ఉంటాయి. దీనిని అంటాక్టోస్టీల్ అంటారు. అథఃశ్చర్మానికి దగ్గరగా ఉన్న నాళికాపుంజాలు చిన్నవిగా, దగ్గర దగ్గరగాను ఉంటాయి. కాండం మధ్యలో ఉన్న నాళికాపుంజాలు పెద్దవిగా, దూరంగాను ఉంటాయి.ప్రతీ నాళికాపుంజము అండాకారములో ఉంటుంది. ప్రతీ నాళికాపుంజం చుట్టూ దృఢకణజాల నారలు ఒక తొడుగులాగా ఏర్పడి ఉంటాయి. అందుకే ఈ నాళికా పుంజాలను తంతుయుత నాళికా పుంజాలు అంటారు.నాళికా పుంజాలు సంయుక్తం, సహపార్శ్వం, సంవృతం. ప్రతి నాళికాపుంజంలో దారువు లోపలివైపు, పోషకకణజాలం వెలుపలి వైపు ఒకే వ్యాసార్థం పైన అమరి ఉంటాయి. వీటి మధ్యన విభాజ్యకణావళి ఉండదు. దారువులో దారునాళాలు, దారుకణాలు, దారునారలు, దారు మృదుకణజాలం ఉంటాయి. దారువులో దారునాళాలు అతి తక్కువ (4) సంఖ్యలో ఉంటాయి. దారువులోని ప్రథమదారునాళాలు లోపలివైపు ‘Y’ ఆకారంలో అమరి ఉంటాయి. దారువు అంతర ప్రథమ దారుకంగా ఉంటుంది. కాండం త్వరగా పెరగడం వల్ల ప్రథమదారునాళం, దానిచుట్టూ ఉన్న కొన్ని మృదుకణాలు చితికిపోయి ఒక లయజాతకుహరం ఏర్పడుతుంది. దీనిని ప్రథమదారు అవకాశం అంటారు. దీనిలో నీరు నిలువ ఉంటుంది. పోషకకణాజాలంలో చాలనీ నాళాలు, సహకణాలు మాత్రమే ఉంటాయి. పోషక కణజాల మృదుకణజాలం ఉండదు. ఏకదళ బీజాలకాండంలో దవ్వ, దవ్వరేఖలుండవు. పరిచక్రం కూడా కనిపించదు."},{"question":"Ano ang pangunahing sangkap sa hummus?","answer":"Ang pangunahing sangkap sa pagkaing hummus ay chickpeas."},{"question":"Ipinlẹ Ọṣun ni Nura atawọn ọrẹ ti kọkọ ja Gbenga lole, ni wọn ba tun da a lọna ni Mowe","answer":"Awọn gende mẹrin yii, Nura Bashir; ẹni ogun ọdun, Awalu Aliyu; ẹni ọdun mejidinlogoji, Shuaibu Abdul Rasheed; ẹni ọdun mẹẹẹdọgbọn ati Abdullah Usman toun jẹ ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogun ti wa lẹka itọpinpin awọn ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ọṣun, ilu ti wọn ti bẹrẹ ole jija, kọwọ too tẹ wọn ni Mowe, ipinlẹ Ogun.Ọjọ kọkanlelogun, oṣu kẹrin yii, lọwọ awọn ọlọpaa ba wọn, lẹyin ti ọkunrin kan, Gbenga Ṣiyanbọla, lọọ fẹjọ sun ni teṣan Mowe, pe nigba toun n bọ lati ipinlẹ Ọṣun, toun n lọ s’Ekoo, mọto oun yọnu soju ọna lagbegbe Mowe. O ni nibi toun ti n tun un ṣe lawọn okunrin mẹrin kan ti yọ soun, ti wọn si gba foonu Samsung toun n lo lọwọ oun.Lẹyin iwadii to gba wọn to ọsẹ diẹ, awọn ọlọpaa tọpasẹ foonu Ṣiyanbọla ti wọn gba ni Mowe de ipinlẹ Ọṣun. Ọkan ninu awọn mẹrin to ja ọkunrin naa lole ni Mowe ni wọn ri foonu naa lọwọ ẹ l’Ọṣun, bi wọn si ti mu un lo ṣatọna bi ọwọ ṣe ba awọn mẹta yooku naa.Nibi iwadii awọn ọlọpaa to n tẹsiwaju ni wọn ti ri i pe awọn ole mẹrin yii ti figba kan fọ ṣọọbu Ṣiyanbọla kan naa, nibi to ti n ta foonu nipinlẹ Ọṣun, wọn ti ji awọn foonu kan lọ nibẹ nigba naa ti ẹnikẹni ko si ri wọn mu.Nigba ti ori yoo ta ko wọn ṣa, Siyanbọla ti wọn ti kọkọ fọ ṣọọbu ẹ ni wọn tun da lọna ni Mowe, ifisun tiyẹn si lọọ ṣe ni teṣan Mowe lo ṣẹṣẹ jẹ ki aṣiri ohun ti wọn ti ṣe tẹlẹ naa han sita, bo tilẹ jẹ pe o ti fẹjọ ole to fọ ṣọọbu ẹ l’Ọṣun naa sun ni teṣan A Division, Moorẹ, n’Ile-Ifẹ, tẹlẹ.Awọn foonu ti wọn ti ji ni ṣọọbu naa tẹlẹ ṣi wa lọwọ wọn pẹlu, gbogbo ẹ lawọn ọlọpaa gba lọwọ wọn bi Alukoro wọn ṣe wi.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa Ogun, Edward Ajogun, ti ni ki wọn ko awọn mẹrẹẹrin pada si ipinlẹ Ọṣun ti i ṣe orisun ole jija wọn, kawọn ọlọpaa ibẹ fawọn le kootu lọwọ."},{"question":"Burburkii dimoqraadiyada somaaliya10- XIRIIRKII RUUSHKA IYO NIDAAMKII 21 OCT.","answer":"Burburkii dimoqraadiyada somaaliya10- XIRIIRKII RUUSHKA IYO NIDAAMKII 21 OCT.Waxey sheegteen hanti wadaaga cilmiga ku dhisan iyadoo dowladihii u googo,ey hanti wadaaga aysan magacaas sheegan. Taliskii 21 oct dimoqoraadiyadii wey burburiyeen halka ay ka taagnayeen hantiwadagna waa la arkey, diinta islaamka moowqifkeey iska taageena weynu aragney. Xaalada oo halkaa taagan ayaa 1977 waxaa biloowdey dagaalki itoobiya iyo somaliya midowga sofiyet oo dowlad weyn ahna waxey si lama filaan ah ula safteen itoobiya markaas ayaa indhohoodu furmeen saraakiishii 21 oct oo ay ogaadeen iney meel cidla ah taagan yihiin, niyad jabkii ku dhacey wey soo kabsan waayeen waayo dhaqankooda siyaasadeed ma aheen mid la jaan qaadin kara doowlado waaweyn sida midowga sofiyeet iyo dowlado kale oo hore u marey waayo siyaasadu sida sy dad badanu qabaan maaha. Siyaasadu ma aha been waa wax jira oo la barto oo loo maro wado sax ah, siyaasadu ma aha dowladnimo iyo madax la noqdey oo keliya siyaasadu waxey gashaa dhaqaalaha iyo arimaha bulshada oo u baahan isku xir iyo kala ilaalin, waxaan dhihi karnaa nolosha baniaadanku waa siyaasada, marka hadii uu been adeegsado qofka ganacsiga ku jiro ama masuul dowlad ah wuxuu noqonayaa miraayad jabtey oo aan ku soo noqon sidii hore wax kastoo uu sheegana laga dhegeysan maayo lagana aaminimaayo bulshada dhexdeeda. "},{"question":"Apa itu Prolog dalam struktur teks drama?Jawaban:","answer":"Prolog mengacu pada kalimat atau pembukaan cerita, dan pengantar atau latar belakang cerita biasanya disampaikan oleh wayang atau tokoh tertentu yang berlatarkan teks drama. Arahannya adalah pengenalan dan pengaturan tindakan dan posisi, meliputi: pengenalan tokoh , pernyataan situasi dan cerita, dan dari awal, konflik yang akan diceritakan dalam cerita yang akan diceritakan dalam drama."},{"question":"வினா:பிரியாணியை இந்த உலகத்திற்கு அறிமுகம் செய்தவர்கள் யார்.?","answer":"விடை : பாரசீகர்கள் "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ਗੁਆਰੇਰੀ ॥ਸਚਾ ਅਮਰੁ ਸਚਾ ਪਾਤਿਸਾਹੁ ॥ਮਨਿ ਸਾਚੈ ਰਾਤੇ ਹਰਿ ਵੇਪਰਵਾਹੁ ॥ ਸਚੈ ਮਹਲਿ ਸਚਿ ਨਾਮਿ ਸਮਾਹੁ ॥੧॥ਸੁਣਿ ਮਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਬਦੁ ਵੀਚਾਰਿ ॥ਰਾਮ ਜਪਹੁ ਭਵਜਲੁ ਉਤਰਹੁ ਪਾਰਿ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਭਰਮੇ ਆਵੈ ਭਰਮੇ ਜਾਇ ॥ਇਹੁ ਜਗੁ ਜਨਮਿਆ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਨ ਚੇਤੈ ਆਵੈ ਜਾਇ ॥੨॥ਆਪਿ ਭੁਲਾ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਭਿ ਆਪਿ ਭੁਲਾਇਆ ॥ਇਹੁ ਜੀਉ ਵਿਡਾਣੀ ਚਾਕਰੀ ਲਾਇਆ ॥ਮਹਾ ਦੁਖੁ ਖਟੇ ਬਿਰਥਾ ਜਨਮੁ ਗਵਾਇਆ ॥੩॥ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਾਏ ॥ਏਕੋ ਨਾਮੁ ਚੇਤੇ ਵਿਚਹੁ ਭਰਮੁ ਚੁਕਾਏ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪੇ ਨਾਉ ਨਉ ਨਿਧਿ ਪਾਏ ॥੪॥੧੧॥੩੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 161 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਜਗਤ ਦਾ) ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਾਤਿਸ਼ਾਹ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਅਟੱਲ ਹੈ । ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਮਨ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰੰਗ) ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਉਸ ਵੇਪਰਵਾਹ ਹਰੀ ਦਾ ਰੂਪ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਉਸ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨਤਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧। ਮਨ ! (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ) ਸੁਣ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਸੋਚ-ਮੰਡਲ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾ ਰੱਖ । ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰੇਂਗਾ, ਤਾਂ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਹਿਂਗਾ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਪਰ ਇਹ ਜਗਤ (ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ) ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸ ਕੇ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ,ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਜੰਮਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਜਗਤ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਚੇਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਤੇ ਜੰਮਦਾ ਮਰਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨। ਇਹ ਜੀਵ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ ਜਾਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਆਪ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪਾ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ (ਇਕ ਗੱਲ ਪਰਤੱਖ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਆਪਣਾ ਅਸਲ ਹਿਤ ਭੁਲਾਈ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸ ਕੇ) ਇਹ ਜੀਵ ਬਿਗਾਨੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਹੀ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ(ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ) ਇਹ ਮਹਾਨ ਦੁੱਖ ਹੀ ਖੱਟਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਗਵਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।੩। ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ,ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ) ਕੇਵਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ, ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਾਲੀ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।। ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ-ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ (ਉਸ ਦੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ, ਮਾਨੋ, ਜਗਤ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ) ਨੌ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੧।੩੧।\\""},{"question":"புத்தரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"இந்தப் பிரபஞ்சத்தில் ஏற்படும் எண்ணற்ற மாற்றங்களுக்குப் பொறுப்பேற்கும் பரம்பொருள் என்ற ஒன்றில்லை."},{"question":"ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਮੁੰਡਾ ਪੂਲ ਦੇ ਕਿੰਗਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਲੱਗਿਆ ਰਿਹਾ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਤੈਰਨਾ ਸਿੱਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਡਰਦਾ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਲਾਈਫਗਾਰਡ ਡਿਊਟੀ 'ਤੇ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਹ ਤੈਰਨਾ ਸਿੱਖਣ ਤੋਂ ਡਰਦਾ ਸੀ।"},{"question":" கேள்வி :    சரியான விடையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து எழுதுக. புரதச்சத்தை சேமித்து உடலுக்கு வழு சேர்ப்பதும், \\"லைசோசோம்களை\\" உருவாக்குவதும் ஆன செல்லின் உறுப்பு எது  ?     அ ) மைட்டோகாட்ரியா     ஆ)  ரிபோசோம்     இ)  கோல்கை உறுப்புகள்      ஈ )  உட்கரு                              ","answer":"பதில் :  புரதச்சத்தை சேமித்து உடலுக்கு வழு சேர்ப்பதும், \\"லைசோசோம்களை\\" உருவாக்குவதும் ஆன செல்லின் உறுப்பு இ)  கோல்கை உறுப்புகள்.        கோல்கை உறுப்புகள்  என்பது லைசோசோம் மற்றும் சென்ட்ரியோல் இது ஒன்றின் மேல் ஒன்றாக அடுக்கப்பட்ட சவ்வினால் சூழப்பட்ட சுரப்பி குழல்களாலான ஓர் அமைப்பாகும்.இது நொதிகளைச் சுரக்கவும், உணவைச் செரிமானம் அடையச் செய்யவும், புரதத்தை உணவிலிருந்து பிரித்துப் பிற செல்களுக்கு அனுப்பவும் உதவுகிறது ."},{"question":"No futebol, a torcida organizada \\"Independente\\" pertence a qual clube?","answer":"\\"Independente\\" pertence ao São Paulo."},{"question":"(Uyahleka, ushaya izandla sakubabaza) He! He! He! Mina lo MaShezi,sengingumama oyinkosikazi yekhansela! Bonke abafazi bale ndawosebengibingelela sengathi babona inkosikazi yenkosi. (Aphinde ashayeizandla) Hhawu! Hamba mzabalazo!(Emamatheka) We! Nina bafazi nijatshuliswa wubala ngempela. Nifanancimishi nezingane.(Ebuka umyeni wakhe emehlweni) Ha! Ha! Ubani ongayeka ukujabulaesesimweni esifana nesami? Uthi wubala baba uqala ukuhola le maliosuyihola? Angithi ngikhuluma nje usuyakhulekelwa wena.(Ubuso bushintshe buhwaqabale) MaShezi! Lokho-ke yikhookungihluphayo. Osibhincamakhasana bayasho ukuthi inkosi yendawouShandu, akeneme futhi bathi ukubeka kucace ukuthi mina sengicabangaukuthi sengiyinkosi. Eqinisweni angazi ukuthi inkosi ikhathazwa yini ngobangakhethwa ngabantu. Angiyona inkosi, kodwa yimi olawula intuthukoyalapha endaweni yakithi.Amakhosi aphelelwe yisikhathi manje. Phela intando yeningi iphoqa ukuthiabaholi mabakhethwe ngabantu. Inkosi yakhethwa nini-ke yona? Sukalapha! Musa nje ukulokhu ucabangana nabantu abasatatazeliswangukuchithwa yisikhathi.Kuzocaca maduze nje ngoba izinhlelo zentuthuko sezizoqalakungekudala. Kufanele ngihlele imihlangano yomphakathi kodwa minangeke ngilokhu ngiyotatazelela inkosi ngicelana nelungelo lokubizaimihlangano. Angithi yona ifuna ukubikelwa, incengwe ngisho nomaumuntu ezokwenza idina lodwa leli.1. Ngokwalesi siqeshana ujatshuliswa yini uMaShezi?","answer":"Ujatshuliswa ukuthi useyinkosikazi yekhansela.√/UDuma usehola imalieningi.√/UDuma useyakhulekelwa.√ Amakhosikazi endawo asembingelelasengathi uyinkosikazi yenkosi."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Under sin presidentvalskampanj hade Eisenhower lovat att få slut på dödläget i Koreakriget. Han hotade med att använda kärnvapen och ett vapenstillestånd undertecknades i juli 1953. Han skrev också ett försvarsavtal med Sydkorea och Kina samt bildade en antikommunistisk allians, \\"SEATO,\\" för att stoppa kommunismens spridning i Asien. Eisenhower accepterade \\"doktrinen om uppdämning,\\" som innebar att USA inte skulle låta kommunismen expandera, men han ville också bekämpa den mer aktivt, genom sabotage och kupper. Ett exempel på detta är att Eisenhoweradministrationen utnyttjade det nybildade CIA för att 1953 störta den iranska premiärministern Mossadeq, som felaktigt beskylldes för att vara kommunist och sovjetvänlig. Andra exempel är kuppen i Guatemala 1954 och inblandningen i Kongokrisen","answer":"1960. I Indokina stödde USA det nybildade Sydvietnam."},{"question":"ニュートンの「運動の３法則」といえば、「慣性の法則」「運動の法則」と何でしょう？","answer":"作用反作用の法則"},{"question":"Zadzisa dimikara rinotevera:Kuchekwa nerakagomerera","answer":"kurwadziswa zvikuru"},{"question":"DISASTERChapter 3","answer":"DISASTERChapter 3Who are you? Nelson asked the callerPlease give my wife the phone. I want to talk to her, replied the caller.Nelson looked at Neme, and she turned her face to the other side immediately.Who is your wife? What's her name?Chinemerem nah, Neme, Neme, Neme... please give her the phone.Nelson ended the call and faced Neme.For how long now, Neme? He asked with a teary voice.I don't know Nelson; you're the cause of all these. You pushed me.I, Nelson, pushed you? Okay, leave my house and never return. He barked.I will leave. I am tired. Let me go and meet Alex. I love Alex, and he is the father of my unborn child. Neme cried, picking up her handbag.The father of your unborn child,I see. Leave this place right now before I summarize your life at this moment.Neme looked at him from head to toe, sighed, and walked away from him.Neme..he calledGet behind me, you Satan, she replied, walking faster.Neme got home, she sat down crying uncontrollably, she wished Alex never called, she has messed up her marriage, and she doesn't even know the real father of her unborn child.Her mom opened the door, and she came in with Alex.What are you doing here, Alex? Neme shoutedI came to check up on you. Who picked up your call today? Why was he asking me those questions? He askedWhich of the questions do you want me to answer? Alex,  please leave now.I'm going nowhere. Neme,why are you ch?You're the caller, I guess. Who are you and Neme?What's the problem, please? Mrs. Cynthia asked, shocked.I am Neme's husband. They responded at the same time.Neme held her hair,ran inside her room, and locked the door.I don't know you, young man, said Mrs. Cynthia.Me? You don't know me, Mrs. Cynthia? Alex shouted with anger written all over his face.Nelson sighed and went to meet Neme.Neme, please, we need to talk...Talk about what initially? Talk about what Nelson said: After cheating on me with Dora, Nelson, I am done, she replied from inside.I'm sorry, Neme,but who is that guy? Why is he claiming to be your husband? Are you married to him? Neme, please open the door.Nelson Just leave. I'll be going to the hospital to abort this pregnancy, Nelson. I am tired. What did I ever do to you? You just paid my bride price weeks ago, and here you are cheating on me. Why can't you wait after the wedding? You can then cheat as you like. Please leave. Besides,  you asked me to leave your house too, so leave here.You are also cheating. Neme, we can fix things, please. Forgive me, and I'll forgive you too. I can't afford to lose you. He pleaded, still knocking on the door.You can't afford to lose me. Why did you cheat on me?Dora drugged me; she did. He lied.Neme stood up, unlocked the door, and stared at him.You disgust me, Nelson. I forgive you, but... where's Alex? Has he gone?Who is Alex? The guy out there? He askedNeme didn't reply; she pushed Nelson and went to the parlor.What was the meaning of that, Neme? Why do you want to bring shame upon this family? You're always disgracing yourself; who was that? Her mom thundered.I don't know him, mom, she replied, turning to face. NelsonLet's go, please, she said, going outside.I'm sorry for what just happened. Neme is always causing confusion at times. Mrs. Cynthia said, patting him.It's mom; see you later. He answered and left.Everyone was busy preparing for Neme and Nelson's wedding. Nelson was in his room in the hotel where he lodged with his friends when Dora came in.Hi Dora. Dan greetedHi Dan, what's up with you guys? She waved, laughing.We are cool. You look pretty. Sam complimentedThank you, Nelson. We need to talk.Talk about what initially? Can't you see I'm busy? He askedNelson, this wedding is not going to hold.Nelson and his friends stared at each other; the whole room was quiet like a graveyard."},{"question":"பாரதிதாசன் தமிழுக்குச் சூட்டியுள்ள பெயர்கள் யாவை?","answer":"அமுதம், நிலவு, மணம்."},{"question":"Write a classical ghazal in Urdu Language.","answer":"Sure here is a ghazal in Urdu Language:کہیں ہوش ہے کہیں بے خودی کہیں تشنگی کہیں جام ہےمرے ساقیا یہ عجیب تر ترے میکدے کا نظام ہےکوئی رازِ دل ہے نہ رہنما کوئی مدعی نہ ہے مدعامجھے منزلوں کی خبر نہیں مرا عشق میرا امام ہےمرے شہرِ دل کی فصیل پر یہ جو روشنی کے ہیں قافیےمرے لوحِ دل پہ لکھا ہوا مرے ہم نفس ترا نام ہےجو ہو نابلد ترے ذکر سے نہ ہو آشنا تری فکر سےوہ رکوع کوئی رکوع ہے وہ قیام کوئی قیام ہےمری بے خودی بھی عجیب تر مری میکشی بھی عجیب ترمیں نظر سے پیتا ہوں شیخ جی یہ حلال ہے کہ حرام ہے مری خلوتوں میں سرور ہے مری جلوتوں کا پتہ نہیں کوئی ہر گھڑی مرے ساتھ ہے کوئی مجھ سے محو کلام ہے  مرے ہمسفر ہے جو کہکشاں میں سناؤں کس کو یہ داستاں بڑی معتبر ہے یہ رہگذر کہ نظر میں ماہ تمام ہےکبھی افضل اپنے خلوص کا کوئی دائرہ نہ سمٹ سکامیں تو روشنی کا سفیر ہوں مجھے اپنے کام سے کام ہے"},{"question":"Ẹfun abeedi, lẹyin ti baale ile kan gba ipe tan lori foonu lo bẹ sodo Ọṣun","answer":"Titi di asiko ti a n ko iroyin yii jọ ni awọn ọlọpaa pẹlu awọn oṣiṣẹ panapana ṣi n wa ọkunrin kan to bẹ sinu odo Ọṣun nirọlẹ Ọjọruu,  Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii.Nnkan bii aago mẹrin kọja ogun iṣẹju la gbọ pe iṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹlẹ lori biriiji Gbodofọn, to wa loju-ọna Gbọngan si Oṣogbo.Ipe kan lọkunrin ti ẹnikẹni ko ti i da mọ naa gba lori foonu rẹ, lẹyin eyi lo ju foonu sinu odo, ko too di pe oun funra rẹ bẹ sinu odo ọhun.Ọkada kan to ni nọmba PKA 915 VI lọkunrin naa wa de ori biriiji ko too gba ipe naa, gẹgẹ bi awọn tiṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju wọn ṣe sọ.Ọkunrin ọlọkada kan, Abidemi Adedire, ṣalaye pe ko sẹni to le fura pe ọkunrin yii le ṣe nnkan to ṣe, o ni ṣe lo n pariwo sọrọ nigba to n gba ipe naa, ṣugbọn ariwo awọn ọkọ to n kọja ko jẹ koun le feti si nnkan to n sọ.O ni ko pa ina ọkada rẹ gan-an lasiko to n gba ipe naa, bo si ṣe sọrọ tan lo ju foonu sinu odo, ki awọn eeyan si too de ọdọ rẹ, o ti bẹ sodo Ọṣun.Alakooso ajọ panapana l’Ọṣun, Ibrahim Adekunle, sọ pe oṣiṣẹ awọn kan to n kọja lọ lasiko iṣẹlẹ naa lo fi to awọn leti, kia lawọn si bẹrẹ igbesẹ lati wa a, ṣugbọn odo to kun bayii le fa idiwọ diẹ.Bakan naa ni Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, SP Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, fidi iṣẹlẹ.naa mulẹ, o ni awọn ti n gbe igbesẹ lati ṣawari ọkunrin naa."},{"question":"Maryam waxee jirtaa 10 sano, halka cabdulahi oo jiro 25.Waxaa wayn  maryam","answer":"Cabdulahi ayaa ka wayn maryam"},{"question":"केंद्र सरकारने मंजुरी दिलेल्या १६ व्या वित्त आयोगाचा कालावधी ___आहे.(A)  १ एप्रिल २०२६ ते ३१ मार्च २०३१(B)  १ मार्च २०२६ ते ३१ एप्रिल २०३१(C)  १ एप्रिल २०२५ ते ३१ मार्च २०३०(D)  १ मार्च २०२५ ते ३१ एप्रिल २०३९","answer":"(A) १ एप्रिल २०२६ ते ३१ मार्च २०३१"},{"question":"ఒక త్రిభుజంలోని కోణాలు సామాన్య భేదం 10గా గల అంకశ్రేణిలో ఉంటే ఆ కోణాలను కనుగొనుము.","answer":"మూడు కోణాలు a, a + d, a + 2d అనుకొనుము.(∵అంకశ్రేఢిలో కలవు), d = 10 మూడు కోణాల మొత్తం .a + a + d + a + 2d = 180°3a + 3d = 18003a + 30 = 180° ( d = 10)3a = 180 – 30 = 150°a = 50°∴ మూడు కోణాలు 50, 60, 70°."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 ユニセフのキャサリン・ラッセル事務局長が日本に来ました。そして、戦争などで苦しんでいる子どもたちを助けてほしいと話しました。ウクライナでは、ロシア軍が電気を送る施設などに攻撃をしています。ラッセル事務局長は「電気が足りなくて、子どもたちには厳しい冬になります。私たちは、助けなければなりません」と話しました。ラッセル事務局長は、気候が変わったことが原因で、苦しんでいる子どもたちも心配だと話しました。エチオピアでは雨が少なくて食べ物が足りなくなっています。パキスタンでは雨で川の水があふれて、たくさんの子どもたちが病気で亡くなっています。今月6日、気候が変わっていることについて話し合う国連の会議「COP27」が始まります。ラッセル事務局長は、子どもを守るために大人が行動しなければならないと言いました。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"के तपाइँ स्वास्थ्य र पोषण बारे केहि जानकारी प्रदान गर्न सक्नुहुन्छ?","answer":"प्रशस्त पानी, फलफूल र तरकारीहरू, नियमित शारीरिक गतिविधि, र स्वस्थ बानीहरूको निरन्तर दिनचर्या कायम राख्ने जस्ता अभ्यासहरू स्वास्थ्य र पोषणमा समावेश हुन्छन्।"},{"question":"நீங்கள் படித்ததில் பிடித்த குறளை எழுதி, காரணத்தைக் குறிப்பிடவும்.","answer":"“எந்நன்றி கொன்றார்க்கும் உய்வுண்டாம் உய்வில்லைசெய்ந்நன்றி கொன்ற மகற்கு.”பிடித்தற்குக் காரணம் :ஒருவனுக்கு மூன்று காலத்திலும் உதவக்கூடிய கல்வியினை செய்ந்நன்றி என்ற வினைத்தொகையால் குறிப்பிட்டு, மறந்தவனுக்கு தப்பிப்பிழைக்க வழியில்லை என்று வள்ளுவன் வார்த்த வடிவம் அதிசயத்தக்கது."},{"question":"मलाई केहि प्रकारको संगीतका प्रकारहरु बताउनुहोस्।","answer":"शास्त्रीय, रक, पप, ज्याज, हिप-हप,  आदि धेरै प्रकारका संगीतहरू छन्, प्रत्येकको आफ्नै अद्वितीय शैली र विशेषताहरू छन्।"},{"question":"அகச்சிவப்பு கதிர்வீச்சுகளைக்   கண்டுபிடித்தவர் யார்?","answer":"அகச்சிவப்பு கதிர்வீச்சுகளைக்   கண்டுபிடித்தவர் வில்லியம் ஹெர்ஷல் . அகச்சிவப்பு கதிர் என்பது அதிக அலைநீளம் கொண்ட மின்காந்த அலையாகும். அலைநீளம் அதிகம் என்பதால் இக்கதிர்கள் கண்களுக்குப் புலப்படுவதில்லை. ஒளியலைகளின் அலைநீளம் குறைவு என்பதால் ஒளி கண்களுக்குப் புலனாகிறது. அகச்சிவப்பு கதிர்கள் சில சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் அகச்சிவப்பு ஒளிக்கதிர் என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுகின்றன. வெள்ளொளியான சூரிய ஒளி ஊதா, கருநீலம், நீலம், பச்சை, மஞ்சள், ஆரஞ்சு, சிவப்பு என்ற ஏழு நிறங்களைக் கொண்டது. இவற்றில் அலைநீளம் அதிகம் கொண்ட சிவப்பு நிறப்பகுதிக்கு அப்பால் கண்ணுக்குப் புலனாகாத சில கதிர்கள் உள்ளன. இவற்றிற்கு 'அகச்சிவப்புக் கதிர்கள்' என்று பெயர். ஒளியலைகள் ஏறத்தாழ 400-700 நா.மீ அலைநீளம் கொண்டவையாகும். அகச்சிவப்புக் கதிர்கள், கண்ணுக்குப் புலனாகும் ஒளியலைகளை விடக் கூடுதலான அலை நீளம் கொண்டவை. அகச்சிவப்பு கதிர்களின் அதிர்வெண் நானூற்று முப்பது  டெராகெர்ட்சு ஆகும் . 700 நா.மீ. முதல் 100 மை.மீ  அலைநீளம் வரை கொண்ட, மின்காந்த அலைகள் கண்ணுக்குப் புலனாகாத அகச்சிவப்புக் கதிர்கள் ஆகும். சில பரிசோதனைகள் வழியாக நம்மால் அகச்சிவப்புக் கதிர்களையும் காணவியலும்.ஒரு பொருளில் உள்ள மூலக்கூறுகள் நகரும் போது அப்பொருள் அகச்சிவப்பு கதிர்களை உள்வாங்கவோ அல்லது வெளியிடவோ செய்யும். அறைவெப்பநிலைக்கு அருகில் உள்ள பெரும்பாலான பொருட்கள் வெளியிடும் வெப்பக் கதிர்வீச்சு அகச்சிவப்புக் கதிர்களேயாகும். மின்காந்த அலைகளைப் போலவே அகச்சிவப்புக் கதிர்களும் மின்காந்த ஆற்றலை சுமக்கின்றன. ஓர் அலை மற்றும் ஓர் ஒளியணு ஆகிய இரண்டின் பண்புகளையும் அகச்சிவப்புக் கதிர்கள் வெளிப்படுத்துகின்றன."},{"question":"வினா: முதிர்ந்த ஆளுமைக்குரிய மூன்று இலக்கணங்கள் யாவை?","answer":"விடை:முதிர்ந்த ஆளுமைக்குரிய மூன்று இலக்கணங்கள்:• தன் ஈடுபாடுகளை விரிவாக வளர்ப்பவனாக இருத்தல் வேண்டும்.• பிறருடைய நலத்திற்கும், இன்பத்திற்கும் பாடுபடக் கூடிய வகையில் ஆளுமையில் விரிவு பெற்றிருக்க வேண்டும்.• தன் வாழ்க்கைக்குச் சுய உரிமைமையைத் தரும் வாழ்க்கைத் தத்துவத்தைக் கடைப்பிடித்து நடத்தல் வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Cuál fue el primer equipo en el que jugó Barry Bonds en las ligas mayores?","answer":"Barry Bonds hizo su debut en las Grandes Ligas con el equipo de los Pittsburgh Pirates. Fue parte de los Pittsburgh Pirates desde 1986 hasta 1992 antes de unirse a los San Francisco Giant en 1993."},{"question":"Dado el título y el resumen de un artículo a continuación, genere un artículo breve o el comienzo de un artículo largo para acompañarlos (máximo 500 caracteres). Título: Por qué el gobierno de AMLO ha deportado a más cubanos en 5 meses que los que expulsaron de México en todo 2018.Resumen: El cubano Raudel González llegó a México en marzo pasado y dos meses después, teme que la odisea que lo llevó a cruzar siete países pueda terminar donde mismo comenzó: en un avión en La Habana.","answer":"Artículo:En los últimos meses, México ha sido testigo de un notable aumento en la deportación de ciudadanos cubanos bajo la administración del presidente Andrés Manuel López Obrador (AMLO). Este fenómeno ha sorprendido a muchos, ya que contrasta significativamente con las políticas migratorias más permisivas que se habían observado en el país en años anteriores.Raudel González es solo uno de los muchos cubanos que han emprendido una peligrosa travesía, cruzando múltiples fronteras y enfrentando innumerables desafíos con la esperanza de encontrar una nueva vida en México o más allá. Llegó a México con la ilusión de encontrar oportunidades y una mejor calidad de vida, pero sus sueños se vieron empañados por la amenaza constante de la deportación.La cuestión que surge es: ¿por qué esta repentina y drástica modificación en la política migratoria hacia los cubanos? Expertos en el tema sugieren que el gobierno de AMLO ha sido presionado por diversos factores, incluyendo acuerdos bilaterales con otros países y la creciente presión para frenar el flujo migratorio hacia Estados Unidos.En 2018, México apenas deportó a un número reducido de cubanos, sin embargo, en tan solo 5 meses de este año, las cifras han superado significativamente las del pasado. La incertidumbre de la situación ha dejado a muchos migrantes cubanos en una situación precaria y temerosos de ser repatriados a su país de origen, donde pueden enfrentar represalias o persecución política.El caso de Raudel González es un ejemplo desgarrador de las dificultades que enfrentan los migrantes cubanos en su travesía hacia una vida mejor. La incertidumbre y el miedo que sienten son palpables, y muchos se preguntan qué les depara el futuro y si alguna vez encontrarán la estabilidad que anhelan.Mientras tanto, la situación continúa siendo un tema de controversia y debate, y queda por ver cómo evolucionarán las políticas migratorias en los próximos meses. Para los cubanos como Raudel, la esperanza sigue siendo un motor poderoso, incluso en medio de la adversidad, mientras buscan una oportunidad para construir un nuevo comienzo en un lugar que les brinde seguridad y oportunidades."},{"question":"Eyi ni bi ọkọ Dangote ṣe tẹ ọmọ iya mẹta pa l’Akungba Akoko","answer":"Ọmọ iya kan naa mẹta ni wọn wa ninu awọn eeyan bii mejila to pade iku ojiji ninu ijamba ọkọ ajagbe simẹnti Dangote to waye niluu Akungba Akoko, lalẹ ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọsẹ to kọja.Inu ṣọọbu iya wọn to wa lẹgbẹẹ geeti Fasiti Adekunle Ajasin to wa niluu Akungba tawọn mẹtẹẹta wa lọkọ ajagbe ọhun ka wọn mọ, to si tẹ gbogbo wọn pa.Meji ninu awọn ọmọ to ku ọhun la gbọ pe wọn jẹ akẹkọọ to wa nipele aṣekagba ni fasiti naa ki wọn too pade iku ojiji lalẹ ọjọ naa.Iroyin iku wọn ni wọn ní iya wọn gbọ toun naa fi subu lulẹ, to si ku loju ẹsẹ.Iṣẹlẹ yii lo mu kawọn alasẹ fasiti naa kede ṣisun idanwo awọn akẹkọọ to yẹ ko bẹrẹ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii siwaju dọjọ mi-in ọjọ ire."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Vaticano?","answer":"Cidade do Vaticano."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਜੁਗਾ ਜੁਗੰਤਰਿ ਖਾਹੀ ਖਾਹਿ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 1 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"(ਸਭ ਜੀਵ) ਸਦਾ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ (ਰੱਬ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਪਦਾਰਥ) ਖਾਂਦੇ ਚਲੇ ਆ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।\\""},{"question":"Nahoana no zava-dehibe ny mandray ny tsy fahombiazana ho ampahany amin'ny fianarana?","answer":"Ny tsy fahombiazana dia ampahany voajanahary amin'ny dingana atao eo amin'ny fianarana. Ny fandraisana azy dia mampirisika ny faharetana, ny fahaiza-mampifanaraka ary ny fahavononana handray risika, izay manampy amin'ny fianarana lalindalina kokoa."},{"question":"Domanda: \\"Hai fratelli o sorelle?\\" Risposta:","answer":"\\"Sì, ho una sorella.\\""},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Nghiên cứu được thực hiện trên 39.000 người chơi, cho thấy không có bằng chứng chỉ ra thời gian chơi game ảnh hưởng đến sức khỏe tinh thần. Theo nghiên cứu, người chơi trung bình sẽ phải chơi nhiều thêm 10 giờ mỗi ngày so với bình thường để cảm nhận được bất kỳ sự khác biệt trong cơ thể. Theo nhóm nghiên cứu đến từ Viện Internet Oxford, định nghĩa về sức khỏe tinh thần của nghiên cứu này được xây dựng từ phản hồi của người được khảo sát về sự thỏa mãn với cuộc sống, các trạng thái tâm lý như hạnh phúc, buồn bã, tức giận và thất vọng. Kết quả của nghiên cứu mới có sự mâu thuẫn với báo cáo cũng được Viện Internet Oxford thực hiện vào năm 2020. Trong nghiên cứu với một nhóm người chơi nhỏ hơn nhiều, giáo sư Andrew Przybylski chia sẻ rằng người chơi game Animal Crossing mỗi ngày cảm thấy hạnh phúc hơn hẳn những người còn lại. \\"Thông thường, mọi người nghĩ nếu bạn có nhiều thời gian rảnh hơn để chơi game, bạn sẽ hạnh phúc hơn. Nhưng ngược lại, trong nghiên cứu mới nhất, chúng tôi đã tìm thấy bằng chứng khá thuyết phục rằng thời gian chơi mỗi ngày không thực sự ảnh hưởng tới cảm xúc người chơi. Nếu mọi người chơi vì họ muốn thay vì bị ép buộc, họ có xu hướng cảm thấy tốt hơn\\", Giáo sư Andrew Przybylski, chủ đề tài cả 2 nghiên cứu chia sẻ về kết quả mới nhất. Nghiên cứu","answer":"mới nhất quy tụ dữ liệu từ nhiều ông lớn trong ngành công nghiệp trò chơi điện tử như Sony, Microsoft và Nintendo. Các công ty trên đã cung cấp dữ liệu với sự đồng ý của người chơi trong 6 tuần từ nhiều tựa game bao gồm: Animal Crossing: New Horizons, Apex Legends, Eve Online, Forza Horizon 4, Gran Turismo Sport và The Crew 2. Trong suốt khoảng thời gian thực hiện nghiên cứu, chỉ có một người chơi bỏ dở giữa chừng. Các ảnh hưởng của trò chơi điện tử lên con người vẫn là một chủ đề gây tranh cãi. Ở Trung Quốc, trẻ em chỉ được phép chơi trò chơi điện tử một giờ mỗi ngày, vào thứ Sáu, thứ Bảy và Chủ nhật. Tuy vậy nhiều game thủ trên khắp thế giới nói rằng việc chơi trò chơi điện tử giúp họ cải thiện sức khỏe tinh thần và những lợi ích mà game mang lại là rất đa dạng. \\"Tôi không chắc lợi ích của trò chơi điện tử là thứ có thể đo lường được với một trạng thái 'hạnh phúc' duy nhất. Mọi thứ trong cuộc sống cũng vậy, đó là sự cân bằng. Việc dành 24 giờ một ngày để chơi không phải là điều tốt không tốt - nhưng việc dành 24 giờ một ngày để ăn uống hoặc tập thể dục cũng không phải là điều tốt\\", Mike Dailly, nhà thiết kế game nổi tiếng, từng tham gia dự án Lemmings và Grand Theft Auto chia sẻ. Nghiên cứu mới được công bố trên tạp chí Khoa học mở của Hiệp hội Hoàng gia Anh."},{"question":"Sử dụng tiêu đề và tóm tắt sau để viết một bài báo tối đa 500 chữ.Tiêu đề: Khởi công cầu 8.000 tỷ đồng bắc qua sông Hậu vào tháng 10Tóm tắt: Dự án cầu Đại Ngãi dài 15,1 km, vốn đầu tư 8.000 tỷ đồng, kết nối tỉnh Trà Vinh – Sóc Trăng được giao đủ mặt bằng để khởi công vào tháng 10.","answer":"Ngày 19/9, tại huyện Cù Lao Dung, UBND tỉnh Sóc Trăng bàn giao mặt bằng mặt bằng dự án đầu tư xây dựng cầu Đại Ngãi. Theo đó, tổng chiều dài tuyến qua địa phận hai huyện Long Phú và Cù Lao Dung khoảng 5,3 km, có 118 hộ bị ảnh hưởng với tổng chi phí bồi thường gần 96 tỷ đồng, hầu hết đã đồng ý.Hai tuần trước, tỉnh Trà Vinh bàn giao mặt bằng 290.000 m2 đất tại huyện Trà Cú và Tiểu Cần để xây dựng cầu Đại Ngãi. Đến nay Trung tâm Phát triển quỹ đất tỉnh Trà Vinh hoàn thành kiểm kê và phê duyệt đền bù cho tất cả 347 hộ dân bị ảnh hưởng dự án với giá trị trên 190 tỷ đồng.Toàn dự án cầu Đại Ngãi dài hơn 15 km, nguồn vốn từ ODA, do Ban Quản lý dự án 85 (Bộ Giao thông Vận tải) làm chủ đầu tư. Giai đoạn 1, cầu chính có bốn làn xe, rộng hơn 17,5 m, vận tốc 80 km/h. Giai đoạn 2, đường dẫn hai bên cầu sẽ được nâng lên bốn làn.Theo ông Nguyễn Thanh Hoài, Giám đốc Ban Quản lý dự án 85, sau khi được giao mặt bằng, dự án sẽ khởi công vào tháng 10, phấn đấu đưa vào sử dụng cuối năm 2025. Trước đó, công trình tính được khởi công đầu năm nay, song không thể thực hiện do vướng phần giải phóng mặt bằng.Công trình khi đưa vào sử dụng sẽ thay phà Đại Ngãi, giúp rút ngắn khoảng cách 80 km so với đi quốc lộ 1 khi đi từ Cà Mau, Sóc Trăng, Bạc Liêu về TP HCM, giảm 1,5- 2 tiếng chờ và di chuyển qua hai phà vượt sông Hậu."},{"question":"Що таке найбільший спільний дільник","answer":"Найбільше натуральне число, на яке ділиться кожне з даних чисел, називають найбільшим спільним дільником цих чисел. "},{"question":"ප්‍රථම ලාංකික පුරාවිද්‍යා කොමසාරිස්වරයා  කවුද?","answer":"ප්‍රථම ලාංකික පුරාවිද්‍යා කොමසාරිස්වරයා   මහාචාර්ය සෙනරත් පරණවිතාන වේ."},{"question":"Conas is féidir liom jeans stonewash a dhéanamh? ","answer":"Tá brón orm ach níl a fhios agam conas iad a dhéanamh, ach chonaic mé pictiúir ar an idirlíon agus is cosúil go bhféadfadh siad a bheith déanta ag baint úsáide as an meaisín seo. Ba chóir duit freagra a chuardach ar Google."},{"question":"Iza no renivohitry ny firenena Portugal?","answer":"I Lisbonne no renivohitry ny firenena Portugal. Ny tantarany : Any Eropa andrefana no ahitana azy izy izay noforonin'ny Phéniciens efa 3000 taona izay .Jeografia : Misy tany lanitra maromaro ao aminy . Andalovan'ny onilahy Tage."},{"question":"வினா: சோழனின் யானைப் படையைக் கண்ட வீரர்களின் செயல்கள் யாவை?","answer":"விடை: சோழனின் யானைப் படையைக் கண்ட வீரர்களின் செயல்கள்:                                         படைக்கூட்டத்திலிருந்து விலகி ஓடினர்.கடலில் தாவிக் குதித்துத் தப்பினர்.யானைகளின் பின்னே மறைந்து கொண்டனர்.எந்தத் திசையில் செல்வது என்று தெரியாமல் மலைக் குகை மற்றும் புதருக்குள் தப்பி ஒளிந்து கொண்டனர்."},{"question":"问题：爱情公寓在中国大陆的影响是什么？","answer":"答案：爱情公寓在中国大陆产生了深远的影响。其独特的幽默风格和亲切的角色设定使得它在年轻观众中获得了极高的人气。许多人都将其视为自己的青春记忆的一部分。此外，爱情公寓也对中国的电视剧制作产生了影响，推动了都市情感喜剧类电视剧的发展。"},{"question":"\\"Les Chiefs se préparent pour leur dernier match de pré-saison jeudi contre les Titans du Tennessee. Le coup d'envoi est fixé à 19h00. L'entraîneur-chef Andy Reid a parlé aux médias de qui jouera, combien de temps les partants obtiendront, ses réflexions sur le nouveau secondeur Reggie Ragland, une mise à jour sur Cairo Santos et plus encore.\\" D'après le passage précédent, est-il vrai que \\"Le match des Cheifs et des Titans débutera à 19h00.\\" ? \\"vrai\\", \\"faux\\", ou \\"incertain\\" ?\\"","answer":"L'assertion est vraie."},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Kagiatan sosial di ieu kota kacida aktipna jeung mangpaatna pikeun masarakat.","answer":"Terjemahan: Kegiatan sosial di kota ini sangat aktif dan bermanfaat bagi masyarakat."},{"question":"නවසීලන්තයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"නවසීලන්තයේ අගනුවර ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ වෙලින්ටන් නුවර වේ."},{"question":"ஹுமுலஸ் லுபுலஸ் தாவரத்தின் பூக்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி மதுபானங்களை காய்ச்சும் இடங்கள் யாவை? முந்தைய கேள்வியைக் கருத்தில் கொண்டு, பதிலைக் கொண்ட சூழலை எழுதுங்கள். இது 1 - 20 வாக்கியங்களாக இருக்கலாம். ","answer":"சூழல்:பாரம்பரிய ஆங்கில மதுபானம் புளித்த மால்ட் மூலமாக மட்டுமே தயாரிக்கப்பட்டது. மதுபானம் தயாரிக்க ஹோப்ஸ் சேர்க்கும் நடைமுறை 15 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் நெதர்லாந்தில் இருந்து அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. 17 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் பிற்பகுதியில் சுயாதீன மதுபானம் தயாரிக்கும் நிறுவனங்கள் தோன்றத் தொடங்கின. நூற்றாண்டின் இறுதியில் கிட்டத்தட்ட எல்லா பீர் வியாபார மதுபானம் தயாரிக்கும் நிறுவனங்களால் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":"Ao amin'ny efitrano fianarana dia misy mpianatra mianatra matematika, siansa ary literatiora. Ny mpianatra rehetra nianatra matematika dia nahatratra naoty ambony noho ny salan'isa, ny mpianatra rehetra nianatra siansa dia nahatratra naoty ambony noho ny salan'isa, ary ny mpianatra rehetra nianatra literatiora dia nahatratra naoty ambony noho ny salan'isa.Inona no azontsika tsoahina avy amin’ireo fanambarana etsy ambony ireo?A. Mianatra matematika ny mpianatra rehetra nahazo isa ambony salan'isa.B. Ny mpianatra mianatra literatiora no mpianatra tsara indrindra.D. Ny mpianatra sasany nianatra siansa dia nahazo naoty ambany.E. Ny mpianatra mianatra siansa no mpianatra tsara indrindra.","answer":"Ny valiny marina dia A. Ny mpianatra rehetra nahazo isa ambony noho ny salan'isa dia mianatra matematika."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الحطمة؟","answer":"الإجابة: النار."},{"question":"කැවුම් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කැවුම් යනු වටිනා හෙළ මවුලකි. සියවස් (හෝ සහස්‍ර) ගණනක අතීතයක් ඇති මෙහි නාමයේ මුල සෙවීමේ දී, 'කන දේ කැවුම්' බව පෙනේ. අතීතයේ දී රාජ්‍ය වටිනාකමක් කැවුමට තිබී ඇති අතර වත්මනේ දී කැවුමේ වැදගත් කම වැඩි වන්නේ සිංහල අලුත් අවුරුද්දේ දීය. පෙර කල කැවුම් වර්ග 18ක් තිබී ඇත. මේ ගැන සද්ධර්ම රත්නාවලියේ ලියවී තිබේ. රජ කාලයේ දී අලුත් අවුරුද්දට රජු බැහැ දැකීමට එන උසස් රාජ්‍ය නිලධාරියෝ ගෙනෙන තෑගිබෝග අතර කැවුමට මුල් තැනක් වූ අතර යුධ පිටියේ දී කැවුම ඖෂධයක් විය. සොල්දාදුවන්ගේ කෑමට තැනින් තැනට පහසුවෙන් කැවුම් ගෙන යා හැකි වූ අතර තුවාල නරක් වීම වැලැක්වීය."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو اللاعب الذي  لعبمع تشيلسي، ثم في الدوري التركي، وتوج بلقب أفضل لاعب في أفريقيا أربع مرات وفاز بكأس أمم ألإريقيا مرتين؟","answer":"الإجابة: صامويل إيتو"},{"question":"Inona no biby haingam-pandeha indrindra eran-tany?","answer":"Ny gepara no biby haingam-pandeha indrindra eran-tany."},{"question":"ස්තුති දීම(Thanksgiving) ජාතික නිවාඩු දිනයක් වන්නේ කුමන රටවලද?","answer":"ස්තුති දීම එක්සත් ජනපදය, කැනඩාව, ග්‍රෙනාඩා, ශාන්ත ලුසියා, ලයිබීරියාව සහ නිල නොවන ලෙස බ්‍රසීලය සහ පිලිපීනය වැනි රටවල සමරනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਚੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਇਕ ਪਾਸੇ ਵਿਹੜੇ ਵਿਚ ਕਿਉਂ ਬਣਾਏ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਸਨ ?","answer":"ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਧੂੰਏਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਾਲਣ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਕਮਰਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਰਸੋਈ ਦਾ ਚੁੱਲ੍ਹਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਚੁੱਲਾ ਇਕ ਪਾਸੇ ਵਿਹੜੇ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ ।"},{"question":"Write a short story about a mysterious old house on the outskirts of the village.","answer":"गाँव की सीमा पर स्थित एक रहस्यमय पुराने घर की एक छोटी कहानी।"},{"question":" در تقاطع هم عرض اگر دو وسیله نقلیه ای که روبروی یکدیگر در حرکتند بخواهند وارد خیابان مجاور شوند حق تقدم با کدام است؟ ","answer":"در تقاطع هم عرض اگر دو وسیله نقلیه ای که روبروی یکدیگر در حرکتند بخواهند با هم وارد خیابان مجاور واحدی شوند، حق تقدم عبور با وسیله ای است که به سمت راست گردش می کند."},{"question":"هل بارق هي عاصمة السعودية؟","answer":"لا، عاصمة المملكة العربية السعودية هي الرياض."},{"question":"Em que estado australiano fica situada a cidade de Sydney?a) Nova Gales do Sulb) Victoriac) Tasmâniad) Queenslande) Norfolk","answer":"Alternativa a: Nova Gales do Sul.Sydney é a capital do estado australiano de Nova Gales do Sul, sendo a cidade mais populosa da Austrália com cerca de 5 milhões de habitantes."},{"question":"සය වැදෑරුම් ගුණ ඇත්තේ","answer":"සය වැදෑරුම් ගුණ ඇත්තේ ධර්ම රත්නයටයි."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'dekat tak tercapai, jauh tak berantara'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu yang diinginkan tetapi tidak berdaya untuk mendapatkannya"},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Pekerjaan yang mempunyai topi yang paling tinggi?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah chef."},{"question":"வினா காகிதப் பணத்தைப் பயன்படுத்திய முதல் நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை:சீனா"},{"question":"Rabat no renivohitr'i Maraoka. Marina sa diso?","answer":"Marina. Rabat no renivohitr'i Maraoka."},{"question":"කෙටි කොටස් විකිණීම ඉහළ අවදානම් ආයෝජන තාක්ෂණයක් වන්නේ ඇයි?","answer":"කෙටි විකුණුම් කොටස් යනු ඉහළ අවදානම් තාක්‍ෂණයකි, මන්ද ඔබ තොගයක් වටිනාකමින් පහත වැටෙනු ඇතැයි ඔට්ටු අල්ලන අතර අවාසි අවදානම අත්‍යවශ්‍යයෙන්ම අසීමිත වේ. ඔබ \\"දිගු\\" තොගයක් මිල දී ගත් විට, කොටස් වලට \\"පමණක්\\" යා හැකි බව ඔබ දන්නවා (0) එබැවින් ඔබේ අවදානම ඔබ ආයෝජනය කළ දෙයයි, ඔබ \\"කෙටි\\" කොටස් විකුණන විට කොටස් වලට සීමාවක් නැත, එය ඉහළ යා හැකිය එබැවින් ඔබට කොපමණ මුදලක් අහිමි විය හැකිද?"},{"question":"Papara 6 ay boyunca kullanılmayan hesaplar ne olur?","answer":"01.11.2023 itibarıyla, 6 ay boyunca kullanılmayan Papara hesaplarından ücret tahsil edilecektir."},{"question":"සංඛ්‍යාතය (f) මනිනු ලබන ඒකකය/ඒකක සඳහන් කරන්න.","answer":"සංඛ්‍යාතය යනු තත්පරයකට වට හෝ දෝලන ගණනයි. සංඛ්‍යාතය (f) මනිනු ලබන ඒකක හර්ට්ස්(Hz) /තත්පරයට(s-1) වේ"},{"question":"Zer da immunologia?","answer":"Immunologia biologia eta medikuntzaren adar bat da, organismo baten immunitate-sistemaren funtzionamendua aztertzen duena. Immunologiak infekzioen kontra babesten duten mekanismoak, autoinmunitatea, alergiak eta transplanteak ikertzen ditu."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Qatar?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Qatar mu ngi tudu Doha."},{"question":"أخبرنى عن الجبن الأبيض من فضلك.","answer":"من دواعى سرورى.يوجد العديد من أنواع الجبن الأبيض المختلفة، ولكن أشهرها الجبن القريش والجبن الريكوتا والجبن الموزاريلا. يُصنع الجبن الأبيض من حليب الأبقار أو الماعز أو الأغنام، ويُعالج بإضافة إنزيم الرنين، الذي يتسبب في تجلط الحليب. يُصنع الجبن الأبيض عادةً من حليب منخفض الدسم، ولذلك يكون قوامه خفيفًا وذو مذاق رقيق. يُستخدم الجبن الأبيض في العديد من الأطباق المختلفة، بما في ذلك السلطات والسندويشات والبيتزا. كما أنه يستخدم في صنع الحلويات، مثل تشيز كيك وكعك الجبن.الجبن الأبيض هو مصدر جيد للبروتين والكالسيوم والفوسفور. كما أنه يحتوي على كمية قليلة من الدهون والسعرات الحرارية."},{"question":"Cuba jawab teka-teki ini: Bila kecil pakai, bila besar tak mahu pakai .","answer":"Jawapannya ialah pampers. "},{"question":"Inona no zava-dehibe ara-tantaran’ny Fanjakana Merina?","answer":"Ny Fanjakana Merina, notarihin’ny Mpanjakavavy Ranavalona I sy ny Mpanjaka Radama I, no nahavita nampiray ny ankamaroan’i Madagasikara tamin’ny taonjato faha-19."},{"question":"அம்பேத்கரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"\\"கல்வியுடன் இருங்கள், கிளர்ச்சியுடன் இருங்கள், ஒழுங்காக இருங்கள், நம்பிக்கையுடன் இருங்கள், ஒருபோதும் கைவிடாதீர்கள், இவையே நம் வாழ்வின் ஐந்து கோட்பாடுகள்\\""},{"question":"س114 - ما إسم النبي الذي صام ثلاثة أيام حتى رزقه اللهولدا ؟","answer":"ج114 - سيدنا زكريا"},{"question":"Sheeg Maalintii, bishii iyo sanadkii la aasaasay Xisbigii Hantiwadaagga Kacaanka           Soomaaliyeed","answer":" Waxaa la aasaasay 1dii July 1976kii"},{"question":"“కీర్తిని సంపాదించడమే గొప్పదని” చెప్పిన బలిచక్రవర్తి మాటలను మీరు ఏ విధంగా సమర్థిస్తారు ?","answer":"కీర్తిని సంపాదించమే గొప్పదని బలిచక్రవర్తి చెప్పిన మాట ఉత్తమమైనది. అది అందరికీ శిరోధార్య మైనది.1 .సిరిసంపదలూ, రాజ్యమూ శాశ్వతమైనవి కావు.2. సత్యవంతుడని పేరు పొందిన హరిశ్చంద్ర మహారాజు వంటి వారికి లభించిన కీర్తి, శాశ్వత మైనది.3. దేశం కోసం తమ సర్వస్వాన్నీ అర్పించి, త్యాగం చేసిన గాంధీజీ, నెహ్రూజీ, పటేలు, సుభాష్ చంద్రబోస్ వంటి వారి త్యాగాన్నీ, దేశసేవనూ నేటికీ లోకులు కీర్తిస్తున్నారు.4. అక్రమ సంపాదనలతో లోకకంటకులైన వారిని లోకం నేటికీ నిందిస్తోంది. కాబట్టి కీర్తి సంపాదన ముఖ్యమన్న బలిచక్రవర్తి మాటను నేను సమర్థిస్తాను."},{"question":"A cidade do Rio de Janeiro pertence a qual estado?","answer":"A cidade do Rio de Janeiro pertence ao estado de mesmo nome. É também a capital do estado, sendo uma grande cidade brasileira à beira-mar, famosa pelas praias de Copacabana e Ipanema, pela estátua de 38 metros de altura do Cristo Redentor, no topo do Corcovado, e pelo Pão de Açúcar, um pico de granito com teleféricos até seu cume. A cidade também é conhecida pelas grandes favelas. O empolgante Carnaval, com carros alegóricos, fantasias extravagantes e sambistas, é considerado o maior do mundo."},{"question":"දීර්ඝතම ගර්භනි කාලයක් සහිත කිරිබී වැඩෙන සත්වයා  කවුද ?","answer":"දීර්ඝතම ගර්භනී කාලය ඇති සත්වයා  අලියා වේ. අලියෙකුගේ ගර්භණී කාලය මාස 22 ක් පමණ පැවතිය හැකිය, එය ඕනෑම ගොඩබිම සතෙකුගේ දීර්ඝතම ගැබ් කාලයවේ. මෙම දීර්ඝ ගැබ් ගැනීම අලියාගේ විශාලත්වය හා  සංකීර්ණ වර්ධනය නිසාය. මෙම කාලය තුළ, කලලරූපය ගර්භාෂයෙන් පිටත ජීවිතය සඳහා  සූදානම් වීම සඳහා  සම්පූර්ණයෙන්ම වර්ධනය වන අතර, එහි සුවිශේෂී කඳ, විශාල මොළය සහ අනෙකුත් වැදගත් අවයවවල වර්ධනය ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"வினா: கட்டிடங்களுக்கு வெள்ளையடிப்பதற்குப் பயன்படுவது \\t1. சோடியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு2. கால்சியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு3. மெக்னீசியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு4. அம்மோனியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு","answer":"பதில்: 2. கால்சியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                கால்சியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு என்பது வேதியலில் காணப்படும் ஒரு சேர்மம் ஆகும். கல்சியம் ஐதராக்சைடு சேர்மம் ஒரு நிறமற்ற படிகம் அல்லது பாலின் நிற பொடியாக காணப்படும். கல்சியம் ஆக்சைட்டுடன் (சுண்ணாம்பு) நீர் சேரும் பொழுது கல்சியம் ஐதராக்சைடு உருவாகிறது. இது உணவு தயாரித்தல் உள்ளிட்ட பல தேவைகளுக்காக பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. கல்சியம் ஐதராக்சைடின் நிறைவுற்ற தீர்வு சுண்ணாம்பு நீர் எனப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"问题：动物中最大的陆地哺乳动物是什么","answer":"答案：非洲象"},{"question":"Kush e fitoi Kampionatin Evropian në vitin 1968?","answer":"Në vitin 1968 Kampionatin Evropian e fitoi Italia."},{"question":"Znajdź rym do słowa \\"krowa\\".","answer":"Oto kilka słów, które rymują się z \\"krowa\\":abszytowa, sowa, supernowa, borowa"},{"question":"Stephanie Okereke Linus","answer":"Stephanie Linus Onyekachi Okereke ( tí wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ kejì, oṣù Ọ̀wàrà, ọdún 1982) jẹ́ òṣèré, olùdarí eré àti afẹwàṣiṣẹ́. Ó ti gba ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ àti àwọn yíyàn fún iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ bí òṣèré, tó fi mọ́ àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti Reel ti ọdún 2003 fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ, àmì-ẹ̀yẹ Afro Hollywood ti ọdún 2006 fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ, àti àwọn yíyàn mẹ́ta míràn fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ ní ipa asíwájú níbi ayẹyẹ Africa Movie Academy Awards ní ọdún 2005, 2009 ati 2010. Ó tún jẹ́ olùdíje níbi ìdíje ẹwà ti Nàìjíríà ní ọdún 2002. Ní ọdún 2011, ìjọba orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà da lọ́lá pẹ̀lú fífun ní oyè Memeber of the Order of the Federal Republic (MFR).Stephanie Okereke ni a bí ní Ngor Okpala, ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ímò . Òun ni ọmọ ẹ̀kẹfà ti ọmọ mẹ́jọ àwọn òbí rẹ̀. Ó parí ilé-ìwé alákọ̀ọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ àti girama ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Dẹ́ltà. Ó kẹ́ẹ̀kọ́ gíga ní Yunifásitì ìlú Calabar, ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Cross River, níbi tí ó ti gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ̀ èdè gẹ̀ẹ́sì.Ní àkókò ìgbà tí ó sì wà ní ọ̀dọ́ ní ọdún 1997, ó hàn nínu àwọn fíìmù Nollywood méjì kan; Compromise 2 àti Waterloo. Níbi ìdíje ẹwà Nàìjíríà ti ọdún 2002 tí ó ti kópa, Okereke ṣe ipò kejì. Ní ọdún 2003, Okereke gba àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ méjì, nínu mẹ́jọ tí wọ́n yàán fún, níbi ayẹyẹ Reel Awards ti ọdún 2003 fún òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ. Lẹ́hìn ìparí ẹ̀kọ́ láti Ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga New York Film Academy ní ọdún 2007, Okereke ṣe àgbéjáde fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Through the Glass èyítì ó ṣe pé òun ni ó ṣètò kíkọ àti dídarí eré náà, tí ó sì tún kópa nínu rẹ̀. Fíìmù náà rí yíyàn Africa Movie Academy fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ní ọdún 2009. Ní ọdún 2014, ó ṣe àgbéjáde fíìmù míràn tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Dry. Òun yìí kan náà lótún ṣètò kíkọ àti dídarí, bẹ́ẹ̀ ló sì tún kópa nínu eré náà, èyí tí ó gba ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ tó fi mọ́ ti Africa Movie Awards ẹlẹ́kejìlá àti ti Africa Magic Viewers Choice Awards ti ọdún 2016 fún fíìmù tí ó dára jùlọ pẹ̀lú ẹ̀bùn ọkọ̀ ayọ́kẹ́lẹ́ tuntun kan. Okereke ti kópa nínu fíìmù tó lé ní àádọ́rùn-ún."},{"question":"ብሪታንያ የፈጠረችው የሮዴዢና ኒያሳላንድ ፌዴሬሽን መቼ ተበተነ?","answer":"በ1956 ዓ.ም."},{"question":"ब्रेन ड्रेनको अवधारणा के हो र यो नेपालसँग कसरी सम्बन्धित छ?","answer":"ब्रेन ड्रेन भन्नाले आफ्नो देशबाट उच्च दक्ष व्यक्तिहरूको बसाइलाई जनाउँछ। नेपालको सन्दर्भमा, डाक्टर, इन्जिनियर र शिक्षाविद्हरू लगायतका प्रतिभाशाली पेशाकर्मीहरू राम्रो अवसरको लागि विदेश पलायन हुने घटना हो, जुन प्रायः सीपको खाडललाई पछाडि छोड्छ।"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Política. ","answer":"¿Ronald Reagan fue presidente durante más tiempo que George H. W. Bush?: La respuesta correcta es: Si. "},{"question":"Zer da genetika mendelista?","answer":"Genetika mendelista Gregor Mendelen lanetan oinarritutako genetikaren teoria bat da, non gene batzuk seme-alaben belaunaldietan nola transmititzen diren azaltzen duena. Mendelen legea bi (bereizgarritasunaren legea eta independentziaren legea) genetikako oinarri bihurtu zen."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Mahay roa hoatra ny lelan'omby, _\\"","answer":"\\"ka sandy any ambava no any ambody\\""},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి పర్యాయ పదాలని ఇవ్వండి: అడుగు","answer":"పాదం, చరణం"},{"question":"Wanne ne Ɓoyayye Wakilin Suna?","answer":"Ɓoyayye: Shi ne wakilin sunan da baya fito da wanda ake magana a kansa fili. Wato idan aka ambata shi, kowa ma yana iya shiga ciki. Waɗannan su ne wane, wance, su wane, su wance. Akan yi amfani da wannan waikilin suna a irin maganganu da suka shafi habaici, baƙar magana, harbin iska, tsegumi, da makamantansu. Misali, idan ana son yin tsegumin wani a cikin mutane, ana iya cewa, ai jiya na ga wane a gefen hanya yana sayen gyaɗa. Ko kuma a cikin habaici a ce, wane, na ga kana wani shisshige min, to ina mai tabbatar maka da cewa hawaniyarka ta kiyayi ramata. Da  sauransu."},{"question":"හිරු උදාවන්නේ කුමන දිසාවෙන්ද?","answer":"නැගෙනහිර දිසාවෙන්."},{"question":"ਔਰਤ ਨੇ ਲਾਈਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਗੁਆ ਦਿੱਤੀ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਲਾਈਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਰ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਲੋਕ ਦਾਖ਼ਲ ਹੋ ਗਏ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਲਾਈਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਹ ਲਾਈਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਹੋ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"من هو الصحابي الذي قام بقتل أمية بن خلف؟\\t","answer":"هو بلال بن رباح."},{"question":"દાસી જીવણ ની \\"મનવો હુઓ રે બૈરાગી\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"મૈયા મારો મનવો હુઓ રે બૈરાગી,મારી લય તો ભજનમાં લાગી રે.સંસાર ને સાર સર્વે વિસરીયો,બેઠો રે સંસારીયો ત્યાગી રે.મનવો હુઓ રે બૈરાગી..કામને કાજનું એ કાઢવા રે લાગે,મનડાની મમતા જાગી રે.મનવો હુઓ રે બૈરાગી..મંત્ર સજીવન શ્રવણે સાંભળીયો રે,મુરલી મધુરી ધૂન લાગી રે.મનવો હુઓ રે બૈરાગી..રાજ મોરાર ને રવિ ગુરૂ મળીયા,ભક્તિ ચરણની માગી રે.મનવો હુઓ રે બૈરાગી.."},{"question":"Quels sont les avantages et les inconvénients de l'énergie solaire comme source d'énergie renouvelable ?\\"","answer":"L'énergie solaire présente de nombreux avantages, tels que l'abondance de la ressource, son caractère renouvelable, et son impact environnemental réduit. Cependant, elle est intermittente, dépendante des conditions météorologiques et nécessite des infrastructures coûteuses pour la conversion et le stockage de l'énergie."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _ \\"Arivo teny , zato kabary, fa iray ny _\\"","answer":"\\"Arivo teny , zato kabary, fa iray ny marina\\""},{"question":"ભૂસ્તર ભ્રમણકક્ષા શું છે?","answer":"ભૌગોલિક ભ્રમણકક્ષા, જેને ભૌગોલિક વિષુવવૃત્તીય ભ્રમણકક્ષા (જીઇઓ) તરીકે પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે, તે પૃથ્વીના વિષુવવૃત્ત ઉપરની itude ંચાઇમાં 35,786 કિમી (22,236 માઇલ) એક ગોળાકાર ભૌગોલિક ભ્રમણકક્ષા છે, 42,164 કિમી (26,199 મી)પૃથ્વીનું પરિભ્રમણ.આવી ભ્રમણકક્ષાના પદાર્થમાં પૃથ્વીના રોટેશનલ અવધિની સમાન ભ્રમણકક્ષાની અવધિ હોય છે, એક બાજુનો દિવસ હોય છે, અને તેથી જમીનના નિરીક્ષકોને તે આકાશમાં નિશ્ચિત સ્થિતિમાં, ગતિહીન દેખાય છે.1940 ના દાયકામાં ટેલિકમ્યુનિકેશન્સમાં ક્રાંતિ લાવવાની રીત તરીકે વિજ્ .ાન સાહિત્ય લેખક આર્થર સી ક્લાર્ક દ્વારા ભૂસ્તર ભ્રમણકક્ષાના ખ્યાલને લોકપ્રિય બનાવવામાં આવી હતી, અને આ પ્રકારની ભ્રમણકક્ષામાં મૂકવામાં આવેલ પ્રથમ ઉપગ્રહ 1963 માં શરૂ કરવામાં આવ્યો હતો.સંદેશાવ્યવહાર ઉપગ્રહોને ઘણીવાર ભૂસ્તર ભ્રમણકક્ષામાં મૂકવામાં આવે છે જેથી પૃથ્વી આધારિત સેટેલાઇટ એન્ટેનાએ તેમને ટ્ર track ક કરવા માટે ફેરવવાની જરૂર નથી, પરંતુ ઉપગ્રહો સ્થિત છે તે આકાશમાંની સ્થિતિ પર કાયમી ધોરણે નિર્દેશ કરી શકાય છે.રીઅલ-ટાઇમ મોનિટરિંગ અને ડેટા કલેક્શન, અને જાણીતા કેલિબ્રેશન પોઇન્ટ પ્રદાન કરવા અને જીપીએસ ચોકસાઈ વધારવા માટે નેવિગેશન ઉપગ્રહો માટે હવામાન ઉપગ્રહો પણ આ ભ્રમણકક્ષામાં મૂકવામાં આવે છે.ભૌગોલિક ઉપગ્રહોને અસ્થાયી ભ્રમણકક્ષા દ્વારા શરૂ કરવામાં આવે છે, અને પૃથ્વીની સપાટી પરના ચોક્કસ બિંદુની ઉપરના સ્લોટમાં મૂકવામાં આવે છે.ભ્રમણકક્ષાને તેની સ્થિતિ રાખવા માટે કેટલાક સ્ટેશનકીંગની જરૂર પડે છે, અને ટકરાતા ટાળવા માટે આધુનિક નિવૃત્ત ઉપગ્રહોને ઉચ્ચ કબ્રસ્તાનની ભ્રમણકક્ષામાં મૂકવામાં આવે છે.\\""},{"question":"Манас эпосундагы Алмамбеттин арманы кайсы?","answer":" Алмамбеттин арманы. \\"Манас\\" эпосундагы трагедиялуу тагдырлардын бири - Алмамбет. Көпчүлүк варианттарда ага атайын чоң орун берилет. \\"Чоң казатка\\" чыкканда Бээжинге чалгын чалуу үчүн Манас кыраакы жоокер, тилди да, жердин ыгын да жакшы билген Алмамбетти тандайт. Ал \\"Ажал жетсе окко учуп, намыс үчүн өлөйүн\\" деп Сыргакты ээрчитип чалгынга жөнөйт. Алардын артынан жете келген Чубак чатак чыгарат, өзүн Алмамбеттен төмөн койгонго намыс көрөт. Ушундан кийин Алмамбет жанындагы Манас, Чубак, Сыргакка өз балалыгын, тагдырын арман кылып айтып берет. Бул эпизод - манасчылар сүйүп айткан бөлүмдөрдүн бири гана эмес, угуучулар көзүнө жаш алып тыңшаган, кайра-кайра айттырып уккан эпизоддордун бири."},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Trên sân nhà, câu lạc bộ Thanh Hoá giành chiến thắng sát nút 1-0 trước Viettel tại vòng 10 Night Wolf V.League 2022. Bàn thắng của đội bóng xứ Thanh đến từ pha đốt lưới nhà của trung vệ Cao Trần Hoàng Hùng ở những phút cuối hiệp 1. Dù vậy, không thể phủ nhận nỗ lực và màn trình diễn khá tốt của Thanh Hoá trong trận đấu này. Các trụ cột như Quốc Phương, Thành Long, Pinto hay Đàm Tiến Dũng,... thi đấu đúng phong độ để mang niềm vui về cho người hâm mộ quê nhà. Chiến thắng quan trọng này cũng giúp câu lạc bộ Thanh Hoá tạm thời \\"thoát hiểm\\" khỏi nhóm cuối bảng. Đoàn quân của huấn luyện viên Petrovic vươn lên vị trí thứ 8 với 11 điểm sau 10 lượt trận. Trước thành quả rất đáng khích lệ, bầu Đoan quyết định thưởng \\"vượt khung\\" 1,1 tỉ đồng cho câu lạc bộ Thanh Hoá. Đây là động lực rất lớn tiếp thêm sức mạnh để đội bóng xứ Thanh tiếp tục phát huy tinh thần quyết tâm và sự nỗ lực trong các lượt trận khó khăn sắp tới. Chia sẻ sau trận đấu, huấn luyện viên Petrovic cho biết: \\"Đây là trận đầu tiên mà tôi hài lòng nhất về mọi mặt dù có 8 cầu thủ chấn thương. Chúng tôi gặp nhiều","answer":"khó khăn nhưng các cầu thủ đã thi đấu rất quả cảm. Tôi rất hài lòng với màn trình diễn của họ. Nếu dứt điểm tốt hơn thì Thanh Hoá đã có thêm bàn thắng. Hôm nay cầu thủ trẻ Đoàn Ngọc Hà được vào sân và đây là bước chuẩn bị cho tương lai\\". Chiến lược gia người Serbia nói thêm: \\"Quốc Phương là cầu thủ quan trọng trong chiến thuật của đội, cậu ấy chơi rất xuất sắc trong 3 trận gần đây. Câu lạc bộ Thanh Hóa cần bổ sung lực lượng cho những vòng đấu tới và giai đoạn 2, nhất là tiền đạo để cải thiện khâu dứt điểm. Đội có nhiều cầu thủ chấn thương và lại mỏng đội hình nên cần bổ sung thêm nhân sự\\". "},{"question":"کەلەرم وشەیەکی کوردیە؟ ","answer":"ڕاستە "},{"question":"英語では「ブローガン（Ｂｌｏｗ Gun）」という、細長い筒に矢を入れ、息を吹き込んで的に当てる遊びを日本語で何というでしょう？","answer":"吹き矢"},{"question":"පංච ඉන්ද්‍රීයන්  යන්නට තනි වචනයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"පසිඳුරන් "},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικό γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Στην εποχή του Κοστσιούσκο, το πολωνικό κράτος είχε διμαλιστεί δύο φορές από τους γείτονές του: τη Ρωσία, τη Μοναρχία των Αψβούργων και το Βασίλειο της Πρωσίας στις αρχές του 1793. Το 1794, ο Κοστσιούσκο ξεκίνησε μια εξέγερση στην Κεντρική Πλατεία της Κρακοβίας, η οποία, παρά τη νικηφόρα Μάχη του Ρατσουαβίτσε εναντίον του αριθμητικά ανώτερου Ρωσικού Στρατού, οδήγησε σε έναν τραγικό τρίτο και τελευταίο διαμελισμό της Πολωνίας. Η Κρακοβία έγινε μέρος της αυστριακής επαρχίας της Γαλικίας για πάνω από έναν αιώνα. Πριν ηγηθεί της εξέγερσης του 1794, ο Κοστσιούσκο είχε πολεμήσει στον Αμερικανικό Επαναστατικό Πόλεμο ως συνταγματάρχης στον Ηπειρωτικό Στρατό. Το 1783, σε αναγνώριση της θητείας του, προήχθει τιμητικά από το Ηπειρωτικό Συνέδριο στο βαθμό του ταξίαρχου και του δόθηκε η ιθαγένεια των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών. Ο Κοστσιούσκο πέθανε στην Ελβετία στις 15 Οκτωβρίου 1817. Το σώμα του θάφτηκε για πρώτη φορά σε κρύπτη μιας εκκλησίας Ιησουιτών στο Σόλοτουρν, από όπου μεταφέρθηκε ένα χρόνο αργότερα στην Κρύπτη του Αγίου Λεονάρδου στον Καθεδρικό Ναό της Κρακοβίας, δίπλα στο σημείο όπου βρίσκεται το μνημείο του.","answer":"εξέγερση"},{"question":"Cầu thủ nào sau đây không có tên ở Đội hình trong mơ của Ronaldo Nazario?","answer":"Cristiano Ronaldo là cầu thủ không được nêu tên trong Đội hình trong mơ của Ronaldo Nazario. Trong phỏng vấn với Globo tháng 2/2023, Ronaldo Nazario chọn 11 cầu thủ hay nhất mọi thời, gồm: Gianluigi Buffon; Cafu, Franz Beckenbauer, Paolo Maldini, Roberto Carlos; Zico, Diego Maradona; Lionel Messi, Ronaldo Nazario, Pele và Ronaldinho Gaucho. Trong đội hình này, có sáu cầu thủ Brazil, hai người Argentina, hai người Italy và một người Đức."},{"question":"Quais são as atividades de um \\"Designer Gráfico?\\"","answer":"Um \\"Designer Gráfico\\" cria elementos visuais, como logotipos e materiais de marketing, com o objetivo de transmitir mensagens visualmente."},{"question":"Menene yawan jama'ar Gaziantep a cikin 2014?","answer":"Miliyan 1.844."},{"question":"Sheeg Yaa Lagu Soo Dejiyey Kutubka Sabuur?","answer":"Waxaa Lagu Soo Dejiyey Nebi Daa’uud CS"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: Η \\"de facto\\" ανεξαρτησία του Βελγίου είχε καθιερωθεί μέσα από εννέα έτη αδιάκοπης πάλης, την","answer":"Βελγική Επανάσταση. Οι υπογράφοντες της συνθήκης (το Ηνωμένο Βασίλειο, Αυστρία, Γαλλία, Πρωσία, Ρωσία, και οι Κάτω Χώρες) τώρα επίσημα αναγνώριζαν το ανεξάρτητο Βασίλειο του Βελγίου, και (χάρη στην επιμονή του Ηνωμένου Βασιλείου) συμφωνούσαν για την ουδετερότητά του."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਦੋਖੀ ਬਿਗੜ ਰੂਪੁ ਹੋਇ ਜਾਇ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕੇ ਦੋਖੀ ਕਉ ਦਰਗਹ ਮਿਲੈ ਸਜਾਇ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਦੋਖੀ ਸਦਾ ਸਹਕਾਈਐ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਦੋਖੀ ਨ ਮਰੈ ਨ ਜੀਵਾਈਐ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕੇ ਦੋਖੀ ਕੀ ਪੁਜੈ ਨ ਆਸਾ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕਾ ਦੋਖੀ ਉਠਿ ਚਲੈ ਨਿਰਾਸਾ ॥ਸੰਤ ਕੈ ਦੋਖਿ ਨ ਤ੍ਰਿਸਟੈ ਕੋਇ ॥ਜੈਸਾ ਭਾਵੈ ਤੈਸਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਇ ॥ਪਇਆ ਕਿਰਤੁ ਨ ਮੇਟੈ ਕੋਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਜਾਨੈ ਸਚਾ ਸੋਇ ॥੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 280 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਭ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਦਰਗਾਹ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਿੰਦਕ ਸਦਾ ਆਤੁਰ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਨਾਹ ਉਹ ਜੀਊਂਦਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਨਾਹ ਮੋਇਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸੰਤ ਦੇ ਨਿੰਦਕ ਦੀ ਆਸ ਕਦੇ ਸਿਰੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੜ੍ਹਦੀ, ਜਗਤ ਤੋਂ ਨਿਰਾਸ ਹੀ ਚੱਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ (ਭਲਾ, ਸੰਤਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਸੋਭਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਮਿਲੇ?) ।ਸੰਤ ਦੀ ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਨਿੰਦਿਆ ਦੀ) ਇਸ ਤ੍ਰੇਹ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ।ਜਿਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਨੀਅਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤਿਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸੁਭਾਉ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਬਚੇ ਭੀ ਕਿਵੇਂ?) ਪਿਛਲੀ ਕੀਤੀ (ਮੰਦ) ਕਮਾਈ ਦੇ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਹੋਏ (ਸੁਭਾਉ-ਰੂਪ) ਫਲ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਮਿਟਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਇਸ ਭੇਤ ਨੂੰ) ਉਹ ਸੱਚਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭।\\""},{"question":"फुर्सदको गतिविधिको रूपमा पढ्ने मनोवैज्ञानिक फाइदाहरू के हुन्?","answer":"फुर्सदको लागि पढाइले तनाव कम गर्छ, संज्ञानात्मक कार्य बढाउँछ, कल्पनालाई उत्तेजित गर्छ, र विश्राम प्रदान गर्दछ, सुधारिएको मानसिक स्वास्थ्य र कल्याणमा योगदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"એશિયાઇ સિંહ વિષે પ્રાથમિક માહિતી આપો.","answer":"એશિયાઇ સિંહ એ બિલાડી કુળનું સૌથી ઊંચું અને આફ્રિકન સિંહ પછી સૌથી મોટું પ્રાણી છે. આ પ્રાણી આખા વિશ્વમાં માત્ર ગુજરાત રાજ્યમાં આવેલા સૌરાષ્ટ્ર વિસ્તારમાં આવેલા ગીર અભયારણ્યમાં જોવા મળે છે. એશિયાઇ સિંહએ ભારતમાં જોવા મળતી ૫ \\"મોટી બિલાડી\\" ઓ માંથી એક છે. અન્ય ચાર પ્રજાતિમાં બેંગોલ ટાઇગર, ભારતીય દિપડો, બરફ નો દિપડો , અને ધબ્બેદાર દિપડો  વગેરે છે. પહેલાના સમયમાં તે અરબસ્તાન થી છેક સુમાત્રા સુધી જોવા મળતા હતાં, ત્યારે તેની ત્રણ પ્રજાતિઓ હતી બંગાળના સિંહ, અરેબીયાના સિંહ અને ઇરાનનાં સિંહ, વખત જતાં આજે તે ફક્ત ભારતનાં થોડા ભાગ પુરતા જ જોવા મળે છે. હાલ આફ્રિકામાં જોવા મળતા સિંહ કરતા તે આકારમાં નાનાં અને રંગ ઝાંખો હોય છે. પરંતુ આક્રમકતા આ બંન્ને પ્રજાતિમાં સરખીજ હોય છે."},{"question":"问题：苏州的交通情况如何？","answer":"答案：苏州交通发达，有高速公路、铁路和航空等多种交通方式相连接，是华东地区的重要交通枢纽。"},{"question":"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ මානව හිමිකම් කවුන්සිලයේ සාමාජික රටවල් ගණන","answer":"47"},{"question":"प्रदूषण की समस्या","answer":"प्रस्तावनाहमारे पूरे पृथ्वी की सबसे बड़ी समस्या प्रदूषण है। प्रदूषण के कारण पूरे पृथ्वी का भविष्य खतरे में है, प्रदूषण के वजह से जीव जंतुओं को और मनुष्य को पृथ्वी पर अपना जीवन व्यतीत करने में परेशानियां होती हैं।प्रदूषण के प्रकारपृथ्वी पर बहुत सारे प्रदूषण होते हैं और इन्हीं की वजह से पृथ्वी का भविष्य खतरे में है प्रदूषण मुख्य चार प्रकार के प्रदूषण होते हैं:-जल प्रदूषणवायु प्रदूषणमृदा प्रदूषणध्वनि प्रदूषणजल प्रदूषण के कारण, नुकसान और उपायकारण:- आज के आधुनिक समय में जल प्रदूषण बहुत ही तेजी से बढ़ रहा है, जैसे जैसे हम विकास कर रहे हैं उसी तरह से प्रदूषण भी बढ़ रहा है, जल प्रदूषण सबसे ज्यादा फैक्ट्री के रसायनिक और गंदे पानी को साफ नदी में उतारने से होता है, जब साफ पानी में गन्दा पानी मिल जाता है तो पूरा पानी प्रदूषित हो जाता है।जल प्रदूषण साफ पानी कचरा फेंकने और जानवरों को नहलाने से भी होता है और भी बहुत से कारण हैं जिनकी वजह से जल प्रदूषण बढ़ता चला जा रहा है।नुकसान:- अगर इसी प्रकार जल प्रदूषण बढ़ता रहा तो भविष्य में साफ पानी की समस्या हो जाएगी आज के समय में बहुत से ऐसे स्थान है जहां पर पीने के लिए पानी नहीं मिल पाता है लोग पानी पीने के लिए कई किलोमीटर दूर चल कर जाते हैं और पानी लेकर आते हैं।अगर इसी प्रकार जल प्रदूषण बढ़ता रहा तो भविष्य में पृथ्वी पर मनुष्य और जीव-जंतुओं का जीवित रहने पाना मुश्किल हो जाएगा।उपाय:- जल प्रदूषण से बचने के लिए हमें फैक्ट्री के पानी को साफ पानी में नहीं मिलाना है और ना ही नदियों और तालाबों में कचरा फेंकना है और न ही जानवरों को नहलाना है और हमें जितना हो सके पेड़ पौधे लगाने हैं।वायु प्रदूषण के कारण और उसके नुकसानकारण:- वायु प्रदूषण आधुनिक वाहनों से निकलने वाले धुये से होता है और कहीं भी प्लास्टिक को जलाया जाता है तो उससे भी जहरीला धुआं निकलता है जिससे वायु प्रदूषण बहुत ही ज्यादा होता है।नुकसान:- वायु प्रदूषण बढ़ने के कारण जीव जंतुओं को सांस लेने में कठिनाई होगी और उनकी मृत्यु हो जाएगी।उपाय:- वायु प्रदूषण को कम करने के लिए हमें ज्यादा से ज्यादा पेड़ पौधे लगाना चाहिए और कहीं भी आने जाने के लिए बैटरी से चलने वाले वाहनों का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए जिससे वायु प्रदूषण नहीं होता है।मृदा प्रदूषण के कारण और उसके नुकसानकारण:- मृदा प्रदूषण मिट्टी में फेंके जाने वाले प्लास्टिक और टायर और खेतों में डाली जाने वाली दवाइयों के कारण होता है।नुकसान:- मृदा प्रदूषण के फैलने के कारण मिट्टी उपजाऊ नहीं रहती है जिससे कोई भी फसल नहीं हो पाता है पेड़ पौधे सही से उत्पन्न नहीं हो पाते हैं जिसके कारण वायु और जल प्रदूषण भी बढ़ जाता है।उपाय:- मृदा प्रदूषण को कम करने हेतु हमें मिट्टी पर प्लास्टिक की थैलियों को नहीं फेंकना चाहिए और खेतों में आवश्यकता अनुसार ही दवाइयों और जैविक का इस्तेमाल करना चाहिए ।ध्वनि प्रदूषण के कारण, नुकसान और उपायकारण:- ध्वनि प्रदूषण सड़कों पर चलने वाले वाहनों के कारण होता है जब वाहन फालतू में हार्न बजाते रहते हैं और जब किसी भी जगह पर उत्सव या समारोह में लगने वाले स्पीकर से तेज निकलने वाली आवाज के कारण भी ध्वनि प्रदूषण होता है ।नुकसान:- ध्वनि प्रदूषण के कारण इंसान को कम सुनाएं दे सकता है और धन प्रदूषण से मनुष्य के शरीर में कई प्रकार की बीमारियां भी उत्पन्न होती हैं ।उपाय:- ध्वनि प्रदूषण को कम करने के लिए हमें बिना किसी जरूरत के वाहन के हार्न को नहीं बजाना है और समारोह में लगने वाले लाउडस्पीकर को कम आवाज पर बजाना चाहिए ।"},{"question":"Araka ity lahatsoratra ity, inona avy ireo endrika isehoan' ny valin-tanana ?\\"Nanomboka hampita ireny hevitra ireny Randria tany am-panangonam-bokatra tany. Saika tsy nino izy nony afaka volana vitsivitsy taty aoriana, betsaka no tsy nino toa azy tamin'ireo olona nitantarany fa misy toerana maromaro ahitana ny fiaraha-miasan'ny tambanivohitra, mampitatra ny valin-tanana, manova ny endriky ny dinam-pokonolona mba hampitodika bebe kokoa ny saina ho amin'ny fiaraha-mamokatra tsyho an'ny tombontsoan'ny fianakaviana fosiny ihany fa ho an'ny faritany manontolo mihitsy.Koa tanana vitsitvitsy mifanakaiky mihitsy aza no indreo mfaninana sy mifarimbona, mifampitarika sy mifanentana ho amin'ny fiaraha-miasa vaovao. Azo tsapain-tanana ny vokatr' izany, na dia miadana dia miadana aza ny fisehony. Nitatra tsikelikely ny lalana azon'ny saretin' omby naleha na dia sarotra aza ny fanatanterahana izany noho ny tsy fananana fitaovana ara-dalana. Nifanentana ny mponina mba hiaro ny vokatry ny taniny tsy hanjakan'ny mpijirika sy ny mpanambaka azy harizay, ary indrindra nataony ty nahita hirika hidirana intsony ireo vahiny mpitratrevatreva nanaraotra ny ty fahalalany sy ny fahasahiranany amin' ny fikarakarany ny vokatra isan-taona. Tsaroany kokoa ankehitriny fa eo am-pelatanany ny hery hiadiana amin'ny hanoanana sy ny ty fisiana mifamotoana amin'ny fahavaratra.\\"","answer":"Ny endrika mety isehoan'ny valin-tanana dia fiaraha-miasan'ny tambanivohitra, fiaraha-mamokatra ho an' ny faritaniny manontolo, tanana mifarimbona amin' ny fiaraha miasa vaovao, fifanentanana miaro ny vokatra."},{"question":"Bu karmaşık soruya bir cevap formüle edin: John Wall Dansı, kolları bükerek ve bileği döndürerek yapılan bir danstır. John Wall, Ulusal Basketbol Birliği'nin (NBA) Washington Wizards takımında oynamış Amerikalı profesyonel basketbol oyuncusudur ve Ekim 2009'da Big Blue Madness'te yaptığı tanıtım sırasında ilk kez aynı adlı dansı","answer":"Kentucky Üniversitesi'nde gerçekleştirmiştir."},{"question":"Pasaport hangi renk olmalı?","answer":"Bordo renklidir, bu nedenle bordo pasaport olarak da bilinir. Bordo pasaport sahipleri vizesiz gidilebilen yerlere pasaportları ile direkt giriş yapabilirler. Bordo pasaport, 38 sayfadan oluşur ve verilen vizeler bu pasaport üzerine işlenir."},{"question":"Euskal Herriko historia: Zer da Euskadi Ta Askatasuna (ETA) eta zer eragina izan du euskal gizartean?","answer":"Euskadi Ta Askatasuna (ETA) 20. mendean sortutako independentzia talde armatu bat izan zen. Bere jarduera militanteari esker, Espainiako eta Frantziako gobernuak presionatu zituen euskal nazioaren autodeterminazioaren alde. Hala ere, bere erasoen ondorioz, hainbat pertsona hil ziren, eta euskal gizartean zulo sakonak sortu ziren. 2018an, ETA bere jarduerari bukaera emateko erabakia hartu zuen, baina bere ondorioak oraindik nabariak dira euskal gizartean."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'berminyak biar lecak'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tiap-tiap pekerjaan janganlah kepalang, biarlah sampai pada akhir kesudahannya"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా గేయ పంక్తులు రాయండి:ఓ కోకిలా! నీవు ఎంతసేపు పాడినా నీ పాటలోని మాధుర్యాన్ని గాని, ఆ పాట పాడడానికి నువ్వు పడుతున్న కష్టాన్ని గాని ఈ విశ్వమనే విద్యాలయము గుర్తించడు అని కవి అనడంలో ఈ రోజుల్లో విశ్వవిద్యాలయాల గుర్తింపు కూడా రాజకీయాలతో ముడిపడి ఉందని సూచించాడు. జాతీయ పక్షి నెమలిని, తెల్లని పావురాన్ని, పాలపిట్టలను అగ్రవర్ణాలకు లేదా డబ్బున్న వారికి ప్రతీకలుగా తీసుకొని డబ్బుద్వారా లేదా కులం ద్వారా మాత్రమే గుర్తింపు లభిస్తుందని ఆవేదన వ్యక్తం చేశాడు.","answer":"కోకిలా ! ఓ కోకిలా !!నీ వెంతపాడినానీ పాటనూ, నీ పాటునూ గుర్తించదు – ఈ “విశ్వ” విద్యాలయం !నిన్ను గుర్తించడానికి నువ్వు – “జాతీయ పక్షివి” కాదు, “ధవళ పారావతానివీ” కాదు; ప్రజలచే మొక్కులందుకోవడానికి – పాలపిట్టవూ కాదు !కోకిలా ! ఓ కోకిలా !!"},{"question":"‘గడ్డి పోచకూడా కత్తిలా మారటం’ అంటే ఏమిటి ?","answer":"సాధారణంగా గడ్డి మనం నడిస్తే పాదాల కింద పడినలిగి తలవంచి నిలబడుతుంది. కానీ కొన్నిసార్లు ఆ గడ్డి పోచలే బిరుసెక్కి అరికాళ్ళలో ముళ్ళలా గుచ్చుకుంటున్నప్పుడు ఒక్క అడుగు కూడా సరిగా వేయలేం. "},{"question":"Quantas estrelas tem a bandeira do Brasil?","answer":"A bandeira do Brasil tem 27 estrelas."},{"question":"ਆਮ ਲੋਕ ਤਕਰੀਬਨ ਏਨਾ ਕੁ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ 135 ਦੇ ਲਗਪਗ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਿਵੇਕਲੀ ਛਾਪ ਛੱਡਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਏ। ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਹੁਤੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਮਕਬੂਲ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਏਨਾ ਟੇਢਾ ਮੇਢਾ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਕਿਆਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀਅਤ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਇੱਕ ਮਈ 1913 ਨੂੰ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਹੋਇਆ। ਪੁਰਖਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਪਿੰਡ ਭੇਰਾ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ, ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਦੇ ਬੜੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰੀ ਹਰਬੰਸ ਲਾਲ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਅਤੇ ਸ੍ਰੀਮਤੀ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਦੇਵੀ ਦਾ ਪੰਜਾਂ ਧੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਜੰਮਿਆ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਨਾਂ ਯੁਧਿਸ਼ਟਰ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਨਾਂ ਲੈਣਾ ਔਖਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਘਰ ਦਾ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਵੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਮਨ੍ਹਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ 'ਗੁਰੂਕਲ ਪੋਠੋਹਾਰ' ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਨੇ ਪਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਫਿਰ ਚੌਥੀ ਜਮਾਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਾਲ 1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਕਾਲਜ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਤੋਂ ਇੰਟਰਮੀਡੀਏਟ ਪਾਸ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਫੈਸਰ ਜਸਵੰਤ ਰਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਭੈਣ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ 1936 ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਇਆ।ਸਾਲ 1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਲਹੌਰ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਲਜ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਲਿਖੀਆਂ।  ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਯਥਾਰਥਵਾਦੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਾ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਤਰ ਸੁਭਾਵਕ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਲਹਿਜ਼ੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੋਲਦੇ ਸਨ। ਪਾਰਸੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚੱਲਤ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਨ ਕਰਦੇ। ਸੰਨ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਲਾਹੌਰ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੀ ਐਮ.ਏ. ਕਰਨ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਾਪਸ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਤੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਵਪਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ। ਇਨ੍ਹੀਂ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਹੀ ਦਵਿੰਦਰ ਸਤਿਆਰਥੀ ਇੱਕ ਮਹੀਨਾ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਘਰ ਰਿਹਾ। ਛੇਤੀ ਹੀ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਪਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਉਕਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਨਵੀਂ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਅੰਗੜਾਈਆਂ ਲੈ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ।  ਫਿਰ ਓਧਰੋਂ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਖੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮੀਆਂ ਬੀਵੀ ਨਾਟਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ  ਦਿਲਚਸਪੀਆਂ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਰਹੇ। ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਬੋਰੀਆ ਬਿਸਤਰਾ ਵਲ੍ਹੇਟ ਕੇ ਕਲਕੱਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਤੁਰ ਪਏ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਰਵਿੰਦਰ ਨਾਥ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕਰ ਲਈ। ਉੱਥੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹਾ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਣ ਸੀ, ਸੋਹਣਾ ਤੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਨ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਵਰਗੀ ਰੂਹ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ। ਉੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਹੋਰਾਂ ਬਰਨਾਰਡ ਸ਼ਾਹ ਦਾ ਨਾਟਕ 'ਆਰਮਜ਼ ਐਂਡ ਦੀ ਮੈਨ' ਖੇਡਿਆ। ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖਾਸ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਰਹੀ ਕਿ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਨੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਬੋਲੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਖਣ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1940 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਅਤੇ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਲਈ ਰਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਗਏ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਚਾਰ ਸਾਲ ਬੀ.ਬੀ.ਸੀ. ਲੰਡਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਹ ਉਹ ਸਮਾਂ ਸੀ ਜਦ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਜਰਮਨ ਜੰਗੀ ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਲੰਡਨ ਉਤੇ ਬੰਬਾਰੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਦਾਦਾ-ਦਾਦੀ ਕੋਲ ਰਿਹਾ। ਜਦ ਬਲਰਾਜ 1944 ਵਿੱਚ ਲੰਡਨ ਤੋਂ ਮੁੜਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਜੰਗ ਦੀ ਭਿਆਨਕਤਾ ਵੇਖ ਆਇਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਕਲਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਬੰਬੇ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਚੇਤਨ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੋਲ ਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਉਹ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਪੀਪਲਜ਼ ਥੀਏਟਰ ਐਸੋਸੀਏਸ਼ਨ (ਇਪਟਾ) ਦਾ ਸਰਗਰਮ ਆਗੂ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ, ਜੋ ਨਾਟਕ ਨੂੰ ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਲਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਦਾ ਹਥਿਆਰ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਸੀ। ਦੇਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਫਿਟਕਾਰਾਂ ਪਾਈਆਂ, ਜਿਹੜਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਸਕਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1949 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਭੂਆ ਦੀ ਕੁੜੀ ਸੰਤੋਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਇਆ। ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਗ੍ਰਿਫਤਾਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ। ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਸਰਗਰਮੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਛੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਜੇਲ੍ਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰੇ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਸੋ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦੇ ਮਾਤਾ ਜੀ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ, ਸ੍ਰੀਮਤੀ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਦੇਵੀ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"\\"ලක්ෂෙට කොඩිය දානවා\\" යන්නෙහි අර්ථය පැහැදිළි කර දෙන්න පුළුවන් ද ?","answer":"අතීතයේ ලක්ෂපතියෙක් හිටියෙ ගමකට එක්කෙනයි. දෙන්නයි.එහෙම පොහොසත් කමක් තිබීම ලොකු අභිමානයක්.ඒක අන්‍යයන්ට පෙන්වාදීමේ ආඩම්බරය සංකේතවත් කලේ ගේ ඉදිරිපිට කොඩියක් දැමීමෙන්. ඒක තමයි ලස්සෙට කොඩි දැමීම කියන්නේ."},{"question":"Tóm tắt phần truyện Don Quixote đã đánh nhau với cối xay gió trong tác phẩm \\"Don Quixote\\".","answer":"Cuộc giao chiến giữa người với vật được tác giả miêu tả bằng giọng văn hài hước, hóm hỉnh. Vừa lúc nổi lên một làn gió nhẹ và các cánh quạt lớn của những chiếc cối xay gió bắt đầu chuyển động, Don Quixote liền nói: \\"Dù cho bọn ngươi có vung nhiều cánh tay hơn cả gã khổng lồ Briaro, các ngươi cũng sắp phải đền tội\\".Nói xong, ông ta nhiệt tình thành tâm niệm cầu mong \\"công nương\\" Dulcinea của mình cứu giúp cho trong lúc nguy nan này rồi lấy khiên che kín thân, tay lăm lăm ngọn giáo, thúc con ngựa phi thẳng tới chiếc cối xay gió gần nhất ở trước mặt. Ông ta đâm mũi giáo vào cánh quạt, vừa lúc gió làm cánh quạt quay tít khiến ngọn giáo gãy tan tành, kéo theo cả người và ngựa ngã văng ra xa.Câu chuyện kết thúc khi một người cạnh nhà Don Quixote hóa trang thành hiệp sĩ để đánh với ông ta với điều kiện \\"nếu ta đánh thua, ta sẽ không làm hiệp sĩ nữa và nếu ngươi thua thì ngươi không được làm hiệp sĩ nữa\\". Don Quixote thua nên ông ta trở về nhà.Gần chết, Don Quixote nhận thức được tai hại và sự nhảm nhí của những cuốn truyện hiệp sĩ mà mình từng đọc. Ông ta viết di chúc rồi qua đời."},{"question":"三次元のことを「３Ｄ」などとよく言いますが、この「Ｄ」とは何という言葉の頭文字でしょう？","answer":"dimension（ディメンション）です。"},{"question":"१० मिटरको आधार र १४ मिटरको उचाइ भएको समानान्तर चतुर्भुजको क्षेत्रफल गणना गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"समानान्तर चतुर्भुजको क्षेत्रफल उचाइले र आधार गुणन बराबर  हुन्छ, त्यसैले क्षेत्रफल १४० वर्ग मिटर (१० मिटर * १४ मिटर) हुन्छ।"},{"question":"鉄道のレールを枕木に固定するときに打つ釘を何というでしょう？","answer":"犬釘です。"},{"question":"德日在经济领域有哪些合作？","answer":"答：德国和日本在汽车制造、科技创新、能源等多个领域都有深入的合作。同时，两国也是各自最大的贸易伙伴之一。"},{"question":" Iza amin'ny valan-javaboarin'i Arzantina no malaza amin'ny fiforonan'ny ranomandry mahavariana?","answer":"Ny Valan-javaboarin'i Los Glaciares ,iray amin'ireo toerana mahasarika mpizahatany betsaka  indrindra ao Arzantina."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'jangan puntung berasap jua'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perselisihan yang telah selesai jangan ada ekor-ekornya lagi supaya keadaan tenang kembali"},{"question":"கேள்வி: தனிநபர்கள் அன்றாட வாழ்வில் தங்கள் கார்பன் தடயத்தை எவ்வாறு குறைக்க முடியும், மேலும் இந்த நடவடிக்கைகள் காலநிலை மாற்றத்தைத் தணிப்பதில் என்ன தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தும்?","answer":"பதில்: ஆற்றல்-திறனுள்ள சாதனங்களைப் பயன்படுத்துவதன் மூலமும், இறைச்சி நுகர்வைக் குறைப்பதன் மூலமும், பொதுப் போக்குவரத்தைப் பயன்படுத்துவதன் மூலமும், புதுப்பிக்கத்தக்க எரிசக்தி ஆதாரங்களை ஆதரிப்பதன் மூலமும் தனிநபர்கள் தங்கள் கார்பன் தடயத்தைக் குறைக்கலாம். ஒட்டுமொத்தமாக, இந்த நடவடிக்கைகள் பசுமை இல்ல வாயு உமிழ்வைக் குறைப்பதற்கும் உலகளாவிய அளவில் காலநிலை மாற்றத்தை எதிர்த்துப் போராடுவதற்கும் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க வகையில் பங்களிக்க முடியும்."},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Корккон адам - кадимки абалына караганда жакшыраак көрө алат."},{"question":"Em que país nasceu a cantora Shakira?","answer":"A cantora Shakira nasceu na Colômbia."},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டில் ரப்பர் அதிக நிலப்பரப்பில் சாகுபடி செய்யப்படும் மாவட்டம்?A. தஞ்சைB. கன்னியாகுமரிC. மதுரைD. திருச்சி","answer":"B. கன்னியாகுமரி"},{"question":"الجملة 1: بلهانموي هي بلدة في منطقة هيران في وسط الصومال. الجملة 2: بلهانحومى مدينة فى المنطقة الوسطى من هيران ، الصومال. سؤال: الجملة 1 والجملة 2 بيعبروا عن نفس المعنى؟ نعم ولا لأ؟","answer":"لأ،  الجملة 1 والجملة 2 مش بيعبروا عن نفس المعنى."},{"question":"How do vaccines work to protect against diseases?","answer":"Vaccines work by mimicking disease agents and stimulating the immune system to build a defense against them. A vaccine introduces a harmless part of the disease-causing microorganism or a modified version of its toxins into the body. This component is known as an antigen. The immune system recognizes this antigen as a foreign invader and mounts an immune response. This includes the production of antibodies, which are proteins that recognize and can neutralize the pathogen. The immune system also develops a memory of the pathogen, so if the body is exposed to the actual disease in the future, the immune system can quickly recognize and fight it off. This process is known as immunological memory, and it can prevent the onset of disease or reduce its severity. Vaccines have been successful in controlling, and in some cases eradicating, many infectious diseases."},{"question":"Kutengeserana kwevaranda vachiyambuka Atlantic kwakakanganisa sei Africa?","answer":"Kutengeswa kwevaranda vachiyambuka Atlantic, uko kwakatanga muzana ramakore rechi 16 kusvika kuzana ramakore rechi 19, kwakatungamirira kukumanikidzirwa kubatwa nokuitwa varanda kwemamiriyoni eAfrica. Yakakonzera kutambura kukuru uye yakabvisa vanhu munzvimbo dzakawanda dzekondinendi."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Vụ việc xảy ra vào khoảng 12h30 ngày 30/7, trên quốc lộ 20 đoạn qua dốc Đại Bình, thuộc địa phận phường Lộc Sơn, TP Bảo Lộc, tỉnh Lâm Đồng. Theo đó, một nam thanh niên trong tình trạng nghi \\"ngáo đá\\" (phê ma túy đá) lao ra đường, rồi lột đồ, kêu gào, la hét. Chưa dừng lại ở đó, nam thanh niên còn có những hành vi nhảy múa rồi nằm ra đường với dấu hiệu mất kiểm soát. Thậm chí, nam thanh niên còn lao vào một nhà dân nhưng rất may người dân kịp thời chốt cửa.","answer":"Sau khoảng 15 phút nhảy múa trên đường khiến giao thông qua lại trên quốc lộ 20 bị tắc cục bộ, thanh niên này bị công an phường Lộc Sơn khống chế, đưa về trụ sở để xử lý theo quy định. Bước đầu cơ quan chức năng xác định đối tượng tên là H.H.V (ngụ phường Lộc Sơn, TP.Bảo Lộc, Lâm Đồng), nghiện ma túy nặng, thuộc diện giám sát, quản lý của cơ quan công an."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي تُسمّى بأحد أركان الإسلام؟","answer":"الإجابة : الحج."},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: Babban birnin Indiya shine New Delhi. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk ubi keledek jepun rebus dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 1 kg ubi keledek Jepun, 1 sudu kecil garam, AirCara memasak:1. Cuci bersihkan ketulan ubi dengan menggosoknya di bawah air paip.2. Potong dua/tiga supaya mudah empuk.3. Masukkan ke dalam periuk bersama garam. Masukkan air sehingga menenggelamkan ubi.4. Tutup periuk dan rebus sehingga empuk. Kalau mengunakan kaedah biasa ia ambil masak dalam 20 minit. Kalau nak cepat boleh guna periuk periuk tekanan - hanya ambil masa 6 minit jika memasak dengan high pressure.5. Bila empuk, tuskan dan biarkan suam sedikit sebelum dimakan"},{"question":"Pada 24 Maret 1882, Robert Koch menemukan bakteri penyebab Tuberkulosis (TBC), Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Momen itu diperingati sebagai Hari Tuberkulosis Sedunia.Berdasarkan konteks kalimat di atas, tanggal berapakah yang diperingati sebagai Hari Tuberkulosis Sedunia?Jawaban:","answer":"Hari Tuberkulosis (TBC) Sedunia diperingati setiap tanggal 24 Maret, sebagai peringatan ditemukannya bakteri penyebab TBC oleh ilmuwan Jerman bernama Robert Koch pada 24 Maret 1882."},{"question":"ਪੇਚ ਕੱਸਿਆ ਗਿਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਂ ਪੇਚ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਰੈਂਚ ਨੂੰ ਘੁਮਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਰੈਂਚ ਨੂੰ ਘੁਮਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।"},{"question":"This gap indicates that, theoretically, there is no vehicle model can travel 174  - 228 miles without needing to be recharged.is there any grammar issues?","answer":"Your sentence has a minor grammar issue related to verb agreement. Here's a revised version:\\"This gap indicates that, theoretically, there are no vehicle models that can travel 174 - 228 miles without needing to be recharged.\\"The correction includes changing \\"is\\" to \\"are\\" to agree with the plural noun \\"vehicle models.\\""},{"question":"నైతిక విలువలు – మనిషిని మహనీయునిగా మారుస్తాయి అంటూ ఒక కరపత్రాన్ని రూపొందించండి.","answer":"ప్రియమైన మిత్రుడా !ఎదుటివారిలో తప్పులు వెదకడం కన్నా వారి నుండి మంచిని స్వీకరించు. ఈ గుణం నీకు వారిలోని మంచిని తెలుసుకోవడానికి, నీలోని మంచితనం లోకానికి తెలియజేయడానికి తోడ్పడుతుంది. నీతిని పాటించే విలువలు నైతిక విలువలు. ఇవి సమాజాన్ని సన్మార్గంలో నడిపించడానికి తోడ్పడతాయి. ఈ విలువలు పాటించిన మహర్షులు, ప్రజా నాయకులు, దేశభక్తులు, దాతలు తరతరాలకు మార్గదర్శకులౌతారు. నైతిక విలువలతో సత్యం, ధర్మం, న్యాయం, మానవీయతలు ప్రకాశిస్తుంటాయి.ఒక అగ్గిపుల్ల తాను మండిపోతూ ఇంకొకదానిని మండిస్తుంది. అట్లాగే నైతిక విలువలు లేని వ్యక్తి తాను నాశనమౌతూ, సమాజానికీ చెడునే చేస్తాడు. ఇది ఎలా అంటారా ? దుర్యోధనుడు ఎప్పుడూ పాండవులకు హాని చేద్దామా అని వారి లోపాలు వెతుకులాటలోనే జీవితాన్ని గడిపాడు. ఇక ధర్మరాజు అన్నివేళలా ధర్మం తప్పని ధర్మమూర్తిగా, తోటివారి పట్ల ప్రేమ మూర్తిగా కనిపిస్తాడు. ఎదుటివారి అవగుణాలు గణింపక, సుగుణాలను స్వీకరించి, తనను తాను తీర్చిదిద్దుకోవడానికే ప్రయత్నించాడు.మన చరిత్రను పరిశీలిస్తే గురుకులాలలో దేవాలయాలలో నైతికవిలువలు ప్రబోధించే, పెంపొందించే కార్యక్రమాలు విరివిగా జరిగాయి. సాహిత్యం, కళలు ద్వారా సమాజంలో మార్పును తేవడానికి ఎందరో మహనీయులు తమ జీవితాలను ధారపోశారు.ఇట్లు,తెలంగాణ వైతాళిక సంఘం."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Caanaha la Karkariyay miyay Ka caafimaad badan yihiin caanaha kale?","answer":"Caanahu waa cunno dhamaystiran oo ay ku jiraan nafaqooyin iyo macdano jirku uusan ka maarmi karin. Waxay hodan ku yihiin kalsiyaam, barootiin, kaarbohaydareetyo, fitamiinno, macdano iyo dufanno, waxayna jirka u leeyihiin faa’idooyin kala duwan oo ay ka mid tahay ilaalinta miisaanka jirka iyo sare u qaadista caafimaadka lafaha. Sida la ogyahay caanaha dhayda ah oo la karkariyo ka hor inta aan la cabin waxay dishaa bakteeriyada waxayna ka hortagtaa cillado badan oo caafimaad.Sida ay daraasaadku tilmaamayaan caanaha xoolaha ee aan warshada soo marin ayaa u baahan in la karkariyo si looga dilo bakteeriyada balse caanaha warshadaysan qasab ma ahan in la karkariyo, haddii la karkariyana dhibaato ma lahan..Caanaha xoolaha ee aan la karkarin waxaa ku jiri kara noocyo bakteeriyada ka mid ah oo halis ah, taas oo dhaawac u geysan karta dadka difaaca jirkoodu uu daciifka yahay, dumarka uurka leh, caruurta iyo dadka waayeelka ah.Caanaha xoolaha ee aan la karkarin waxaa ku badan nafaqada, si kastaba ha ahaatee, waxaa ku jirta bakteeriyo dhibaato leh, taas oo keeni karta cudurro halis ah. Sidaas darteed, waxaa lagu dardaarmaa in caanaha la karkariyo ka hor inta aan la cabin.Caanaha geela waxaa mararka qaar laga qaadaa jeermisyo halis ah oo caafimaadka ama noloshaba qatar gelin kara, taasi waxaa sabab u ah dadka geela lisa badankood oo aan nadaafadda ku dadaalin, gacmahane iska dhaqin, sidoo kale weelasha lagu liso oo aan nadiif ahayn, waxaa intaa sii dheer geela waxaa la mariyaa sun si cayayaanka iyo cudurradaba looga daaweeyo, taasoo si sahlan caanaha ugu gudubto, intaasoo halis ah iyadoo ay jirto haddana caanaha geela lama karkariyo oo sidooda ayaa lagu cabaa, markuu qofka ku xanuunsadane horay dhakhtar kama tago illaa uu ka fuuq baxo iyadoo loo malaynayo shubankii lagu yaqiinay caanah geela.!!"},{"question":"USithole walususa unyawokazi lwakhe olwalulokhu luthe nzi entanyeni kuMoloi.Wavuka-ke, wazithuntutha. Wazingcengela kuSithole ukuba bangabe besaqhubekanalo mdlalo ngoba uyingozi. USithole waphuma waqonda emotweni yakhe phandle.Wayidumisa, kwasuka amaphepha.UMoloi naye wanwabuluka waqonda kweyakhe imoto. Wafika wayivula, wangena,wahlala phansi. Indololwane yakhe yagqula phezu kwedolo, isihlathi sacamelaentendeni yesandla wacabanga:'Yaze yangiklinya inja! Kuzofanele ngivuke kusasa ngiyobonana nodokotela. Ngifunaukuba angibheke lapha emqaleni. Umminzo angisawuzwa nje kahle ukusebenzakwawo.' Wathi uphakamisa amehlo uMoloi, wathola abantu sebethe ngu emotweniyakhe. Bathi bayambuza ukuthi kwenzenjani, kodwa wangathanda ukuphendula.Wakhuphula amawindi emoto wawavala ngci.UDumazile waphuma endlini encane selidume ledlula. Abantu base begcwele igcekelonke. Wayesangene ukusangana lokhu. Wasondela kuLerato, wathi:'Abalimazananga kodwa?' Lutho uLerato ukuphendula. Wayekhala mi izinyembezi,ezibhonqa phansi ebaleni. Kwaze kwasiza uMtholephi okunguyena owakwaziukulandisa unina:'Eyi bewungabona! Bewungathi yile nto esasivame ukuyibona kuTV. UDaddybewungathi uSuperman! Usuke izithonto wahlala emqaleni kubaba kaSisi Lerato. Eyingibone esephenqa amehlo amhlophe, bengithi useyagqashuka! Libe selithayimaithayima lami, lamdedela.' UDumazile wazama ukuya kuMoloi emotweni, kodwa wathiethi gagaga, wayisusa imoto uMoloi. Wabe esehamba ebuza kunoma ngubani njeahlangana naye ukuthi kwenzenjani. Abantu bazizwa becasuka nje ukubonauDumazile ezenza isiphukuphuku sohlanya.Wawuze uzwe banye abantu sebethi:'Nx! Kudala sabona ukuthi lo mfazi uzoshayanisa amadoda! Elakobani nje isokalomfazi?' Babe sebehlakazeka abantu beNkosi beshiya uDumazile nenkinga yakhe. 1. Kwakuyoba namthelela muni emshadweni kaDumazile ukuba wagcinaeboshiwe ngenxa yamacala ayembandakanyeka kuwona. ","answer":"Kwakuyoba nomthelela omubi ngoba kwakungenzeka uMtalaselwa afakeisehlukaniso ngoba ebona ukuthi uganwe yinkosikazi eyisigebengu/izinganezaziyobuyela koyise bazo noma eMzimkhulu/ uSithole wayengawudayisaumuzi waseMafezini ngoba wawuthengwe uyena. "},{"question":"Ijọba apapọ ṣi papakọ ofurufu mẹrinla","answer":"Ijọba apapọ ilẹ Naijiria ti fọwọ si ṣiṣi awọn papakọ ofurufu mẹrinla lẹyin awọn eto ati atunṣe to waye.Minisita feto irinna ofurufu, Hadi Sirika, lo kede ọrọ naa lonii, ọjọ Aiku, Sannde.Awọn papakọ naa nijọba ti pa lẹyin ti arun Korona wọ Naijiria loṣu keji, ọdun yii.Awọn papakọ ofurufu naa ni: Murtala Muhammed Murtala Muhammed International Airport, Eko; Nnamdi Azikwe International Airport, Abuja; Malam Aminu Kano International Airport, Kano; Port Harcourt International Airport, Omaguwa; Sam Mbakwe Aiport, Owerri; Maiduguri Airport, Maiduguri.Awọn to ku ni: Victor Attah Airport, Uyo; Kaduna Airport, Kaduna; Yola Airport, Yola; Margaret Ekpo Airport, Calabar; Sultan Abubakar Airport, Sokoto; Birnin Kebbi Airport, Kebbi; Yakubu Gowon Airport, Jos; ati Benin Airport, Benin.Lọwọlọwọ bayii, Victor Attah Airport, tilu Uyo, nikan lo laṣẹ lati gbalejo baluu to n lọ tabi pada lati oke-okun."},{"question":"Waxan Alle ka baryaa","answer":"waxaan mar walba illaahay ka baryaa inaan janada ku kulano maalin maalmaha kamid ah walaahi Suhuureey xabiibti labo sanad ayaan ku jiraa kooxdaan sanadahaasi waxay ii noqdeen sanadihii aan guulo badan gaadhay sababtoo ah waxaan kaa bartay mucjisooyin Arimahayga oo dhan ii fududeeyay waana saliga ibraahimiyada iyo istiqfaarta adiga ayaan kaa bartay intaa wixii ka dambaysay waligay qof waxba ma waydiisan illaahay ayaan baryaa waan saliyaa xataa waxyar oo basiida hadan ubaahdo wallaahi deg deg ayuu wanaagsane iiga farxiyaa waan ooyaa markasta oon helo wixiii aan daqiiiqado kahor kurbo igu hayay een Rabbigay baryaye sida aan kuu jeclahay dajiya illaahay hakuu jeclaado , "},{"question":"Wangsulana pitakonan berdasarkan paragraf wacan ing ngisor iki:Ing salah sijining deso kang subur lan makmur, wargane akeh seng kerjo dadi petani. Poro petani podho nandur pari, jagung lan sayuran. Pak Sugeng salah sijine petani kang nandur ketimun. Timune sae-sae lan seger. Saben dino ditilik’i, dirabuk lan disirami supoyo subur. Timune Pak Sugeng wes wayahe arep panen.Pitakon:Apa sing ditandur Pak Sugeng?Wangsulan:","answer":"Wangsulan: timun."},{"question":"Awọn araalu n binu si Ọba wọn lEkoo","answer":"Niluu Ajiran nijọba ibilẹ Eti Ọsa l’Ekoo lawọn eeyan kan ti n binu o, ẹni ti wọn si n binu si ko ju kabiyesi wọn lọ, Ọba Tijani Akinloye, Ojomu tiluu Ajiran.Ọkunrin kan ti wọn pe orukọ ẹ ni Yẹkinni Wasiu lo duro gẹgẹ bi agbẹnusọ fawọn eeyan to n binu yii. Ẹsun ti wọn si fi kan Ọba alaye naa ni pe gbogbo ohun to jẹ ogun ibi awọn pata lo ti ta tan, ti ohun idagbasoke kan bayii ko si ninu ilu naa.Wọn ni ko si ileewe kan to jẹ ojulowo, ọsibitu naa ko si atawọn ohun amayedẹrun mi-in bẹẹ lawọn to jẹ arugbo paapaa ko ri anfaani gidi kan bayii jẹ ninu gbogbo owo ti kabiyesi ti gba lọwọ awọn to ta ilẹ ilu naa fun.Iwọde lawọn eeyan yii ṣe lọ sileeṣẹ iwe iroyin lEkoo nibi ti wọn ti fidi ẹ mulẹ wi pe awọn ti fọrọ ọhun to ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa leti, bẹẹ lawọn oloye ilu naa mọ si i daadaa, ṣugbọn ti won ko ri ohunkohun ṣe si i. Bẹẹ gẹgẹ ni wọn sọ pe awọn ti ba ọba alaye ọhun sepade lọpọ igba, ṣugbọn pabo ni gbogbo igbiyanju awọn ja si.Wọn ni pupọ ninu awọn ileeṣẹ nlanla bii Chevron, ileepo Shell atawọn mi-in ni wọn wa lori ilẹ Ajiran, ṣugbọn gbogbo anfaani to yẹ ki awọn ọmọ ilu maa jẹ, ọdọ ọba alaye yii lo n wọlẹ si.Ẹsun tawọn eeyan yii fi kan ọba wọn ree, bẹẹ lo jọ pe Kabiyesi paapaa ko ṣetan lati ba awọn oniroyin sọ ohunkohun. Balogun ilu Ajiran, Alhaji Yẹkinni Bakare ni tiẹ sọ pe, lori iṣẹlẹ ọhun, ohun kan bayii ko ni i tẹnu oun jade."},{"question":"Aiza avy ny toerana eto Madagasikara hahitana sekoly ambony polyteknika ?","answer":"Toerana roa no ahitana ny sekoly ambony polyteknika, izay hita any Antananarivo ary any Antsiranana "},{"question":"Dokończ sekwencję: luty, marzec, kwiecień, maj, ...","answer":"Następny jest czerwiec, lipiec, sierpień i tak dalej..."},{"question":"句子1: 在第二次世界大战结束之前, 约格斯拉夫邦的罗马天主教人数最多是德国人. 句子2: 在第二次世界大战结束之前, 罗马天主教徒最多的地区是南斯拉夫的德国人. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"相同"},{"question":"كم ورد لفظ(الصمد)في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"مرة واحدة "},{"question":"वर्धन घराण्याचा संस्थापक कोण होता ?","answer":"पुष्पभूती"},{"question":"Rema","answer":"Divine Ikubor (ibí 1 May 2000),Orúkọ orí itage rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ REMA, akọrin ti orílẹ-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ayé mo Rema nígbà tí ó gbé orin tí àkọlé rẹ ń jẹ́ \\"Iron Kan\\", èyí tí ó jẹyọ nínú summer playlist ti Barack Obama ni ọdún 2019. Bákan náà ní 2019, Ó sí fọwọ́ sí láti bá Jonzing World ṣíṣe, èyí tí ó wa labẹ Mavin Records.Divine Ikubor jẹ́ ọmọ tí wón bí sí ilé bí ìgbàgbọ Kíìtẹ́nì ni ìpínlẹ̀ Benin ni orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Bí o ṣé ń dàgbà ní ọ má ń kọ Orin, béè sì ní ọ má ń Rap, nígbà tí ó wà ní ilé ìwé Sẹ́kọ́ńdírì. Ó ká ìwé alákọ̀bẹ́rẹ́ tí primary àti Sẹ́kọ́ndiri rẹ ni Ighile Group of School ni ipinlẹ Edo."},{"question":"ප්‍රංශයේ උසම කන්ද කුමක්ද?","answer":"ප්‍රංශයේ උසම කන්ද මොන්ට් බ්ලැන්ක් ය. ප්‍රංශ භාෂාවෙන් \\"සුදු කන්ද\\" යන අරුත ඇති මොන්ට් බ්ලැන්ක්, ඇල්ප්ස් සහ බටහිර යුරෝපයේ උසම කඳු මුදුන ද වේ. එය මුහුදු මට්ටමේ සිට ආසන්න වශයෙන් මීටර් 4,808 (අඩි 15,774) උසින් පිහිටා ඇත. මෙම කන්ද ග්‍රේයන් ඇල්ප්ස් කඳුවැටියේ පිහිටා ඇති අතර ප්‍රංශය සහ ඉතාලිය අතර මායිමේ පිහිටා ඇත."},{"question":"Wọn ni eeyan meje lawọn ọlọpaa yinbọn pa l’Ogbomọṣọ, wọn tun ti rọ ọpọ ọdọ da satimọle n’Ibadan","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde, ti ṣeleri atilẹyin rẹ fawọn to n pe fun ki opin de ba SARS, iyẹn ẹka ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to n gbogun ti idigunjale. O ni kijọba apapọ tete fopin si awọn oṣiṣẹ alaabo ọhun nitori iya ti wọn fi n jẹ araalu ju anfaani ti wọn n ṣe fun wọn lọ.Lasiko to n ba awọn to n fẹhonu han sọrọ ni sẹkiteriati ijọba ipinlẹ naa to wa l’Agodi, n’Ibadan, Gomina Makinde, ẹni ti Ọnarebu Debọ Ogundoyin ti i ṣe abẹnugan ileegbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ọyọ,  pẹlu diẹ ninu awọn igbimọ alaṣẹ ijọba naa kọwọọrin pẹlu ẹ, ṣeleri pe gbogbo igbesẹ to yẹ loun ti gbe lati ri i pe wọn ko yinbọn pa ẹnikẹni mọ lasiko ti wọn ba n ṣewọde tako ohun ti ko dun mọ wọn ninu nitori ẹtọ wọn ni lati sọ nnkan to n dun wọn lọkan sita.Bakan naa lo fi awọn ọdọ oniwọọde naa lọkan balẹ pe gbogbo awọn olufẹhonu han ti awọn ọlọpaa ti rọ dà satimọle pata loun yoo ri i pe oun yọ jade.Ṣe lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, to kọja la gbọ pe awọn ọlọpaa yinbọn pa eeyan ti ko din ni meje niluu Ogbomọṣọ, lasiko iwọde ti wọn ṣe pe kijọba fopin si awọn ọlọpaa SARS.Ṣaaju ni igbakeji gomina ipinlẹ naa, Ẹnjinnia Rauf Ọlaniyan ti gbiyanju lati pẹtu si awọn olufẹhonu han yii ninu, ṣugbọn ti wọn yari kanlẹ, wọn ni gomina gan-an lawọn fẹẹ ri.Gẹgẹ bi Gomina Makinde ṣe sọ, “Ṣaaju asiko yii lemi paapaa iba ti wa pẹlu yin, Ogbomọṣọ ti mo lọ lo fa a, mo lọ sibẹ lati lọọ ṣabẹwo si awọn mọlẹbi awọn eeyan to padanu ẹmi wọn nibi iwọde to waye l’Ogbomọṣọ ni Satide to kọja ni.“Labẹ ofin orileede yii, ẹtọ yin ni lati fẹhonu han lati beere ẹtọ yin. Ṣugbọn mo bẹ yin lati ma ṣe gbe iwọde yin gba ilana jagidijagan nitori idagbasoke kan ko le waye lawujọ ti idarudapọ ba ti n waye.“Gbogbo ara ni mo fi wa pẹlu yin. Mo ti ba ọga agba ọlọpaa (ipinlẹ Ọyọ) sọrọ. Mo si fi da yin loju pe gbogbo awọn to ti wa latimọle lori iwọde ti ẹ n ṣe yii la maa gba beeli wọn.”Lẹyin ti awọn ọdọ kaakiri orileede yii ti fi gbogbo ọsẹ to kọja ṣe iwọde lati rawọ ẹbẹ si ijọba apapọ lati fopin si awọn ọlọpaa SARS, ti Aarẹ orileede yii, Ọgagun Muhammadu Buhari, ati Adamu Muhammed ti i ṣe ọga agba awọn ọlọpaa nilẹ yii si ti ṣeleri pe ko ni i si ohun to n jẹ SARS lara awọn ọlọpaa mọ, sibẹ  awọn ọdọ kaakiri igboro Ibadan tun tẹsiwaju ninu iwọde wọn lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ana, wọn ni ọpọ ileri bẹẹ nijọba apapọ ti ṣe nipa SARS ṣaaju ṣugbọn ti ayipada kankan ko tori ẹ waye.Ẹgbẹẹgbẹrun awọn ọdọ lo ya soju titi kaakiri igboro Ibadan fun iwọde ọhun, ti wọn si da sun-kẹrẹ-fa-kẹrẹ silẹ lọpọlọpọ awọn ọna to ṣe koko nigboro ilu naa.Niṣe lawọn oluwọde yii di ẹnu ọna sẹkiteriati ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ pa, nigba ti oriṣii awọn ikọ oluwọde meji pade nibẹ lẹẹkan ṣoṣo, Awọn ikọ oluwọde ti wọn bẹrẹ tiwọn ni Iwo Road gba ọna ile ijọba l’Agodi wọle, nigba ti awọn to kóra jọ siwaju Fasiti Ibadan (UI) lati bẹrẹ iwọde ọhun gba Bodija wọle, gbogbo wọn ba fabọ siwaju ileeṣẹ ijọba l’Agodi.Iwọde ti wọn ṣe ni Iwo Road, n’Ibadan, lo gbẹnu tán, nitori awọn to ṣewọde nibẹ ko din lẹgbẹrun mẹta eeyan, sun-kẹrẹ-fa-kẹrẹ ti wọn da silẹ nibẹ ko si mọ lori awọn oni nnkan irinsẹ nikan, tipatipa lawọn to n fẹsẹ rin paapaa fi n rọna kọja.Ko jọ pe iru iwọde bẹẹ ṣẹlẹ ri n’Ibadan. Awọn ti àárẹ̀ ba ti mu laarin awọn olufẹhonu han yii, kaka ki wọn pada sile wọn jẹẹjẹ, niṣe ni wọn n wa ibi kan nitosi lọọ sinmi, ti wọn si tun n pada sibi ifẹhonu han wọn ti ara wọn ba ti mokun.Ọkan ninu awọn oluwọde naa, ẹni to kọ lati darukọ ẹ fakọroyin wa ṣalaye pe “Ṣe ẹ ri i pe ọlọpaa kankan ko jade si wa lonii, nigba ti Gomina Makinde wa niluu Akurẹ fun amojuto eto idibo ti wọn ṣe lọjọ Satide lo pe ọga wọn pe wọn ko gbọdọ koju awọn to ba n ṣewọde mọ. “Ta a ba wo awọn SARS yii, loootọ ni wọn ni iwulo tiwọn, ṣugbọn ta a ba da iṣẹ ti wọn n ṣe si mẹwaa, aburu wọn lo ko mẹjọ nibẹ.  Bii apẹẹrẹ, ti wọn ba fura pe ọmọ Yahoo lẹnikan, wọn aa fi tipatipa gbowo lọwọ ẹ, lẹyin naa ni wọn maa pa a danu ko ma baa pada tu wọn laṣiiri lọjọ iwaju. Eeyan ti wọn ti ṣe bẹẹ pa danu ko niye.”"},{"question":"Analog signal-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"ஒப்புமை சமிக்ஞை"},{"question":"Huraikan pendapat anda tentang amalan gaya hidup sihat yang sewajarnya dipraktikkan oleh setiap individu. ","answer":"Amalan gaya hidup sihat memang banyak kepentingannya kepada manusia. Dengan mengamalkan gaya hidup sihat, seseorang akan sentiasa sihat, cergas dan bertenaga. Oleh itu, setiap orang hendaklah melakukan aktiviti yang dapat mengeluarkan peluh iaitu, sekurang-kurangnya tiga kali seminggu. Tindakan ini ibarat menyediakan payung sebelum hujan, iaitu seseorang itu akan dapat mengekalkan kecergasan dan seterusnya badan akan menjadi sihat melalui aktiviti senaman. Amalan ini seterusnya akan melahirkan rakyat yang sihat dan produktif selaras dengan matlamat kerajaan untuk meningkatkan produktiviti negara.     Amalan yang perlu dilakukan oleh anggota masyarakat ialah pengambilan makanan yang seimbang. Oleh itu, tubuh orang yang mengamalkan pemakanan seimbang ini akan mendapat khasiat dan vitamin yang diperlukan. Sebagai contohnya, seseorang itu perlu banyak mengambil makanan yang berserat seperti sayur-sayuran dan buah-buahan serta mengurangkan makanan yang berlemak atau mengandungi kolesterol yang tinggi. Dengan cara itu, penyakit berbahaya seperti penyakit jantung koronari, tekanan darah tinggi, dan diabetis akan dapat dielakkan kerana mencegah penyakit lebih baik daripada mengubatinya.     Amalan lain yang perlu diamalkan adalah dengan bersukan atau beriadah. Aktiviti sukan dan riadah yang dilakukan akan menyihatkan seseorang kerana aktiviti itu akan melancarkan perjalanan darah dan badan akan mengeluarkan peluh. Seseorang itu boleh bersukan seperti bermain badminton, bola sepak, menunggang basikal, berjoging, atau berenang. Jika badan seseorang itu sihat dan cergas, sudah pastilah daya pemikirannya juga cerdas kerana otak yang cerdas datangnya daripada tubuh yang cergas.     Setiap anggota masyarakat perlu melakukan pemeriksaan kesihatan secara berkala. Hal ini akan memastikan anggota dalaman tubuh seseorang itu seperti, jantung, hati, buah pinggang, dan pankreas berfungsi dengan baik. Melalui cara itu juga, penyakit berbahaya seperti penyakit jantung koronari, diabetis, dan tekanan darah tinggi dapat dapat dikesan lebih awal melalui peralatan moden dalam bidang perubatan. Dengan cara itu, langkah pemulihan akan dapat dilakukan dengan segera. Hal ini dikatakan demikian kerana alat-alat perubatan moden dapat mengesan sesuatu penyakit lebih awal dan tidaklah sudah terhantuk baru nak tengadah.     Sebagai kesimpulannya, amalan gaya hidup sihat memang perlu dijadikan budaya untuk melahirkan rakyat yang sihat. Jadi, Kementerian Kesihatan perlulah mengambil langkah yang proaktif untuk merealisasikan impian negara kita itu. Sekiranya langkah tersebut tidak diambil, sudah tentu hasrat untuk melahirkan masyarakat yang sihat dan cergas tidak akan menjadi kenyataan. Oleh itu, hasrat untuk melahirkan rakyat yang sihat dan cergas akan menjadi realiti jika semua pihak saling bekerjasama iaitu, yang berat sama dipikul, yang ringan sama dijinjing."},{"question":"*كم زوجة تزوج الملك البريطاني هنري الثامن ؟","answer":"6 زوجات"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'putih tapak kaki'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud lari sekuat-kuatnya. Contoh ayat: Putih tapak kakinya ketika melarikan diri apabia dikejar oleh anjing liar itu."},{"question":"උපයෝග්‍යතාවාදය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"උපයෝග්‍යතාවාදයේ හරය නම් සන්තුෂ්ටිය / සන්තෝෂය සහ දොම්නස / වේදනාව යන සංකල්පයයි. උපයෝග්‍යතා දර්ශණවාදය සන්තුෂ්ටිය වර්ධනය කර දොම්නස / වේදනාව අඩු කරන්නාවූ ඕනෑම දෙයක් \\"යහපත්\\" ලෙස දකී. ධය ප්‍රතිඵලයේ දර්ශණ වාදයයි. යම් ක්‍රියාවක ප්‍රතිඵලය සන්තෝෂය / සන්තුෂ්ටිය වර්ධනය කර දොම්නස / වේදනාව අඩු කරන්නේ නම්, එම ක්‍රියාව \\"යහපත්\\" ලෙස සළකනු ලැබේ. එහි අධිෂ්ඨානය නම්, උපයෝය්‍යතාවාදය යනු සුඛ පරමවාදී දර්ශණ වාදයයි. උපයෝග්‍යතාවාදයේ ඉතිහාසයේ අනුරේඛනය පුරාණ ග්‍රීක දර්ශණවාදියෙකු වන එපිකියුරස් දක්වා විහිදී යන නමුදු චින්තන ගුරුකුලයට අනුව උපයෝග්‍යතාවාදයේ ගෞරවය ලබන්නේ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ජාතික ජෙරමි බෙන්තම්ය. මෙි සියලුම දේ තුළින් උපයෝග්‍යතාවාදය දර්ශන විද්‍යාව ජීවිතය හැකි තරම් දුරට දොම්නස / වේදනාව / දුක තොර, දිවියකට හැකි තරම් සෙනඟක් වෙත ළඟා කරදීමේ උත්සාහයක යෙදේ. මතුපිටින් එය අගය කළයුතු ඉලක්කයක් ලෙස පෙනේ. ලොව පුරා දුක් විඳින ජනතාව ඉන් මුදවාලීමට කාටද අවශ්‍යතාවයක් නැත්තේ? පොළොවෙහි ජීවිතයෙන් එහා පැවැත්මක් පිළිබඳ බයිබලය පවසයි. අප ජීවත්වන්නේ මේ පොළොවෙහි ප්‍රීතිය උපරිම ලෙස භුක්ති විඳීමට නම්, අපට ඇති විශාල ඉමහත් යථාදර්ශණය අපගෙන් ගිලිහී යයි / මඟහැරී යයි."},{"question":"महाराष्ट्रातील कोणत्या जिल्ह्यात पुरुषांपेक्षा स्त्रियांचे प्रमाण अधिक आहे?","answer":"रत्नागिरी"},{"question":"¿Cuál es la respuesta correcta a esta pregunta?: ¿Cuántos equipos de Las Ligas Mayores jamás han ganado una Serie Mundial?","answer":"La respuesta correcta a la pregunta ¿Cuántos equipos de Las Ligas Mayores jamás han ganado una Serie Mundial? es 6 equipos"},{"question":" Qual país foi o vice-campeão da Copa do Mundo de Futebol Feminino de 2019?","answer":"A Holanda"},{"question":"Steeti ole dị na Naịjirịa. Depụta ha na isi obodo ha?","answer":"Enwere steeti iri atọ na isii na NaịjirịaNdị a bụ ndepụta State na isi obodo steeti Naijiria .Steeti\\t                   Isi obodoAbia steeti\\t           UmuahiaAdamawa\\t           YolaAkwa Ibom\\t           UyoAnambra\\t           AwkaBauchi\\t               BauchiBayelsa\\t               YenagoaBenue\\t                   MakurdiBorno\\t                   MaiduguriCross River\\t       CalabarDelta\\t                    AsabaEbonyi\\t                AbakalikiEdo\\t                        Obodo BeninEkiti\\t                        Ado EkitiEnugu\\t                    EnuguGombe\\t                GombeImo\\t                        OwerriJigawa\\t                UgwuKaduna\\t                KadunaKano\\t                    KanoKatsina\\t                KatsinaKebbi\\t                    Kebbi obodoKogi\\t                        LokojaKwara\\t                    IlorinLagos\\t                    IkejaNasarawa\\t            LafiaNiger\\t                   MinnaOgun\\t                   AbeokutaOndo\\t                   AkureOsun\\t                   OshogboOyo\\t                       IbadanPlateau\\t               JosOsimiri\\t               Port HarcourtSokoto\\t               SokotoTaraba\\t               JalingoYobe\\t                   DamaturuZamfara\\t               GusauFederal Capital Territory\\tAbuja"},{"question":"أنا طويل حينما أكون صغيرًا، وأكون قصيرًا حينما أصبح كبيرًا في السن، فمن أنا؟","answer":"الشمعة ، لإن الشمعة تكون طويلة في البداية ومن ثم تحترق وتصبح أصغر مع مرور الوقت."},{"question":"Title: ఉత్తరాంధ్రలో ఏనుగుల గుంపులు: దాడి సంకేతాలను ముందే గుర్తించడం ఎలాnSummary: విజయనగరం, శ్రీకాకుళం జిల్లాలను ఏనుగులు వణికిస్తున్నాయి. ఏనుగుల గుంపులు పంట చేలను నాశనం చేయడంతో పాటు, అప్పుడప్పుడూ మనుషులపై కూడా దాడి చేసి చంపేస్తున్నాయి.nArticle (Max 500 characters):","answer":"రెండు నెలల్లో ఐదుగురు వ్యక్తులు ఏనుగుల దాడిలో ప్రాణాలు కోల్పోయారంటే పరిస్థితి అర్థం చేసుకోవచ్చు. ఏనుగుల విధ్వంసం గురించి తెలుసుకొనేందుకు బీబీసీ తెలుగు బృందం పార్వతీపురం అటవీ ప్రాంతంలో పర్యటించింది.ఉత్తరాంధ్రలో ఏనుగుల గుంపులు: దాడి సంకేతాలను ముందే గుర్తించడం ఎలాఏనుగుల స్వైరవిహారం విజయనగరం జిల్లా పార్వతీపురం అటవీ రేంజ్ పరిధిలో ఏనుగులు స్వైరవిహారం చేస్తున్నాయి. ఒడిశాలోని లకేరీ అభయారణ్యం నుంచి ఎనిమిది ఏనుగుల గుంపు 2017లో విజయనగరం వచ్చింది. వాటిలో రెండు చనిపోగా, ఆరు ఏనుగులు తిరుగుతున్నాయి. ఇవేక"},{"question":"Àkóónú: Bí ẹlẹ́ṣin ṣe ń sunkún àìrílẹ̀ fi ẹṣin rìn, laláṣọ náà ń pariwo àìríòde fi lọ.Bí oníṣẹ́ ṣe ń pariwo àìráyè lọ ṣiṣẹ́ pawó sínú àpò l'aláìníṣẹ́ náà ń pariwo àìráyè káàkiri ibi àti wáṣẹ́ òòjọ́ lọ.Nítorí náà, kò sẹ́ni tí yóò gbọ́ ọ̀rọ̀ tí opóbìnrin Monínúọlá Ọ̀pẹ́bìyí bá BBC News Yorùbá sọ tí kò ní báa kẹ́dùn.A leè ṣe àkópọ̀ àkóónú yìí bayìí:","answer":"Kìí ṣe àsọdùn bí a bá wí pé ìpèníjà ńlá ni àsìkò àjàkálẹ̀ àrun coronavirus yìí ti mú jáde fún gbogbo mùtúmùwà."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"asam di darat, ikan di laut bertemu dalam belanga\\"?","answer":"Kalau sudah jodoh akan bertemu juga betapa pun jauhnya (jodoh itu tidak dapat ditentukan)"},{"question":"เหตุการณ์สำคัญจากข้อความต่อไปนี้คืออะไร: ใน ค.ศ. 625 เขามีส่วนร่วมในยุทธการที่อุฮุด ซึ่งฝ่ายมุสลิมพ่ายแพ้และเขาได้รับบาดเจ็บ ก่อนเริ่มสงคราม ลูกชายของเขา อับดุรเราะฮ์มาน อิบน์ อบีบักร์ ในตอนนั้นยังไม่เข้ารับอิสลาม และอยู่ฝ่ายกุเรช เดินมาข้างหน้าและท้าดวล อะบูบักร์รับคำท้า แต่ท่านศาสดามุฮัมมัดหยุดเขาไว้ จากนั้น อับดุรเราะฮ์มานเผชิญหน้ากับพ่อเขาและบอกว่า \\"นายเล็งผมเป็นเป้าหมาย แต่ผมหลีกหนีไปจากเจ้า และไม่ฆ่าเจ้า\\" อะบูบักร์จึงตอบว่า \\"อย่างไรก็ตาม ถ้าเจ้าเล็งข้าเป็นเป้าหมาย ข้าจะไม่หนีไปจากเจ้า\\"","answer":"ยุทธการที่อุฮุด"},{"question":"தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி என்றால் என்ன ? எடுத்துக்காட்டுக.","answer":"தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி:இயல்பாய் நிகழும் ஓர் நிகழ்ச்சியின் மீது கவிஞன் தன் குறிப்பினை ஏற்றிக் கூறுவது போல் அமையும் செய்யுகளை தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி என்றழைக்கின்றோம்.(எ.கா.) ‘போருழந் தெடுத்த ஆரெயில் நெடுங்கொடி  வாரல் என்பனபோல் மறித்துக்கை காட்ட’பொருள்:கோட்டை மதில் மேல் இருந்த கொடியானது வரவேண்டாம் எனத் தடுப்பதுபோல, கை காட்டியது என்பது பொருள்.அணிப்பொருத்தம் :கோவலனும், கண்ணகியும் மதுரை மாநகருக்குள் சென்றபோது மதிலின் மேலிருந்த கொடிகள் காற்றில் இயற்கையாக அசைந்தன. ஆனால், இளங்கோவடிகள் கோவலன் மதுரையில் கொலை களப்படுவான் எனக்கருதி அக்கொடிகள் கையை அசைத்து, ‘இம்மதுரைக்குள் வரவேண்டா’ என்று தெரிவிப்பது போலக் காற்றில் அசைவதாகத் தம் குறிப்பைக் கொடியின் மீது ஏற்றிக் கூறுகிறார். இவ்வாறு இயல்பாக நிகழும் நிகழ்ச்சியின் மீது கவிஞன் தன் குறிப்பை ஏற்றிக் கூறுவது தற்குறிப்பேற்ற அணி எனப்படும்."},{"question":"તુષાર શુક્લ ની \\"હોઇએ આપણ જેવા\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"હોઇએ આપણ જેવા એવા દેખાવાની મોસમ આવી,અંદર બહાર થઈને લથબથ લહેરાવાની મોસમ આવી.ઘડીક વાદળ, ઘડીક તડકો, ઘડીક વર્ષા, ઘડીક ભડકો,એક-મેકમાં ખોવાવાની, જડી જવાની મોસમ આવી.એકબીજાને દૂર દૂરથી જોયા કરતાં આમ ભલેને,આજ અડોઅડ એક-મેકને અડી જવાની મોસમ આવી.રેશમ રેશમ રૂપને પાછું ભીનું થઈને બહેકે અડકો,આજ પારદર્શક સુંદરતા નડી જવાની મોસમ આવી.વીતેલાં વર્ષોને ભુલી ચાલ ફરીથી પલળી જઇએ,ફરી ફરીને, ફરી પ્રેમમાં પડી જવાની મોસમ આવી."},{"question":"Quem foi a primeira mulher a ganhar o Prêmio Nobel em 1903?","answer":"Marie Curie. Ela recebeu o Prêmio Nobel de Química por suas investigações mais aprofundadas sobre rádio e polônio."},{"question":"Rabe-Raben Insha’i","answer":"Insha’i na Labari.Insha’i na Muhawara.Insha’i na Bayani.Insha’i na wasiƙa."},{"question":" Abwaan careys ciise kaarshe xagee ayuu kudhashtey? ","answer":" Waxa uukudhashtey deegaanka labaatan arifoof eegalbeedka kaxigta magalada kismaayo. 1"},{"question":"नर्मदा नदी खालीलपैकी कोणत्या राज्यात सर्वात जास्त वाहते?(A) उत्तीर्ण(B) राजस्थान(C) मध्य प्रदेश(D) महाराष्ट्र=> ","answer":"(C) मध्य प्रदेश"},{"question":"தமிழின் இலக்கணங்கள் மொத்தம் எத்தனை? அவை யாவை?","answer":"தமிழ் இலக்கணம் ஐந்து வகையாகப் பிரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. எனவே ஐந்திலக்கணம் என்ற சொல்மரபு வழங்கி வருகிறது. அவை, எழுத்து, சொல், பொருள், யாப்பு, அணி ஆகியவை ஆகும். இவற்றில் எழுத்து, சொல் இலக்கணங்கள் மொழிக்கு இலக்கணம் கூறுபவை ஆகும். அறிஞர்கள் தமிழ் இலக்கணத்தை மூன்று வகை இலக்கணம் என்றும் ஆறு இலக்கணம் என்றும் ஏழு இலக்கணம் என்றும் வகைப்படுத்துவர்."},{"question":"پوښتنه دا ده چې: \\"د موټربوټ یا موټربوټ برعکس چې د کښتۍ لاندې یا شاته په اوبو کې پروپیلر کاروي ، جیټ بوټ د کښتۍ لاندې اوبه د کښتۍ دننه پمپ ته راوباسي ، بیا یې په شا کې د نوز له لارې خارجوي.\\"? موضوع د جیټ بوټ دی.","answer":"د اوبو جیټ کښتۍ څنګه کار کوي؟"},{"question":"తెలుగు వ్యావహారిక భాషలో తరచు వాడే కింద ఇచ్చిన జాతీయం గురించి వివరించండి:  దిక్కులు పిక్కటిల్లడం","answer":"‘అంతటా వ్యాపించు’ అనే అర్థంలో వాడే జాతీయం."},{"question":"Iretiola Doyle","answer":"Ìrètíọlá Doyle (tí orúkọ ìbí jẹ́ Ìrètíọlá Olúṣọlá Àyìnkẹ́ ) jẹ́ òṣèré ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà.A bí Doyle ní ọjọ́ 3 Oṣù Karùn-ún Ọdún 1967 ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Òndó ṣùgbọ́n ó lo àwọn ìgbà èwe rẹ̀ pẹ̀lú ẹbí rẹ̀ ní Boston, orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà. Lẹ́hìn tí ó padà sí Nàìjíríà, ó lọ sí Ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ Christ's School ní Adó Èkìtì ó sì parí ilé-ìwé gíga Yunifásitì ti Jos pẹ̀lú oyè ní Eré Tíátà.Fún ìgbà tó ti lé ní ogún ọdún ní ìdi iṣẹ́ eré ìdárayá ti Nàìjíríà, Ìrètíọlá ti ní lórúkọ rẹ̀, àwọn iṣẹ́ lọ́lọ́kan-ò-jọ̀kan láti orí ìpele dé tẹlifíṣọ̀nù àti fíìmù.Ìrètíọlá Doyle jẹ́ ònkọ̀wé, òṣèré, olùgbéréjáde àti atọ́kùn ètò. Ó ṣe àgbéjáde àti àgbékalẹ̀ ètò kan tí ó dá lóri oge ṣíṣe àti ọ̀rọ̀ ìgbésí ayé tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ \\"Oge With Iretiola\\" fún ọdún mẹ́wàá, ó sì tún ṣe atọ́kùn ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn ètò tẹlifíṣọ̀nù bíi Morning Ride pẹ̀lu Today lóri ìkànnì STV àti Nimasa This Week lóri ìkànnì Channels TV. Ó jẹ́ ònkọ̀wé, ó sì ti kọ ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn eré.Ó ti rí yíyàn lẹ́ẹ̀kan rí fún ẹ̀ka ti òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ Reel Awards ní ọdún 1998 fún ipa rẹ̀ nínu fíìmù All About Eré àti lẹ́ẹ̀mejì fún ẹ̀ka ti òṣèré amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ AMAA Awards ní ọdún 2007 àti 2009 fún àwọn ipa rẹ̀ nínu Sitanda àti Across The Niger. Wọ́n sì tún ti kéde rẹ̀ rí gẹ́gẹ́ bi òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ ní ipa asíwájú níbi ayẹyẹ GIAMA Awards tí ó wáyé ní ìlú Houston Texas ní ọdún 2013, àti gẹ́gẹ́ bi òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ ní ipa asíwájú níbi ayẹyẹ Nollywood Movie Awards ti ọdún 2014 fún ipa rẹ̀ ti Ovo, nínu eré aṣaragágá Torn. Iṣé yìí tún fun lánfàní yíyàn fún àmì ẹ̀yẹòṣèré amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ tí ó dára jùlọ ní ọdún 2015 níbi African Magic Viewers' Choice Awards. Wọ́n tún yàán fún àmì ẹ̀yẹ míràn ní ọdún 2016 fún ipa asíwájú tí ó kó gẹ́gẹ́ bi Dr. Elizabeth nínu fíìmù Ebony Life aláṣeyọrí kan ti ọdún 2015 tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ FIFTY."},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  Alexis Ponnet (Bruxelas, 9 de março de 1939) é um ex-árbitro de futebol belga. Em 1986–87 arbitrou a","answer":"final da Taça dos Clubes Campeões Europeus entre o FC Porto e o Bayern de Munique."},{"question":"इलन मस्क","answer":"इलन मस्क एक अमेरिकी उद्यमी, उद्योग निर्माता र उपग्रहकार हुन्। उनले विभिन्न क्षेत्रहरूमा आफ्नो महत्त्वपूर्ण योगदान गरेका छन् र विज्ञान, प्रविधि, उर्जा, अङ्क, वाणिज्य, आदि क्षेत्रहरूमा उनको महत्त्वपूर्ण योगदान थियो।इलन मस्कले टेसला मोटर्स, स्पेसएक्स, न्यूरालिंक, बोरिंग कम्पनी जस्ता कम्पनिहरू स्थापित गरेका छन्। उनका मुख्यत्वमा आविष्कार र प्रविधि नवीनीकरणहरूमा उनले प्रमुख भूमिका खेलेका छन्।इलन मस्कले बिजुली गाडीहरू, उर्जा संग्रह तालिका, गगनयात्रा, मानव मस्तिष्क इन्टर्फेस जस्ता क्षेत्रहरूमा नयाँ अवसर र सम्भावनाहरू खोज्छन्।इलन मस्कले सार्वजनिक मन्चमा उनका वाद-विवादास्पद ट्विटर पोस्ट र आवश्यकता छाड्ने प्रशासनिक फैसलाहरूले मन परेको छ। उनको कार्यकलापहरूले उनलाई वैश्विक मान्छे बनाएको छ र उनलाई आत्मनिर्भक विज्ञानिक।"},{"question":"An bhfuil sé ceart go leor do leanaí scannán scanrúil a fheiceáil? ","answer":"Sea, tá sé go maith. Ach ní díreach roimh chodladh! Agus braitheann sé freisin ar aois an linbh agus cé chomh scanrúil is atá an scannán."},{"question":"Kinsa ang imong gika-uban sa Valentine's Day ug unsa ang imong gipanghimo?","answer":"Sa Valentine's Day, gika-uban nako ang akong uyab ug nagdala kami og kaon sa usa ka matahum nga restaurant."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত অনুচ্ছেদ সম্পূর্ণ করুন:দ্বিতীয় ফয়সাল (আরবি : الملك فيصل الثاني \\"Al-Malik Fayṣal Ath-thānī\\") (২রা মে ১৯৩৫ – ১৪ই জুলাই ১৯৫৮) ছিলেন ইরাকের শেষ বাদশাহ। ১৯৩৯ সালের ৪ এপ্রিল থেকে ১৯৫৮ সালের জুলাইয়ে নিহত হওয়ার আগ পর্যন্ত তিনি শাসন করেন। ১৪ জুলাই বিপ্লবে","answer":"তিনি তার পরিবারের অধিকাংশ সদস্যদের সাথে নিহত হন। এই হত্যাকান্ডের মাধ্যমে ইরাকে ৩৭ বছরব্যপী চলমান হাশেমি রাজত্বের অবসান ঘটে। এরপর কোনোপ্রকার গণভোট ছাড়াই ইরাককে প্রজাতন্ত্র ঘোষণা করা হয়।"},{"question":"په دې تپې کې، د پشکال څه معنی ده:د پشکال ګرمي پۀ زور ده زلفې دې غونډې کړه چې نۀ دې تنګوينه","answer":"دا کلمه د کال د اوړي د باران موسم معنی لري. پشکال د موسمي کال څلورمه میاشت ده. دې ته ساوڼ پشکال هم ویل کیږي."},{"question":" Sheeg Maxaa La Oran Jiray Ninkii Dilay Cumar Bin Khadaab","answer":" Cumar Bin Khadaab Ninkii Dilay Waxa La Oran Jiray Abuu Lu’lu Al Majuuz"},{"question":"*ما المدة التي يتحمل فيها العقرب العطش ؟","answer":"3 سنوات"},{"question":"ഒരു ഔട്ട്ഡോർ തലയിണ എങ്ങനെ ഉണ്ടാക്കാം? നിങ്ങൾക്ക് സാധ്യമായ രണ്ട് പരിഹാരങ്ങളുണ്ട്:പരിഹാരം 1: ഒരു ടിൻ ക്യാനിൽ ഊതി റബ്ബർ ബാൻഡ് ഉപയോഗിച്ച് കെട്ടുക. പരിഹാരം 2: ഒരു ട്രാഷ് ബാഗിലേക്ക് ഊതി റബ്ബർ ബാൻഡ് ഉപയോഗിച്ച് കെട്ടുക. ","answer":"പരിഹാരം 2 കൂടുതൽ ന്യായമാണ്. ഒരു ടിൻ ക്യാനിനെ അപേക്ഷിച്ച് ഒരു ട്രാഷ് ബാഗിലേക്ക് ഊതുന്നത് വളരെ എളുപ്പമാണ്."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fitaterana an'habakabaka?","answer":"ny atao hoe fitaterana an'habakabaka dia fitaterana amin'ny alalan'ny voromby lehibe"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ashirin da tara a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 29"},{"question":"Trong bài thơ Lượm của tác giả Tố Hữu, tác giả gọi Lượm bằng nhiều từ ngữ xưng hô khác nhau. Hãy tìm và cho biết mỗi từ ngữ đó thể hiện thái độ và tình cảm gì?","answer":"Tác giả gọi Lượm bằng nhiều từ ngữ xưng hô khác nhau:- Cháu → Sự thân thiết, gần gũi của mối quan hệ chú cháu.- Chú bé → Yêu mến khi ngắm nhìn dáng vẻ yêu đời, lạc quan khi làm nhiệm vụ của Lượm.- Lượm → Sự xót xa, thương cảm trước sự hi sinh của chú bé.- Chú đồng chí nhỏ → Mối quan hệ đồng chí với nhà thơ và cũng thể hiện Lượm là của mọi người, mọi nhà hi sinh vì quê hương, đất nước."},{"question":" ’அர்ஜூனா ‘ பதக்கம் எந்தத் துறையில் இருப்பவருக்கு வழங்கப்பப்படுகிறது?","answer":"விடை: விளையாட்டுத்துறை"},{"question":" waqala ngomphi unyaka uCanaan Banana ubangumongameli ?","answer":"Ngo 1980"},{"question":"Quando o Santos FC foi fundado?","answer":"O Santos FC foi fundado em 14 de abril de 1912."},{"question":"Ifẹhonu han la maa fi ayẹyẹ ‘June 12’ tọdun yii ṣe- Ẹgbẹ Akẹkọọ","answer":"Ẹgbẹ awọn akẹkọọ ilẹ wa, National Association of Nigerian Studens (NANS) ti kede pe ayẹyẹ ajọdun ijọba demokiresi ti wọn maa n ṣe lọjọ kejila, oṣu kẹfa, tọdun yii, ki i ṣe tilu-tifọn rara, iwọde ati ifẹhonu han ta ko ijọba Buhari ati eto aabo to mẹhẹ lawọn maa fi ṣe ni gbogbo ipinlẹ.Aarẹ apapọ ẹgbẹ naa, Ọgbẹni Sunday Dare Asefọn, lo sọrọ yii fawọn oniroyin lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii.Asefọn ni eto aabo ti dẹnu kọle debii pe awọn ọmọleewe ko le dori kọ ileewe pẹlu ifọwọsọya pe awọn maa pada sile lai sewu mọ, o lọrọ naa ti de gongo gidi.“Ka sọrọ sibi tọrọ wa, ijọba apapọ atawọn agbofinro ti ja wa kulẹ gan-an ni, ko seyii ta a le gbẹmi-in le ninu wọn mọ.”“Bi wọn ṣe n ji awọn ọmọleewe gbe lọgọrun-un lọgọrun-un lati bii ọdun meji sẹyin yii ti su wa, a o le maa wo ọrọ yii niran mọ, tori okun ajọṣe to so wa pọ niṣọkan lo ti fẹẹ ja yii.A maa ṣe iwọde lati ipinlẹ kan si ekeji, a fẹ kijọba apapọ tete ṣeto apero tawọn agbaagba ti maa fori kori, ki wọn si wa ojuutu gidi si iṣoro yii, konikaluku sọ ero ati ifẹ ọkan rẹ jade.A tun fẹ kijọba apapọ kede titi ilẹkun gbogbo awọn ileewe to wa lagbegbe Oke-Ọya pa ni saa yii na, titi ti wọn fi maa pese aabo to muna doko sibẹ."},{"question":"Адашкандын айыбы жок кайра үйүрүн тапкан соң.Ачылгандын айыбы жок өзү билип жапкан соң.Макалды чечмелеп бериңиз?","answer":"Адам баласы өз кемчилигин өзү билип моюнга алуусу, кемчилигин үстүндө иштеп оңолуусу, кайра үйнө кайтып келүүсү жөнүндө сөз болуп жатат."},{"question":"Inona ary izany : mihiratra tsy mahita azy, mikimpy vao mahita azy ?","answer":"Ny valiny dia: Torimaso no ikimpiana vao mahita azy."},{"question":"Ang mga sumusunod nga sentensya kay Ingels, e-translate sa Bisaya\\"How are you today?\\"","answer":"\\"Kumusta?\\""},{"question":"\\"රජුට අනුශාසනා කරන්නා\\" යන්නට වඩාත්ම ගැලපෙන කෙටි පදය කුමක්ද? (ඔබට භාවිතා කල හැක්කේ එක වචනයක් පමණි)","answer":"\\"පුරෝහිතයා\\" වඩාතම ගැලපෙන තනි පදයයි."},{"question":"من هو عازف الطبول الأول في فرقة البيتلز؟","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي بيت بيست - Pete Best."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Niala fisentoana tokoa izy rehefa hitany ireo entany very. »","answer":"Maneho hafaliana izany. Faly ilay olona satria hita indray izay saika very."},{"question":"Quando o Corinthians foi fundado?","answer":"O Corinthians foi fundado em 1º de setembro de 1910."},{"question":"කම්පාලා නගරය කිනන් රටක අගනුවරද ?","answer":"උගන්ඩාව"},{"question":"十二生肖是指什么？","answer":"十二生肖，又叫十二属相，是中国传统的一种用来表示年份的方法。它将十二种动物与十二地支相配，形成：子鼠、丑牛、寅虎、卯兔、辰龙、巳蛇、午马、未羊、申猴、酉鸡、戌狗、亥猪。"},{"question":"เขียนความถัดไปสําหรับข้อความนี้ - รีสโดยทั่วไปถือว่าเป็นตํานานในโลกของโป๊กเกอร์ ในปี 1991 เขากลายเป็นนักพนันที่อายุน้อยที่สุดที่ได้รับการยกย่องในหอแห่งชื่อเสียงโป๊กเกอร์ การชนะครั้งสุดท้ายของเขาเกิดขึ้นใน 2006 World Series of Poker","answer":", ที่เขาได้รับรางวัลเป็นเงินจำนวน 1,784,640 ดอลลาร์สหรัฐในกิจกรรม HORSE."},{"question":"O que significa o nome MAR de um novo museu brasileiro?","answer":"Museu de Arte do Rio."},{"question":"Continue the paragraph: The respiratory system is more than just a conduit for oxygen...","answer":"It is a dynamic system where gaseous exchange powers cellular functions. Lungs, with their vast alveolar surface area, facilitate the transfer of oxygen into the bloodstream and the removal of carbon dioxide. The rhythmic act of breathing, regulated by the brainstem, ensures a constant supply of fresh air, while the protective mechanisms, like cilia and mucus, guard against pathogens and pollutants. The intricate balance of this system is evident in conditions like asthma or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, where airflow is compromised."},{"question":"Kámẹ́rà","answer":"Kamẹ́rà jẹ́ àpótí rébété tí ó ní ojú tí a lè fi yan àwòrán yálà àwòrán onígun méjì tàbí mẹ́ta. Gbogbo àwọn kámẹ́rà ni wọ́n ma ń jẹ́ àpótí rébété kan tí a kàn pa tí ó ní ihò bíntín tí oyè ìmọ́lẹ̀ lè gbà kọjá láti gba àwòrán sílẹ̀ sínú dígí tí wọ́n ti ṣepa sínú rẹ̀. Kámẹ́rà ní àwọn irinṣẹ́ kan tí wọ́n ma ń lò láti fi ya àwòrán ní àsìkò tí kò bá sí inọ́lẹ̀ tó já geere. Lára rẹ̀ ni lẹ́nsì tí wọ́n sopọ̀ mọ́ àpótí kámẹ́rà náà. Lára rẹ̀ náà ni ìrìnṣẹ́ tí wọ́n ń pe ní shutter speed, èyí ni ó ma ń ka iye àsìkò àti eré tí mọ̀nà-mọ́ná gbà keje nínú Kámẹ́rà náà.Àwòrán tí ó dúró bọrọgidi ni won sábà ma ń fi Kámẹ́rà yà, ba kan náà ni wọ́n ti ń fi kámẹ́rà ya àwọn àwòrán tí wọ́n ń lọ tí wọ́n bọ̀. Irúfẹ́ àwọn àwòrám tí wọ́n ń lọ bọ̀ yí a wọ́n ń ṣàkójọ rẹ̀ tí wọ́n fi ń ṣe fíímù agbéléwò tàbí sinimá."},{"question":"સમય જતાં ગ્રેના શરીરરચના શોમાં દવાનું ચિત્રણ કેવી રીતે વિકસિત થયું છે?","answer":"ગ્રેની એનાટોમીને દવાના વાસ્તવિક ચિત્રણ માટે વખાણવામાં આવી છે, અને શોએ નવીનતમ તબીબી પ્રગતિઓ પર અદ્યતન રહેવાનો પ્રયાસ કર્યો છે. જો કે, શોની તેની પ્રસંગોપાત અચોક્કસતા અને તબીબી ઘટનાઓને સનસનાટીભર્યા બનાવવાની વૃત્તિ માટે ટીકા પણ કરવામાં આવી છે."},{"question":"Ity fanambarana manaraka ity dia amin'ny teny malagasy, adikao amin'ny teny frantsay\\"Te handray anjara amin'ny fiarovana ny tontolo iainana aho.\\"","answer":"Je veux contribuer à la conservation de l'environnement."},{"question":"Dê-me um exemplo de curiosidade nesta categoria: esportes.","answer":"Qual time venceu o Super Bowl V? Baltimore Colts"},{"question":"வினா:உலகில் வாழும் மக்களில் சிலர் கனியிருக்கக் காய் புசித்தலைப்போல, இன்சொல் இருக்க வன்சொல் பேசி இன்னற்படுகின்றனர்.","answer":"விடை:புவியில் வாழும் மானுடர்கள் சிலர் பழமிருக்கக் காய் உண்பதைப்போல இன்சொல் இருக்க வன்சொல் பேசி துன்பப்படுகின்றனர்."},{"question":"د لاندې متن لیکلو ته دوام ورکړئ: ویلیوس ګالټیر ته وکتل. \\"زه کیپل اتیر یم.\\" ګاولټیر د خپل جاکټ څخه یوه ورځپاڼه راوویستله.","answer":"ورځپاڼه"},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள் - இசுராலின் சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தை தனது முழுமையான கட்டுப்பாட்டுக்குள் கொண்டு வந்த பின்னர் (1930 கள் தொடக்கம்) தேசியங்கள் தொடர்பான கொள்கைகள் நேர் எதிராக மாறின. தேசியங்கள் உருசிய சோவியத்துடன் ஒத்துப் போவது, நடுவன் அரசிற்கு கட்டுப்படுவது அவருக்கு முக்கியம் ஆகிற்று. உருசிய மொழியும் பண்பாடும் முதன்மை பெற்று, அவையே சோவியத் ஒன்றியத்தின் இணைப்புக் கூறுகளாக அவரால் முன்னிறுத்தப்பட்டன. இதனால் உருசியர் இல்லாத தேசியங்களை நசுக்குவதில் அவர் ஈடுபட்டார். இதன் ஒரு கோரமான ஒரு வெளிப்பாட யுக்ரேனிய மக்களை கட்டாயைப் பட்டினிப் படுகொலை செய்த கோலதமோர்","answer":"."},{"question":"Indro misy toe-javatra: \\"Ny elefanta, ireo goavam-be terestrialy ireo, dia manana rafitra ara-tsosialy sarotra ary mahay mitadidy lalana sy loharanon-drano.\\" Inona no fanontaniana mety napetraka raha ohatra ka \\"Elefanta\\" no valiny?","answer":"Inona avy ireo biby an-tanety malaza amin'ny rafitra ara-piarahamonina sarotra sy mahay mitadidy lalana sy loharanon-drano?"},{"question":"Iza no tena mpandray anjara amin'ny ady an-trano?","answer":"Ny mpandray anjara fototra dia mety ahitana ny governemanta, vondrona mpikomy, antokom-poko na fivavahana, ary koa ireo mpilalao iraisam-pirenena manohana antoko samihafa."},{"question":"2021 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්වලට අනුව ඉදිරියෙන්ම සිටින විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"2021 ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ විශ්වවිද්‍යාල ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම්වලට අනුව ඉදිරියෙන්ම සිටින විශ්වවිද්‍යාලය  කොලඹ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයයි."},{"question":"أخبرنى عن الجبن الأبيض من فضلك.","answer":"من دواعى سرورى.يوجد العديد من أنواع الجبن الأبيض المختلفة، ولكن أشهرها الجبن القريش والجبن الريكوتا والجبن الموزاريلا. يُصنع الجبن الأبيض من حليب الأبقار أو الماعز أو الأغنام، ويُعالج بإضافة إنزيم الرنين، الذي يتسبب في تجلط الحليب. يُصنع الجبن الأبيض عادةً من حليب منخفض الدسم، ولذلك يكون قوامه خفيفًا وذو مذاق رقيق. يُستخدم الجبن الأبيض في العديد من الأطباق المختلفة، بما في ذلك السلطات والسندويشات والبيتزا. كما أنه يستخدم في صنع الحلويات، مثل تشيز كيك وكعك الجبن.كما يعتبر الجبن الأبيض هو مصدر جيد للبروتين والكالسيوم والفوسفور. كما أنه يحتوي على كمية قليلة من الدهون والسعرات الحرارية."},{"question":"Àwo̩n Ò̩jò̩gbò̩n Nínú Èdè àti Lítírés̩ò̩ Yorùbá","answer":"Àwo̩n Ò̩jò̩gbò̩n Nínú Èdè àti Lítírés̩ò̩ Yorùbá Professors of the Yorùbá Linguistics, Language, Literature & CultureS/N Oruko Yunifasiti 1. Emeritus Professor Adeboye Babalola University of Lagos 2. Emeritus Professor Ayo Bamgbose University of Ibadan 3. Professor Oladele Awobuluyi Adekunle Ajasin University 4. Professor Sope Oyelaran Obafemi Awolowo University 5. Professor Wande Abimbola Obafemi Awolowo University 6. Professor Olatunde Olatunji University of Ibadan 7. Professor Akinwumi Isola Obafemi Awolowo University 8. Professor Kola Owolabi University of Ibadan 9. Professor Adegboyega Alaba University of Lagos 10. Professor Afolabi Olabimtan University of Lagos 11. Professor Bade Ajuwon Obafemi Awolowo University 12. Professor T. M. Ilesanmi Obafemi Awolowo University 13. Professor (Mrs.) Olutoye University of Lagos 14. Professor Adebisi Ogunsina University of Ilorin 15. Professor L. Olufemi Adewole Obafemi Awolowo University 16 Professor Rotimi Badejo University of Maiduguri 17. Professor Adedotun Ogundeji University of Ibadan 18. Professor Yinka Folorunso Lagos State University 19. Professor Goke Akinlabi University of Ibadan 20. Professor Bade Ajayi University of Ilorin 21. Professor Olabode University of Ibadan 22. Professor Sola Adebajo Ogun State Univeristy Ago-Iwoye 23. Professor S. O. Oyetade University of Ibadan 24. Professor (Mrs.) Oluyemisi Adebowale Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba 25. Professor Olusola Olateju University of Ibadan 26. Professor Jibola Abiodun Ekiti State University Ado-Ekiti 27. Professor Tunde Akinyemi University of Florida 28. Professor (Mrs.) Arinpe Adejumo University of Ibadan 29. Professor Francis Oyebade Adekunle Ajasin University Akungba 30. Professor Duro Adeleke University of Ibadan 31. Professor (Mrs.) Laide Sheba Obafemi Awolowo University 32. Professor Taiwo Olunlade Lagos State University 33. Professor O̩ladiipo Ajiboye University of Lagos 34. Professor Oye Taiwo University of Ibadan 35. Professor Lere Adeyemi University of Ilorin 36. Professor Harrison Adeniyi Lagos State University 37. Professor Felix Abidemi Fabunmi Obafemi Awolowo University 38. Professor George Olusola Ajibade Obafemi Awolowo University"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:కృష్ణవేణి ఈ నాటికలో మధ్యతరగతి అమ్మాయి. ఇంటిని పోషించడం కోసం ఉద్యోగం చేస్తుంటుంది. తల్లి, అన్నయ్యలను ఎంతో అభిమానంగా చూసుకుంటుంది. తెల్లారి లేస్తూనే ఇంట్లో చాకిరీ, తరువాత ఆఫీసులో పని, తిరగి ఇంటికి వచ్చాక వంట మొదలైన పనులతో నిరంతరం విసుగు లేకుండా పనిచేస్తూ ఉంటుంది.ధైర్య సాహసాలు గల వ్యక్తిగా కనబడినా ఎక్కడో ఆడపిల్లనని గుర్తుచేసే సందర్భాల వల్ల కొంత బెరుకుతనం గల స్త్రీమూర్తి.మేడమీద అద్దెకు దిగిన వ్యక్తి మీరేనా అంటూ పరిచయం చేసుకుంటుంది. గోడకు మేకులు కొట్టి మాకు నిద్రాభంగం కలిగించారని నిర్మొహమాటంగా చెప్తుంది. ఇంటిగలాయన మేకులు కొడితే ఊరుకోడు. బంగారు గోడలు పాడయిపోతాయని బాధ పడతాడని అంటుంది. చల్లగాలికి ఆహ్లాదంగా సినిమాకు వెళ్ళితే బాగుంటుందని మనసులో మాట బయటకే అనేస్తుంది. పాటలంటే మీకు ఇష్టమా ?","answer":"అయితే మా ఇందిర బాగా పాడుతుందని యువకునితో అంటుంది. గల్లీలో ఎవరో పోయిన సందర్భంలో శవాలంటే భయం అంటూ ఇంట్లోకి వెళ్ళిపోతుంది. పేరు అడగలేదని యువకుడు అనుకుంటూ అంత ధైర్యంలోనూ పిరికితనం ఇదే మానవ నైజం అని అనుకుంటాడు.పై గదిలో అద్దెకు వచ్చిన అబ్బాయి పేరేమిటని అన్నయ్యను అడుగుతుంది. అందుకు అన్నయ్య విసుక్కుంటాడు. పనిపాట లేక వాళ్ళ పేరేమిటి ? వీళ్ళ పేరేమిటి అని ఇటువంటి ఆలోచనలు ఎందుకు. తనకే గనక ఉద్యోగం దొరికితే ముందు చెల్లెల్ని ఉద్యోగం మానిపించేస్తానని అంటాడు. అందుకు చాలా బాధపడుతుంది. నా ఉద్యోగం మానిపించేంత వరకు నీకు మనశ్శాంతి ఉండధా ? ఏం మనుషులో ఏ మాత్రం సంతృప్తిగా ఉన్నా సహించలేరు. అదంతా అభిమానమేననుకుంటారు.అంత ప్రేమలేక పోయినా కాస్త సుఖపడేదాన్ని అని బాధపడుతుంది కృష్ణవేణి. నిద్రపట్టక కృష్ణవేణి ఇందిర, ఆనందలక్ష్మిల ఇంటికి వస్తుంది. ఇంత రాత్రివేళ వచ్చావేంటి అంటుంది ఇందిర. పగలంతా ఆఫీసులో పని. ఇంట్లో మళ్ళీ వండి వార్చినా నీకు నిద్ర రాకపోవటం ఏమిటి అని లక్ష్మీ అడుగుతుంది. మా అన్నయ్య రెండు వందల ఏళ్ళ క్రిందట పుట్టవలసినవాడు. వాడికి ఉద్యోగం దొరకటం లేదన్న కసితో నా ఉద్యోగాన్ని మానిపించేయాలని అంటూ ఉంటాడు. నా జీతం మీద ప్రేమే మళ్ళీ.ఎంత అభిమానంగా చేసినా ఈ మాటలు పడలేకపోతున్నాను. ఎంతకాలం మాటలు పడను చెప్పు. ఎవరి కోసం, ఎందుకోసం ఈ త్యాగం అని స్నేహితురాళ్ళతో తన బాధనంతటినీ చెప్పుకుంటుంది. జీవితంపై విరక్తిని పెంచుకొని నిరాశలో బ్రతుకుతుంది. చివరకు తాతగారి ఉపదేశం వల్ల మళ్లీ కొత్త ఆశలతో ధైర్యంగా తన పని ఏదో తాను చేసుకోగలుగుతుంది కృష్ణవేణి."},{"question":"آیا روش پخت برنج قهوه‌ای با برنج سفید فرق می‌کند؟","answer":"پخت برنج قهوه‌ای آب کمتری می‌خواهد. مثلاً اگر یک پیمانه برنج دارید، باید یک و سه‌چهارم پیمانه آب داشته باشید. وقتی هم برنج درست شد، ده دقیقه بگذارید دم‌کنی روی آن باشد. اگر همان لحظه دم‌کنی را بردارید برنج خشک و سفت می‌شود."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഭാഗം വായിച്ച് ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക. ഖണ്ഡിക:ഡിറ്റക്ടീവ് നോവലുകൾക്കും ചെറുകഥകൾക്കും പേരുകേട്ട പ്രശസ്ത ബ്രിട്ടീഷ് എഴുത്തുകാരിയായിരുന്നു അഗത ക്രിസ്റ്റി, പലപ്പോഴും \\"നിഗൂഢതയുടെ രാജ്ഞി\\" എന്ന് വിളിക്കപ്പെടുന്നു. അവളുടെ ശ്രദ്ധേയമായ വിവരണങ്ങളിൽ പലപ്പോഴും ഹെർക്കുൾ പൊയ്‌റോട്ട്, മിസ് മാർപ്പിൾ തുടങ്ങിയ ഐക്കണിക് ഫിക്ഷൻ ഡിറ്റക്ടീവുകൾ ഉണ്ടായിരുന്നു. ക്രിസ്റ്റിയുടെ സൃഷ്ടികൾ അവരുടെ സങ്കീർണ്ണമായ പ്ലോട്ടുകൾ, നന്നായി വികസിപ്പിച്ച കഥാപാത്രങ്ങൾ, അപ്രതീക്ഷിത ട്വിസ്റ്റുകൾ എന്നിവയ്ക്ക് പ്രശംസിക്കപ്പെട്ടു, ലോകത്തെ ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ വായിക്കപ്പെടുകയും വിവർത്തനം ചെയ്യപ്പെടുകയും ചെയ്ത എഴുത്തുകാരികളിൽ ഒരാളായി അവളെ മാറ്റി.ചോദ്യം: ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഈ ഭാഗം അഗത ക്രിസ്റ്റിയുടെ ഒരു ഹ്രസ്വ അവലോകനം നൽകുന്നു, ഡിറ്റക്ടീവ് നോവലുകളുടെയും ചെറുകഥകളുടെയും സമൃദ്ധമായ ബ്രിട്ടീഷ് രചയിതാവ് എന്ന നിലയിൽ അവളുടെ ശ്രദ്ധേയമായ സംഭാവനകളെ കേന്ദ്രീകരിച്ച്, അവളുടെ സങ്കീർണ്ണമായ പ്ലോട്ടുകൾക്കും ഐക്കണിക് ഫിക്ഷൻ ഡിറ്റക്ടീവുകൾക്കും വേണ്ടി ആഘോഷിക്കപ്പെടുന്നു."},{"question":"En el refrán: \\"La tecnología avanza sin cesar, pero la sabiduría de usarla es el verdadero tesoro\\". Cual es el tema principal?","answer":"La sabiduría y la tecnología "},{"question":"Tóm tắt văn bản sau: Hội thảo được tổ chức với mục tiêu phân tích và đánh giá tiềm năng mà chuyển dịch năng lượng mang tới cho sự phát triển kinh tế cũng như thị trường lao động Việt Nam. Theo đó, chuyển dịch năng lượng cần phải xem xét và kết hợp các khía cạnh xã hội, văn hóa, môi trường, kinh tế và bản sắc để đảm bảo công bằng, không ai bị bỏ lại phía sau.Sự kiện thu hút gần 200 đại biểu tham gia trực tiếp và hơn 300 đại biểu tham gia trực tuyến đến từ Quốc hội, Bộ Lao động-Thương binh và Xã hội, Bộ Công thương, Tập đoàn Điện lực Việt Nam, Phòng Thương mại và Công nghiệp Việt Nam, Viện Hàn lâm Khoa học Xã hội Việt Nam, Viện nghiên cứu Việc làm Đức, Viện Tương lai Bền vững – Đại học Công nghệ Sydney và các đại diện khu vực tư nhân.Phát biểu khai mạc hội thảo, TS. Guido Hildner, Đại sứ CHLB Đức tại Việt Nam chia sẻ kinh nghiệm của nước Đức: \\"Ở Đức, trong giai đoạn từ năm 2012 đến năm 2020, số lượng nhân viên làm việc trong các ngành nghề có kỹ năng xanh đã tăng 56,7% lên 5 triệu người. Điều này cho thấy quá trình chuyển dịch năng lượng là một quá trình phức tạp với đòi hỏi khắt khe, nhưng cũng là những cơ hội to lớn mang lại lợi ích cho người dân và nền kinh tế\\".Bà Nguyễn Thị Hà, Thứ trưởng Bộ Lao động - Thương binh và Xã hội Việt Nam ghi nhận tầm quan trọng của việc bồi dưỡng và nâng tầm kỹ năng cho người lao động và cho rằng đây là giải pháp cần thiết để hỗ trợ người lao động duy trì việc làm, chuyển đổi việc làm từ đó duy trì sinh kế và ổn định cuộc sống trong quá trình chuyển đổi năng lượng.Bà kỳ vọng các chuyên gia, đại biểu tham dự chia sẻ những kinh nghiệm thực tế về việc khai mở tiềm năng về chuyển đổi năng lượng, đề xuất những giải pháp cụ thể liên quan tới việc làm, đào tạo các kỹ năng cho người lao động để phục vụ thực hiện mục tiêu chuyển đổi năng lượng công bằng.Hội thảo có phần thảo luận nhóm chuyên sâu ở 5 lĩnh vực: điện gió, điện mặt trời, vai trò của phụ nữ trong ngành năng lượng, hiệu quả năng lượng và giao thông xanh. Các đại biểu đến từ khu vực công - tư cùng thảo luận, phân tích và đề xuất các giải pháp đột phá cho quá trình chuyển dịch năng lượng công bằng ở Việt Nam.Các chuyên gia khẳng định rằng cần phải có các giải pháp phát triển kỹ năng và thúc đẩy việc làm để hiện thực hóa tiềm năng việc làm trong lĩnh vực này. Đồng thời cần lưu tâm đến vấn đề bình đẳng giới và nâng cao vai trò của phụ nữ trong quá trình chuyển dịch năng lượng.Ông Tạ Đình Thi, Phó chủ nhiệm Ủy ban Khoa học, Công nghệ và Môi trường của Quốc hội khẳng định: \\"Việt Nam cùng với cộng đồng quốc tế cam kết phấn đấu đạt mục tiêu trung hòa carbon vào năm 2050 và theo đuổi quá trình chuyển đổi năng lượng công bằng. Chúng tôi nhận thức được tầm quan trọng của việc phát triển các kỹ năng cần thiết và sẵn sàng học hỏi từ các điển hình tốt trên thế giới; đồng thời, đánh giá cao mối quan hệ Hợp tác Việt - Đức và tin tưởng mối quan hệ này sẽ đóng góp tích cực vào quá trình chuyển đổi năng lượng công bằng và tương lai xanh, phát triển bền vững cho Việt Nam\\".Hội thảo kỳ vọng tạo ra một diễn đàn để đưa chủ đề chuyển dịch năng lượng gắn liền với chuyển dịch việc làm đến gần với công chúng, và quan trọng hơn hết là Việt Nam có những quyết sách đúng đắn và phù hợp để chuyển dịch năng lượng một cách công bằng và bền vững.","answer":"Hôm 20.9, tại Hà Nội, sứ quán Đức tại Việt Nam chủ trì Hội thảo 'Chuyển dịch năng lượng công bằng = Cơ hội cho thị trường lao động Việt Nam? Góc nhìn của Đức và Việt Nam về nhu cầu lao động và kỹ năng'."},{"question":"नियमों का एक सेट जो अक्सर कंप्यूटर द्वारा समस्या का हल करने के लिए उपयोग किया जाता है, उसे क्या कहा जाता है? पिछले प्रश्न को देखते हुए, एक संदर्भ लिखें जिसमें उत्तर हो। यह 1 से 20 वाक्यों का सकता है। संदर्भ:","answer":"जटिलता वर्ग-पी को अक्सर उन कम्प्यूटेशनल कार्यों की मॉडलिंग करने वाले गणितीय अमूर्त के रूप में देखा जाता है जो एक कुशल एल्गोरिथ्म को स्वीकार करते हैं। इस परिकल्पना को कोबहम-एडमंड्स थीसिस कहा जाता है। दूसरी ओर, जटिलता वर्ग-एनपी में कई समस्याएं होती हैं जिन्हें लोग कुशलता से हल करना चाहते हैं, लेकिन जिनके लिए कोई कुशल एल्गोरिथ्म ज्ञात नहीं है, जैसे कि बूलियन संतुष्टता समस्या, हैमिल्टनियन पथ समस्या और वर्टेक्स कवर समस्या। चूंकि निर्णायक ट्यूरिंग मशीनें विशेष गैर-निर्णायक ट्यूरिंग मशीनें हैं, यह आसानी से देखा जा सकता है कि पी में प्रत्येक समस्या भी वर्ग एनपी की  सदस्य हैं।"},{"question":"What are reading skills ?","answer":"Reading skills are the abilities that allow us to read and understand written text. They include a variety of sub-skills, such as:Decoding: the ability to identify and pronounce wordsFluency: the ability to read smoothly and accurately at a pace that allows us to understand the text.Vocabulary: the knowledge of the meaning of words.Comprehension: The ability to understand the meaning of a text, including the main ideas, supporting details, and inferences.Critical thinking: the ability to think about and evaluate the text, including its purpose, author's point of view, and evidence.Text structure: the ability to identify the different parts of a text and how they are organized.Inference: the ability to make logical deductions from the text.Summarization: The ability to condense the text into a brief, accurate statement of the main points.Visualization: the ability to create mental images of the events or scenes described in the text.These skills are all interrelated and work together to allow us to read and understand written text. The more developed our reading skills are, the better we will be able to read and understand a variety of texts, from simple stories to complex textbooks.There are many things we can do to improve our reading skills. Here are a few tips:Read often. The more we read, the better our reading skills will become.Read a variety of texts. This will help us develop a broad range of reading skills.Read challenging texts. This will help us push ourselves and improve our skills.Take breaks: Don't try to read for too long at a time without taking a break.Ask questions. If we don't understand something, don't be afraid to ask questions.Talk about what we read. This will help us to solidify our understanding of the text.Reading skills are an essential part of learning and communication. By developing our reading skills, we can open up a world of knowledge and opportunity."},{"question":"చోళుల స్థానిక స్వపరిపాలనలోని గొప్ప అంశాలను తెలియచేయండి.","answer":"చోళుల పాలనా వ్యవస్థలోని ముఖ్య లక్షణం వారి స్థానిక స్వపరిపాలనా విధానం. చోళుల గ్రామ పరిపాలననే “స్థానిక స్వపరిపాలన” అని కూడా అంటారు. మొదటి పరాంతకుని ఉత్తరమేరూర్ శాసనంలోను, కులోత్తుంగుని శాసనాల్లోను చోళుల గ్రామ పాలనా పద్ధతి వివరించబడింది.గ్రామ పాలన: చోళుల సామ్రాజ్యంలో ప్రతి గ్రామానికి స్వయం పాలనాధికారం ఉంది. ప్రతి గ్రామంలోను గ్రామ పెద్దల సభ వుండేది. ఈ గ్రామ సభ స్వరూప స్వభావాలను గ్రామ గ్రామానికి మారుతుండేవి.గ్రామ సభలు: చోళుల కాలంలో గ్రామాల్లో మూడు రకాల సభలుండేవి. అవి: 1) ఊర్. 2) సభ. 3) నగరం. ఊర్ అనే సభలో గ్రామంలోని భూస్వాములందరూ సభ్యులే. “సభ”లో బ్రాహ్మణ అగ్రహారంలోని వారు మాత్రమే సభ్యులుగా ఉండేవారు. ‘నగరం’ అనేది వర్తకులకు సంబంధించిన సభ. బ్రాహ్మణ అగ్రహారంలోని సభ్యులకు దేవాలయమే సమావేశపు స్థలం. కొన్ని గ్రామాల్లో ప్రత్యేకించి కచేరీలుండేవి.సభ్యుల ఎన్నిక: చోళుల కాలంలో ప్రతి గ్రామాన్ని 30 వార్డులుగా విభజించారు. ప్రతి వార్డు నుండి ఒక సభ్యుడ్ని లాటరీ పద్ధతిపై ఎన్నుకునేవారు. ఈ సభ్యులను గ్రామసభ ఉపసంఘాలుగా నియమించేది. చెరువులు, సత్రాలు, ఆలయాలు, తోటలు, పాఠశాలలు, నేర విచారణ, పన్నుల వసూలు మొదలైన వాటికి ప్రత్యేక ఉపసంఘాలుండేవి. “పంచదార వారియం” అనే ఉపసంఘం మిగిలిన సంఘాల కార్యక్రమాలను పరిశీలించేది.అర్హతలు: గ్రామసభలోని సభ్యుల అర్హతలను గురించి ప్రత్యేక నిబంధనావళిని రూపొందించి అమలు చేశారు. సభ్యులుగా ఎన్నుకోబడుటకు ఒక వ్యక్తికి కొన్ని అర్హతలుండాలి. అతడు30 నుండి 70 సంవత్సరాల లోపు వయస్సు కలిగి వుండాలి.విద్యావంతుడై వుండాలి.సొంత ఇల్లు కలిగి భూమికి యజమానై వుండాలి.అనర్హతలు: గ్రామసభ సభ్యులకు కొన్ని అర్హతలతో పాటు కొన్ని అనర్హతలు కూడా నిర్దేశించారు. గ్రామసభకు ఎన్నుకోబడదలచుకున్న వ్యక్తిపంచ మహాపాపాలు చేసినవాడై ఉండకూడదు.గత మూడు సంవత్సరాలుగా ఏ ఉపసంఘంలోను సభ్యుడిగా ఉండరాదు.ఒకసారి సభ్యుడిగా ఉండి లెక్కలను సరిగా అప్పగించని వాడు కూడా అనర్హుడే.నేరస్తులు వారి బంధువులు కూడా ఈ ఎన్నికల్లో పాల్గొనకూడదు.గ్రామ సభ అధికారాలు: గ్రామంలోని భూములపై యాజమాన్యపు హక్కు సభకు ఉన్నది. పన్నులను విధించుట, అడవులను నరికించి కొత్త భూములను సాగులోకి తీసుకువచ్చుట మొదలగునవి ఈ సభ ముఖ్య విధులు. వీటితోపాటు భూమి, నీటి తగవులను పరిష్కరించుట, నేరాలను విచారించుట కూడా దీని విధులుగా చెప్పుకోవచ్చు. అయితే ఆదాయ వనరులు తక్కువ కావటంతో కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వమే రహదారులు నిర్మించగా వాటిపై అజమాయిషీని సభ నిర్వహించేది. గ్రామసభలకు సలహాలివ్వటానికి అధికారులుండేవారు. కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వము యొక్క అనవసర జోక్యము ఈ సభలలో ఉండేది కాదు.ముగింపు: చోళుల గ్రామ పాలన సమర్థవంతమైనది, ఆదర్శవంతమైనది. చోళులు గ్రామ పరిపాలనను ఏర్పరచి అందులో ప్రజలను భాగస్వాములను చేయటం వల్ల పాలనలో ప్రభుత్వానికి, ప్రజలకు మధ్య సమన్వయం సాధ్యపడింది."},{"question":"Quem pintou a Mona Lisa?","answer":"Leonardo da Vinci é o nome do artista que pintou a Mona Lisa."},{"question":"دې پوښتنې ته ځواب ووایاست: کوم نبات د جنوب په لور هیواد کې دی، اریوبوتریا یا روشیا؟","answer":"روشیا"},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mampatahotra\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mampatahotra\\" dia \\"Mapidi-doza\\""},{"question":"Jawab teka-teki yang lawak ini: Dalam kebanyakan makanan ikan, ikan apa yang tiada kepala, ekor dan mulut?","answer":"Jawapan: Bebola ikan."},{"question":"Iza no filohan’i Madagasikara nitondra ny firenena  tamin’ny taona 2002 ka hatramin’ny 2009?","answer":" I Marc Ravalomanana no nitondra ny firenena tamin’ny taona 2002 ka hatramin’ny 2009."},{"question":"Tenho rabo, mas não sou cãoNão tenho asas, mas sei voarSe me largarem, não subo,Mas saio ao vento a brincar.Quem sou eu?","answer":"Uma pipa."},{"question":"Shin batun me ake magana a wannan mai zuwa? \\"Gwamnatin kaduna ta Gindaya sharuddan Jinyar El-zakzaky\\". ","answer":"Jumlar : \\"Gwamnatin kaduna ta Gindaya sharuddan Jinyar El-zakzaky\\" ya nuna akwai takamammen iyaka ko ka’idoji da gwamnatin jihar Kaduna ta gindaya na ganin El-Zakzaky ya je asibiti."},{"question":"Ilang bagyo ang tumatama sa Pilipinas kada taon?","answer":"Umaabot ng mahigit-kumulang na 20 na bagyo ang pumapasok sa Philippine Area of Responsibility o PAR kada taon, at mas kaunti sa mga ito ang direktang tumatama sa Pilipinas. Madalas na pumapasok ang mga bagyo sa PAR dahil matatagpuan ang Pilipinas sa tropikal na rehiyon malapit sa ekwator at ng Karagatang Pasipiko, kung saan nabubuo ang maraming bagyo mula sa mainit na tubig."},{"question":"Qual substância não se mistura com a água?","answer":"Resposta: o óleo."},{"question":"Write about the country Cameroon","answer":"Cameroon is a country located in Central Africa. It is bordered by Nigeria to the north, Chad to the northeast, the Central African Republic to the east, Equatorial Guinea, Gabon, and the Republic of the Congo to the south, and the Gulf of Guinea to the southwest."},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?ආගන්තුක ","answer":"නේවාසික"},{"question":"Ina sọ niwaju ọfiisi Gomina l’Ogun, tanka epo lo gbina","answer":"Ọjọ Abamamẹta, Satide, yii ni tanka epo kan deede gbina niwaju ọfiisi Gomina ipinlẹ Ogun, Ọmọọba Dapọ Abiọdun.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ina to sọ naa ko ṣọṣẹ kankan ju tanka epo to jo naa lọ, ko sohun to jẹ ki eyi ri bẹẹ ju pe awọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ panapana tete debẹ, wọn si ri ina ọhun pa.Dẹrẹba to wa mọto epo bẹntiroolu naa, Nurudeen Yusuf, ṣalaye pe ninu ẹnjinni ọkọ naa ni kinni kan ti ṣana, nigba tawọn yoo si fi wo o ni ina nla ṣẹ yọ niwaju ọfiisi gomina ti mọto naa de lasiko yẹn.O ṣalaye pe Ijọra, niluu Eko, loun atawọn ọmọ ẹyin ọkọ meji ti n gbe bẹntiroolu naa bọ, Adatan, l’Abẹokuta, lawọn si n lọ ko too di pe ina sọ lojiji, to jo mọto naa run.Ohun to jọọyan loju ninu iṣẹlẹ yii ni pe tanka to n gbe epo bọ lati ọna jinjin bii eyi ko ni ohun ti wọn fi n pana ninu ọkọ bi ina ba ṣẹ yọ lojiji bii eyi."},{"question":"नेपालको लाङटाङ राष्ट्रिय निकुञ्जको बारेमा लेख्नुहोस्। ","answer":"गतिविधिहरू: पदयात्रा, पर्वतारोहण, तामाङ संस्कृतिको अनुभवआवास: लज, शिविर, टीहाउसपहुँच: धुन्चेबाट, जुन काठमाडौंबाट सडकबाट ११७ किलोमिटर टाढा छवन्यजन्तु: जंगली कुकुर, रातो पाण्डा, पिका, मुन्टजाक, कस्तुरी मृग, हिमालयन कालो भालु, हिमालयन तहर, घोरल, सेरो, रेसस बाँदर, लङ्गुर बाँदर, हिउँ चितुवाचराहरू: ट्रागोपन र इम्पियन फिजेन्ट सहित ३७३ प्रजातिका चराहरूवनस्पति: १००० मिटर मुनिको उप-उष्णकटिबंधीय वनहरूले अल्पाइन झाडी र घाँसे मैदानहरूलाई बाटो दिन्छउत्तम सिजन: अक्टोबर-नोभेम्बर र मार्च-मे (उच्च उचाइमा चिसो), जुन-सेप्टेम्बर (मनसुन), डिसेम्बर-फेब्रुअरी (हिउँ)पार्क मुख्यालय: धुन्चेथप आकर्षण: गोसाइँकुण्ड ताल, लाङ्टाङ उपत्यका, हेलम्बुप्रवेश शुल्क: नेपाली - प्रति व्यक्ति रु २५ प्रति प्रवेश, सार्क नागरिक - प्रति व्यक्ति रु १५०० प्रति प्रवेश, विदेशी - प्रति व्यक्ति रु ३,०००"},{"question":"FIFA ලෝක කුසලානය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"FIFA ලෝක කුසලානය යනු ක්‍රීඩාවේ ලෝක ශූරයා තීරණය කරන පිරිමි ජාතික කණ්ඩායම් සඳහා වන සිව් අවුරුදු පාපන්දු (පාපන්දු) තරඟාවලියකි."},{"question":"Muotoile seuraava lause uudelleen: Norjalainen gyrokopteri on tippunut Kilpisjärven lähistöllä. Sen kyydissä oli putoamishetkellä kaksi ihmistä.","answer":"Norjalainen gyrokopteri on pudonnut lähellä Kilpisjärveä, ja siinä oli kaksi matkustajaa onnettomuuden sattuessa."},{"question":"Waa max Talo qoyska?","answer":"Qoys kasta waxaa u soo baxa qof jabiya silsilada saboolnimada, waxaan kuu rajaynayaa in aad noqoto qofkaa, laakiin si aad u noqoto waa:In aad Alle aaminto kuna kalsoonaatoIn aad is-bedel dhab ah sameysoIn aad garato mas’uuliyad weyn in ay ku saaran tahay, wax kastana adigu aad mas’uul ka tahayIn aad barato wax ku anfaca iyo xirfado cusubIn aad ka faa’iideysato fursad kasta oo faa’iido kuu leh kuna soo martaIn aad ku dadaasho sidi aad ganacsi u samayn lahayd xitaa mid yarIn aad badiso Saburka iyo SalaadaIn aad fahanto ujeedada nolosha iyo waxa aad u nooshahayIn aad ka fogaato waqti lumis iyo wax kasta oo aan dan kuugu jirinIn aad dadka caawiso, xushmeysid, una naxariisatidIn aad sameyso wixi wanaag ah oo aad Jeceshahay.In aad Alle ugu mahad celiso nimcada uu ku siiyay xilli kasta xitaa haday yar tahayIn aad dabeecadaada hagaajisid, kuna dhaqantid daacadnimo iyo cadaalad In aad aqbasho Qadarta Alle. Ogaatid wax kasta inay ku dhacaan sababIn aad u noolaato si fudud, dhulkana u socotid si tartiib ahIn aad daryeesho naftaada, kuna dedaasho horumarinta mustaqbalkaadaIn aad aaminto in fudayd ka dambeeyo culeys kastaWaxaan kuu rajaynayaa in aad noqoto qofki naftiisa iyo Qoyskiisa u horseedi lahaa Barwaaqo iyo Baraare balaaran"},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra ny \\"The Lord of the Rings\\"?","answer":"\\"The Lord of the Rings\\" dia nosoratan'ny mpanoratra britanika J.R.R. Tolkien. Ity dia trilogy fantasy epic."},{"question":"अपठित शब्द का अर्थ क्या है ?","answer":"‘अपठित’ शब्द अंग्रेजी भाषा के शब्द ‘unseen’ का समानार्थी है। इस शब्द की रचना ‘पाठ’ मूल शब्द में ‘अ’ उपसर्ग और ‘इत’ प्रत्यय जोड़कर बना है। इसका शाब्दिक अर्थ है-‘बिना पढ़ा हुआ।’ अर्थात गद्य या काव्य का ऐसा अंश जिसे पहले न पढ़ा गया हो। "},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa nebigii dabka lagu tuuray?","answer":"Nebigii dabka lagu tuuray wuxuu ahaa Nebi Ibraahim CS."},{"question":"من هو السلطان العثماني المشهور الذي لقب بإسم سليمان القانوني ؟","answer":"الإجابة هي : هو السلطان العثماني سليمان الأول بن سليم الأول ."},{"question":"How are Sri Lankan national parks contributing to wildlife conservation?","answer":"Sri Lankan national parks play a crucial role in wildlife conservation through various measures:Biodiversity Protection: Parks like Yala and Wilpattu preserve diverse ecosystems and endemic species.Habitat Preservation: Protected areas ensure the preservation of natural habitats for flora and fauna.Eco-Tourism: Controlled tourism promotes awareness and generates funds for conservation efforts.Research and Monitoring: National parks serve as research hubs for studying wildlife behavior and ecosystems.Anti-Poaching Measures: Strict measures are in place to combat poaching and illegal activities that threaten wildlife.The conservation efforts in national parks contribute to maintaining the island's rich biodiversity."},{"question":"चन्द्राननार्धदेहाय चन्द्रांशुसितमूर्तये ।चन्द्रार्कानलनेत्राय चन्द्रार्धशिरसे नमः ॥","answer":"अर्थ : चंद्रमुखी पार्वती ही ज्याची अर्धांगिनी आहे, जो चंद्रकिरणांप्रमाणे शीतल आहे, ज्याचे तीन नेत्र चंद्र, सूर्य आणि अग्नीप्रमाणे आहेत, ज्याने आपल्या मस्तकावर अर्धचंद्र धारण केलेला आहे अशा भगवान श्रीशंकराला माझा नमस्कार असो."},{"question":"Rubuta dubu  uku da  takwas a matsayin lambar?","answer":"Amsa: 3008."},{"question":" waa maxay geerar? ","answer":" Geerar waa God kamid ah godadka maansada kuwa ugu miisanka Wayn. "},{"question":"Mikä on talvihoitoluokka II?","answer":"Hoitoluokka II (15 409 km: 20 % tiepituudesta, 7 % liikenteestä, 5 % raskaasta liikenteestä)Tien pinta on pääosin polannepintainen, ja polanne voi olla osittain urautunut. Lunta voi sataa useampia senttejä, ennen kuin toimenpiteet alkavat. Uusimmissa urakoissa toimenpiteet aloitetaan vähän aikaisemmin, klo: 02-20 välisenä aikana. Teiden pintoja karhennetaan sekä risteysalueet, mäet ja kaarteet hiekoitetaan säännöllisesti. Kaikkein ongelmallisimmilla keleillä, myös tiet hiekoitetaan kokonaan. Hiekoitustarve varmistetaan keliolosuhteiden mukaan. Tieverkon auraus- ja liukkaudentorjuntareitit ovat pitkiä, jolloin niiden läpiajamiseen kuluu useampi tunti.Tiellä on normaalitilanteissa riittävä kitka ja tasaisuus maltilliseen liikennöintiin. Vaikeissa säätilanteissa, esimerkiksi sään äkillisesti lauhtuessa tai heti lumisateiden jälkeen, liikenteessä edellytetään varovaisuutta."},{"question":"Berikan peribahasa yang sama maksud atau hampir sama maksud dengan peribahasa berikut:-\\"Yang dikejar tak dapat, yang dikendong berciciran\\"","answer":"Ibarat mendengar guruh di langit, air di tempayan dicurahkan."},{"question":"वाक्यांश 1: प्रारंभिक खगोल विज्ञान में, उनकी प्रसिद्धि गणितीय ग्लोब के परिचय और ग्रहों की गति को समझने के लिए उनके खगोलीय योगदान के कारण है । वाक्यांश 2: प्रारंभिक खगोल विज्ञान में, उनकी प्रसिद्धि गणितीय ग्लोब के परिचय के कारण है, और ग्रहों की गति को समझने के लिए उनके खगोलीय योगदान के कारण है । प्रश्न: क्या वाक्य 1 और वाक्य 2 एक ही अर्थ व्यक्त करते हैं? हाँ या नहीं?","answer":"नहीं, वाक्य 1 और वाक्य 2 एक ही अर्थ व्यक्त नहीं करते हैं। दोनों वाक्यों में अर्थ में छोटी सी अंतर है। वाक्य 1 में प्रसिद्धि दो कारणों के लिए है - \\"गणितीय ग्लोब के परिचय\\" और \\"ग्रहों की गति को समझने के लिए उनके खगोलीय योगदान के कारण\\"। वाक्य 2 में, प्रसिद्धि केवल \\"गणितीय ग्लोब के परिचय\\" के कारण है, और \\"ग्रहों की गति को समझने के लिए उनके खगोलीय योगदान के कारण\\" को छोड़ दिया गया है।"},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Afganistan'ın Soviyetler Birliği'nin etkisi altına girmeye başlaması, İngiltere'ye karşı bu ülkeden yardım almaya başladığı 1919 yılına dayanmaktadır. 1950'li yıllarda başlayan teknik ve askerî yardımlara paralel olarak ekonomik ilişkilerde iyice gelişti ve 1979 yılında gerçekleşen","answer":"komünist darbe ile ikili ilişkiler daha da üst boyuta taşındı. Afgan komünist yönetimini, iktidarına karşı tehlike oluşunca, Sovyetler Birliği'ni Afganistan'a davet etti. İşgal 24 Aralık 1979'da başladı. SSCB 280 uçakla, Kabil'e, 8500'er kişilik üç tümeni de kapsayan, çok büyük bir askerî sevkiyat gerçekleştirdi. Bir iki gün içinde Sovyet askerleri tüm ülkeye hakim oldu. İlk olarak başkent Kabil'deki Darulaman Sarayı'na gönderilen özel bir birlik, kısa ve ve şiddetli bir çatışmadan sonra, devlet başkanı Hafızullah Amin'i öldürerek tasfiye etti. Amin'in yerine, Afganistan Demokratik Halk Partisi'nin Perçemciler fraksiyonunun sürgündeki lideri Babrak Karmal, SSCB tarafından devlet başkanlığı görevine getirildi."},{"question":"D vitamini eksik olursa ne olur?","answer":"El ve ayak bilekleri, omuz eklemeleri ve parmaklarda ağrı, değişken ruh hali, depresyon, uykusuzluk, baş ağrısı, saç dökülmesi gibi belirtiler de bulunabilir. Yetişkinlerde uzun süreli D vitamini eksikliği; kemik erimesi, kemik yapısında bozukluk, kas güçsüzlüğü ve düşme riskinde artışa neden olur."},{"question":"ముంబై నగర ప్రధాన ఉపాధి వనరులలో ప్రచార మాధ్యమం ఒకటి.అనేక దూరదర్శన్ మరియు ఉపగ్రహ (శాటిలైట్) నెట్‌వర్క్‌లు, అలాగే ప్రధాన ప్రచురణా సంస్థలు ఇక్కడనుండి ప్రారంభం అయినవే.హిందీ చలన చిత్రాలకు ముంబై ప్రధాన కేంద్రం. చందు","answer":"భారతీయ హిందీ సినీ రంగం ఏ నగరంలో ఉంది?"},{"question":"Inona no vokatry ny fiovan'ny toetr'andro?","answer":"Ny fiovaovan'ny toetr'andro dia mitarika trangan-javatra toy ny fiakaran'ny maripana , ny ranomandry mitsonika, ny fiakaran'ny haavon'ny ranomasina ary ny fisehoan'ny toetr'andro mahery vaika."},{"question":"Qui était la cinéaste Céline Sciamma ?","answer":"Céline Sciamma est acclamée pour ses explorations intimes et sensibles de l'identité, du genre et des relations. Ses films, tels que « Naissance des Pieuvres », « Tomboy » et « Portrait de la jeune fille en feu », capturent les nuances de jeunes personnages qui naviguent dans leur croissance personnelle et les attentes de la société."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi An Iordáin. ","answer":"Tír Arabach sa Mheánoirthear is ea an Iordáin nó Ríocht Hashemite na hIordáine, a dtugtar uirthi go hoifigiúil. Tá teorainneacha aici leis an tSiria thuaidh, an Iaráic thoir thuaidh, an Araib Shádach thoir agus theas, agus Iosrael agus an Phalaistín thiar. Tar éis an roinn na hÁise iartharacha tar éis an Chéad Chogadh Domhanda leis An Bhriotáin agus An Fhrainc, bhí an tír aitheanta go hoifigiúil le comhairle Chonradh na Náisiún i 1922. I 1946, D'éirigh an Iordáin a bheith stáit ceannasach neamhspleách. Tar éis ag gabháil an Bruach Thiar i rith an Cogadh Arabach-Iosraelach 1948, thóg Abdullah I an teideal Rí na hIordáine. Ar an 17 Meán Fómhair 1970, bhris cogadh cathartha amach san Iordáin, nó \\"Meán Fómhair Dubh\\". "},{"question":"*كم تبلغ سرعة الصاروخ في الثانية ؟","answer":"11 كيلو متر"},{"question":"Eyi ni bawọn aṣaaju Hausa-Fulani ṣe ba Naijiria yii jẹ (14)","answer":"Awọn ọrọ ti mo n sọ wọnyi, mo fẹ ka ṣe akọsilẹ ati afọkansi wọn daradara. Alaye ti mo n ṣe wọnyi, ka fi le mọ ibi ti nnkan ti wọ wa ni. Bi a ba mọ ibi to ti wọ wa, a oo le mọ ohun to yẹ ni ṣiṣe. Ṣe ẹ ri i lati 1960 ti ijọba Naijiria ti bọ sọwọ awọn eeyan wa lawọn baba wa gbogbo lati ilẹ Yoruba ti ri aṣiṣe wọn. Nigba ti yoo fi di ọdun 1961 si 1962, aṣiṣe naa ti foju han debii pe wọn kabaamọ ohun ti wọn ṣe nibi ipade Ibadan ọdun 1950 ti mo sọrẹ ẹ fun yin. Wọn ri i pe awọn Sardauna ti gba Naijiria lọwọ awọn, wọn ti fi ara wọn ati awọn ọmọ tiwọn si ipo aṣaaju ni Naijiria, yoo ṣoro gan-an lọjọ iwaju lati gba a pada lọwọ wọn. Bo ba jẹ nigba ti tawọn ọba ilẹ Hausa yii n halẹ pe awọn fẹ ki Naijiria pin lawọn eeyan tiwa naa ni bi Naijiria ba fẹẹ pin ko pin ni, ọrọ naa ko le bajẹ mọ wa lọwọ to bẹẹ. Ṣugbọn nnkan ti bajẹ, ko too waa di 1962 ti wọn n mura atunṣe.Igba yẹn ni wọn ti mura pe eto ikaniyan ti awọn ba tun ṣe, awọn yoo ri i pe ko si aaye magomago ninu ẹ, wọn fẹẹ ṣọ awọn Sardauna lọwọ, ki wọn ṣọ wọn lẹsẹ, lati ri i pe wọn ko tun lu Yoruba ni jibiti lẹẹkan yii, wọn fẹ ki kaluku mọ iye to jẹ gan-an. Igba tawọn Balewa tiẹ sọ pe awọn gba oyinbo kan ko waa ṣeto ikaniyan yii, idunnu lo jẹ fawọn eeyan tiwa nilẹ Yoruba ati ilẹ Ibo, wọn mọ pe ko ni i si eru ninu ohun ti oyinbo ba dari fun wọn. Ohun to gbe J. J. Warren delẹ wa ree, oun loyinbo to ba wa ṣeto ikaniyan ni 1962. Awọn Sardauna ti wọn fẹẹ gba agbara lọwọ wọn naa o sun, ṣe wọn mọ pe agbara kan naa ti awọn ni ni ariwo pe awọn lawọn pọ ju ni Naijiria, bi agbara yẹn ba si ti bọ, nnkan ṣe wọn niyẹn. Ọgbọn ti wọn da ni lati ri i pe ẹnu awọn eeyan naa ko ko, wọn wa ọna lati tu wọn ka.Azikiwe ti wa ninu ijọba, wọn ti gbe aparutu agbara kan le e lọwọ. Nitori ẹ, ki i ri ohun to buru rara ninu ohun tawọn Balewa tabi Sardauna ba ṣe. Ẹyin wọn lo wa. Awolọwọ nikan ni iṣoro wọn. Awolọwọ pẹlu ẹgbẹ Ọlọpẹ ẹ. Awọn eeyan yii kuku mọ pe aburu lawọn ṣe fun wa, wọn si mọ pe aṣiri ọrọ naa fẹẹ tu. Lo ṣe jẹ bi wọn ti mọ pe eto ikaniyan n bọ ni 1962 lawọn naa ti bẹrẹ eto lati da ẹgbẹ Awolọwọ ru, tabi ti wọn fi le pa Awolọwọ funra ẹ saye, ti o fi ni i lagbara lati di wọn lọwọ ohunkohun ti wọn ba n ṣe. Akintọla ni wọn ri lo lati fi ba tiwa jẹ. Lojiji ni Sardauna bẹrẹ si i fa oju ẹ mọra. O n paara Ibadan, o n sọ pe oun waa ki i. Asiko yii naa ni Akintọla bẹrẹ si i ta Awolọwọ lẹnu, to ni Awolọwọ ti lo saa tiẹ, ko jẹ ki oun naa lo saa toun.Nigba to fi maa di ibẹrẹ ọdun 1962, Sardauna ti mu Akintọla, o ti kọ ẹyin oun ati Awolọwọ sira wọn. Akintọla ko gba Awolọwọ bii ọga mọ. Ohun to n wa yii ru bo o loju ti ko fi mọ pe Sardauna n tan oun ni. Ohun to fa a niyẹn to jẹ titi ti wọn fi bẹrẹ sẹnsọ 1962 yii, ti wọn si pari ẹ, ninu hilahilo ni ilẹ Yoruba wa, ko sẹni to roju ara wọn. Ẹgbẹ Action Group ṣeto ipade gbogbogboo si Jos ninu oṣu keji, kaka ki Akintọla to jẹ olori ijọba Western Region wa nipade, o  wa n’Ibadan to n gba Sardauna lalejo. Sardauna mọ pe ẹgbẹ awọn Awolọwọ nipade o, o si mọ pe ko si ẹni ti wọn bi daadaa bẹẹ ninu awọn ọmọlẹyin oun to jẹ ṣe bẹẹ soun nibi ipade ẹgbẹ tawọn.Ṣugbọn nitori pe Akintọla n wa agbara, oun o fura si gbogbo eyi, o ro pe Sardauna fẹẹ gbeja oun ni. Ibinu ọrọ yii lawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ fi yọ kuro ninu ẹgbẹ Action Group ibi ipade Jos yii. Ni gbogbo igba ti ija yii wa n gbona gan-an ninu oṣu karun-un, 1962, eto ikaniyan n lọ lọwọ ni Naijiria, bẹẹ ijọba Western Region ko raaye dari awọn eeyan tiẹ, ija buruku yii o jẹ. Ọjọ kẹtala, oṣu karun-un, 1962, ni wọn ti bẹrẹ eto naa, gbogbo igba ti ijọba Balewa si n fi ipa gba ijọba Western Region lọwọ ẹgbẹ AG, ti wọn fi Moses Adekoyejọ Majẹkodunmi ṣe olori ijọba ibẹ, wọn ṣi n ṣeto ikaniyan yii lọwọ. Ta lo roju sẹnsọ nilẹ Yoruba! Ohun ti awọn Sardauna gbe kalẹ, ti Akintọla ati awọn ọmọ Yoruba to ti i lẹyin ko mọ niyẹn.J. J. Warren kuku ba iṣẹ naa jalẹ, ṣugbọn oun funra ẹ ri magomago tawọn Hausa yii ṣe, atawọn Ibo naa. Pẹlu ẹ naa, nigba ti wọn ka awọn eeyan tan, apapọ ilẹ Yoruba ati ilẹ Ibo ju ilẹ Hausa lọ. Awọn eeyan miliọnu mejilelogun ni wọn ri ka nilẹ Hausa, mẹtalelogun miliọnu ni apapọ ilẹ Ibo ati Yoruba. Niṣe lawọn Balewa yari. Warren to ṣeto sẹnsọ ni ilẹ Ibo ati ilẹ Hausa ni ojooro wa, awọn si le ṣe atunṣe diẹdiẹ to wa nibẹ, ti gbogbo nnkan si maa ri bo ṣe yẹ ko ri. Ibẹru leleyii fun Sardauna atawọn eeyan ẹ, wọn ro pe Warren fẹẹ tọwọ bọ nnkan loju fawọn ni. Wọn mọ pe awọn ibi kan wa ti wọn o kaayan nilẹ Hausa yii, to jẹ wọn kan bu iye kan fawọn to ṣeto ni; aṣiri ẹ ti tu si Warren lọwọ, atunṣe to fẹẹ ṣe niyẹn.Waziri Ibrahim ni minista fun eto idagbasoke ilu nigba naa, abẹ ẹ ni eto ikaniyan yii wa. Wọn ni ki Warren fi bi wọn ṣe kaayan nilẹ Hausa silẹ, ti ilẹ Ibo nikan ni ko tun ṣe, oyinbo ni iyẹn o ṣee ṣe. O ni ibi mẹtẹẹta lawọn gbọdọ ṣe, nitori wahala to n wa nilẹ Yoruba ko jẹ ki awọn eeyan kọbiara si eto ikaniyan ọhun, wọn ko si ri ọpọ eeyan ka nibẹ. Waziri beere lọwọ Warren pe ṣe ti wọn ba tun eto naa ṣe, njẹ o ṣee ṣe ki ilẹ Hausa pọ ju apapọ ilẹ Yoruba ati Ibo lọ. Warren ni pẹlu ohun ti oun ti ri yii, bi awọn ba tun eto naa ṣe, awọn eeyan ilẹ Hausa maa dinku gan-an ni, nitori wọn ko to iye ti wọn kọ siwee waa foun. Waziri gbe ọrọ pada fawọn Balewa, Sardauna ni iyẹn o le ṣee ṣe, Hausa gbọdọ pọ ju Yoruba ati Ibo lọ, bi bẹẹ kọ, iya le jẹ awọn.Ni wọn ba sọ fun Warrren pe o gbọdọ tun eto naa ṣe ti yoo fi jẹ Hausa lo pọ ju, lọkunrin yii ba ni oun o le ṣe bẹẹ. Nipari oṣu kin-in-ni, 1963, Waziri ba gbe iwe lọ si ile-igbimọ aṣofin pe ki wọn jẹ ki awọn le Warren lọ, nitori ko ṣe iṣẹ ẹ daadaa. Awọn aṣofin ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu NCNC lawọn o gba, awọn ti AG naa lawọn o fẹ, ni wọn ba binu jade. Awọn aṣofin ilẹ Hausa to jẹ awọn ni wọn pọ ju jokoo, ni wọn ba fọwọ si i pe ki wọn le Warren lọ. Nigba ti wọn le Warren lọ, Balewa gba iṣẹ naa, ni wọn ba tun kaayan ni 1963. Nigba ti wọn ka wọn tan, to jọ pe ko tun to iye ti wọn fẹ, ijọba Balewa ṣe ayipada nla kan. Wọn fi miliọnu mejọ  ataabọ kun iye awọn eeyan ti wọn wa nilẹ Hausa.Gbogbo ohun ti mo n sọ yii, Akintọla mọ daadaa pe magomago ni, nitori nigbẹyin, miliọnu marundinlọgọta ni wọn pe gbogbo Naijiria, ilẹ Hausa ni awọn ni miliọnu ọgbọn o le, wọn ko eyi to ku fun ilẹ Yoruba ati Ibo.  Michael Okpara, olori ijọba ilẹ Ibo naa mọ o.  Ṣugbọn ni gbogbo igba ti Okpara n lọ si kootu, to n fa wahala lori ọrọ sẹnsọ yii, to n so pe ko daa, irọ ati iyanjẹ ni, Akintọla dakẹ jẹẹ, ko le wi kinni kan, nitori o mọ pe agbara Sardauna loun fi wa nile ijọba, oun ko si gbọdọ ṣe ohun kan ti yoo lodi si ohun ti Sardauna ba fẹ. Bo ṣe jẹ ọna kan ṣoṣo ti wọn iba fi bọ ninu ajaga to wa lọrun wa titi doni yii, Akintọla ati awọn ọmọ Yoruba ẹyin ẹ bii Fani-Kayọde, Ayọ Roṣiji, Richard Akinjide, Adisa Akinloye, Ọdẹlẹyẹ Fadahunsi, ati awọn mi-in bẹẹ tun ba a jẹ niyẹn. Wahala ti eleyii tun mu dani, n oo maa tẹ siwaju lori ẹ lọsẹ to n bọ.  "},{"question":"تعهد ترامب وكيم جونج أون بالتعاون على صعيد نزع السلاح النووي من شبه الجزيرة الكوريةونقلت صحيفة واشنطن بوست عن مسؤولين أمريكيين، لم تسمهم،  قولهم إن صورا التقطها قمر تجسس أمريكي أظهرت نشاطا في موقع شهد بناء صواريخ باليستية في وقت سابق. ونقلت وكالة أنباء رويترز عن مصدر أمريكي أن الصور لم تظهر إلى أي مرحلة وصل العمل على بناء الصواريخ. والتقى الزعيمان ترامب وكيم في  قمة تاريخية غير مسبوقة بين رئيس أمريكي في الخدمة وزعيم كوري شمالي في سنغافورة في يونيو/ حزيران الماضي، ما أسفر عن قدر كبير من التقارب بين الجانبين في الفترة الأخيرة. وتعهد الزعيمان عقب القمة بنزع السلاح النووي من شبه الجزيرة الكورية، ما دفع ترامب إلى التأكيد على أن \\"كوريا الشمالية لم تعد تشكل تهديدا نوويا\\". وواجه الرئيس الأمريكي انتقادات لتقديمه \\"تنازلات\\" دون الحصول على تعهدات مؤكدة من الزعيم الكوري بإنهاء برامج تصنيع الصواريخ الباليستية. ماذا قالت التقارير الأخيرة؟نشرت واشنطن بوست تصريحات لمسؤولين ترجح أن كوريا الشمالية تطور صاروخا باليستيا أو اثنين في منشأة سانومدونغ بالقرب من العاصمة بيونغيانغ. وشهد هذا المصنع إنتاج أول صاروخ باليستي يمكنه الوصول إلى الولايات المتحدة، وفقا للصحيفة الأمريكية. أعلنت كوريا الشمالية في إبريل/ نيسان الماضي وقف تجاربها الصاروخية والنوويةوأظهرت الصور التي التقطها قمر تجسس أمريكي أن مركبات تتحرك من وإلى الموقع، لكنها لم تحدد إلى أي مرحلة تحديدا وصل العمل في تطوير الصواريخ، وفقا لوكالة أنباء رويترز. وليست تلك التقارير الأولى التي ترجح استمرار كوريا الشمالية في برامج التسليح، ما يثير شكوكا حيال الأثر الحقيقي للقمة التي انعقدت بين الجانبين في يونيو/ حزيران الماضي. ونشرت وسائل إعلام أمريكية تقارير تضمنت ما زعمت أنه تسريبات لمعلومات استخباراتية رجحت أن بيونغيانغ حدثت مواقع تخصيب اليورانيوم علاوة على أنشطة أخرى ذات صلة. وقال مايك بومبيو، وزير الخارجية الأمريكي، الأسبوع الماضي إن مصانع كوريا الشمالية \\"مستمرة في إنتاج مواد انشطارية\\" تستخدم في تطوير الأسلحة النووية. وأعلنت بوينغيانغ في إبريل/ نيسان الماضي وقف تجاربها الصاروخية والنووية.  يمكن تلخيص النص التالي ك:","answer":"رجحت تقارير إعلامية أمريكية أن  كوريا الشمالية بدأت  تطوير صواريخ باليستية  رغم التقارب الذي طرأ على العلاقات في الفترة الأخيرة بين الرئيس الأمريكي دونالد ترامب والزعيم الكوري الشمالي كيم جونج أون."},{"question":"Di belakang rumah atuk saya terdapat se _______ anak sungai dan dua _______ lombong yang dijadikan kolam untuk menternak ikan.","answer":"batang....buah"},{"question":"ગુજરાતી મા \\"પ્રેમ \\" ઉપર એક કવિતા લાખો.","answer":"કવિતા\\"પ્રેમ\\"પ્રેમ એક અનુભવ છે,જે બધાને થાય છે,પરંતુ તેનો અર્થ દરેકને અલગ અલગ લાગે છે.પ્રેમ એક ભાવ છે,જે આપણને ઉચ્ચતા તરફ લઈ જાય છે,પરંતુ તે આપણને નીચે પણ લઈ જઈ શકે છે.પ્રેમ એક શક્તિ છે,જે આપણને બદલી શકે છે,પરંતુ તે આપણને તોડી પણ શકે છે.પ્રેમ એક રહસ્ય છે,જેનો કોઈ જવાબ નથી,પરંતુ તે આપણા જીવનને સમૃદ્ધ બનાવે છે."},{"question":"కంపెనీలకు లభించే ప్రధానమైన దీర్ఘకాలిక, స్వల్పకాలిక ఆర్థిక వనరుల గురించి చర్చించండి.","answer":"దీర్ఘకాలిక విత్త వనరులు: కంపెనీ తన దీర్ఘకాలిక ఆర్థిక వనరులను దిగువ మూలాల ద్వారా సేకరిస్తుంది. 1. వాటాలు, 2. డిబెంచర్లు, 3. నిలిపి ఉంచిన ఆర్జనలు.1. వాటాలు: కంపెనీ వ్యవస్థలో మూలధనాన్ని చిన్న చిన్న భాగాలుగా లేదా యూనిట్లుగా విభజిస్తారు. ఒక్కొక్క యూనిట్ను వాటా అంటారు. పెట్టుబడిదారుల నుంచి నిధులు సేకరించడానికి కంపెనీలు రెండు రకాల వాటాలను జారీ చేస్తాయి. అవి i) ఆధిక్యపు వాటాలు ii) ఈక్విటీ వాటాలు.i) ఆధిక్యపు వాటాలు: ఆధిక్యపు హక్కులు కలిగిన వాటాలను ఆధిక్యపు వాటాలు అంటారు. చట్టము ప్రకారం వీటికి రెండు ఆధిక్యపు హక్కులుంటాయి. ప్రతి సంవత్సరం నిర్ణీతమైన లాభాంశాలను ఈక్విటీ వాటాదారుల కంటే ముందుగా పొందే హక్కు, కంపెనీ రద్దు అయినపుడు ఈక్విటీ వాటాదారుల కంటే ముందుగా మూలధనాన్ని పొందే హక్కు ఆధిక్యపు వాటాలలో సంచిత, అసంచిత, మళ్ళీ భాగాన్ని పంచుకునే, విమోచనీయ, అవిమోచనీయ, పూచీగల, మార్పుకు వీలులేని వాటాలుగా జారీ చేసి మూలధనాన్ని సేకరిస్తాయి.ii) ఈక్విటీ వాటాలు: వీరు కంపెనీకి యజమానులు. కారణము వీరికి ఓటింగ్ హక్కు ఉంటుంది. ఆధిక్యపు వాటాదారులకు డివిడెండ్ చెల్లించిన తర్వాత వీరికి డివిడెండ్ చెల్లిస్తారు. వీరికి చెల్లించే డివిడెండు రేటు కంపెనీ గడించే లాభాలపై ఆధారపడి ఉంటుంది. లాభాలు ఎక్కువగా ఉంటే ఎక్కువ డివిడెండు, లాభాలు రాకపోతే వీరికి డివిడెండు రాకపోవచ్చు. వీరు ఎక్కువ నష్టభయాన్ని స్వీకరిస్తారు. కంపెనీ రద్దు అయినపుడు ఋణదాతలకు, ఆధిక్యపు వాటాదారులకు, చెల్లించిన తర్వాతనే వీరికి మూలధనము వాపసు చేస్తారు. ఈక్విటీ వాటాల జారీ ద్వారా కంపెనీలు శాశ్వత మూలధనాన్ని ఏర్పాటు చేసుకోవచ్చు.2. డిబెంచర్లు: వాటా మూలధనమువలె కంపెనీ డిబెంచర్లను జారీ చేస్తుంది. డిబెంచరు కంపెనీ తీసుకున్న అప్పుకు స్వీకృతి తెలిపే పత్రము, ‘అప్పును అంగీకరిస్తూ ఆ సొమ్మును భవిష్యత్తులో ఒక నిర్ణీత కాలములో, నిర్ణీత వడ్డీతో చెల్లించడానికి అంగీకరిస్తూ కంపెనీ అధికార ముద్రతో లిఖిత పూర్వకముగా వ్రాసి జారీ చేసిన పత్రాన్ని డిబెంచరు అంటారు. ఈ పత్రాన్ని కొన్నవారిని డిబెంచర్దారులు అంటారు. ఋణధ్రువ పత్రము కంపెనీ తీసుకున్న అప్పుకు ఇచ్చే రశీదు. దీనిలో ఋణపత్రదారుని పేరు, అప్పు విలువ, అప్పు షరతులు, అప్పు తీర్చే పద్ధతి’ మొదలైన వివరాలు ఉంటాయి. కంపెనీ దీర్ఘకాలిక అవసరాలకు డిబెంచర్లను జారీ చేస్తాయి.3. నిలిపి ఉంచిన ఆర్జనలు: సాధారణముగా ఒక కంపెనీ ఆర్జించిన లాభము మొత్తాన్ని వాటాదారులకు డివిడెండుగా పంచరు. కొంత మొత్తాన్ని భవిష్యత్ అవసరాలకై వేరుగా ఉంచుతారు. ఈ మొత్తాన్ని నిలిపి ఉంచిన ఆర్జన అంటారు. కంపెనీ అంతర్గత ఆర్థిక వనరులలో ఇది చాలా ముఖ్యమైనది. ఈ విధముగా లాభాల నుంచి రిజర్వునిధిగా ఏర్పరచిన మొత్తాన్ని మూలధన వనరులుగా వినియోగించుకోవడాన్ని ‘లాభాల పునరాకర్షణ’ అంటారు.స్వల్పకాలిక విత్తవనరులు: ఒక వ్యాపారానికి అవసరమయ్యే నిర్వహణ మూలధన అవసరాలకు స్వల్పకాలిక నిధులు అవసరము. స్వల్పకాలము అంటే ఒక సంవత్సరము కంటే తక్కువ కాలము.స్వల్పకాలిక నిధులకు మూలాధారాలు:1. బ్యాంకు పరపతి: వ్యాపార సంస్థలకు అవసరమయ్యే స్వల్పకాలిక వనరులను బ్యాంకులు ఋణాలు, క్యాష్ క్రెడిట్లు, ఓవర్ డ్రాఫ్ట్ రూపములో ధనసహాయము చేస్తాయి.ఎ) ఋణాలు: ఈ పద్ధతిలో బ్యాంకులు పెద్ద మొత్తములో అడ్వాన్సు చేస్తుంది. ఈ ఋణాలని చరాస్థులు లేదా స్థిరాస్థుల హామీ మీద మంజూరు చేస్తారు. అనుమతించిన ఋణం మొత్తంపై వడ్డీని చెల్లించాలి.బి) క్యాష్ క్రెడిట్: ఇది ఒక పరపతి సదుపాయము సర్దుబాటు. బ్యాంకులు వ్యాపార సంస్థలకు ఒక పరిమితికి లోబడి పరపతిని మంజూరు చేస్తుంది. ఈ పరపతిలో ఎంత అవసరమో అంత మొత్తాన్నే వ్యాపార సంస్థ వాడుకుంటుంది. వడ్డీని వాడుకున్న మొత్తానికే చార్జి చేస్తారు.సి) ఓవర్ డ్రాఫ్ట్: ఈ విత్త సదుపాయము ప్రకారము బ్యాంకరు వ్యాపార సంస్థ ఖాతాలో నిల్వ కంటే ఎక్కువ మొత్తాన్ని వాడుకునే అవకాశము కల్పిస్తుంది. దీనిని ఓవర్ డ్రాఫ్ట్ సౌకర్యము అంటారు. ఈ పరిమితిని బ్యాంకరు నిర్ణయిస్తాడు. నిల్వ కంటే మించి వాడిన మొత్తము మీదనే వడ్డీని చార్జి చేస్తారు.2. వర్తక ఋణాలు: ఒక సంస్థ తన ఖాతాదారులకు అరువు ఇచ్చినట్లే తరుచుగా తన సప్లయిదారుల నుంచి అరువు సౌకర్యాన్ని పొందుతుంది. దీనిని వర్తకపు ఋణము అంటారు. దీనిని నగదు పూర్వకముగా ఇవ్వడం జరగదు. కాని కొనుగోలు చేసిన సరుకునకు వెంటనే నగదు చెల్లించనవసరము లేదు. ఆర్థికపుష్టి, గుడ్విల్ ఉన్న సంస్థలకు, ఖాతాదారులకు వర్తకపు ఋణాన్ని ఇస్తారు.3. వాయిదా పరపతి: యంత్రాలు, యంత్రపరికరాలు సప్లయిదారుల నుంచి వ్యాపార సంస్థలు పరపతిని పొందవచ్చు. సాధారణముగా సప్లయిదారులు కొనుగోలు చేసిన ఆస్తుల విలువను 12 నెలలు అంతకంటే ఎక్కువ కాలానికి చెల్లించడానికి అంగీకరిస్తారు. నగదు ధరలో కొంత మొత్తము చెల్లించి, మిగిలినది కొన్ని వాయిదాలలో చెల్లించవలసి ఉంటుంది.4. వినియోగదారుల నుంచి అడ్వాన్సులు: సాధారణముగా వ్యాపార సంస్థలు ఆర్డర్లతో పాటు కొంత మొత్తాన్ని | అడ్వాన్సుగా స్వీకరించవచ్చును. ఖాతాదారుల ఆర్డర్ ప్రకారము వారికి భవిష్యత్తులో సప్లయి చేసే వస్తువుల ధరలో కొంత భాగాన్ని వినియోగదారుల అడ్వాన్సు సూచిస్తుంది. ఇది స్వల్పకాలిక మూలధన వనరు.5. వాణిజ్య పత్రాలు: ఒక సంస్థ స్వల్పకాలానికి నిధులను అంటే 90 రోజుల నుంచి 365రోజుల లోపు కాలవ్యవధితో సేకరించడానికి జారీ చేసే హామీ లేని ప్రామిసరీ నోటు “వాణిజ్య పత్రము”. దీనిని ఒక సంస్థ వేరొక సంస్థకు, భీమా కంపెనీలకు, బ్యాంకులకు, పెన్షన్నిధి సంస్థలకు జారీ చేస్తుంది. ఈ ఋణంపై హామీ లేనందున మంచి పరపతి రేటింగ్ ఉన్న సంస్థలే వీటిని జారీ చేస్తాయి."},{"question":"લેવા ગયો જો પ્રેમ – મરીઝ રચિત  કવિતા લખો","answer":"લેવા ગયો જો પ્રેમ તો વહેવાર પણ ગયો,દર્શનની ઝંખના હતી, અણસાર પણ ગયો.એની બહુ નજીક જવાની સજા છે એ,મળતો હતો જે દૂરથી સહકાર પણ ગયો.રહેતો હતો કદી કદી ઝુલ્ફોની છાંયમાં,મારા નસીબમાંથી એ અંધકાર પણ ગયો.સંગતમાં જેની સ્વર્ગનો આભાસ હો ખુદા,દોઝખમાં કોઈ એવો ગુનેગાર પણ ગયો.એ ખુશનસીબ પ્રેમીને મારી સલામ હો,જેનો સમયની સાથે હ્રદયભાર પણ ગયો.એ પણ છે સત્ય એની ઉપર હક નથી હવે,એવુંય કંઈ નથી કે અધિકાર પણ ગયો.સાકી છે સ્તબ્ધ જોઈ નશાની અગાઢ ઊંઘ,પીનારા સાથે કામથી પાનાર પણ ગયો.કેવી મજાની પ્રેમની દીવાનગી હશે !કે જ્યાં ‘મરીઝ’ જેવો સમજદાર પણ ગયો"},{"question":"බුදු දහමේ එන  ලිංග පරිවර්තනය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"සමහර විට ලිංග පරිවර්තනයෙන් ස්ත්‍රීහු පිරිමි බවට ද, පුරුෂයෝ ගැහැණු බවට ද පැමිණෙති. “තෙන ඛො පන සමයෙන අඤ්ඤතරස්ස භික්ඛුනො ඉත්ථිලිංගං පාතුභූතං හොති, තෙන ඛො පන සමයෙන අඤ්ඤතරස්ස භික්ඛුනියා පුරිසලිංගං පාතුභූතං හොති” යි විනයෙහි ද ඒ බව දක්වා තිබේ. ලිංග පරිවර්තනය වන්නේ ද කර්මයෙනි. බලවත් අකුශලයෙන් පුරුෂ ලිංගය අතුරුදහන් වී ස්ත්‍රී ලිංගය පහළ වේ. ලිංග පරිවර්තනය පිළිබඳව කියයුතු කර්ම තත්ත්වය ගැඹුරු කරුණෙකි. එය අභිධර්මය නො දන්නවුන් වරදවා ගන්නා තැනකි. මනුෂ්‍යාත්මභාවය කුශලයකින් ම ලැබෙන්නකි. මිනිස් සිරුරෙහි කුශලකර්මජරූප මිස අකුශල කර්මජ රූප නැත. මිනිස් පුරුෂයා විසින් ලිංගවිපර්යාසයට හේතු වන බලවත් අකුශලයක් කළ කල්හි ඔහු ගේ ජනකකර්මය (උප්පත්තියට හේතු වූ කර්මය) එයින් දුබල වේ. එය ඉන් පසු පුරුෂභාව රූපයන් ඉපදවීමට නො සමත් වෙයි. කර්මයේ පීඩනයෙන් දුබල ජනක කර්මය ඉන් පසු ඒ සන්තානයෙහි ස්ත්‍රීභාව රූප උපදවයි. කලින් පැවැත්තා වූ පුරුෂභාවරූප ඒවායේ ආයුෂය ගෙවීමෙන් නිරුද්ධ වෙයි. ඉන් පසු පුරුෂයා ස්ත්‍රියක් වෙයි. පසු ව ඔහු ගේ සන්තානයෙහි ස්ත්‍රීභාවරූප ඇති කළා වූ ද කලින් පුරුෂභාව රූප ඇති කළා වූ ද කර්මය එකක් ම ය. එය ඔහුගේ උත්පත්තියට හේතු වූ කුශල කර්මය ම ය. මේ විර්‍ප්‍යාසයට දුරින් හේතු වන අකුශල කර්‍මය දැක්වීම පිණිස එය ප්‍ර‍ධාන කොට කතා කිරීමේ දී බලවත් අකුශලයෙන් පුරුෂලිංග අතුරුදහන් වී ස්ත්‍රී ලිංගය පහළ වෙතැ යි කියනු ලැබේ. එය පර්‍ය්‍යාය කථාවෙකි. එය පිළිබඳ ව කිය යුතු දෑ බොහෝ ඇතත් ඒවා දක්වන්නට ගිය හොත් පරමාර්ථ ධර්ම ලක්ෂණයෙන් බැහැරට බොහෝ දුර යැවෙන බැවින් මෙය මෙතෙකින් නවත්වනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"Inona no fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 08 ora alina fahiny ?","answer":"Ny fiantsoan'ny Ntaolo ny amin'ny 08 ora alina fahiny dia : \\"Manokom-bary olona\\". "},{"question":"Awakọ tirela gba oni-Maruwa lẹṣẹẹ, niyẹn ba ku patapata","answer":"Ẹka ti wọn ti n gbọ ẹsun ipaniyan ni ọkunrin kan bayii torukọ ẹ n jẹ Wasiu Adegbenro, wa bayii, nipinlẹ Ogun. Idi ni pe o gba ọkunrin kan to n wa kẹkẹ Maruwa lẹṣẹẹ lọsan-an ọjọ Ẹti to kọja yii, ni marosẹ Eko s’Ibadan, n lọkunrin naa torukọ ẹ n jẹ Oseni Sẹmutu ba bẹrẹ si i pọ ẹjẹ, bo ṣe ku niyẹn.Ohun ti DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, sọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii ni pe ọrọ kan lo di ija laarin Wasiu to n wa tirela ati Oseni to n wa Maruwa, lo ba di pe wọn yọwọ ẹṣẹ sira wọn, iyẹn ni nnkan bii aago meji ọsan kọja ogun iṣẹju lọjọ Jimọ naa.Nibi ti wọn ti n ja ija ọhun ni Wasiu ti fun Oseni lẹṣẹe kan to lagbara, bi Oseni ṣe bẹrẹ si i pọ ẹjẹ lẹnu niyẹn ti ẹjẹ si tun n yọ nimu rẹ pẹlu.Ọrọ di ti ọlọpaa gẹgẹ bi Alukoro ṣe wi, awọn ọlọpaa naa ni wọn si sare gbe Oseni lọ si ọsibitu to wa nitosi, ṣugbọn awọn dokita sọ pe ẹṣẹ to jẹ ko maa pọ ẹjẹ naa ti pa a, bi ọkunrin oni Maruwa naa ṣaa ṣe jẹ Ọlọrun nipe niyẹn.Ẹsẹkẹsẹ ni wọn ti mu Wasiu ti wọn lo fi ẹṣẹ pa a ju satimọle, CP Edward Ajogun si ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn mu un lọ sẹka to n gbọ ẹsun awọn apaniyan, ibẹ lo wa ta a fi pari akojọpọ iroyin yii."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe joro ary inona no atao mandritra ny joro?","answer":"Ny joro dia fomba Malagasy iray avy any amin'ny faritra avaratry ny nosy. Amin'ny finoana Malagasy, ny joro dia fipetrahan'ny fanahin'ny mpanjaka iray efa maty, anaty vatan'olombelona mba hahafahany mandray anjara amin'ny asa-piarahamonina. Mandritra io dia misy ny famonoana omby ho fangataham-pitahiana amin'ny razana, na ho sorona amin'ny zanahary. Izay no atao mandritra ny joro."},{"question":" வினா : மெட்ஸ் என்ற இடம் எங்குள்ளது?","answer":"விடை : பிரான்ஸ்"},{"question":"ఒక లంబకోణ త్రిభుజములోని భుజాలు పూర్ణాంకములు అయితే దానిలో కనీసము ఒక కొలత …………..A) 3 యొక్క గుణిజముB) 9 యొక్క గుణిజముC) 2 యొక , గుణిజముD) 7 యొక్క గుణిజము","answer":"C) 2 యొక , గుణిజము"},{"question":"Nitori ṣọja atawọn mi-in ti wọn ji gbe, awọn agbofinro ya lu igbo ọna Ibadan s’Ijẹbu-Ode ","answer":"Ba a ṣe n wi yii, inu igbo ni ikọ oluwadii laarin awọn agbofinro ipinlẹ Ọyọ wa, lati tu ṣọja atawọn obinrin meji ti awọn ajinigbe ji gbe silẹ ninu igbekun.Ikọ awọn agbofinro ọhun, eyi ti awọn ọlọpaa lewaju ẹ ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an aarọ Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee yii, lo ko ikọ eleto aabo ipinlẹ Ọyọ ta a mọ si Amọtẹkun atawọn fijilante pẹlu awọn agbaagba ọdẹ ibilẹ to wa nijọba ibilẹ Oluyọle, ni Idi-Ayunrẹ, n’Ibadan, sinu.Akọroyin ALAROYE atawọn oniroyin mi-in pẹlu awọn agbofinro ninu irinajo ọhun. O kere tan, afurasi ọdaran mẹta lo fẹsẹ fẹ ẹ nigba ti wọn gburoo awọn ọlọpaa to n bọ lọọọkan.Meji ninu wọn lo n da maaluu kiri ninu igbo nla naa, bi wọn ṣe ri awọn agbofinro lọọọkan ni wọn sọ ede ajejeji kan si awọn maaluu ọhun, ti awọn nnkan ọsin naa si ki ere buruku mọlẹ lojiji, ti wọn bẹrẹ si i sare tagbara tagbara. “Lẹẹkan naa lawọn darandaran wọnyi poora mọ aarin wọn, ti wọn si ṣe bẹẹ ra sinu aginju igbo naa pẹlu bi akitiyan awọn agbofinro lati ba awọn olowo wọn sọrọ ko ṣe seso rere debi ti wọn yoo ri wọn mu.Lẹyin wakati meji sigba naa la ri ọkunrin kan naa lọọọkan to bẹrẹ mọlẹ to n sare lọ. Lojiji lawọn ọlọpaa to gba ya a ko deede ri i mọ, ti wọn ko si tun gburoo ẹsẹ rẹ mọ titi ti irinajo ọhun fi pari.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ aabọ aarọ ọjọ kejila, oṣu kẹta, ọdun 2021 yii, lawọn ọbayejẹ kan ji obinrin ṣọja kan, Bọlanle Ogunrinde, atawọn meji mi-in ti wọn n jẹ Abọsẹde Adebayọ ati Abilekọ Ọkẹowo gbe labule ti wọn n pe ni Onipẹẹ, lọna to ti Ibadan lọ s’Ijẹbu-Ode nigba tawọn eeyan naa n ti Ibadan lọ sọna Ijẹbu-Ode pẹlu ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ Toyota wọn ti nọmba rẹ jẹ AGL 66 FY.Iwadii akọroyin wa fidi ẹ mulẹ pe lati ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọhun lawọn agbofinro ko ti sun, ti wọn ko wo lori itọpinpin awọn olubi ẹda naa.Laarin gbugbun aginju naa lapata nla kan wa, ninu eyi ti awọn agbofinro to wọ inu ẹ lọ ti ri oogun ara riro ati beba ti awọn eeyan kan tẹ silẹ lati fi ṣe ibusun, eyi to fi han pe awọn afurasi ọdaran kan n fara pamọ si aaye naa. O si ṣee ṣe ko jẹ pe ibẹ lawọn ọbayejẹ naa kọkọ gbe awọn ẹni ẹlẹni pamọ si ki wọn too gbe wọn lọ sibomi-in gẹgẹ bo ṣe jẹ pe awọn ajinigbe ki i gbe awọn eeyan ti wọn ba ji gbe duro soju kan.Lara awọn ikọ ọlọpaa to n fi tọsan toru wa awọn ọdaran naa ni ẹka ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to n gbogun ti ijinigbe, iyẹn Anti Kidnapping Squard, atawọn ikọ to n gbogun ti iwa ọdaran bii Puff Arder, Skynet, ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.Lati ọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii, lawọn kan ninu ikọ AKS, iyẹn ẹka ọlọpaa to n gbogun ti iṣẹlẹ ijinigbe ti fi inu igbo nla to so Ibadan pọ mọ Ijẹbu-Ode ṣebugbe, to jẹ pe ibẹ ni wọn n sun, ti wọn si n tẹsiwaju ninu iṣẹ iwadii wọn ninu igbo naa bi wọn ba ti ji.Nigba to n ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ lẹyin irinajo naa ni nnkan bii aago marun-un irọlẹ yii, AC Ops, iyẹn igbakeji ọga agba ọlọpaa to n mojuto iṣọwọ-ṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinle Ọyọ, ACP Gbenga Ojo, sọ pe “gẹgẹ ba a ṣe mọ, awọn iṣẹlẹ ijinigbe waye lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii lọna Ibadan si Ijẹbu-Ode, eyi lo jẹ ka fọn awọn ọlọpaa sita pẹlu iranlọwọ awọn fijilante atawọn ọdẹ ibilẹ.“Bo tilẹ jẹ pe a ko ri ẹnikan kan mu, a ko ni i kaaarẹ lori akitiyan wa lati gba awọn eeyan ti wọn ji gbe silẹ laaye. Loorekoore la oo maa fọ gbogbo inu igbo ti awọn oniṣẹ ibi n fara pamọ si bayii nitori a ko fẹẹ maa duro de awọn ọdaran wọnyi loju titi mọ bayii, a fẹẹ lọọ maa ka wọn mọnu igbo ni.”"},{"question":"Cé hé Jeff Merkley? ","answer":"Is é Jeffrey Alan Merkley seanadóir Stáit Aontaithe Mheiriceá sóisearach ó Oregon. Is ball den Pháirtí Daonlathach é. Ar 24 Deireadh Fómhair 1956 a rugadh é. "},{"question":"Qual é o nome da maior empresa de tecnologia da Coréia do Sul?","answer":"Samsung"},{"question":"క్రింది వానిలో అసత్య వాక్యం / వాక్యాలను గుర్తించండి.i) వాహక నిరోధం అపదార్థ స్వభావంపై ఆధారపడుతుంది.ii) వాహక నిరోధం వాహకం మధ్యచ్ఛేద వైశాల్యంపై ఆధారపడదుiii) వాహక నిరోధం వాహకం పొడవుపై ఆధార పడుతుంది.iv) వాహక నిరోధం వాహకం ఉష్ణోగ్రతపై ఆధారపడదు.A) (i) & (ii)B) (ii) & (iii)C) (ii) & (iv)D) (iv) మాత్రమే","answer":"C) (ii) & (iv)"},{"question":"આકારવાચક વિશેષણ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"આકારવાચક વિશેષણ: જેમાં આકાર અંગેનો વિશેષ ગુણ દર્શાવવામાં આવેલ હોય તેને આકારવાચક વિશેષણ કહે છે.ઉદાહરણ:ગોળ, લંબગોળ, અર્ધગોળ, ત્રિકોણ, ચોરસ, નળાકાર વગેરે આકારવાચક વિશેષણ સૂચવે છે."},{"question":"Kristallerin oynadığı nasıl anlaşılır?","answer":"En belirgin özelliği ise baş dönmesine neden olmasıdır. Bulunduğu bölgeden kopan kristaller, baş hareketleri ile birlikte yer değiştirir. Bu nedenle denge hücreleri uyarılır ve baş dönmesi ortaya çıkar. Kulak kristalinin oynaması nedeniyle oluşan baş dönmesi, genelde 15 – 60 saniye sürer."},{"question":"Me kalmar: \\"Goat\\" ke nufi a harshen Hausa? ","answer":"Kalmar \\"Goat\\" na nufin Akuya a harshen Hausa"},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa fibọn fọ mi lẹyin, wọn sọ mi di arọ, n ko si le bimọ mọ- Ọlasunkanmi","answer":"Awọn eeyan ti ko mọ Ọgbẹni Ọlasunkanmi Fagbemi ri fẹrẹ le maa ba a sunkun nigba ti ọkunrin ẹni ọdun marundinlaaadọta (45) naa n ṣalaye bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe yinbọn mọ ọn lọdun 2010, to si ṣe bẹẹ di ẹni ti ko le fẹsẹ ara ẹ rin mọ, ti ko si tun le fun obinrin kankan loyun mọ laye.Kootu Majisireeti Iṣabọ, l’Abẹokuta, ni Ọlasunkanmi ti ṣalaye ohun to ṣẹlẹ si i. Mọnde, ọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu yii, lo rojọ naa niwaju igbimọ to n gbọ ẹjọ awọn ti ọlọpaa ti fiya jẹ ri lọna aitọ.Ọkunrin naa jokoo ninu aga to fi n ṣe ẹsẹ rin ( Wheel chair), o si ṣalaye pe, ‘’Mo n lọ s’Ibadan lọjọ kejidinlogun, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun 2010, inu mọto ero ni mo wa ni nnkan bii aago meje alẹ, nigba naa ni awọn ọlọpaa to wa lagbegbe Fidiwọ si Alapako, ni marosẹ Eko s’Ibadan, da mọto wa duro.‘’Wọn gba ọndirẹdi naira lọwọ dẹrẹba wa, wọn si ni ko paaki mọlẹ daadaa kawọn le fun un ni ṣenji ọgọrin naira (#80).‘’Lẹyin ti dẹrẹba paaki tan, o sọkalẹ lati lọọ gba ṣenji rẹ, bi ọlọpaa kan to wa lodi-keji ọna ṣe yinbọn mọ mọto wa niyẹn. Ibọn yẹn ba mi lọrun, o si lọ si isalẹ eegun ẹyin mi. Nigba tawọn ọlọpaa naa ri ohun to ṣẹlẹ, niṣe ni wọn sa lọ.‘’Mi o mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ mọ, ileewosan ẹkọṣẹ iṣegun oyinbo to wa n’Ibadan (UCH), ni dẹrẹba atawọn ero ọkọ gbe mi lọ. Wọn da mi duro sọsibitu naa lati ṣiṣẹ abẹ, ọjọ kẹrin ni wọn too ri ọta ibọn naa yọ lara mi.‘’Mo n mura lati ṣegbeyawo nigba naa ni, ṣugbọn lẹyin iṣẹlẹ yii, ko ṣee ṣe mọ, nitori awọn dokita sọ fun mi pe mi o le fun obinrin kankan loyun mọ, afi ti mo ba lo ilana ọmọ bibi ti wọn n ṣe lasiko yii, ti wọn yoo gba nnkan ọmọkunrin mi, ti wọn yoo si gbe e sinu obinrin. Mi o ti i fẹyawo latigba naa, bẹẹ ni mi o ti i bimọ kankan’’Fagbemi loun ti kọwe si gbogbo ẹka to yẹ ko gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ yii, ṣugbọn ko so eso rere. O royin owo buruku to ti na nitori ati ri alaafia, ati bo ṣe jẹ pe wọn ti gbe oun lọ si India fun itọju, ṣugbọn lẹyin gbogbo ẹ naa, oun ko le fẹsẹ oun rin mọ, inu ṣia onirin yii naa loun n wa. Bẹẹ, ọlọpaa lo sọ aye oun di nnkan mi-in, toun ko le da nnkan kan ṣe mọ.Alaga igbimọ yii, Adajọ Solomon Olugbemi, sọ pe awọn yoo kọ lẹta si kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun, awọn to yẹ ko waa jẹjọ lori ọrọ yii yoo si yọju.O sun igbẹjọ si ọjọ kin-in-ni, oṣu kẹrin, ọdun 2021."},{"question":"Nitori Bọde George, wọn fẹẹ da sẹria fun Fayoṣe","answer":"Ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP l’Ekoo ti fun gomina ipinlẹ Ekiti tẹlẹ ni gbedeke ọjọ meje ko fi tọrọ aforiji lọwọ awọn agbaagba ẹgbẹ ọhun, paapaa Alagba Bọde Goerge, nitori to sọrọ kobakungbe si i.Peter Ayọdele Fayoṣe sọ lasiko ti ẹgbẹ naa n n ṣe ifilọlẹ eto idibo sileegbimọ aṣofin pe, niṣe lo yẹ ki awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ PDP Eko fẹyin baba ọhun ti bayii ninu ẹgbẹ.Fayoṣe sọ pe ti ẹgbẹ naa ba fẹẹ laṣeyọri gidi nipinlẹ Eko, afi ki wọn yọwọ Bọde George kuro ninu ọrọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu naa.Ọrọ to da wahala silẹ ree, bẹẹ lẹni to jẹ Alukoro fun ẹgbẹ naa nipinlẹ Eko, Ọgbẹni Gani Taofeek, ti sọ pe ọrọ ti Fayoṣe sọ yii le da ẹgbẹ ru, ati pe o le mu awọn ọdọ kọju oro si Oloye Bọde George, ti nnkan si le ṣe bẹẹ daru mọ ẹgbẹ naa lọwọ nipinlẹ naa.Wọn ti sọ pe Fayoṣe gbọdọ tọrọ aforiji ni, ti ko ba fẹẹ ki ẹgbẹ da sẹria nla fun oun lori ọrọ yii.O fi kun un pe ki i ṣe iru asiko ti PDP n palemọ gidigidi lati gba ipinlẹ Eko mọ APC lọwọ, paapaa fun ipo gomina lọdun 2023, lo yẹ ki Fayoṣe sọ ọrọ to le tu ẹgbẹ ọhun ka.Ni bayii, wọn ti fun un ni ọjọ meje ko fi ṣatunṣe si ohun to ṣe yii, bakan naa ni wọn fi kun un pe ti ko ba tọrọ aforiji, ko ni i lẹtọọ lati kopa ninu eto kankan ti ẹgbẹ ba n ṣe, nitori ọkunrin naa ko duro gẹgẹ bii awokọṣe rere fawọn ọdọ ninu ẹgbẹ naa."},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  «... هم به نمایش درآمد، اما وارد مرحله‌ی نهایی نشد. جشنواره فیلم کن ۱۹۷۰ فیلم در تولدو، اسپانیا فیلم‌برداری شده‌ است. فیلم تریستانا نامزد دریافت جایزه اسکار بهترین فیلم غیر انگلیسی‌زبان شد و در ...»","answer":"جشنواره فیلم کن ۱۹۷۰"},{"question":"Me kalmar: \\"swear\\" ke nufi a harshen Hausa?","answer":" Kalmar \\"swear\\" na nufin \\"rantse\\" a harshen Hausa"},{"question":"Narendra Modi","answer":"Narendrabhai Damodardas Modi ni Mínísítà àgbà India kẹrìnlá àti mínísítà àgbà tí India lọ́wọ́ lọ́wọ́ lati ọdun 2014. O jẹ oloselu kan lati Bharatiya Janata Party, agbari-iṣẹ oluyọọda ara ilu Hindu kan. Oun ni Prime Minister akọkọ ni ita ti Ile-igbimọjọ ti Orilẹ-ede India lati ṣẹgun awọn ofin itẹlera meji pẹlu opoju to kun ati ekeji lati pari diẹ sii ju ọdun marun ni ọfiisi lẹhin Atal Bihari Vajpayee.Ti a bi si idile Gujarati ni Vadnagar, Modi ṣe iranlọwọ fun baba rẹ lati ta tii bi ọmọde ati pe o ti sọ pe nigbamii o ta iduro tirẹ. O ṣe agbekalẹ si RSS ni ọmọ ọdun mẹjọ, bẹrẹ ibasepọ pipẹ pẹlu agbari. Modi fi ile silẹ lẹhin ti pari ile-iwe giga ni apakan nitori igbeyawo ọmọde si Jashodaben Chimanlal Modi, eyiti o kọ silẹ ti o gba ni gbangba ni ọpọlọpọ awọn ọdun sẹhin. Modi rin kakiri India fun ọdun meji o si ṣabẹwo si ọpọlọpọ awọn ile-iṣẹ ẹsin ṣaaju ki o to pada si Gujarat. Ni ọdun 1971 o di oṣiṣẹ akoko kikun fun RSS. Lakoko ipo pajawiri ti wọn fi paṣẹ kaakiri orilẹ-ede ni ọdun 1975, Modi fi agbara mu lati lọ pamọ. RSS naa fi i si BJP ni ọdun 1985 ati pe o waye ọpọlọpọ awọn ipo laarin awọn ipo-iṣe ẹgbẹ titi di ọdun 2001, dide si ipo ti akọwe gbogbogbo.Modi dari BJP ni idibo gbogbogbo ọdun 2014 eyiti o fun ẹgbẹ naa ni ọpọlọpọ ninu ile aṣofin kekere ti India, Lok Sabha, akoko akọkọ fun eyikeyi ẹgbẹ kan lati 1984. Ijọba Modi ti gbiyanju lati gbe idoko-owo taara ajeji ni aje India. ati dinku inawo lori eto ilera ati awọn eto iranlọwọ ni awujọ. Modi ti gbiyanju lati mu ilọsiwaju ṣiṣe ni iṣẹ-ṣiṣe ijọba; o ti ni agbara agbedemeji nipasẹ didi Igbimọ Eto. O bẹrẹ ipolongo imototo ti profaili giga, bẹrẹ ipilẹṣẹ ariyanjiyan ti awọn iwe ifowopamọ ti orukọ giga, ati dinku tabi paarẹ awọn ofin ayika ati iṣẹ.Ni atẹle iṣẹgun ti ẹgbẹ rẹ ni idibo gbogbogbo 2019, iṣakoso rẹ fagile ipo pataki ti Jammu ati Kashmir. Ijọba rẹ tun ṣe agbekalẹ ofin Atunse ti Ilu-ilu, eyiti o mu ki awọn ehonu jakejado jakejado orilẹ-ede naa. Ti a ṣe apejuwe bi imọ-ẹrọ iṣe atunṣe oselu si iṣelu apa-ọtun, Modi jẹ nọmba ti ariyanjiyan ni ile ati ni kariaye lori awọn igbagbọ ti orilẹ-ede Hindu rẹ ati ipa ti o fi ẹsun kan lakoko awọn rudurudu Gujarat 2002, ti a tọka si bi ẹri ti eto iyasoto iyasoto."},{"question":"भारतीय मुद्रेचे नाव “रूपया” सर्वात पहिले कोणत्या शासकाने ठेवले ?","answer":"शेरशहा सुरी"},{"question":"නේපාලයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"නේපාලයේ අගනුවර කත්මන්ඩු ය. එය රටේ විශාලතම නගරය පමණක් නොව එහි සංස්කෘතික හා  ආර්ථික කේන්ද්‍රස්ථානය ලෙසද කටයුතු කරයි. කත්මණ්ඩු එහි පොහොසත් ඉතිහාසය, විචිත්‍රවත් සංස්කෘතිය සහ යුනෙස්කෝ ලෝක උරුම ස්ථාන කිහිපයක් ඇතුළුව ඓතිහාසික ස්ථාන රැසකට ප්‍රසිද්ධය."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي احتوت على آيات المواريث؟","answer":"الجواب: سورة النساء."},{"question":" Sheeg Imisa Ciidood Ayuu ISLAAMKU Lee Yahay","answer":" ISLAAM-KA Wuxu Lee Yahay 3 Ciidood,1- Ciida Carafa (Al Adxa)2- Ciida Soonka (Fidriga)3- Ciida Maalinta Jimcaha"},{"question":"Idiat Ṣóbándé","answer":"Idiat Ṣóbándé jẹ́ gbajúmọ̀ Òṣèrébìnrin sinimá àgbéléwò èdè Yorùbá ọmọ Nàìjíríà. Wọ́n yàn án fún àmìn ẹ̀yẹ ti Òṣèrébìnrin tó dára jù ní ìpò olú-ẹ̀dá-ìtàn, Africa Movie Academy Award for Best Actress in a Leading Role lọ́dún 2011 fún ipa tí ó kó nínú sinimá àgbéléwò, Aramotu.Idiat jẹ́ ọmọ bíbí Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn. Ó dara pọ̀ mọ́ iṣẹ́ tíátà lọ́dún 1995. In 2011, Idiat revealed to Vanguard, that her role in Aramotu as a woman of affluence, prompted her to champion a case for gender equality in Nigeria. Idiat ti kópa nínú ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ sinimá àgbéléwò èdè Yorùbá, lára wọn ni; Iyawo Sààráà, Àbọ̀dé Mecca, Kóńdó Ọlọ́pàá, Ọmọ Ìyá Àjọ and Aramotu. Other notable films includes, Kondo Olopa (2007), Láròdá òjò (2008) and Ìgbẹ̀yìn Ewúro (2009).Lọ́dún 2010, Idiat kópa olú ẹ̀dá ìtàn nínú sinimá Aramotu. Sinimá tó sọ nípa ipa pàtàkì tí àwọn obìnrin Yorùbá láwùjọ. Ipa yìí mú kí wọ́n yàn án fún àmìn-ẹ̀yẹ Òṣèrébìnrin tó dára jù ní ìpò olú-ẹ̀dá-ìtàn, Africa Movie Academy Award for Best Actress in a Leading Role, bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé kò gbà á. Ó pàdánù àmì ẹ̀yẹ fún akẹgbẹ́ rẹ̀, Ama Abebrese"},{"question":"Awọn aṣofin pariwo, wọn ni were n pọ si i l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Pẹlu bawọn were atawọn alairilegbe ṣe gba igboro Abẹokuta kan nipinlẹ Ogun, ti wọn si n fojoojumọ pọ si i, ile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ naa ti ke si awọn tọrọ kan nijọba pe ki wọn wa nnkan ṣe si i.Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, lawọn aṣofin gbe ọrọ awọn were naa yẹwo nileegbimọ to wa l’Oke -Mosan, l’Abẹokuta.Olori wọn, Ọnarebu Ọlakunle Oluọmọ, sọ pe iṣẹ wa fun ileeṣẹ to n ri si ọrọ awọn obìnrin nipinlẹ Ogun,  pẹlu awọn ẹka bii tiẹ lati ṣe lori apọju were tawọn tori ẹ pepade yii.O lo jẹ oun ti ko ṣee dagunla si bo ṣe jẹ pe èèyàn ko le rin jinna ko too kan alarun ọpọlọ kaakiri ilu Abẹokuta.Oluọmọ rọ Kọmiṣanna fọrọ awọn obinrin, Abilekọ Funmi Ẹfuwapẹ, pe ko pe awọn ẹka ti ọrọ yii kan, ki wọn jọ tete bẹrẹ eto lori bi wọn yoo ṣe ko awọn were atawọn to sọ titi dile naa kuro nigboro Abẹ́òkútaBakan naa ni wọn sọrọ lori ipo idọti ti odo ẹran Kara wa, iyẹn loju ọna marosẹ Eko s’Ibadan. Awọn aṣofin bii Dare Kadiri (Igbakeji abẹnugan) Atinukẹ Bello(Akojaanu), Ganiyu Oyedeji ati bẹẹ lọ, ṣalaye pe ipo to le ko ba ilera eeyan ni ọja ti wọn ti n pa ẹran maaluu yii wa, bẹẹ, ibẹ lọpọ eeyan ti n ra ẹran ti wọn n jẹ.Wọn rọ awọn ẹka imọtoto lati mojuto Kara, fun ilera to peye awọn eeyan kaakiri."},{"question":"මිනිස් වාසයක් සහිත ලොව ශීතලම ප්‍රදේශය","answer":"ඔ‍යැම්ප්කොන්"},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : సిక్కు మత స్థాపకులు ఎవరు? సిక్కుమతంలోని ప్రధాన సూత్రాలేవి?","answer":"సిక్కు మత స్థాపకుడు – గురునానక్,సిక్కు మత ప్రధాన సూత్రాలు :ఇతడు దేవుడు ఒక్కడే అని మరియు సోదర భావాన్ని కలిగి ఉండాలని విశ్వసించాడు.సాధారణ ప్రజల భాషలో తన బోధనలు చేశాడు. గురునానక్ అనుచరులను సిక్కులుగా పిలుస్తారు.దేవుడు ఒక్కడే, మానవులందరూ ప్రత్యక్షంగా దేవునితో అనుసంధానం కాగలరు అనేవి గురునానక్ బోధనలలో విశేష ప్రాచుర్యం పొందినవి.కుల వ్యవస్థను నిరసించడం, కులం మరియు లింగ భేదం లేకుండా అందరూ సమానమేనని బోధించడం గురునానక్ బోధనలలోని ప్రగతిశీల అంశాలు."},{"question":"1945 இல் ஹிரோஷிமா மற்றும் நாகசாகிக்கு என்ன நடந்தது?","answer":"ஆகஸ்ட் 6 மற்றும் 9, 1945 இல், அமெரிக்கா ஜப்பானிய நகரங்களான ஹிரோஷிமா மற்றும் நாகசாகி மீது முறையே இரண்டு அணுகுண்டுகளை வெடிக்கச் செய்தது."},{"question":"Boğaz Köprüsünde havai fişek gösterisi ne zaman?","answer":"Cumhurbaşkanı Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, saat 19.23'te 100. yıl mesajını vatandaşlarla paylaşacak. Etkinlikler kapsamında 19.50'de ise 15 Temmuz Şehitler Köprüsü'nde 2023 dron ile İstanbul Boğazı'nda ışık ve havai fişek gösterileri yapılacak."},{"question":"北海道のアイヌ民族に伝わる英雄叙事詩のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"ユーカラ"},{"question":"फ्रान्सेली क्रान्तिको बारेमा केही भन्नुहोस्।","answer":"फ्रान्सेली क्रान्ति त्यो समय थियो जब फ्रान्सले महत्वपूर्ण राजनीतिक परिवर्तनहरू पार गर्यो। यो १७८९ को एस्टेट जनरलबाट सुरु भयो र नोभेम्बर १७९९ मा फ्रान्सेली वाणिज्य दूतावास बनाउँदा समाप्त भयो। फ्रान्सेली क्रान्तिको समयमा सिर्जना गरिएका धेरै विचारहरूलाई उदारवादी लोकतन्त्रको आवश्यक अंग मानिन्छ र आज फ्रान्सेली सरकारमा धेरै महत्त्वपूर्ण छ।धेरै फरक कुराहरूले यसको कारण बनायो। ज्ञानको युग भयो, र सरकारले कसरी काम गर्नुपर्छ भन्ने बारे मानिसहरूमा नयाँ विचारहरू थिए। फ्रान्स पनि ऋणमा परेको थियो किनभने उनीहरूले अमेरिकी क्रान्तिकारी युद्धमा संयुक्त राज्य अमेरिकालाई सहयोग गर्न पैसा खर्च गरे। तिनीहरूले सात वर्षको युद्ध र अस्ट्रियाको उत्तराधिकारको युद्धमा धेरै पैसा खर्च गरे। त्यतिबेला धेरै फ्रान्सेली जनताले सरकारलाई मन पराएनन्। सरकार राजतन्त्र थियो।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'orang dapur'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang perempuan. Contoh ayat: Hidangan ini disediakan oleh orang dapur saya, kata ayah kepada tetamu yang datang."},{"question":"ක්‍රි.ව. 851 දී ලංකාවට පැමිණ, මෙම ද්වීපය \\"සෙරෙන්ඩිබ්\\" ලෙස තම වාර්තාවල සඳහන් කරන ලද අරාබි ජාතික සංචාරකයා කවුද ?","answer":"එ​ම අරාබි ජාතික සංචාරකයා සුලෙයිමාන් අබුසහිඩ්ය."},{"question":"Inona no zava-nitranga nanamarika ny fiandohan’ny Ady Lehibe Voalohany?","answer":"Ny famonoana an’i Archduke Franz Ferdinand avy any Aotrisy tamin’ny 28 Jona 1914 tany Sarajevo no nanamarika ny fanombohan’ny Ady Lehibe Voalohany."},{"question":"请给以下的文言文它的译文：（颜）回年二十九，发尽白，蚤死。孔子哭之恸，曰：“自吾有回，门人益亲。”鲁哀公问：“弟子孰为好学？”孔子对曰：“有颜回者好学，不迁怒不贰过。不幸短命死矣，今也则亡。”","answer":"颜回二十九岁，头发全白了，过早地死了。孔子哭得十分伤心，说：“自从我有了颜回，学生们（以颜回为榜样）更加亲近我。”鲁哀公问（孔子）：“（你的）学生中谁是最好学的？”孔子回答说：“有个叫颜回的最好学，（他）从不把脾气发到别人的身上，也不重犯同样的错误。不幸年纪轻轻死了，现在没有（像颜回那样好学的人）了。"},{"question":"问题：三星公司的品牌口碑如何？","answer":"答案：三星公司凭借其产品质量、创新能力和用户体验赢得了良好的品牌口碑。"},{"question":"総合格闘技の大会「Ｋ－１グランプリ」で、４度とこれまでに最も多く優勝しているオランダの選手は誰でしょう？","answer":"アーネスト＝ホーストです。"},{"question":"ஈ.த இராஜேஸ்வரி அம்மையார் குறிப்பு வரைக?","answer":"• இராஜேஸ்வரி அம்மையார் 1906 முதல் 1955 வரை வாழ்ந்தவர்.• தமிழ், இலக்கியம், அறிவியல் ஆகிய துறைகளில் சிறந்து விளங்கினார்.• திருமந்திரம், தொல்காப்பியம், கைவல்யம் போன்ற நூல்களில் உள்ள அறிவியல் உண்மைகள்• குறித்துப் பல சொற்பொழிவுகள் ஆற்றினார்.• சூரியன், பரமாணுப்புராணம் போன்ற அறிவியல் நூல்களை எழுதியுள்ளார்."},{"question":"Uma cozinheira colocou sal a mais no feijão que estava cozinhando. Para solucionar o problema, ela acrescentou batatas cruas e sem tempero dentro da panela. Quando terminou de cozinhá-lo, as batatas estavam salgadas, porque absorveram parte do caldo com excesso de sal. Finalmente, ela adicionou água para completar o caldo do feijão.O sal foi absorvido pelas batatas por:a) osmose, por envolver apenas o transporte do solvente.b) fagocitose, porque o sal transportado é uma substância sólida.c) exocitose, uma vez que o sal foi transportado da água para a batata.d) pinocitose, porque o sal estava diluído na água quando foi transportado.e) difusão, porque o transporte ocorreu a favor do gradiente de concentração.","answer":"A resposta correcta é a alternativa: e) difusão, porque o transporte ocorreu a favor do gradiente de concentração."},{"question":"Ciết bài luận ngắn khoảng 500 từ về quan niệm sống của bản thân.","answer":"Trong cuộc sống của chúng ta, luôn tồn tại vấn đề được và mất trong cuộc sống, chính vì thế trong Trong bài Một Khúc ca Tố Hữu đã trình bày quan điểm sống: “ Sống là cho đâu chỉ nhận riêng mình”.Đây cũng là một trong những quan niệm sống mà bản thân em tâm đắc nhất. “Cho”, tức là cho đi những thứ quý giá không chỉ về mặt vật chất mà còn về cả mặt tinh thần, đó có thể là tình yêu thương sự đồng cảm, “nhận”, đó chính là những thứ mà chúng ta có được sau khi cho đi. Thực chất câu nói của Tố Hữu muốn khẳng định, hãy biết cho đi mà không cần nhận lại, đó mới là cuộc sống có ý nghĩa. Vậy tại sao “sống là cho đâu chỉ nhận riêng mình”? Trong cuộc sống có rất nhiều người có hoàn cảnh khó khăn, bất hạnh chúng ta cần phải biết giúp đỡ, san sẻ để họ vượt qua những khó khăn đó. Hãy dùng tình yêu thương, tấm lòng nhân ái của mình để kết nối hàng triệu trái tim sát lại gần nhau và khi làm những điều đó đừng bao giờ mong muốn được nhận lại. Bởi ngoài kia còn rất nhiều người cần nhận sự giúp đỡ của chúng ta.  Sau khi cho đi ta sẽ cảm thấy mình nhận được nhiều thứ quý giá hơn gấp nhiều lần, đó là những ánh mắt biết ơn, những lời cảm ơn chân thành.Hồ Chí Minh là một tấm gương cho lối sống cao đẹp này. Bác luôn mở lòng để yêu thương và trân trọng đồng bào, bởi với người dân là gốc, dân là con, là máu thịt. Chính tư tưởng ấy đã chiến thắng sự bạo tàn của kẻ thù. Dự án gia sư tình nguyện do bạn trẻ Hồ Diên Tuấn Anh khởi xướng là một hoạt động có ý nghĩa tiêu biểu cho lối sống, là cho đi đâu chỉ nhận riêng mình và sau gần 4 tháng hoạt động dự án đã thu hút hơn 500 bạn trẻ tham gia làm gia sư miễn phí cho các em nhỏ có hoàn cảnh khó khăn bất hạnh. Tuy nhiên bên cạnh đó vẫn còn nhiều người có lối sống ích kỷ không muốn cho đi chỉ muốn nhận lại hoặc cho đi để mình được nhiều người biết đến… Mỗi người chúng ta cần phải biết phê phán những con người có lối sống trên, hãy luôn giúp đỡ mọi người xung quanh khi họ cần mà không mong muốn nhận lại để cuộc sống tốt đẹp hơn."},{"question":"लाङटाङ क्षेत्रको कुन पदयात्रा मार्गले सांस्कृतिक अन्वेषण र लाङटाङ र गणेश हिमालको मनोरम दृश्यहरूको संयोजन प्रदान गर्दछ?","answer":"लाङटाङ गणेश हिमाल पदयात्राले सांस्कृतिक अन्वेषण र लाङटाङ र गणेश हिमाल पर्वतश्रृङ्खलाको मनोरम दृश्यहरूको संयोजन प्रदान गर्दछ, जसले पदयात्रीहरूलाई हिमालयको राम्रो अनुभव प्रदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Iza no nitondra an'i Frantsay nandritra ny  vanim-potoanan' ny fampihorohoroana?","answer":"Maximilien de Robespierre dia anisan'ny mpitondra ny Frantsay nandritra ny vanim-potoanan'ny fampihorohoroana."},{"question":"चीन ने अपने पहले मंगल रोवर का नाम रखा ‘झुरोंग’","answer":"यह रोवर वर्तमान में चीन के मार्स प्रोब तियानवेन -1 पर स्थित है, जिसने 24 फरवरी को मंगल की कक्षा में प्रवेश किया था और जीवन के साक्ष्य खोजने के लिए यह मई माह में लाल ग्रह पर उतरेगा."},{"question":"\\"Nandraraka divay tamin'ny akanjoko ilay mpandroso sakafo nandritra ny sakafo hariva.\\" Inona ny fihetseham-po raketin'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Raha ny fanadihadiana an'io fanambarana io dia tsy mampiseho fihetseham-pon'ilay olona voararaka divay tamin'ny ankanjony io fanambarana io fa milaza ny zava-nitranga fotsiny."},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் இயற்கை எழில் எந்த வகையில் அற்புதமானது?","answer":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் இயற்கை எழில் அற்புதமானது. தமிழ்நாட்டில் பல அழகான கடற்கரைகள், மலைகள், காடுகள் உள்ளன. தமிழ்நாட்டின் இயற்கை எழில் சுற்றுலாப் பயணிகளை கவர்கிறது. தமிழ்நாட்டின் இயற்கை எழில் மனதை கொள்ளை கொள்கிறது."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny diso tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Nirohondrohona ny onjan-dranomasna, ka nahatrtra haavo manaitra.\\" .","answer":"Ity ny fehezanteny marina : \\"Nirohondrohona ny onjan-dranomasina ka nahatratra haavo manaitra.\\" ."},{"question":"በኢትዮጵያ ዘመን አቆጣጠር የመጀመሪያው ቀን መች ይጀምራል?","answer":"መስከረም ፩"},{"question":"Name the national river of India?","answer":"The national river of India is the Ganges, also known as the Ganga. It was declared as the national river of India in November 2008 with the aim of increasing public awareness and efforts towards its conservation. The Ganges is deeply revered and holds a significant place in the culture, tradition, and mythology of India. It is also one of the most important and holy rivers for Hindus. The river originates from the Gangotri glacier in Uttarakhand, India, and flows through several states in Northern India before entering Bangladesh, where it eventually merges with the Bay of Bengal."},{"question":"Iza no namorona ny orinasa malagasy TIKO?","answer":"I Marc RAVALOMANANA izay filoha nitondra an' i Madagasikara teo aloha no namorona ny orinasa malagasy TIKO."},{"question":"කොවිඩ් ඩෙල්ටා ප්ලස් වයිරසය මුලින්ම වාර්තාවුන රට","answer":"ඉන්දියාව"},{"question":"O que são transgênicos?","answer":"Transgênico é sinônimo para a expressão \\"Organismo Geneticamente Modificado\\" (OGM). É um organismo que recebeu um gene de outro organismo doador. Essa alteração no seu DNA permite que mostre uma característica que não tinha antes. Na natureza, as alterações ou mutações naturais ocorrem com frequência. No caso de um OGM, os cientistas controlam essa alteração e depois estudam a fundo se o produto final é equivalente ao produto não modificado."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: Κατά τη διάρκεια των Βαλκανικών Πολέμων το χωριό κατακτήθηκε από τμήματα του βουλγαρικού στρατού, αλλά μετά τον","answer":"Δεύτερο Βαλκανικό πόλεμο το 1913 το χωριό ελευθερώθηκε και προσαρτήθηκε στην Ελλάδα."},{"question":"\\"Scooby-Doo သည် ၁၉၆၉ ခုနှစ်မှ ယနေ့အထိ ထုတ်လုပ်ခဲ့သော ရုပ်ရှင် ရုပ်သံဇာတ်လမ်းတွဲများစွာပါဝင်သော အမေရိကန် ရုပ်ရှင် ကာတွန်းဇာတ်ကားဖြစ်သည်။\\" သို့ ချိတ်ဆက်ထားသော စာမျက်နှာများ အကြောင်းအရာက Scooby-Doo ပါ။","answer":"\\"Scooby Doo က  ရုပ်သံဇာတ်လမ်းတွဲ အကြောင်း ပြောပြပါ\\""},{"question":"Hoe kan ik me het beste voorbereiden op een presentatie op een conferentie?","answer":"Een goede voorbereiding zorgt ervoor dat je niet zenuwachtig hoeft te zijn. Bespreek met de organisator wat de wensen zijn, en wie je kunt verwachten als publiek. Begin op tijd met eventuele slides of ander materiaal wat je wil laten zien. Oefen een paar keer voor de spiegel. En vooral: ontspan, je bent er voor je plezier!"},{"question":"ለሚከተለው ጽሁፍ ርዕስ ይፍጠሩ: ከዛሬ ጀምሮ ለአንድ ወር የሚቆይ የነዳጅ ምርቶች የችርቻሮ ዋጋ ይፋ መሆኑን የንግድና ቀጣናዊ ትስስር ገልጿል። ሚኒስቴሩ በዛሬው ዕለት ባወጣው መግለጫ የዓለም ነዳጅ ዋጋ ከሚያዝያ ወር 2015 ጀምሮ እስከሰኔ ወር መጨረሻ ድረስ አንጻራዊ መረጋጋት እንደታየበት ገልጿል፡፡በዚህም ፥ ላለፉት አራት ወራት በችርቻሮ መሸጫ ዋጋ ላይ ለውጥ ሳይደረግ መቆየቱን አስታውሷል፡፡ ሆኖም ግን የዓለም ነዳጅ ዋጋ ከሐምሌ ጀምሮ የነዳጅ ዋጋ በከፍተኛ ሁኔታ እያሳየ በመምጣቱ ዋጋውን ማሻሻያ ማድረግ ማስፈለጉ ተገልጿል፡፡","answer":"በእርግጥ፣ ለተሰጠው ጽሑፍ ርዕስ ይኸውና: ነዳጅ ምርቶች የችርቻሮ ዋጋ ጭማሪ ተደርጓል።"},{"question":"ஒலிம்பிக்கில் பதக்கம் வென்ற முதல் இந்தியப் பெண் யார்?","answer":"பளுதூக்கும் வீராங்கனை கர்ணம் மல்லேஸ்வரி 2000 ஆம் ஆண்டு சிட்னியில் நடந்த ஒலிம்பிக்கில் வெண்கலப் பதக்கம் வென்ற முதல் இந்தியப் பெண்மணி ஆவார்."},{"question":"Kaip dar vadinamos infekcinės ligos? Atsižvelgiant į ankstesnį klausimą, parašykite kontekstą, kuriame būtų atsakymas. Tai gali būti nuo 1 iki 20 sakinių. Kontekstas:","answer":"Infekcinės ligos kartais vadinamos užkrečiamomis ligomis, kai jos lengvai perduodamos kontaktuojant su sergančiu asmeniu arba jo sekrecija (pvz., gripu). Taigi užkrečiama liga yra infekcinių ligų, kurios yra ypač užkrečiamos arba lengvai perduodamos, dalis. Kiti infekcinių / užkrečiamų / užkrečiamų ligų tipai, kuriems būdingi labiau specializuoti infekcijos keliai, pvz., perdavimo per vektorių ar lytinio perdavimo, paprastai nelaikomi \\"neplastiškais\\" ir dažnai nereikalauja, kad aukos būtų izoliuotos (kartais laisvai vadinamos karantinu). Tačiau ši specializuota žodžių \\"nešiojamų\\" ir \\"nešiojamų ligų\\" (lengvai perduodamų) konotacija ne visada gerbiama visuomene."},{"question":"Türk Telekom neden LTE yazıyor?","answer":"LTE (Long Term Evolution) ağ teknolojilerine dayalı yüksek hızlı kablosuz veri aktarıma verilen addır. 4.5G hızının bir başka adı olan LTE'yi yüksek hızlı mobil internete veriln ad olarak da tanımlamak mümkün. LTE 2G ya da 3G gibi bağlantıların aksine, tamamen IP bazlıdır."},{"question":"சங்க காலத்திலேயே தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டுள்ளது என்பதை தகுந்த சான்றுடன் நிறுவுக.","answer":"‘மாபாரதம் தமிழ்ப் படுத்தும் மதுராபுரிச் சங்கம் வைத்தும்’ என்னும் சின்னமனூர் செப்பேடு குறிப்பின் மூலம் சங்க காலத்திலேயே தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு உள்ளது என்பதை உணர முடிகிறது."},{"question":"පුලන්නා යන පදයට දිය හැකි අර්ථ කථනය කුමක්ද ඕනෑම කෙනෙකු සදහා මේ පදය යෙදිය හැකිද?","answer":"යමක් ලබා ගැනීමේ අපේක්ෂාවෙන් නොයිල්ලා බලා ඉන්න අයට තමයි පුලන්නන් කියන්නෙ. සිඟන්නන් පුලන්නන්ගෙන් වෙනස් වෙන්නෙ ඒ අය ඉල්ලන නිසා."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'laut ditimba akan kering'? Berikan contoh ayat. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud harta akan habis jika selalu dibelanjakan walaupun banyak harta pada awalnya. Contoh ayat: Laut ditimba akan kering, janganlah boros membelanjakan wang yang diwarisi, laburkannya demi perancangan kewangan untuk masa hadapan. "},{"question":"வினா:அரசரும், அமைச்சர்களும் கூடும் இடம்.","answer":"விடை:அரசவை."},{"question":"\\"අඹ යාළුවෝ \\"පොත ලිව්වේ කවුරුන් ද?","answer":"\\"අඹ යාළුවෝ\\" ග්‍රන්ථය ශ්‍රී ලාංකේය කීර්තිමත් ලේඛකයෙකු වන ටී.බී. ඉලංගරත්න විසින් රචිත සිංහල නවකතාවකි. මෙය සිංහල සාහිත්‍යයේ සම්භාව්‍ය කෘතියක් ලෙස සැලකෙන අතර ලාංකීය පාසල් ළමුන් අතර ඉතා  ජනප්‍රිය ය. ළමා ජීවිතය සහ එම කාලය තුළ ළමුන් දෙදෙනකු අතර ගොඩනැගුණු ගැඹුරු මිත්‍රත්වය මින් නිරූපණය කරයි. මෙම කතාව ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ගමක් පසුබිම් කර ගනිමින් රටේ ගැමි ජීවිතය සහ සංස්කෘතියේ හරය ග්‍රහණය වන පරිදි ලියැවී ඇත."},{"question":"Namna ya kuandaa ugali","answer":"Kuandaa ugali kunaitaji vitu vifuatavyo, moto, maji, sifuria, unga wa mahindi/mtama/mhogo/uwele... chemsha maji yako kisha andaa kwa kuchukua ynga kiasi mimina kwenye chombo kidogo , koroga hadi uchanganyikane kisha weka kwa maji yako yanayo chemka jikoni , subili hadi mchanganyiko huo uchanganyikane kisha, baada ya kuchemka weka unga wako songa kwa zaidi"},{"question":"This is an understanding","answer":"This is an understanding that several might be introduced to; however, it was done from a different perception of life. Bearing one's yoke means being able to discipline yourself through the enhancement of the seed of greatness deposited inside of you by God. When an individual lives a carefree life, there's a lot at stake, not just for the individual but also for those attached to such a person who must eat the fruit born out of the seed's development. Many have taken a different path to achieving their goals, which differs from what God is expecting us to do. When we see several characters in the scripture and, moreso, several in today's world who have bared their yoke through a burning desire erupted inside of them by virtue of discovering something that they can't let go of except it materialize, which has much substance embedded leading to a value proposition, First, where we seek to harness that seed, the environment where that is done is paramount and essential as to how and when that seed will germinate in a forest. Youth should seek out this truth through the Spirit of God and discipline themselves through study, meditation, mentoring, friend selection, habit withdrawal, and passion for excellence and destiny fulfillment. Until one bears his or her yoke, it will be impossible to fulfill purpose. Several take a quick path, but the end isn't pleasant. If you are on the right path, don't lose guard, stay focused, and surround yourself with the right mindset, you are on your way to the top."},{"question":"Bermuka dua bermaksud ____","answer":"tidak jujur"},{"question":"Marina ve fa mitelina hala ny olombelona rehefa matory?","answer":"Tsia, angano malaza an-tanàn-dehibe ilay hevitra hoe mitelina hala ny olombelona rehefa matory."},{"question":"வினா: ஏழைகளின் ஆப்பிள் என அழைக்கப்படும் பப்பாளி பழத்தின் மகத்துவம் என்ன?","answer":"விடை: ஆப்பிளைவிட சிறந்த பழம் பப்பாளி. இதில் ஆப்பிளில் உள்ளதைவிட அதிக அளவு சத்துக்கள் நிறைந்துள்ளன. விலையும் மிகமலிவு. இதனால் இதை ஏழைகளின் ஆப்பிள் என்றே அழைக்கலாம். பழங்களில் மிக மிக குறைவான கலோரி பப்பாளியில் தான் உள்ளது. 100 கிராம் பப்பாளியில் 32 கலோரிகளே உள்ளன. ஆப்பிளைக் காட்டிலும் இனிப்பான பழம் பப்பாளி. பப்பாளியை தினமும் நம் உணவுடன் சேர்த்து சாப்பிட்டால் நோய் நொடியின்றி நல்ல ஆரோக்கியமாக வாழலாம்.பப்பாளியை நாம் எந்தக் காலத்திலும் எப்பொழுது வேண்டுமானாலும் சாப்பிடலாம். இது ஒரு திகட்டாத பழம் என்பதால், நாம் அளவுக்கதிகமாக சாப்பிட்டு விடுவோம். அப்பொழுதுதான் பிரச்னை. அளவோடு சாப்பிடும் வரை இது அபூர்வமான பழம். முகெலும்பு பிதுக்கம் அல்ல நழுவல் காரணமாக வரும் கடுமயான வலிக்கு பப்பாளியில் உள்ள 'கமோ பாப்பன்' என்ற கெமிக்கல் நல்ல குணமளிப்பதாக அமெரிக்காவில் ஆய்வு செய்து கண்டுபிடித்துள்ளனர்.பொதுவாகவே பப்பாளி தலைமுடி, சருமம், கண்பார்வை, தொண்டை, வயிறு, சிறுநீரகம் அனைத்துக்கும் மிகவும் ஏற்றது. எக்காரணத்தைக் கொண்டும் பப்பாளியை நாம் தவிர்த்தால், நம் ஆரோக்கியத்தை நாம் தவிர்க்கிறோம் என்றுதான் அர்த்தம்.வாய்ப்புண்ணுக்கு மருந்தாகும் பப்பாளிப் பால்! ஏழைகளின் ஆப்பிள் என்று வர்ணிக்கப்படும் பப்பாளி பழம், பப்பாளி காய் மற்றும் அதன் பாலின் மருத்துவ குணங்கள் மற்றும் வீட்டில் எளிய முறையில் இவைகளை எவ்வாறு பயன் படுத்த வேண்டும் என்பதை பார்ப்போம்.... யாருக்கு நல்லது: மூட்டுவலி உள்ளவர்களுக்கும், உடல் எடையை குறைக்க விரும்புபவர்களுக்கும் நீரிழிவு நோயாளிகளுக்கும். யாருக்கு வேண்டாம்: கர்ப்பிணிப் பெண்கள் முதல் எட்டு வாரங்களுக்கு தவிர்க்கவும். பலன்கள்: சருமத்தில் சுருக்கம் விழாமல் பாதுகாக்கும். குடல் பூச்சிகளைச் அழித்துச் சுத்தம் செய்யும். * பப்பாளி பழத்தை அடிக்கடி குழந்தைகளுக்கு கொடுத்து வர உடல் வளர்ச்சி துரிதமாகும். எலும்பு வளர்ச்சி, பல் உறுதி ஏற்படும். * பப்பாளிக் காயை கூட்டாக செய்து உண்டு வர குண்டான உடல் படிப்படியாக மெலியும். தொடர்ந்து பப்பாளிப் பழத்தை சாப்பிட்டு வர கல்லீரல் வீக்கம் குறையும். * பப்பாளிப் பழத்தை தேனில் தோய்த்து உண்டு வர நரம்புத் தளர்ச்சி குறையும். * நன்கு பழுத்த பழத்தை கூழாக பிசைந்து தேன் கலந்து முகத்தில் பூசி, ஊறிய பின் சுடுநீரால் கழுவி வர முகச்சுருக்கம் மாறி, முகம் அழகு பெறும். * பப்பாளி விதைகளை அரைத்து பாலில் கலந்து சாப்பிட நாக்குப்பூச்சிகள் அழிந்து விடும். * பப்பாளிக் காயின் பாலை வாய்ப்புண், புண்கள் மேல் பூச புண்கள் ஆறும். * பப்பாளிப் பாலை, பசும்பாலுடன் கலந்து சேற்றுப் புண்கள் மேல் தடவி வர புண்கள் ஆறும். * பப்பாளிப் பாலை குழந்தைகளின் தலையில் ஏற்படும் புண்களில் பூசி வர புண்கள் ஆறும். * பப்பாளி இலைகளை அரைத்து கட்டி மேல் போட்டு வர கட்டி உடையும். * பப்பாளி இலைகளை பிழிந்து எடுத்து வீக்கங்கள் மேல் பூசி வர வீக்கம் கரையும். * பப்பாளி விதைகளை அரைத்து தேள் கொட்டிய இடத்தில் பூச வலி, விஷம் இறங்கும். * பப்பாளிக் காய் குழம்பை, பிரசவித்த பெண்கள் உணவில் சேர்த்து வர பால் சுரப்பு கூடும்."},{"question":"පළමුවැනි ලෝක යුද්ධයට එක් හේතුවක් වෙමින් ඇල්සේස් සහ ලොරේන් ප්‍රදේශවල අයිතිය වෙනුවෙන් සටන්කල රටවල් දෙක මොනවාද?","answer":"එම ප්‍රදේශවල අයිතිය වෙනුවෙන් සටන්කල රටවල් දෙක වන්​නේ ජර්මනිය සහ ප්‍රංශයයි."},{"question":"Verilen metin hangi konu hakkındadır?: Türkiye'deki kadın hakları mücadelesi uzun bir geçmişe sahiptir ve çeşitli dönemlerde önemli gelişmeler kaydetmiştir. Osmanlı İmparatorluğu'nda kadın hakları mücadelesi, 19. yüzyılda başladı. Bu dönemdeki kadınlar, eğitim, iş ve sosyal katılım hakları için çaba harcadılar. Özellikle Tanzimat Dönemi'nde (1839-1876) kadınların eğitim hakkı tanındı ve ilk okullar açıldı. Türkiye'nin Cumhuriyet dönemi, kadın hakları mücadelesi için önemli bir dönüm noktasıdır. 1926'da Türk Medeni Kanunu kabul edildi ve bu, kadınların medeni haklarını önemli ölçüde genişletti. Kadınlar bu dönemde eğitim, iş ve siyasi katılım konularında daha fazla fırsat elde etmeye başladılar.","answer":"Paragraf, Türkiye'de kadın mücadelesinin tarihsel süreci hakkındadır."},{"question":"Açıkta kalan öğrenciler ne yapacak 2023 LGS?","answer":"Boş kalan kontenjanlar ve hiçbir yere yerleşemeyen öğrenciler için il/ilçe öğrenci yerleştirme ve nakil komisyonlarınca yerleştirme başvuruları 8-16 Ağustos'ta alınacak. Okul ve kurumlar yatılılık başvurularını 22-25 Ağustos'ta alacak. 31 Ağustos'ta ise yatılılık yerleştirme sonuçları ilan edilecek."},{"question":"সময় যাত্রার সাথে সম্পর্কিত যমজ প্যারাডক্সের বর্ণনা দাও।","answer":"সময় ভ্রমণের সাথে সম্পর্কিত যমজ প্যারাডক্স হল একটি কল্পনামূলক পরিস্থিতি যা দুটি যমজ ভাইয়ের মধ্যে ঘটে যাদের মধ্যে একজন সময় ভ্রমণ করে। প্যারাডক্সটি হল যে, সময় ভ্রমণকারী যমজ তার ভ্রমণের কারণে তার ভাইয়ের চেয়ে বেশি বয়সী হয়ে ফিরে আসবে।প্যারাডক্সটি প্রথমবারের মতো ১৯১১ সালে ইংরেজ পদার্থবিদ হেনরি ওয়েলস রচনা করেছিলেন। ওয়েলস তার ১৮৯৫ সালের উপন্যাস \\"দ্য টাইম মেশিন\\"-এ এই প্যারাডক্সের একটি সংস্করণ বর্ণনা করেছিলেন।প্যারাডক্সটি একটি বৈজ্ঞানিক সমস্যা কারণ এটি সময় ভ্রমণের সম্ভাব্যতার উপর ভিত্তি করে তৈরি। যদি সময় ভ্রমণ সম্ভব হয়, তাহলে যমজ প্যারাডক্সের মতো পরিস্থিতির সম্ভাবনা রয়েছে। যমজ প্যারাডক্সের একটি সংক্ষিপ্ত বিবরণ হলো এই যে - দুটি যমজ ভাই, ধরা যাক রাম এবং শ্যাম, একই সময়ে জন্মগ্রহণ করে। রাম কিছু সময়ের জন্য সময় ভ্রমণ করে ও তারপর ফিরে আসে এবং দেখা যায় যে শ্যাম তার চেয়ে বেশি বয়সী।যমজ প্যারাডক্স হল সময় ভ্রমণের সাথে সম্পর্কিত একটি চ্যালেঞ্জিং সমস্যা। এটি সময় ভ্রমণের সম্ভাব্যতা এবং এর প্রভাবগুলির উপর আমাদের বোঝার জন্য একটি গুরুত্বপূর্ণ পরীক্ষা। প্যারাডক্সটি সমাধান করার জন্য বেশ কয়েকটি সম্ভাব্য উপায় রয়েছে। একটি সম্ভাব্য সমাধান হল যে, সময় ভ্রমণকারী যমজ সময়ের অবিচ্ছিন্নতাকে লঙ্ঘন করে। অন্য একটি সম্ভাব্য সমাধান হল যে, মহাবিশ্বের একটি বহুবিশ্ব রয়েছে, এবং সময় ভ্রমণকারী যমজ অন্য একটি বহুবিশ্বে ফিরে আসে। এই প্যারাডক্সটি সমাধান করার জন্য বেশ কয়েকটি সম্ভাব্য সমাধান রয়েছে, তবে কোনওটিই সর্বজনীনভাবে গৃহীত হয়নি।"},{"question":"પ્રશ્નવાચક વિશેષણ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"પ્રશ્નવાચક વિશેષણ: જે વિશેષણ પ્રશ્ન પૂછવા માટે વપરાય તેને પ્રશ્નવાચક વિશેષણ કહે છે. પ્રશ્નવાચક વિશેષણમાં પ્રશ્નાર્થ ચિહ્ન હશે.સુચક શબ્દો: કોણ, કોણે, શું, કોના, કયાં, કેવી રીતે, શેનો, કયારે કેવી, કેટલું, કર્યું, વગેરે જેવા શબ્દો પ્રશ્નવાયક વિશેષણ સૂચવે છે.પ્રશ્નવાચક વિશેષણના ઉદાહરણ:કોણ આવ્યું હતું?રામાયણ કોણે લખ્યું છે?તમારે શું કામ છે?તમે કયું પુસ્તક ખરીધું?કસ્તૂરબા કોના પુત્રી હતા?ત્યાં કોણ મહેમાન આવ્યા છે?તમે ક્યાં જવાના છો?કેવી વાત કરો છો?ગાંધીજીનો જન્મ કયાં થયો હતો?"},{"question":"සිංගප්පූරුවේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"සිංගප්පූරුවේ අගනුවර සිංගප්පූරුව නම් වේ. සිංගපුරුව (ස්වදේශික නාමය සිංහපුර, නිල නාමය රිපබ්ලිකා සිංහපුරා) මලයා අර්ධද්වීපයේ දකුණු කෙලවරේ පිහිටි සමකයට කිලෝමීටර් 137ක් උතුරින් පිහිටි අග්නිදිග ආසියාතික රටකි.සිංගපුරුවට දුපත් 63 ඇත."},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la siguiente pregunta :¿Quién fue Michel Jordan?. ","answer":"La categoría corresponde a deportes. "},{"question":"ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਟ੍ਰਿਬਿਊਨ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਹਾਲੇ ਤੱਕ 64 ਤਸਕਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਾਇਦਾਦ ਜ਼ਬਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕੀ। ਖ਼ਬਰ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ  ਆਰਟੀਆਈ ਤੋਂ ਮਿਲੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਮੋਗਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੰਘੇ ਦਸ ਵਰ੍ਹਿਆਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ 66 ਪੁਲਿਸ ਕੇਸਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ 72 ਨਸ਼ਾ ਤਸਕਰਾਂ ਦੀ 16.09 ਕਰੋੜ ਦੀ ਜਾਇਦਾਦ ਜ਼ਬਤ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਕੇਸ 'ਸਮਰੱਥ ਅਥਾਰਿਟੀ' ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਕੋਲ ਭੇਜੇ ਗਏ ਸਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ 'ਚੋਂ 29 ਕੇਸ ਪੈਂਡਿੰਗ ਪਏ ਹਨ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਬਾਕੀ 43 ਕੇਸਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਰੀ ਝੰਡੀ ਮਿਲ ਗਈ ਹੈ।ਖ਼ਬਰ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ  ਬਠਿੰਡਾ ਜ਼ੋਨ ਦੇ ਆਈਜੀ ਐੱਮਐੱਫ ਫਾਰੂਕੀ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਤਸਕਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਾਇਦਾਦ ਜ਼ਬਤ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਲੰਮੀ ਚੌੜੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਪੜਾਵਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੇਸ ਲੰਘਦਾ ਹੈ।","answer":"ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਲੰਧਰ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਸ਼ੇ ਦੀ ਬਰਾਮਦਗੀ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੋਈ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਪੁਲਿਸ।"},{"question":"أكمل الجملة التالية: خلال حقبة إعادة الأعمار","answer":"وُضِعت قوانين جيم كرو قيد التنفيذ للحد من حركة الأمريكيين من أصل أفريقي ومشاركتهم في المجتمع الذي يهيمن عليه البيض. كان على الرجال السود خلال هذا الوقت إثبات هويتهم الخاصة، والذي قد يبدو مستحيلًا بسبب كل القيود المفروضة عليهم. كافح العديد من الرجال السود، مثل بول دي، للعثور على قيمتهم في مجتمعهم وتحقيق أهدافهم بسبب «التعجيزات» التي حصرتهم في جزء معين من التسلسل الهرمي الاجتماعي."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:ఆ. ఏల యెఱుక లేని యితరులయట్ల నీ ఉన్నవెఱుఁగ ననుచుఁబలికె దెఱిఁగి యెఱింగియేన కాని దీని నెఱుఁగ రిందొరు లనితప్పఁబలుక నగునె ధార్మికులకు.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :నీవు = నువ్వు (దుష్యంతుడు)ఎఱిఁగి + ఎటిఁగి = అన్ని విషయాలు బాగా తెలిసి కూడాఎఱుఁగను + అనుచున్ = తెలియదు అంటూఎఱుకలేని = ఏమి తెలియనిఇతరులు + అ + అట్లు + అ  = ఇతరులు ఎవరో మాట్లాడినట్లుపలికెదు = మాట్లాడుతున్నావుఇందున్ = ఇక్కడదీనిని = ఈ విషయాన్నిఏను + అ, కాని : నేను (శకుంతలను) మాత్రమే కానీఒరులు = ఇతరులుఎఱుఁగరు + అని = తెలియరనిధార్మికులకున్ = ధర్మాత్ములైన మీకుతప్పన్ + పలుకన్ +అగును + ఎ = అబద్ధం ఆడటం తగునా ? (తగదని భావం)తాత్పర్యం :ఓ రాజా ! నీవు అన్ని విషయాలు బాగా తెలిసి కూడా ఏమీ తెలియని ఇతరులు ఎవరో మాట్లాడినట్లు తెలియదు అని అంటున్నావు. ఇక్కడ. ఉన్నవారిలో ఈ విషయం నాకు తప్ప ఎవరికీ తెలియదని ధర్మాత్ములైన మీకు అబద్ధం ఆడటం భావ్యమా ! అని తాత్పర్యం."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Maskaxda Bili’aadanka Waa Imisa Qeybood?","answer":"Jawaab: Maskaxda Bili’aadanka Waxa Loo Qeybiyaa Seddex (3) Qeybood."},{"question":" समुदाय आधारित पोषण व्यवस्थापन लागू करणारे पहिले राज्य कोणते?","answer":"उत्तर :   समुदाय आधारित पोषण व्यवस्थापन लागू करणारे पहिले राज्य मध्य प्रदेश . "},{"question":"Siapakah ahli sunnah?","answer":"Penganut agama Islam yang kuat berpegang terhadap ajaran (hadis) Nabi Muhammad (s.a.w)"},{"question":"மராத்தியப் பேரரசுக்கும், ஆப்கானித்தானின் துராணிப் பேரரசுக்கும் இடையே கிபி 1761ல் பானிபட்டில் நடைபெற்ற","answer":"மூன்றாம் பானிபட் போரில் 40,000 ரோகில்லா படைகள், ஆப்கானிய துராணிப் படைகளுடன் இணைந்து மராத்தியப் படைகளுக்கு எதிராக போரிட்டனர். போரில் மராத்தியர்கள் தோல்வியடைந்ததால், இந்தியாவில் ரோகில்லா இன மக்களின் அரசியல் செல்வாக்கு கூடியது."},{"question":"Аз сегменттүүлөр деген эмне ?","answer":"Аз сегменттүүлөр — (лат. Oligomera ?) айбанаттын бир чоң тиби."},{"question":"تُعَدّ كل المشطيات تقريباً ضارية، فهي تقتات على فرائس متنوعة من اليرقات المجهرية إلى الحيوانات الدولابية، وحتى القشريات الصغيرة البالغة، أما الاستثناءات فهي نوعين ناشئين يعيشان كفطريات على السالبيات التي تقتات عليها الأنواع البالغة منها. يمكن للمشطيات في أفضل الظروف أن تأكل عشرة أضعاف وزنها في اليوم. وقدتم التعريف فقط 100-150 نوعا، هناك تقريبا 25 نوعا آخر لم يتم تعريفه وتسميته. ومن أمثلة مشطيات البحر الموجودة في الكتاب هناك ذوات الجسم البيضاوي وع زوج من المجسات القابلة للانكماش وهي تهدّبها المويجسات (\\"مجسّات صغيرة\\") تغطيها مولدات المادة الغروية، وهي خلايا تلتصق بالفريسة لتثبيتها. أما الشعبة فبها العديد من الأشكال البدنية مثل نوغ بليتيتسنيدا المسطّحة والكائنة في أعماق البحر، ويفتقر البالغون من هذا النوع إلى الثقوب، نوع البروادا التي ليس لها مجسات وتقتات على المشطيات الأخرى باستعمال فم كبير مزود بمجموعة من الأهداب المتصلبة التي تعمل عمل الأسنان. وتمكن هذا الاختلافات الأنواع المتعددة من التكاثر بشكل كبير وفي نفس المنطقة، فلكل من هذه الأنواع فرائس مختلفة والتي تختلف طريقة صيدها كاختلاف طريقة صيد العناكب لفرائسها.أقرأ ما سابق ثم أجب كم يمكن لمشطي ستينوفورا أن يأكل في اليوم؟","answer":"يمكن لمشطي أكل ما يوازي عشرة أضعاف وزنها."},{"question":"கேள்வி: வளிமண்டல அழுத்தத்தை அளந்தறியப் பயன்படுவது எது?கீழ் காணப்படும் நான்கு பதிலில் இருந்து சரியான பதிலை தேர்ந்து எடுக்கவும்:அ)  திருகு அளவிஆ) பாதரசக் குழாய்இ) டாரிசெல்லி பாரமாணிஈ) போர்டான் அளவி","answer":"சரியான பதில்: இ) டாரிசெல்லி பாரமாணிவளிமண்டல அழுத்தம் என்பது புவியின் வளிமண்டலத்தால் அதன் மேற்பரப்பில் ஒர் அலகில் உணரப்படும் அழுத்தமாகும். வளிமம் கண்களுக்கு புலப்படவில்லையென்றாலும் அவைகளும் குறிப்பிட்ட அளவு நிறையினை கொண்டுள்ளன. புவியீர்ப்பு விசையின் காரணமாக பெருமளவிலான வாயு மூலக்கூறுகள் புவியின் மேற்பரப்பில் தக்க வைக்கப் படுகின்றன. எனவே புவியின் மேற்பரப்பிற்கு மேலே செல்லச் செல்ல, வாயு மூலக்கூறுகளின் அடர்த்தி குறைவதினால் வளிமண்டல அழுத்தமும் உயரத்திற்கு ஏற்றாற் போல் குறைகின்றது. புவியீர்ப்பு விசையே பெருமளவு தாக்கத்தினை எற்படுத்தினாலும் புவி மேற்பரப்பின் வெப்பநிலையும் வளிமண்டல அழுத்தினை நிர்ணயிக்கும் காரணிகளில் ஒன்றாகின்றது. பெரும்பாலான தருணங்களில் வளிமண்டல அழுத்தம் நீர்ம நிலையழுத்திற்கு ஒத்துப் போகின்றது."},{"question":"السؤال: كم لبث الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم في مكة يدعو الناس قبل الهجرة؟","answer":"الإجابة: 13 عامًا"},{"question":"மலைப்பகுதியில் அரியதாகக் கிடைக்கும் நெல்லிக்கனி. அது நீண்ட ஆயுள் தரும். \\"அதியனே நீவிர் உண்ணாது. எம் சாதல் ஒழிய கொடுத்த பெருமகனே\\" என்று ஔவையார் வாழ்த்துகிறார் . இதனைப் புறப்பொருள் வெண்பா மாலை கூறும் இலக்கணம் வழி விளக்குக.","answer":"புறப்பொருள் வெண்பாமாலை கூறும் இலக்கணம் :பாடுவதற்குத் தகுதி உடைய ஓர் ஆளுமையாளரின் கல்வி, வீரம், செல்வம், புகழ், கருணை முதலியவற்றைப் போற்றிப்பாடுவது பாடாண் திணையாகும்.விளக்கம் :அதியமானின் புகழை ஒளவையார் பாடுவதால், இஃது பாடாண் திணையாகும்."},{"question":"Беш таш, топ таш оюндары тууралуу маалымат бер. ","answer":"Беш таш, топташ – жаш балдардын, көбүнчө кыздардын чакмакка окшогон оюну. Аны ойногонго 2ден көбүрөөк балдар катышат. Оюнга катышкандардын 1-тарабынан бирөө колундагы таштарды жерге чачат. Арасынан бир ташты алып аны жогору ыргытып, ал жогорудан келгенче жерден бир таш алып ыргытылган ташын тосуп алат. Жыдыбай жердеги төртөөнү бирден алып, оюнун улантып, экиден, үчтөн, акыры төртөөнү чогу бир жолу алып утат. Эгерде макулдашуу узак ойноо болсо, беш ташты көкөлөтө акырын ыргытып, анын бирөөсүн колунун сыртына тосуп, анан аны кайра жогору ыргытып, ташты ыргыткан колунун алаканы менен тосуп алат. Жерге түшкөн таштарды сол колунун бармак, сөөмөйүн жерге такап, экөөнү алдынан өткөрө бирден шилтейт. Жыдыбай баарын өткөрсө, оюнун улап экиден, үчтөн, акыры төртөөнү бир шилеп өткөрөт. Жыдыса, оюнду атаандашынын кезектегисине берет"},{"question":"Inona ary izany ? Dobokelin'Andriamanitra tsy azo ilomanosana?","answer":"Maso no dobokelin'Andriamanitra tsy azo ilomanosana"},{"question":"Revolution Now fẹhonu han layaajọ ọjọ Ominira l’Oṣogbo","answer":"Titi di asiko ta a fi pari iroyin yii lawọn ẹgbẹ ajafẹtọọ-ọmọniyan ti wọn n jẹ Revolution Now n fẹhonu han wọọrọwọ kaakiri isọri-isọri ilu Oṣogbo.Pẹlu orin ati patako lọwọ wọn ni wọn n sọ pe omi ominira ti n di omi inira mọ awọn ọmọ orileede yii lọwọ, wọn ni pupọ ninu wahala ti orileede yii n dojukọ, lati ọwọ awọn adari wa lo ti wa.Ninu ọrọ ẹni to dari wọn, Lijofi Victor, o ṣalaye pe ko si nnkan kan to le mu ori eeyan wu rara pẹlu ayajọ ọdun kọkanlelogọta ti orileede Naijiria n ṣe, nitori gbogbo nnkan lo ti dorikodo.O sọ siwaju pe lori eto ọrọ-aje, o nira fun ọpọ eeyan lati jẹun ẹẹmẹta lasiko yii, nigba ti ọpọ ti wọn nile lori tẹlẹ ti di alainile mọ latari ọwọngogo nnkan lọja.Ni ti eto aabo, Lijofi ṣalaye pe dipo kijọba gbaju mọ bi wọn yoo ṣe kapa awọn aṣekupani ti wọn n gbẹmi awọn alaiṣẹ kaakiri, awọn olufẹhonu han lalaafia ni wọn n dẹ pampẹ mu kaakiri.O ni awọn ikọ alaabo gbogbo ti Naijiria ni mọ awọn ti wọn wa nidii iṣekupani ati igbesunmọ mi to n ṣẹlẹ kaakiri, ṣugbọn ṣe ni wọn n fi ẹtẹ silẹ lati pa lapalapa.O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe ohun to bojumu fun awọn adari lasiko yii ni ki wọn kọwe fipo silẹ ti wọn ba mọ pe gbogbo nnkan ko ye awọn mọ, ti wọn ba si mọ pe ko si ohun ti awọn le ṣe lati yanju gbogbo wahala to wa nilẹ yii."},{"question":"வினா:தமிழில் கலைக்களஞ்சியம் அடிப்படையில் அமைந்த நூல் எது? ","answer":"விடை: அபிதான கோசம்.அபிதானகோசம் என்பது தமிழிலே முதன் முதலாகத் தோன்றிய இலக்கியக் கலைக்களஞ்சியமாகும். வடமொழி, தென்மொழி ஆகிய இரு மொழிகளிலும் இயற்றப்பெற்ற வேதங்கள், புராணங்கள், இதிகாசங்கள், தருமநூல்கள், இலக்கியங்களிற் காணப்பெற்ற தெய்வம், தேவர், இருடி, முனிவர், அசுரர், அரசர், புலவர், புரவலர் முதலிய விபரங்களை அகர வரிசையிலே தொகுத்தளிக்கும் முயற்சி அபிதானகோசம் ஆகும்."},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਵੱਧ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ: ਕਰਮਾ (ਛੋਟੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ)","answer":"\\"ਕਰਮਾ\\" (ਅੰਗ੍ਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਮ: Karma) ਭਾਰਤੀ ਲੇਖਕ ਖੁਸ਼ਵੰਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਲਿਖੀ ਇੱਕ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਅਸਲ ਵਿੱਚ 1989 ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀਆਂ ਇਕਜੁਟ ਕਹਾਣੀਆ ਦੀ ਕਿਤਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ਿਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ਇਹ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ \\"ਜੈਂਟਲਮੈਨ\\" ਬਾਰੇ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਉੱਚੇ ਦਰਜੇ ਦੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਢੰਗ ਨੂੰ ਅਪਣਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ \\"ਰਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ\\" ਬੋਲਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਸਦੇ ਸਬੰਧ ਬਾਰੇ ਹੈ।== ਥੀਮ ==ਕਰਮ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਕਹਾਵਤ \\"Pride Comes Before a Fall\\" ਦੀ ਵਿਆਖਿਆ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਘਮੰਡ ਪਤਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਇੱਕ ਘੁਮੰਡੀ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਦੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਆਪਣੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੀ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ, ਜੀਵਨਸ਼ੈਲੀ ਆਦਿ ਬਾਰੇ ਬੁਰਾ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਨੂੰ ਨੀਵਾਂ ਦਿਖਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਆਮ ਔਰਤ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਆਪਣੀ ਅਮੀਰ ਅੰਗਰੇਜੀ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਪਾਉਂਦੀ। ਕਈ ਹੋਰ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਹਨ: ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ੀ ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ, ਵਿਆਹ ਤੋਂ ਨਾਖੁਸ਼, ਸੱਭਿਆਚਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਜੀਵਨਸ਼ੈਲੀ ਦੇ ਉਲਟ, ਅਮੀਰਸ਼ਾਹੀ ਅਤੇ ਦੇਸ਼ਭਗਤੀ।== ਪਲਾਟ ==ਮੋਹਨ ਲਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਮੱਧ-ਉਮਰ ਵਾਲਾ ਆਦਮੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਰਾਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹੋਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਰਮ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਲਈ ਉਹ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਾਂ ਐਂਗਲੀਸਾਈਜ਼ਿਡ ਹਿੰਦੁਸਤਾਨੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੋਲਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉੱਚ ਪੱਧਰੀ ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਅਫ਼ਸਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਪਹਿਨਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਅੰਗ੍ਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਾਲ ਗਿਆਨ ਨੂੰ ਦਿਖਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕ੍ਰਾਸਵਰਡ ਪਜ਼ਲਜ਼ ਭਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਲੱਛਮੀ ਇੱਕ ਰਵਾਇਤੀ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਔਰਤ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਅੰਤਰ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਿੱਠੀ ਵਿਵਾਹਕ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਗੁਜਰਦੀ ਹੈ।ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਘਟਨਾ ਇੱਕ ਰੇਲ ਗੱਡੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੋਹਨ ਲਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਲਛਮੀ ਦੀ ਯਾਤਰਾ ਤੇ ਵਾਪਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਲਛਮੀ ਆਮ ਡੱਬੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਿਠਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੀਟ ਨੂੰ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀ ਦੇ ਡੱਬੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਬਰਤਾਨਵੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਲਈ ਸੀ। ਉਥੇ ਉਹ ਦੋ ਬਰਤਾਨਵੀ ਫੌਜੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਦੁਰਵਿਵਹਾਰ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਜਦੋਂ ਹੰਕਾਰੀ ਮੋਹਨ ਲਾਲ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਰੋਧ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਰੇਲ ਗੱਡੀ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਸੁੱਟ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਚੱਲ ਰਹੀ ਰੇਲ ਗੱਡੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਰੇਲਜ਼ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਦੇਖ ਸਕਦਾ ਸੀ।== ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ==ਸਰ ਮੋਹਨ ਲਾਲ - ਇੱਕ ਹੰਕਾਰੀ ਮੱਧ-ਉਮਰ ਵਾਲਾ ਆਦਮੀ।ਲੇਡੀ ਲਾਲ - ਇੱਕ ਆਮ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਔਰਤ ਜੋ ਮੋਹਨ ਲਾਲ ਦੀ ਪਤਨੀ ਬਣਦੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਬੇਟਲ ਪੱਤੀਆਂ ਚਬਾਉਣੀ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ।ਇੱਕ ਅਹੁਦੇਦਾਰਇੱਕ ਪੌਰਟਰਦੋ ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਸੈਨਿਕ (ਬਿਲ ਅਤੇ ਜਿਮ)।== ਹਵਾਲੇ ==ਸਿੰਘ, ਖੁਸ਼ਵੰਤ.\\"ਕਰਮਾ\\". ਖੁਸ਼ਵੰਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀ ਸੰਗ੍ਰਹਿਤ ਛੋਟੀਆਂ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ (2005 ਐਡੀ.) ਓਰੀਐਂਟ ਬਲੈਕਸਵਾਨ / ਗੂਗਲ ਕਿਤਾਬਾਂ ਸਫ਼ੇ 8-12 ISBN 8175300442. 15 ਜਨਵਰੀ, 2014 ਨੂੰ ਪਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤਾ.ਸਰ ਮੋਹਨ ਲਾਲ ਦੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ: ਖੁਸ਼ਵੰਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀ \\"ਕਰਮਾ\\"- ਕੇ. ਨਰਾਇਣ ਚੰਦਨ [1]"},{"question":"Cryptocurrency","answer":"cryptocurrency kan, crypto-owo, tabi crypto jẹ owo oni-nọmba ti a ṣe apẹrẹ lati ṣiṣẹ bi alabọde ti paṣipaarọ nipasẹ nẹtiwọọki kọmputa kan ti ko gbẹkẹle eyikeyi aṣẹ aringbungbun, gẹgẹbi ijọba tabi banki, lati ṣe atilẹyin tabi ṣetọju rẹ. Ó jẹ́ ètò ìṣàkóso fún ìjẹ́rìísí pé àwọn ẹgbẹ́ sí ìdúnàádúrà ní owó tí wọ́n sọ pé wọ́n ní, yíyọ ìdí fún àwọn alárinà ìbílẹ̀ kúrò, gẹ́gẹ́ bíi àwọn ilé ìfowópamọ́, nígbà tí wọ́n bá ń gbé owó láàárín àwọn ilé-iṣẹ́ méjì.Olukuluku owo nini igbasilẹ ti wa ni fipamọ ni a oni iwe, eyi ti o jẹ a computerized database lilo lagbara cryptography lati ni aabo idunadura igbasilẹ, šakoso awọn ẹda ti afikun eyo, ki o si jẹrisi awọn gbigbe ti owo ìní. Pelu orukọ wọn, awọn owo-iworo ko ṣe akiyesi lati jẹ awọn owo ni itumọ ibile, ati lakoko ti awọn itọju oriṣiriṣi ti lo si wọn, pẹlu classification bi awọn ọja, awọn sikioriti, ati awọn owo nina, awọn owo-iworo ni a wo ni gbogbogbo bi kilasi dukia ti o yatọ ni iṣe.Diẹ ninu awọn crypto ètò lo validators lati bojuto awọn cryptocurrency. Nínú àwòṣe ẹ̀rí ìpín, àwọn onílé gbé àmì wọn sókè gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹ̀bùn. Ní ìdápadà, wọ́n gba àṣẹ lórí àmì náà ní ìbámu pẹ̀lú iye tí wọ́n fi sí. Ní gbogbogbò, àwọn olùkópa àmì wọ̀nyí máa ń gba àfikún ìní nínú àmì náà pẹ̀lú àkókò nípasẹ̀ owó nẹ́tíwọ́ọ̀kì, àwọn àmì tí wọ́n ṣẹ̀ṣẹ̀ ṣe, tàbí irú àwọn ìlànà èrè bẹ́ẹ̀.Cryptocurrency ko si ni fọọmu ti ara (bii owo iwe) ati pe kii ṣe ipinfunni nipasẹ aṣẹ aringbungbun. Cryptocurrencies ojo melo lo decentralized Iṣakoso bi o lodi si a aringbungbun ifowo oni owo (CBDC).Nigbati a cryptocurrency ti wa ni minted, tabi da ṣaaju ki o to ipinfunni, tabi oniṣowo nipasẹ kan nikan issuer, o ti wa ni gbogbo kà centralized. Nigba ti muse pẹlu decentralized Iṣakoso, kọọkan cryptocurrency ṣiṣẹ nipasẹ pin ledger ọna ẹrọ, ojo melo a blockchain, ti o sin bi a àkọsílẹ owo idunadura database.Awọn akọkọ cryptocurrency wà Bitcoin, eyi ti a akọkọ tu bi ìmọ-orisun software ni 2009. Bi ti June 2023, nibẹ wà diẹ ẹ sii ju 25,000 miiran cryptocurrencies ni oja, ti eyi ti diẹ ẹ sii ju 40 ní a oja capitalization kọja  1 bilionu."},{"question":"ক্লাউন মাছের সাথে সামুদ্রিক অ্যানিমোনের একটি সিম্বিওটিক সম্পর্ক আছে কিভাবে?","answer":"সামুদ্রিক অ্যানিমোনগুলি ক্লাউন মাছকে সমুদ্রের অ্যানিমোনের সুরক্ষায় বাঁচতে দেয়। বিনিময়ে ক্লাউন মাছ সমুদ্রের অ্যানিমোনে প্রয়োজনীয় পুষ্টি সরবরাহ করে"},{"question":"ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਸਹਿਯੋਗੀ ਸਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੀ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਦੇ ਕਾਲਕਾ ਚੌਂਕ 'ਤੇ ਵੀਰਵਾਰ ਦੁਪਹਿਰੇ ਦੋ ਗੁੱਟਾਂ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਝੜਪਾਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ। ਇਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਚੱਲੀਆਂ ਗੋਲੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਕਾਰ ਸਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਦੋ ਹੋਰ ਜਖ਼ਮੀ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਪਹੁੰਚਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਪੁਲਿਸ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਦਰਜਨਾਂ ਰਾਊਂਡ ਫਾਇਰ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਹੈ।ਘਟਨਾ ਵਾਲੀ ਥਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਪਹੁੰਚੇ ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਦੇ ਆਈਜੀ ਪੂਰਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ, \\"ਪੁਲਿਸ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕਾਰਵਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਕਰੀਬ 20 ਰਾਊਂਡ ਫਾਇਰ ਕੀਤੇ ਗਏ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਦੋ ਲੋਕ ਜਖ਼ਮੀ ਹਨ।\\"ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਦੇ ਡੀਐੱਸਪੀ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ, \\"ਹੁਣ ਤੱਕ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਗਰੁੱਪਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਸਾਡੀਆਂ ਟੀਮਾਂ ਜਾਂਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਹਨ।\\" ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਦੇ ਐੱਸਐੱਸਪੀ ਹਾਮਿਦ ਅਖ਼ਤਰ ਨੇ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ, \\"ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੈਂਗਵਾਰ ਲੱਗ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ, ਹਮਲਾਵਰ ਕਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਏ ਅਤੇ ਚਾਰ ਲੋਕਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੇਆਮ ਗੋਲੀਆਂ ਚਲਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ।\\"","answer":"ਅੰਬਾਲਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਿਨ-ਦਿਹਾੜੇ ਚੱਲੀਆਂ ਗੋਲੀਆਂ, ਦੋ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ।"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Quỹ Gates Foundations do Bill Gates làm chủ tịch, tập trung vào các hoạt động gồm phát triển nông nghiệp, dịch vụ tài chính cho người nghèo, nước sạch và vệ sinh môi trường, giáo dục toàn cầu, sức khỏe và dinh dưỡng. ","answer":" Quỹ còn thực hiện các hoạt động trong mảng y tế công cộng và sức khỏe toàn dân, tập trung các bệnh truyền nhiễm, phổ biến và các bệnh khu vực nhiệt đới.Ngoài quỹ này, Bill Gates đã thành lập công ty Energy Breakthrough Venture (EBV) và Gates Ventures nhằm thúc đẩy đổi mới về năng lượng bền vững, giảm phát thải khí nhà kính. EBV đầu tư vào nhiều công ty khởi nghiệp đang cố gắng thương mại hóa các công nghệ mới. Còn Gates Ventures, một tổ chức tư vấn về các vấn đề sức khỏe và phát triển toàn cầu cũng như danh mục đầu tư công nghệ."},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity.Fanambarana: \\"Tsy handeha irery amin'ny lalana maizina intsony aho.\\"","answer":"Io fanambarana io dia maneho tahotra. Tsy sahy mandeha irery intsony satria ny maizina tsy mba namana."},{"question":"O ṣẹlẹ: Awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ mu Magu, ọga EFCC","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ilẹ yii (DSS) ti mu ọga ajọ to n gbogun ti ṣiṣe owo ilu baṣubaṣu (EFCC),  Ibrahim Magu.ALAROYE gbọ pe wọn mu Magu lori dukia mẹrin to ni lọna aitọ, ati pe o n ko owo pamọ soke-okun.Olu-ileeṣẹ ọtẹlẹmuyẹ to wa ni Aso Drive niluu Abuja la gbọ pe wọn gbe e lọ, iyẹn lẹyin to ti kọkọ wa ni ọfiisi ileeṣẹ naa ni Wuse II, niluu kan naa.Gẹgẹ bi iroyin to n lọ, iṣẹlẹ naa ko ṣẹyin iwadii awọn DSS lọdun 2016, eyi to sọ pe Magu n gbe ile nla kan towo ẹ to miliọnu lọna ogoji naira ti Ọgagun-fẹyinyi Umar Mohammed to jẹ adari nileeṣẹ ọmọ-ogun ori omi tẹlẹ ra fun un.Bakan naa la gbọ pe ẹka to n ṣakoso ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, Police Service Commission, sọ pe o jẹbi ẹsun aṣemaṣe kan an lọdun 2010.Ajọ DSS ko ti i sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, bẹẹ ni gbogbo awọn to ti gbọ nipa ọrọ naa n reti abajade rẹ.Ọjọ kẹsan-an, oṣu kọkanla, ọdun 2015, ni Magu di adele ọga-agba EFCC, ipo adele lo si wa di akoko yii."},{"question":"Hiện tượng cát hát chỉ diễn ra trên sa mạc?","answer":"Cát hát, còn gọi là cát reo, cát huýt sáo hoặc cát nhạc, là những vùng cát ở sa mạc hoặc bờ biển có thể tạo ra âm thanh một cách tự nhiên trong gió do sự kết hợp giữa các đặc điểm vật lý như kích thước và thành phần cấu tạo của hạt cát."},{"question":"இந்த உரை என்ன முக்கியமான நிகழ்வு:முதல் முயற்சியில் இத்தாலியின் படுதோல்வியால் லிபியாவின் கிழக்குப் பகுதியாகிய சிரெனைக்காவின் பெரும்பகுதி பிரிட்டானிய கட்டுப்பாட்டில் வந்தது. முசோலினிக்கு உதவ இட்லர் ஜெர்மானியப் படைப்பிரிவுகளை அனுப்பினார். அவை பெப்ரவரி 11, 1941ம் தேதி லிபியாவை அடைந்தன. இந்த படை நகர்த்தல் நிகழ்வுக்கு சோனென்புளூம் நடவடிக்கை என்று குறிப்பெயர் இடப்பட்டிருந்தது. இந்நடவடிக்கை மேலும் சில மாதங்கள் நீடித்து கூடுதல் படைப்பிரிவுகள் லிபியாவுக்கு அனுப்பபட்டன. ஆப்பிரிக்கா கோர் என்று பெயரிடப்பட்ட இப்படைப்பிரிவுக்குத் தலைமைதாங்க புகழ்பெற்ற ஜெர்மானியத் தரைப்படைத் தளபதி ரோம்மல் வடக்கு ஆப்பிரிக்காவுக்கு அனுப்பப்பட்டார்.","answer":"இந்த உரை சோனென்புளூம் நடவடிக்கை பற்றியது ."},{"question":"jawiga kawaran walaal","answer":"aad ayuu u fiicanyahay"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: ముద్ర","answer":"గుర్తు, ప్రభావము "},{"question":"هل أبو عريش هي عاصمة السعودية؟","answer":"لا، عاصمة المملكة العربية السعودية هي الرياض. بينما محافظة أبو عريش هي محافظة سعودية تتبع لإمارة منطقة جازان، جنوب غرب المملكة العربية السعودية، وحاضرتها مدينة أبو عريش، ويتبع المحافظة عدد من المراكز والقرى. تقدر مساحة المحافظة بحوالي 900 كم2. بلغ عدد سكان محافظة محافظة أبو عريش (187,060) نسمة حسب تعداد السعودية 2022، عدد السعوديين (139,518) نسمة، وعدد غير السعوديين (47,542) نسمة."},{"question":"Wat is Stoicisme?","answer":"Stoicisme is een school van Hellenistische filosofie opgericht door Zeno van Citium in Athene in het begin van de 3de eeuw voor Christus. Het is een filosofie van persoonlijke deugdethiek die wordt geïnformeerd door haar systeem van logica en haar opvattingen over de natuurlijke wereld, waarbij wordt gesteld dat de praktijk van deugd zowel noodzakelijk als voldoende is om eudaimonia (geluk, letterlijk 'goedhartigheid') te bereiken: men bloeit door een ethisch leven te leiden. De Stoïcijnen identificeerden de weg naar eudaimonia met een leven dat besteed wordt aan het beoefenen van deugd en het leven in overeenstemming met de natuur. Naast de ethiek van Aristoteles vormt de Stoïcijnse traditie een van de belangrijkste grondleggende benaderingen van deugdethiek. De Stoïcijnen staan vooral bekend om het onderwijzen dat \\"deugd de enige goedheid\\" is voor de mens, en dat externe zaken, zoals gezondheid, rijkdom en plezier, op zichzelf niet goed of slecht zijn (adiaphora), maar waarde hebben als \\"materiaal voor deugd om op te treden\\". Veel Stoïcijnen - zoals Seneca en Epictetus - benadrukten dat omdat \\"deugd voldoende is voor geluk\\", een wijze emotioneel veerkrachtig zou"},{"question":"Kí ni ipò tí Hamza al-Mustapha dìmú nínú ìjọba ológun ti Sani Abacha?","answer":"Olórí àwọn Ẹ̀ṣọ́ aláàbò"},{"question":"Ọdún wo la dá ìpínlẹ̀ Èkìtì?","answer":"Ọdún 1996."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo seha-pikarohana efatra azon’ny mpiofana isafidianana ao amin’ny Sampana Teny Malagasy?","answer":"Ao amin’ny Sampana Teny Malagasy, dia misy seha-pikarohanaefatra azon’ny mpiofana isafidianana: ny fitsipiky ny teny, ny riba, nyhaifampianarana, ary ny literatiora. Mifameno ny fahalalana azo avyamin’ireo"},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 東京電力の福島第一原子力発電所では、2011年の事故のあと、放射線を出す物質が入った水が増え続けています。東京電力が放射線を出す物質を取る処理をしていますが、トリチウムなどが残ります。処理をしたあとの水は増え続けて、134万tになりました。約1000個のタンクの98%まで水が入っています。政府は、処理をした水に海の水を入れて、トリチウムの濃度を薄くして海に流すことを決めました。東京電力が海の水で薄めて、1Lの濃度が43から63ベクレルになりました。国の基準の6万ベクレルよりとても低くなりました。このため、東京電力は24日午後1時ごろから海に流し始めました。処理をした水を全部流し終わるまで30年ぐらいかかると言われています。長い間、安全に気をつける必要があります。","answer":"福島第一原発　24日から処理した水を海に流し始めた"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الأسماء الخمسة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: أبو، أخو، حمو، ذو، فو"},{"question":"Astaamaha qofka hanka sare leh   Astaanta 7aad: - Taymuur linki. ","answer":"Taymuur linki. Taymuur linki wuxuu ahaa hogaamiye ka tirsan ciidamadii maquuliyiinta ee ku soo duulay wadamada islaamka, Taymuur waxaa lagu jabiyay dagaal dagaalada ka mid ah, isagoo ay iskugu darsantahay dhaawac, gaajo, jab iyo leeleel kasoo gaaray dagaalkii, ciidankiisii oo kala yaacay oo kala firxaday, ayuu niyadjab wuxuu lagalay meel god ah, markaas ayuu arkay quraanjo larafanaysa inay qaadato hal xabbo galay ah, wuxuu u fiirsaday inta jeer ay galaydaas ka dhacday quraanjaduna ay isku dayday  wuxuu arkay inaysan  quraanjadu daalayn , noogayn, quusanayn, waxay larafataba ugu danbaynii quraanjadii xabbadii  galayda ahayd  wey la kortay oo waa ay qaadatay, tarmuur intuu naftiisa la hadlay ayuu ku yiri :- ma quraanjadan ayaa kaa xoog badan, kaa dulqaad badan, quraanjaduba ma quusane maxaan u quusanayaa isla markiiba intuu fadhiga ka kacay ayuu gudagalay siduu u ururinlahaa ciidamadiisii oo uu dagaalka ugu rogaal celinlahaa, dadaal dheer kadib taymuur dagaalkii ayuu ku noqday waana ku guulaystay.  Imaamu Kisaa'ii. Imaamu Kisaa'ii, wuxuu imaam ku ahaa naxwaha iyo akhrinta qur'aanka ( qiraa'aatka), waxaa la yiraahdaa naxwaha ayaa aad ugu adkaaday,  markuu isku arkay inuusan baran karin naxwaha ayuu ka tagay meeshu ka baran jiray isagoo iska dhaadhiciyay naxwe ma baran kartid, mar'uu dhexda siimaraayo ayuu wuxuu arkay quraanjo la rafanaysa inay xabad masango ah, quraanjadii ayuu u fiirsaday markaas ayuu arkay inaysan quusanayn oo aysan noogayn waxay la rafataba xabadeedii waa qaadatay derbigana waa la kortay, markaas ayuu naftiisa ku yiri ma quraanjaa kaliidataa, waa in aan ku  rogaal celiyaa barashadii naxwaha, maliintii uu go'aankaas qaatay intii ka danbaysay imaam looga danbeeyo naxwaha ayuu noqday. Faaiido : - waxaana jirta xikmad tiraahda saddex Quraan  jada kaga dayda (1) joogtaynta shaqada (2) ku celcelinta isku dayga(3) sixida khaladka. Faa'iidadaan waxaa ii faa'iidayeeyay saaxiibkayga qaaliga ah CUMAR NUUR CALI. Sheekha la yiraahdo imaamu Sarkhasi ayaa jeelka la dhigay oo la xiray intuu xabsiga ku jirey ayuu wuxuu ku qoray kitaabkiisa layiraahdo ( Almabsuud) oo ka kooban 30 mujalad, sidoo kale imaamka la yiraahdo Ibnu  asiir markuu jeex qalalku ku dhacay wuxuu alifay oo qoray intuu xanuunsanaa kitabakiisa la yiraahdo ( Jaamic al-usuul wannihaayah ) oo ka kooban 30 mujalad, imaamu Ibnu Taymiyah markii la xiray xabsiga dhexdiisa ayuu wuxuu ku qoray kitaabkiisa la yiraahdo ( Alfataawaa ) oo ka kooban 30 mujalad. Soo ilama aragtaan iimaamyadaas inay ka dhigeen dhibtii ku dhacday shay ay ka faa'iidaystaan oo uusan ku dhallin niyad jab hankoodiina hoos u dhigin ?"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'musuh dalam selimut'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud musuh yang tiada diketahui, yang sangat dekat atau yang ada dalam lingkungan sendiri."},{"question":"Tasarımda görsel devamlılık nedir?","answer":"Görsel tasarım ilkelerinden olan görsel devamlılık, yüzey tasarımını oluşturan unsurların bir bütün olarak algılanmasında önem arz eder. “Göz bir unsurdan diğerine doğru kesintisiz geçişler yapabiliyorsa, devamlılık sağlanmış demektir” (Becer, 2002, s.70)."},{"question":"كم يبلغ عدد أسنان الإنسان البالغ؟","answer":"عددهم 32 سنة."},{"question":"\\"Мезгил учат\\" Аалы Токомбаевдин повестинен мазмуну жөнүндө үзүндү?","answer":"\\"Мезгил учат, мезгил канаттуу жылкыдай учуп баратат, ал зыпылдап жандай бергенче, жүгөндөп пайдалануу керек» деген пикир Жапардын башынан жылт этип өтө берди\\". Демек, повесть мезгил тууралуу, ошол мезгилдеги адамдардын тагдыры тууралуу болуу менен бизди мезгилди туура пайдаланып, аны пайдалуу ишке жумшоо керектигин үйрөтөт."},{"question":"Tính (– 909) + 909.A. 1818     B. 1     C. 0     D. – 1818","answer":"Lời giảiTa có: (– 909) + 909 = 909 – 909 = 0Chọn đáp án C."},{"question":"magaalo cagaaran dhismeheeduna casaanyahay dadkeeduna madow yihiin?","answer":" Qaraha."},{"question":"Kedu ụzọ ọzọ m nwere ike isi kwu \\"naanị\\"?","answer":"Ọ bụrụ na ị chọghị ikwu \\"naanị\\", ị nwere ike iwere olundi nọchi anya ya. Ọmụmatụ bụ ịsị \\"sọọsọ\\" maọbụ \\"sọ\\"."},{"question":"Gomina Sanwoolu ṣabẹwo si Aṣiwaju Tinubu ni London","answer":"O ti to ọjọ mẹta tawọn kan ti n gbe iroyin naa kiri pe Aṣiwaju ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC, Bọla Hammed Tinubu ti ku.Gbogbo akitiyan agbẹnusọ rẹ lori eto iroyin, Ọgbẹni Tunde Rahman lati pana ọrọ yii lo ja si pabo pẹlu bi awọn kan tun ṣe n sọ pe irọ ni.Nibi ti ina ọrọ naa ran de, obinrin kan to maa n sọrọ lori ẹrọ ayelujara jade si gbangba, o si ni oun ni ẹri lọwọ pe Tinubu ti ku.Eyi ni awọn eeyan n gbe kiri ori ẹrọ ayelujara ti akọwe iroyin Tinubu fi tun jade lọsẹ to kọja pe baba naa ko ku, bẹẹ ni ko wa nidubulẹ aisan gẹgẹ bi awọn kan ṣe n gbe e kiri.O ni o ti di gbogbo igba ti ọkunrin oloṣelu yii ba ti rin irinajo lọ si ilu oyinbo kawọn eeyan maa gbe ahesọ yii kiri pe o ti ku. O waa beere lọwọ wọn pe awọn wo gan-an ni ẹru Tinubu n ba ti wọn fi n gbe iru ahesọ yii kiri.Ṣugbọn gbogbo okoto irọ naa ti ja bayii, ẹri si ti fi han pe irọ lawọn to sọ pe Aṣiwaju ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC naa ti ku n pa pẹlu bi Gomina ipinlẹ Eko, Babajide Sanwoolu, ṣe sabẹwo si ọkunrin naa niluu London. Tinubu wa lori ijokoo, gomina naa wa nibẹ tawọn mejeeji si jọ n sọrọ. Bẹẹ ni wọn ya fọto papọ lati fi han pe nnkan kan ko ṣe gomina ipinlẹ Eko tẹlẹ naa.Ṣugbọn ẹnikan to ba akọroyin wa sọrọ lori ahesọ naa sọ pe loootọ ni ara gomina tẹlẹ nipinlẹ Eko yii ko ya, ṣugbọn ko pọ to bi wọn ṣe n gbe e kiri, bẹẹ ni ki i ṣe pe o ti ku pẹlu bi fọto rẹ ṣe wa kaakiri ori ayelujara pẹlu gomina Eko bayii."},{"question":"Que língua é falada no país Equador?","answer":"espanhol"},{"question":"A quale categoria appartiene la seguente domanda: Quanti Presidenti degli Stati Uniti What category is this question from: Qual è il numero totale dei presidenti degli Stati Uniti?","answer":"La categoria di appartenenza di questa domanda è: storia"},{"question":"ਪੁਸ਼ਟੀ ਲਈ ਕਾਰਣ ਦਿਓ :-(ਉ) ਪਾਣੀ ਕਮਰੇ ਦੇ ਤਾਪਮਾਣ ‘ ਤੇ ਦੂਵ ਹੈ ।(ਅ) ਲੋਹੇ ਦੀ ਅਲਮਾਰੀ ਕਮਰੇ ਦੇ ਤਾਪਮਾਨ ‘ਤੇ ਠੋਸ ਹੈ ?","answer":"(ੳ)    ਪਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ ਜਿਸ ਵੀ ਬਰਤਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਵੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਆਕਾਰ ਲੈ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਕਮਰੇ ਦਾ ਤਾਪਮਾਨ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਉਬਾਲ ਦਰਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਜਮਾਵ ਦਰਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਹੈ ।    ਪਾਣੀ ਵੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਹ ਮਜ਼ਬੂਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।(ਅ)    ਲੋਹੇ ਦੀ ਅਲਮਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਨਿਸਚਿਤ, ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਸੀਮਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਸਥਿਰ ਆਇਤਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।    ਨਾਂ ਮਾਤਰ ਦਬੀਣਯੋਗਤਾ ਹੈ । ਕਮਰੇ ਦਾ ਤਾਪਮਾਨ ਲੋਹੇ ਦੇ ਉਬਾਲ ਦਰਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਪਿਘਲਣ ਦਰਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਹੈ | ਕਮਰੇ ਦੇ ਤਾਪਮਾਨ ਤੇ ਉਸਦੀ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਪਰਿਵਰਤਨ ਸੰਭਵ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਇਸ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਉਸ ਤਾਪਮਾਨ ਤੇ ਠੋਸ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ 秋田県男鹿市にある「男鹿水族館GAO」という水族館には、ペンギンが70羽ぐらいいます。頭に大きな羽の飾りがある「キタイワトビペンギン」と、くちばしと足が黄色い「ジェンツーペンギン」です。この中で、4月中旬から1か月ぐらいの間に、キタイワトビペンギンの赤ちゃんが7羽生まれました。体全部に柔らかい羽が生えていて、かわいい赤ちゃんです。7羽の赤ちゃんは、この水族館では今までで最も多くて、育てる親のペンギンなどが足りません。このため、6羽は大人のペンギンと同じところで一緒にいるのを見ることができますが、1羽は別の部屋で水族館の人が育てています。水族館によると、7羽は元気に育っています。水族館の人は「今しか見ることができない柔らかい羽や、親のペンギンから食べ物をもらうところをぜひ見てほしいです」と話しています。","answer":"秋田県でかわいいペンギンの赤ちゃんが7羽生まれた"},{"question":"जीवनका चुनौतीहरूको सामना गर्न सकारात्मक सोच र लचिलोपन बीचको सम्बन्ध अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"सकारात्मक सोचले व्यक्तिहरूलाई चुनौतीहरूलाई विकासको अवसरको रूपमा हेर्न प्रोत्साहित गरेर लचिलोपन बढाउँछ। एक लचिलो मानसिकताले मानिसहरूलाई असफलताबाट फर्किन, अनुभवहरूबाट सिक्न र बलियो हुन सक्षम बनाउँछ।"},{"question":"  ਸਮਝੇ ਅਤੇ ਖਾਲੀ ਖਾਨੇ ਭਰੋ :   897 899  678 ____","answer":"678 680"},{"question":"Apakah sejarah NTV7 di Malaysia?","answer":"Ditubuhkan pada 7 April 1998 oleh Tan Sri Datuk Seri Mohd Effendi Norwawi, NTV7 mendapat sambutan yang memberangsangkan daripada segenap lapisan penonton di Malaysia. Penyiaran disiarkan melalui 10 pemancar yang terletak di seluruh Malaysia dan siaran biasanya bermula pada pukul 7:00 pagi hingga 1:00 pagi hari berikutnya. Kini siaran NTV7 hingga 2:00 pagi hari berikutnya.Pada 4 April 2022, NTV7 memulakan siaran 24 jam sehari buat pertama kalinya dan disambungsiar dari Hot FM.Kini Hot FM bersiaran Ahad Hingga Jumaat pukul 12 tengah malam hingga pukul 9.30 pagi dan setiap Sabtu pukul 12 tengah malam hingga pukul 7 pagi di NTV7. Pada Oktober 2005, Media Prima Berhad mengumumkan pengambilalihan NTV7. Media Prima juga memiliki 3 stesen TV swasta yang lain di Malaysia iaitu TV3, 8TV dan TV9 serta keseluruhan saham majoriti di The New Straits Times Press (Malaysia) Bhd. Pengambilalihan NTV7 oleh MPB diselesaikan pada 30 Disember 2005. Stesen NTV7 dijadikan sebagai saluran pilihan di kalangan keluarga urban. Ini dilengkapkan dengan pengenalan logo baru pada bulan Julai 2006 yang menegaskan kembali tujuan NTV7 untuk menyediakan kandungan unggul dan berkualiti untuk penonton setianya. NTV7 memfokuskan kepada penonton urban dan berbahasa Inggeris.Menurut laporan Berita Harian pada 31 Mac 2006, berdasarkan statistik AGB Nielsen, NTV7 menjadi saluran pilihan utama di kalangan penonton berbangsa Cina dengan jumlah penonton 145,000 pada waktu perdana. NTV7 menguasai kira-kira 36 peratus penonton masyarakat Cina berusia 25 tahun ke atas.Diimbas kembali, suatu ketika dulu NTV7 yang mula beroperasi sejak tahun 1998 pernah meniti zaman kegemilangan apabila dibarisi nama hebat seperti Wan Kamaruddin, Zaini Ahmad, Norazlina Awang Had dan beberapa personaliti lain.Bagaimanapun, sengat NTV7 mula hilang apabila seorang demi seorang personalitinya meninggalkan stesen ini yang pernah menjulang nama mereka dalam dunia penyiaran. Pemergian mereka meninggalkan kesan bukan sedikit kepada NTV7, malah tidak keterlaluan dikatakan keputusan mereka menyebabkan stesen ini semakin hilang keceriaannya.Pada tahun 2009, keseluruhan isi kandungan NTV7 telah disegarkan semula tentang program bertemakan gaya hidup yang sihat, hiburan, isu semasa dan program sukan yang menepati citarasa penonton Cina dan Urban.NTV7 kini sudah mencecah usia 15 tahun pada tahun 2013. Selama 15 tahun jugalah saluran itu telah cuba sedaya upaya menghasilkan kandungan-kandungan bermutu dan cuba menarik perhatian lebih ramai penonton saban tahun. Seiring dengan sambutan ulang tahunnya yang bakal tiba, NTV7 mengatur percaturan dengan memperkuat kedudukannya sebagai antara peneraju utama rangkaian televisyen serta menawarkan rancangan berkualiti yang bakal menarik seisi keluarga untuk setia menonton rancangan-rancangannya tanpa jemu. NTV7 akan memperkenalkan KEDUDUKAN TERBARU stesen itu untuk tahun 2013 yang bakal membawa saluran itu ke fasa yang lebih menarik dalam evolusinya tahun depan. Saluran itu kini telah mengenal pasti kedudukannya dengan menyasarkan jenama premiumnya kepada golongan profesional (professionals), pengurus (managers), eksekutif (executives), ahli perniagaan (businessmen) atau singkatannya (PMEBs) yang juga dikenali sebagai takrif Modern Urban Progressive Adults (MUPAs). MUPAs adalah mereka yang berusia 25 – 45 tahun dengan pemikiran urban dan global yang dikenali memiliki beberapa ciri seperti – bijaksana & bergaya, moden dengan citarasa global, mempunyai gaya hidup yang sibuk, berada di mana-mana sahaja (on-the-go) dan berorientasikan keluarga adalah di antaranya. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai asal selamat ke seberang, biar bergantung di ekor buaya\\"?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini ialah amat memerlukan pertolongan, apa jua bentuk pertolongan pun diterima."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'dapat karun timbul'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud mendapat keuntungan besar dengan tidak bekerja susah-susah"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిగరుకు అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం (RER) నునుపు అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం (SER) ల మధ్యగల భేదాల్ని తెలపండి.","answer":"గరుకు అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం (RER)1. అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం ఉపరితలంపైన రైబోసోమ్లు అతుక్కొని వుంటే దానిని ‘గరుకు అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం’ అంటారు.2. ప్రోటీన్ల నిర్మాణం, స్రావక్రియలు చురుకుగా జరుగుతున్న కణాలలో RER కనిపిస్తుంది.నునుపు అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం (SER)1. అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం ఉపరితలంపైన రైబోసోమ్లు లేకపోతే దానిని ‘నునుపు అంతర్జీవ ద్రవ్యజాలం’ అంటారు.2. లిపిడ్ సంశ్లేషణకు, లిపిడ్ంటి స్టెరాయిడ్ హార్మోనుల ఉత్పత్తి లో SER కనిపిస్తుంది."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'hitam-hitam gajah, putih-putih udang kepai'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud meskipun cantik rupanya yang hina tetap hina dan yang mulia tetap mulia meskipun buruk rupanya"},{"question":"Ọnụ siri si bere isi,","answer":"Oruo ka ebeere isi, ọnụ so ya"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਰਾਰਾ ਰੇਨ ਹੋਤ ਸਭ ਜਾ ਕੀ ॥ਤਜਿ ਅਭਿਮਾਨੁ ਛੁਟੈ ਤੇਰੀ ਬਾਕੀ ॥ਰਣਿ ਦਰਗਹਿ ਤਉ ਸੀਝਹਿ ਭਾਈ ॥ਜਉ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਰਾਮ ਨਾਮ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਈ ॥ਰਹਤ ਰਹਤ ਰਹਿ ਜਾਹਿ ਬਿਕਾਰਾ ॥ ਗੁਰ ਪੂਰੇ ਕੈ ਸਬਦਿ ਅਪਾਰਾ ॥ਰਾਤੇ ਰੰਗ ਨਾਮ ਰਸ ਮਾਤੇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਰ ਕੀਨੀ ਦਾਤੇ ॥੪੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 259 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸਾਰੀ ਲੋਕਾਈ ਜਿਸ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਚਰਨ-ਧੂੜ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਭੀ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦਾ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ, ਤੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਕੋ੍ਰਧ ਦੇ ਸੰਸਕਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਲੇਖਾ ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਏ ।ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਇਸ ਜਗਤ-ਰਣ-ਭੂਮੀ ਵਿਚ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਕਾਮਯਾਬ ਹੋਵੇਂਗਾ, ਜਦੋਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜੇਂਗਾ । ਪੂਰੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆਂ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਵਿਕਾਰ ਸਹਜੇ ਸਹਜੇ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਤੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਹਰੀ-ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਸੁਆਦ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ (ਤੇ ਉਹ ਦੂਜਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਰੋਸ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਦੀ ਸੋਧ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ) ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਹਰੀ-ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ ।੪੪।\\""},{"question":"Ya ake Nazarin Wasan Kwaikwayo?","answer":"Manazarcin wasan kwaikwayo zai kula da abubuwa kamar haka:JigoWarwarar JigoZubi da Tsari/Salo:Tauraro"},{"question":"Phân tích khổ 3 bài thơ \\"Chiều xuân\\" của Anh Thơ.","answer":"Trong bài thơ \\"Chiều xuân\\" của Anh Thơ, khổ 3 được mô tả như sau:\\"Trời xanh lặng lẽ, nắng vàng êm đềm,Cánh diều bay cao, gió thoảng mát lành.Người đi trên đường, cười vui, hát ca,Thôn quê yên bình, đời sống an lành.\\"Bức tranh quê dù đẹp đẽ, thanh bình đến đâu chăng nữa cũng sẽ trống trải nếu thiếu hình ảnh con người. Con người xuất hiện làm cho bức tranh thiên nhiên trở thành bức tranh sinh hoạt:Trong đồng lúa xanh rờn và ướt lặng,Lũ cò con chốc chốc vụt bay ra.Làm giật mình một cô nàng yếm thắm,Cúi cuốc cào cỏ ruộng sắp ra hoa.Khung cảnh thực mà giống như trong một giấc mơ. Giữa cánh đồng lúa xanh rờn nổi bật lên hình ảnh một cô nàng yếm thắm tràn đầy sức sống của tuổi xuân. Hình ảnh đáng yêu ấy thể hiện chất trữ tình lãng mạn đậm đà trong tâm hồn nữ thi sĩ nổi tiếng của phong trào Thơ mới. Tiếng động bất ngờ của Lũ cò con chốc chốc vụt bay ra khiến cô gái giật mình ngơ ngác là một điểm nhấn nghệ thuật. Hình ảnh cô thôn nữ với cái dáng cắm cúi, chuyên cần làm việc giữa khung cảnh chiều xuân êm đềm như thế quả đã làm xúc động lòng người, vẻ đẹp của cô thôn nữ bên cạnh vẻ đẹp của thiên nhiên khiến cho cảnh sắc bình thường, thân quen bỗng trở nên đẹp đẽ lạ thường. Thủ pháp lấy động tả tĩnh đã làm nổi bật vẻ thanh bình, vắng lặng của chiều xuân chốn đồng quê."},{"question":"¿Dónde queda la laguna del cacique Guatavita?","answer":"Se encuentra en la cordillera oriental de Colombia, en la vereda Tierra Negra del municipio de Sesquilé, bajo jurisdicción de la corporación Corporación Autónoma Regional CAR, a una distancia de 75 km al nordeste de Bogotá, provincia de Almeidas, departamento de Cundinamarca."},{"question":"لیست کارهای خانه تکانی عید در پذیرایی و نشیمن چیست؟","answer":" یکی از مهم‌ترین بخش‌هایی که با نزدیک شد به عید نوروز باید به طول کامل تمیز شود، پذیرایی و نشیمن خانه است. از آنجایی که نشیمن خانه محل پذیرایی از مهمان‌های عید است، می‌بایست با ظرافت بیشتر و توجه بیشتری تمیز شود. در ادامه به لیست کارهای تمیزکاری عید برای پذیرایی و نشیمن اشاره شده است:پاک کردن لوازم تزئینی و برقیتمیز کردن لوستر و آباژورپاک کردن دیوار و کفپوشتمیز کردن مبلمان و کوسن‌هاشستن فرشتمیز کردن میز ناهارخوریپاک کردن پنجره‌هاشستن پرده‌هاشستن موکتپاک کردن و تمیز کردن گلدان‌هاپاک کردن پریزهای برق"},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 リサイクルを行っている東京都板橋区の施設が、子どもたちにクリスマスのプレゼントをあげました。板橋区に住む人から使わなくなったおもちゃを集めて、袋に入れて、150人にあげるプレゼントを用意しました。そして23日から25日まで、施設に来た子どもたちにあげました。袋の中には、ぬいぐるみやけん玉などいろいろなおもちゃが入っています。袋からおもちゃを出して、楽しそうに遊ぶ子どももいました。プレゼントをもらった男の子は「恐竜のおもちゃがとてもうれしかったです」と話していました。施設の人は「小さな子どもたちに、ものや環境を大切にする生活ができるようになってほしいと思います」と話していました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Peter sọ fawọn ọrẹ ẹ pe ọga oun lowo lọwọ, n l’Arowolo atawọn ẹgbẹ ẹ ba lọọ digun ja a lole l’Ekoo","answer":"Bii ajẹ to jẹ̣ eepo ọbọ ni ọdomọkunrin kan, Arowolo Ibrahim, ṣe n ka pẹlu awọn ẹlẹgbẹ ẹ ti wọn jọ digunjale, nigba ti kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ṣafihan wọn han ni olu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa to wa ni Eleweeran, niluu Abẹokuta, l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, nigba ti wọn ko wọn dewaju awọn oniroyin.Mẹrin lawọn janduku ọmọ keekeeke yii ti ọjọ ori wọn wa laarin ọdun mejidinlogun si mẹrinlelogun. Awọn eeyan naa niwonyi; Arowolo Ibrahim, Yakubu Ibrahim, Yusuf Alani Azeez, Ṣowẹmimọ Faruq ati Peter Okenu, ọmọ Ibo ti wọn loun lo ṣatọna wọn debẹ.Ọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu kejila, ọdun 2020, ni wọn sọ pe ọwọ tẹ awọn eeyan yii ni kete ti ọkunrin ti wọn digun ja lole, Stephen Anyi, fẹjọ sun ni teṣan ọlọpaa niluu Ifọ, ipinlẹ Ogun, pe awọn janduku kan kọ lu oun nile oun.Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa sọ pe alaye ti ọkunrin to pe awọn yii ṣe ni pe nile oun to wa ni Kajola Phase II, n’Ifọ, ni wọn waa ka oun mọ, ati pe oju windo ni wọn gba wọle.Mọto ẹ, Toyota Highlander, ti nọmba ẹ jẹ KJA 38 FZ, naa pẹlu awọn nnkan ti wọn ko lọ pẹlu laptop, foonu alagbeeka ati owo. Awọn ọlọpaa sọ pe loju-ẹsẹ naa ni teṣan ọlọpaa ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ, ti ọwọ si tẹ awọn janduku yii laduugbo Mushin, l’Ekoo, nibi ti wọn ti fẹẹ ta awọn ẹru ti wọn ji ko ọhun.Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa fi kun un pe awọn ọdaran ti wọn mu yii ti jẹwọ, alaye ti wọn si ṣe ni pe Peter Okenu, ẹni ti ṣe ọmọọṣẹ ọkunrin ọmọ Ibo ti awọn lọọ ja lole yii lo ni ki awọn waa ko ile ọhun.Wọn ni funra Peter lo sọ pe ki awọn maa bọ wa, owo rẹpẹtẹ lawọn pa ni sọọbu awọn lọjọ naa, ile si lawọn n ko o lọ.ALAROYE gbọ pe oun yii kan naa lo tun ṣi windo fun wọn nigba ti wọn de loru. Awọn ọlọpaa sọ pe Peter yii nikan ni wọn ko gba foonu ẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn ko tun fiya jẹ pẹlu, eyi to jẹ ki wọn tete fura si i ki awọn ole paapaa too sọ pe oun gan an lo ni ki awọn maa bọ waa jale nile ọga oun.Ninu ifọrọwerọ wa pẹlu awọn janduku yii, alaye ti Arowolo Ibrahim ṣe ni pe Peter lo sọ fun awọn ki awọn waa jale nibẹ. O ni ọkunrin kan naa wa to sun mọ ọn daadaa, Ganiu lorukọ ẹ n jẹ, oun lo sọ fun pe awọn n ta daadaa ni gbogbo asiko ọdun yẹn, ati pe owo bii miliọnu meje naira lawọn maa n gbe lọ sile lojumọ.Ọdọmọkunrin to n ṣiṣe kafinta yii sọ pe miliọnu meje naira ti oun gbọ lo jẹ ki eti oun na, ti oun si sọ fun un pe ko ṣeto bi awọn yoo ṣe ra nnkan ti awọn yoo fi ṣiṣẹ naa.Ẹgbẹrun mẹta naira lo sọ pe ọmọ Ibo ko fun awọn, ada si lawọn fi ra.O ni bo ṣe di oru lawọn gba ile ọkunrin naa lọ, nigba ti awọn si debẹ, niṣe lo sọ pe oun ko gbe owo kankan wale, nigba ti awọn naa si tu gbogbo ile ọhun yẹbẹyẹbẹ, awọn ri i pe ko si miliọnu meje kankan nibẹ, nibi ti awọn ti sọ fun un pe ko fun awọn ni ohunkohun to ba ni niyẹn, to si ko ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọta (N60,000) naira jade.Arowolo sọ pe loju-ẹse naa lawọn gba kọkọrọ mọto Highlander ẹ, bẹẹ lawọn gba foonu atawọn dukia mi-in ninu ile wọn.O fi kun un pe nigba ti awọn wọle sọdọ ọmọ Ibo to ni ki awọn waa jale ọhun, oun ko jẹ ki awọn yooku oun na an, bẹẹ loun tun sọ pe ki wọn da foonu ẹ ti wọn gba lọwọ ẹ pada fun un.O ni bi awọn ṣe kuro nibẹ niyẹn ti awọn si kan’na si igbo, ti awọn n fa a lọ ninu mọtọ onimọto ti wọn gbe ninu ile ọkunrin naa.Nibi ti wọn ti n lọ lo ti sọ pe ọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ awọn, ti awọn naa ko si janpata lati ṣe jẹẹjẹ pẹlu wọn.Oṣu kan lo sọ pe awọn ti kọkọ lo l’Ekoo, ki wọn too ko awọn wa si olu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ni Eleweran, niluu Abẹokuta.Ọmọ yii sọ pe ọmọ ọdun mẹrinlelogun loun, ọmọ Ijẹbu si ni oun, bẹẹ lo fi kun un pe oun nikan naa ni iya oun bi.Ọmọ ogun ọdun ni Ibrahim yii loun wa ti oun ti kuro labẹ iya oun, tiyẹn n gbe ni Ikọtun, l’Ekoo. Bẹẹ lo fidi ẹ mulẹ pe mama naa ko mọ pe oun ti ha sọwọ ọlọpaa bayii.Ọmọ Ibo, Peter Okenu ti wọn lo ranṣe pe wọn yii naa ba ALAROYE sọrọ, alaye to ṣe ni pe oun ko mọ wọn ri, o ni irọ ni wọn pa mọ oun.O ni ohun ti oun mọ ni pe nitori ti oun jọ ọga oun daadaa ni wọn ṣe lero pe tawọn ba parọ, boya wọn yoo jọ tu awọn silẹ ni.Ọmọ ọdun mẹrinlelogun loun naa pera ẹ. Eyi to kere ju ninu wọn, ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogun ni, Ṣowẹmimọ Faruq lo pe orukọ ara ẹ, bakan naa lo sọ pe oun ti kabaamọ gidigidi, nitori oun ko mọ pe iṣẹ buruku ti wọn pe oun fun niyẹn ki oun too wọ wahala bayii.Lara awọn nnkan ti wọn ba lọwọ wọn niwọnyi; Mọto Toyota Highlander kan pẹlu ibọn ibilẹ meji, ada meji, foonu Samsung kan, foonu techno tablets kan ati Samsung galaxy a-10 kan."},{"question":"«Nataon’ny razana koa fa ny mety , na dia tsy maintsy ho faty aza any am-parany, dia ny mitandrina izay rehetra hampaharitra ny aina. « Fa ny mahery tsy maody tsy ela velona ». Nefa misy fetrany io hakanosana na fitandreman-tena io. Raha tonga amin’ny zavatra inoany ho ambony vidy noho ny ainy, mahay mihenjana izy hanao vy very ny ainy ary tsy mataho-maty. »Inona ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra eo ambony io ?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra io dia ny fitsimbinana ny aina."},{"question":"Mọto lọọ ya ba iya atawọn ọmọ rẹ meji l’Ogbomọṣọ, lo ba te wọn pa","answer":"Igbe ikunlẹ abiamọ lawọn olugbe atawọn  abanikẹdun n ke lagbegbe Crown FC Hostel, niluu Ogbomoṣọ, nibi ti ijamba ọkọ ti gbẹmi eeyan mẹta, ti ọpọ eeyan si fara pa yannayanna.Laaarọ ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, to kọja, niṣẹlẹ ọhun waye nitosi ilegbee ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu Crown FC, iyẹn Crown FC Hostel, to wa lọna Ọja Tuntun, niluu Ogbomọṣọ.Ohun to tubọ mu ki isẹlẹ yii pa gbogbo abiamọ agbegbe naa lẹkun ni pe ẹjẹ kan naa lawọn mẹtẹẹta to ku ọhun, iya atọmọ rẹ meji ni.Gẹgẹ b’ALAROYE ṣe gbọ, ijanu ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ Mistubishi ọhun ti nọmba ẹ jẹ LND 69 AR lo feeli lojiji, eyi to mu ki ọkọ naa ya bara kuro loju titi, to lọọ kọ lu iya kan ti ọpọ eeyan mọ si Iya Onike pẹlu awọn ọmọ rẹ meji ninu ṣọọbu wọn nibẹ.Olugbe adugbo ọhun kan to fiṣẹlẹ yii to akọroyin wa leti sọ pe awọn to wa nitosi lasiko iṣẹlẹ to ba ni ninu jẹ yii ni wọn sare gbe iya atawọn ọmọ rẹ mejeeji naa lọ sileewosan fun itọju.Ṣugbọn awọn dokita ko ri ipa kankan ṣa lati ra ẹmi wọn pada lọwọ iku oro, o jọ pe loju-ẹsẹ ni gbogbo wọn ti jade laye.Wọn ni ileewosan lọpọ ninu awọn to fara pa ninu iṣẹlẹ yii ṣi wa titi ta a fi pari akojọ iroyin yii.Ninu awọn to fara pa ọhun la ti ri dẹrẹba mọto to lasidẹnti naa pẹlu ero meji to wa ninu ẹ."},{"question":"දාවිත්ගේ ගිවිසුම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"දාවිත්ගේ ගිවිසුමෙහි, අනාගතවක්තෘ නාතාන් තුළින් දාවිත්ට දුන් පොරොන්දු ගැන සඳහන් වන අතර එය 2 සාමුවෙල් 7 හි සොයා ගත හැකි අතර පසුව 1 ලේකම් 17:11-14 සහ 2 ලේකම් 6:16 හි සාරාංශ කොට ඇත. මෙය දෙවියන්වහන්සේ සහ දාවිත් අතර ඇති කෝන්දේසි විරහිත ගිවිසුමකි. මෙසියස් (යේසුස් ක්‍රිස්තුස්වහන්සේ) දාවිත්ගේ පෙළපතෙන් හා යුදා ගෝත්‍රයෙන් පැමිණ සදාකාලයටම පවතින රාජ්‍යයක් ස්ථාපිත කරන බවට දෙවියන්වහන්සේ දාවිත්ට සහ ඉශ්‍රායෙලයට පොරොන්දු වුනි. දාවිත්ගේ ගිවිසුම කොන්දේසි විරහිත ගිවිසුමක් වන්නේ එය සපුරාලීම සඳහා දෙවියන් වහන්සේ දාවිත් මත කිසිම ආකාරයක කීකරුකමේ කොන්දේසියක් ඔහු මත නොපැටවූ බැවින්ය. පොරොන්දු වල ඇප සහතිකය රඳා පවතින්නේ දෙවියන්වහන්සේගේ විශ්වාසවන්තකම මත වන අතර එය කිසිසේත් දාවිත්ගේ හෝ ඉශ්‍රායෙලයේ කීකරුකම මත නොවේ. දාවිත්ගේ ගිවිසුම දාවිත්ට දුන් ප්‍රධාන පොරොන්දු කිහිපයක් මත කේන්ද්‍රගත වේ. පළමුව දෙවියන්වහන්සේ ඉශ්‍රායෙලය සමඟ කළ පළමු ගිවිසුම් දෙකෙහි (අබ්‍රහම් සහ පලස්තීන ගිවිසුම) දුන් දේශය පිළිබඳ පොරොන්දුව නැවත තහවුරු කරයි. මෙම පොරොන්දුව 2 සාමුවෙල් 7:10 හි දැක ගත හැකිය. මගේ සෙනඟවූ ඉශ්‍රායෙල් තමුන්ගේම ස්ථානයෙහි වාසය කරමින් තවත් අහක් නොවන ලෙස මම ඔවුන්ට ස්ථානයක් නියම කොට ඔවුන් පිහිටු වන්නෙමි. දුෂ්ට සෙනඟ තවත් ඔවුන්ට පීඩා නොකරනු ඇත. ඉන්පසු, දාවිත්ගේ පුත්‍රයා ඔහුගෙන් පසු ඉශ්‍රායෙල්හි රජ බවට පත් වන බවත්, මේ පුත්‍රයා (සාලමොන්) දේව මාළිගාව ගොඩ නඟන බවත් දෙවියන් වහන්සේ පොරොන්දු විය. මෙම පොරොන්දුව 2 සාමුවෙල් 7:12-13 දක්වා දැක ගත හැකිය. \\"මම නුඹෙන් පැවත එන නුඹේ බීජය නුඹට පසුව පිහිටුවා ඔහුගේ රජකම ස්ථීර කරන්නෙමි. ඔහුම මාගේ නාමයට ගෘහයක් ගොඩ නඟන්නේය\\".දවිතගේ \\"ගෘහය\\", \\"රාජ්‍යය\\", සහ \\"සිංහාසනය\\" සදහටම ස්ථාපිත වන බවට දුන් පොරොන්දුව වැදගත් වන්නේ මෙසියස්වහන්සේ පැමිණෙන්නේ දාවිත්ගේ පෙළපතෙන් බවට පෙන්නුම් කරන නිසා ඔහු රජකම් කරන රාජ්‍යයක් පිහිටුවනවා ඇත. ගිවිසුම සාරාංශ ගත කර ඇත්තේ දාවිත්ගේ පෙළපතෙහි රාජවංශයක් පොරොන්දු වන \\"නිවස\\" යන වචන වලින්ය. \\"රාජ්‍යය\\" යන්නෙන් රජෙකු විසින් පාලනය කරනු ලබන සෙනඟක් ගැන සඳහන් කරයි. මෙයින් අවධාරණය කරනු ලබන්නේ දාවිත්ට සහ ඉශ්‍රායෙලයට දුන් මෙම පොරොන්දුවේ සදාකාලික හා කෝන්දේසි විරහිත ස්වභාවය අවධාරණය කරමින්ය."},{"question":"Kryptonita é a fraqueza de qual super-herói?","answer":"Kryptonita é a fraqueza do Super-Homem."},{"question":"ඉරානයේ ජාතික භාෂාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"පර්සියන්"},{"question":"سیندونه د تمدنونو د کلتوري او ټولنیزو اړخونو په جوړولو کې څه رول لوبوي؟","answer":"سیندونه د تمدن په کلتوري او ټولنیز جوړښت باندې ژور اغیز لري. د اوبو شتون د کثافاتو نفوس ملاتړ کوي او د ښاري مرکزونو رامینځته کولو کې اسانتیاوې رامینځته کوي چې د متنوع کلتورونو پراختیا لامل کیږي. سیندونه اکثرا د ټولنیزو فعالیتونو لپاره مرکزي نقطې کیږي، د ټولنې سره د دوی په څنډو کې د مراسمو، مراسمو او جشنونو لپاره راټولیږي. برسیره پردې، د سیند د ایکوسیستم بډایه ژوولو تنوع د ټولنو کلتوري هویت کې مرسته کوي، په هنر، افسانه، او مذهبي باورونو اغیزه کوي. د سیندونو د سیسټمونو سره وصل کول د مختلفو سیمو ترمنځ کلتوري تبادلې او ارتباط ته وده ورکوي، د تمدنونو ډله ایز هویت جوړوي."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਾਵੈ ਕੋ ਗੁਣ ਵਡਿਆਈਆ ਚਾਰ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 1 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਕੋਈ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਰੱਬ ਦੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਗੁਣ ਤੇ ਸੋਹਣੀਆਂ ਵਡਿਆਈਆਂ ਵਰਣਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। \\""},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa waxa ku waajibay qofkii qofkale ugu yeedha in ay ciyaaraan khamaar?","answer":"Qofkii qof ugu yeedha iney khamaaraan ama khamaar ciyaaraan, wuxuu bixinayaa saddaqo sida ka sugnaatay Nabiga (scw).    "},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um editor de conteúdo?","answer":"Um editor de conteúdo revisa, aprimora e gerencia o conteúdo escrito, garantindo sua qualidade e relevância."},{"question":"ഈ ഖണ്ഡിക ആരെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്: \\"നാടകത്തിലുള്ള കമ്പം കാരണം അടൂർ 1962 ഇൽ പൂന ഫിലിം ഇൻസ്റ്റിറ്റ്യൂട്ടിൽ സംവിധാനം പഠിക്കുവാൻ പോയി. ചലച്ചിത്ര സംവിധാനം പഠിക്കുന്നത് തന്നെ ഒരു നല്ല നാടകസംവിധായകൻ ആക്കുമെന്ന വിശ്വാസമായിരുന്നു ഇതിനു പ്രചോദനം. പക്ഷേ ചലച്ചിത്രം എന്ന മാദ്ധ്യമത്തിന്റെ കഴിവുകളെ അവിടെവെച്ച് അടൂർ കണ്ടെത്തുകയായിരുന്നു. തിരക്കഥാരചനയിലും സംവിധാനത്തിലും ഡിപ്ലോമയുമായി 1965-ൽ പൂനെ ഫിലിം ഇൻസ്റ്റിറ്റ്യൂട്ടിൽ ചലച്ചിത്രപഠനം പൂർത്തിയാക്കിയ അടൂർ ഗോപാലകൃഷ്ണൻ, അതേ വർഷം തന്നെ കുളത്തൂർ ഭാസ്കരൻ നായരുടെ പങ്കാളിത്തത്തോടെ കേരളത്തിലെ ആദ്യത്തെ ഫിലിം സൊസൈറ്റിയായ തിരുവന്തപുരത്തെ ചിത്രലേഖ ഫിലിം സൊസൈറ്റിയും, സ്വതന്ത്രമായി സിനിമകളുടെ നിർമ്മാണവും വിതരണവും പ്രദർശനവും നിർവഹിക്കാനായി ചിത്രലേഖ ഫിലിം കോപ്പറേറ്റീവും സ്ഥാപിക്കുകയുണ്ടായി.\\"","answer":"അടൂർ ഗോപാലകൃഷ്ണൻ എന്ന ഇന്ത്യൻ ചലച്ചിത്രസംവിധായകനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് ഈ ഭാഗം സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്. അടൂർ ഗോപാലകൃഷ്ണൻ (ജനനം 3 ജൂലൈ 1941) ഒരു ഇന്ത്യൻ ചലച്ചിത്ര സംവിധായകനും തിരക്കഥാകൃത്തും നിർമ്മാതാവുമാണ്, ഇന്ത്യയിലെ ഏറ്റവും ശ്രദ്ധേയവും പ്രശസ്തവുമായ ചലച്ചിത്ര നിർമ്മാതാക്കളിൽ ഒരാളായി അദ്ദേഹം കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നു."},{"question":"A palavra \\"mirim\\" é um palíndromo?","answer":"Sim, pois ao ler de trás para frente temos a mesma palavra."},{"question":"Cuntooyinka Maskaxda ugu Fiican waxaa ka midda ah. ","answer":"Maskaxdeenu waa yaab, sidaas darteed waa muhiim in aan waxyaabo la yaab leh u samayno maskaxdeena! Ma ogeyd:• Macluumaadka maskaxdeenu wuxuu socon karaa ilaa 268 mayl saacaddii! Neurons waxaa lagu kiciyaa maskaxda taas oo kicisa garaaca korantada kaas oo si degdeg ah uga socda unug ilaa unug.• Waa khuraafaad in aan isticmaalno 10% oo kaliya maskaxdayada. Sida laga soo xigtay dhakhaatiirta neerfayaasha, waxaan isticmaalnaa dhammaan maskaxdeena oo ay xitaa firfircoon tahay inta aan hurudno.• Maskaxdu waxay miisaankeedu celcelis ahaan, qiyaastii saddex rodol ah, laakiin cabbirka maskaxdeennu xidhiidh lama laha garaadka.Waa kuwan qaar ka mid ah cuntooyinka lagu daro cuntadaada si loo hubiyo in maskaxdaadu ay si adag kuugu shaqaynaysoSALAMON • Salmoonku waxa ku badan dufanka caafimaadka qaba ee maskaxda loo yaqaan Omega-3 fatty acids. Omega-3s aad ayey muhiim ugu tahay shaqada maskaxda iyo xusuusta. Waxaa lagu talinayaa inaad cunto salmon qiyaastii laba ilaa saddex jeer usbuucii si aad u hesho Omega-3s ee maskaxdaada iyo jidhkaagu u baahan yihiin.• Isku day inaad ku dubto ama ku dubto salmon leh xawaashyada aad jeceshahay. Ku dar salmon la kariyey saladh, bariis, khudaar, ama ku darso cambe iyo salsa cananaaska ah. Keega Salmon sidoo kale waa hab wanaagsan oo lagu daro Omega-3s cuntadaada.Kalluunka kale ee uu ku badan yahay Omega-3 fatty acids waa mackerel, herring, trout, iyo tuna.UKUN• Ukuntu waxaa ka buuxa nafaqooyin aad u wanaagsan maskaxdeena. Choline, oo laga helo jaallolo ukun, ayaa la ogaaday inay yarayso bararka maskaxda taasoo kordhin karta xusuusta. Waxa kale oo ay ku badan yihiin tryptophan oo ah amino acid ka caawisa in la dhiso \\"kiimikada farxadda leh,\\" serotonin. Isku day inaad cuntid hal ukun maalintii si aad maskaxdaada uga faa'iidaysato.• Ukuntu way fududahay in lagu daro cuntooyinkeena. U diyaari habka aad ugu jeceshahay quraacda oo ay la socdaan rooti rooti iyo midho. Way fududahay in lagu daro saladhka dushooda, ka sameeyaan sandwiches salad ukun ah, ama ukun la shiiday.blåbærBuluuga waxaa loo tixgaliyaa inay yihiin \\"cunto-superfood\\" sababtoo ah dhagaxyadan yar yar waxaa ka buuxa antioxidants. Flavanoids, oo ah nooc ka mid ah antioxidants, waxay kicisaa socodka dhiigga iyo ogsijiinta maskaxda si ay u wanaajiso xusuusta iyo xoojinta. Isku day inaad ku darto 1/2 koob oo blueberries ah maalintii si loo kordhiyo caafimaadka maskaxda.• Blueberries iskood aad bay u fiican yihiin laakiin waxaa lagu dari karaa maraqa, caano fadhi, ama salad khudaar ah.Khudaarta Cagaaran ee Caleenta leh.• Cagaarka caleenta ah sida caleenta, isbinaajka, iyo arugula waxa ku badan fitamiin E, kaas oo la ogaaday in uu unugyada ka ilaaliyo dhaawaca. Faytamiin K ayaa la muujiyay inuu wanaajiyo xusuusta iyo beta carotene ayaa la muujiyay inay hoos u dhigto hoos u dhaca garaadka. Isku day inaad hesho qiyaastii laba koob oo cagaar caleen ah maalintii.• Saladku waa hab fiican oo lagu cuno cagaarka caleenta ah. Ku dar waxyaallaha macaan sida digaag la dubay ama la dubay, ukun adag oo la karkariyey, yicib ama walnuts, yaanyo, iyo qajaar. Ku dar cagaarka caleenta ah ismarisyadaada, duubabka, maraqyada, iyo suxuunta baastada.MidhuhuMiraha waxaa ku jira faa'iidooyin nafaqo oo badan. Qaar ka mid ah lawska ee xirxira feerka nafaqeynta ugu fiican waa yicib, pistachios, iyo looska macadamiya, laakiin walnuts ayaa lagu qiimeeyaa kuwa ugu sarreeya nafaqadooda. Waxay ka kooban yihiin xaddi badan oo Omega-3s iyo DHA, kuwaas oo ka ilaaliya bararka. Isku day inaad cunto 1 – 2 wiqiyadood maalintii, ama qadar ku habboon gacantaada.• Cun lawska cunto fudud ahaan ama ku dar saladh, badarka, ama caano fadhi."},{"question":"கேள்வி : எந்தப் பறைவைக்கு சிறகு இல்லை ? ","answer":"பதில் : கிவி."},{"question":"Кыргызстандын Ош шаарындагы Ак-Буура дарыясы эмнеден ушундай аталып калган?","answer":"Илгери илгери Даңги 🏞️ капчыгайынын оозунда адырларда Төлөйкөндө Боогачы уурулары  жашаган. Боогачы уруусунан бир карыянын аппак ак түстө буурасы (төө) болгон. Дарыя ошол ак төөнүн атынан Ак-Буура деп аталып калган.Дарыядан суу өтө улуу шар аккан, эки жээктеги адамдын үнү бир-бирине угулган эмес(азыр деле угулбайт). Карыянын төөсү алдуу күчтүү толуп турган маалы экен. Бир ошол төө дарыянын жайык жеринен өтө алчу экен, адамдардын буйум-тайымдарын ал өйүздөн-бүйзгө ташып өткөрүп турчу экен. Көп жыл элге кызмат кылат. Бир күнү суу улуу келип, шаркырап аккан суу Буураны агызып жөнөйт,төө канчалык мөңкүп турайын дейт, бирок суу күчтүүлүк кылып коё бербейт. Элдер жардам бергенине карабай, ээсинен жардам күткөн төө, таштан-ташка урулуп, суу астына чөгүп, ачуу кыйкырык менен агып кеткен. Ошентип дарыя  Ак-Бууранын атынан аталып калган экен."},{"question":"સામે  એક  ટેકરી છે, ત્યાં વડનું ઝાડ છે.વડને વડવાઈઓ છે, ઠંડી મજાની હવા છે.\\tકાલે  ત્યાં  જાશું   ભાઈ,   હીંચકા  ખાશું   ભાઈ! ઉજાણી પણ કરશું ભાઈ, રમીને જમીને જશું ભાઈ!બાળગીત પુર્ણ કરો.","answer":"સામે  એક  ટેકરી છે, ત્યાં વડનું ઝાડ છે.વડને વડવાઈઓ છે, ઠંડી મજાની હવા છે.\\tકાલે  ત્યાં  જાશું   ભાઈ,   હીંચકા  ખાશું   ભાઈ! ઉજાણી પણ કરશું ભાઈ, રમીને જમીને જશું ભાઈ!આ દાતરડું કેવું?  ઘાસ કાપે એવું!આ  ઘાસ   કેવું? ગાય ખાય એવું!\\tઆ ગાય કેવી? દૂધ આપે એવી!આ  દૂધ  કેવું ? દહીં થાય એવું!આ દહીં  કેવું?  છાસ  થાય  એવું!આ છાસ કેવી? માખણ થાય એવી!આ  માખણ કેવું ?  ઘી  થાય  એવું!આ  ઘી  કેવું ?  લાડવા  થાય એવું!આ લાડવા કેવા?  મને ભાવે એવા!\\tએક હતી  છોકરી,  એણે  પાળી બકરીછોકરી ગઈ  ફરવા,   બકરી ગઈ ચરવાફરીને આવી છોકરી, ભાળી નહિ બકરીરડવા  લાગી  છોકરી,   એં    એં    એંઆવી પહોંચી  બકરી,   બેં    બેં    બેં"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Libros","answer":"¿Quién escribió la serie de libros Amanecer rojo? Pierce Brown"},{"question":"\\"කුළු බඩු සහ ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව\\" ගැන කියන්න.","answer":"කුළු බඩු පිළිබඳ සාකච්ඡා කිරීමේදී ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවට හිමිවනුයේ සුවිශේෂී ස්ථානයකි. ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව කලින් කලට විවිධ යුරෝපා ජාතීන්ගේ යටත් විජිතයක් බවට පත්විය. ස්වාභාවික වරායන් සහිත වූ දිවයිනක් වශයෙන් යටත් විජිත වාදීන්ගේ ආකර්ෂණය ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාව වෙත යොමු විය. යුරෝපීයයන්ගේ යටත් විජිතයක්වීමට පෙරද ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුළු බඩු ලෝක ප‍්‍රසිද්ධ වී තිබුණි. එනම් උදාහරණයක් වශයෙන්ඈත අතීතයේ සිටි සුප‍්‍රසිද්ධ දේශාටකයෙකු වූ ඉබන් බතුතා විසින්ද ශ‍්‍රී ලංකාවේ කුළු බඩු සම්බන්ධව තම අදහස් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත. ඔහු දක්වන පරිදි, ‘‘එම දිවයිනේ වෙරළාසන්න ප‍්‍රදේශයේදී කුරුඳු ශාකයන්හී අතුපතර විහිදී ගිය ආවරණයක් නිර්මාණය කර තිබිණ. වෙළඳුන් එම කුරුඳු විශාල වශයෙන් තම රටවලට ගෙන ගියේ ස්වදේශික ජනයාට කිසිඳු ගෙවීමක් නොකරය. එහෙත් ඇතැම් විට ඔවුන් තමන් සතු වියන ලද රෙදි පිළි සහ වෙනත් සුවඳ විලවුන් ද්‍රව්‍ය ස්වදේශිකයන්ට තිළිණ වශයෙන් හිමිකර දි තිබුණි.’’ යනුවෙන් ප‍්‍රකාශ කර ඇත."},{"question":"वाराणसी नाम का अर्थ?","answer":"वाराणसी नाम का उद्गम संभवतः यहां की दो स्थानीय नदियों वरुणा नदी एवं असि नदी के नाम से मिलकर बना है। ये नदियाँ गंगा नदी में क्रमशः उत्तर एवं दक्षिण से आकर मिलती हैं। नाम का एक अन्य विचार वरुणा नदी के नाम से ही आता है जिसे संभवतः प्राचीन काल में वरणासि ही कहा जाता होगा और इसी से शहर को नाम मिला। इसके समर्थन में शायद कुछ आरम्भिक पाठ उपलब्ध हों, किन्तु इस दूसरे विचार को इतिहासवेत्ता सही नहीं मानते हैं। लंबे काल से वाराणसी को अविमुक्त क्षेत्र, आनंद-कानन, महाश्मशान, सुरंधन, ब्रह्मावर्त, सुदर्शन, रम्य, एवं काशी नाम से भी संबोधित किया जाता रहा है। ऋग्वेद में शहर को काशी या कासी नाम से बुलाया गया है। इसे प्रकाशित शब्द से लिया गया है, जिसका अभिप्राय शहर के ऐतिहासिक स्तर से है, क्योंकि ये शहर सदा से ज्ञान, शिक्षा एवं संस्कृति का केन्द्र रहा है। काशी शब्द सबसे पहले अथर्ववेद की पैप्पलाद शाखा से आया है और इसके बाद शतपथ में भी उल्लेख है। लेकिन यह संभव है कि नगर का नाम जनपद में पुराना हो। स्कंद पुराण के काशी खण्ड में नगर की महिमा १५,००० श्लोकों में कही गयी है। एक श्लोक में भगवान शिव कहते हैं: तीनों लोकों से समाहित एक शहर है, जिसमें स्थित मेरा निवास प्रासाद है काशीवाराणसी का एक अन्य सन्दर्भ ऋषि वेद व्यास ने एक अन्य गद्य में दिया है: गंगा तरंग रमणीय जातकलापनाम, गौरी निरन्तर विभूषित वामभागम.नारायणप्रियम अनंग मदापहारम, वाराणसीपुर पतिम भज विश्वनाथम"},{"question":"Uche Ekwunife","answer":"Uche Lilian Ekwunife (Orúko abiso rè ni Ogudebe) ti a bi 12 January 1970 jẹ oloṣelú omobibi orílè-èdè Nàìjirià. Ó wà lara awon ti ọmọ ile igbimọ aṣo(Senato) kesan ti Nàìjirià, óún se a o ṣoju awọn eniyan Anambra Central Senatorial District ti Anambra.A bi Ekwunife ni 12 December 1970 ni ilu Igbo-Ukwu, Anambra si inú idile Emmanuel ati Lucy Ogudebe. Ekwunife losi yunifasiti ti Calabar, o si kékó gboye ninu Business ati Accounting ni odun 1993. O tesiwaju lati gba oye MBA re ní ilé-ìwé giga Nnamdi Azikiwe ni 2002. Ó fé Chief Larry Ekwunife.Ekwunife díje fun ipo gomina Anambra lẹẹmeji laisi aṣeyọri. O díje fun ile igbimo asofin kekere(house of representative) lati se aṣoju agbegbe Anaocha/Njikoka/Dunukofia ti Anambra ni odun 2007, o sì jawe olubori. O jẹ ọkan ninu awọn obinrin mokanla ti a diboyan sí ipò náà ní ọdun 2007 ti a tún diboyan ni ọdun 2011. Awọn obinrin toku ti a yan ni Juliet Akano, Mulikat Adeola-Akande, Abike Dabiri, Nkiru Onyeagocha, Nnena Elendu-Ukeje, Olajumoke Okoya-Thomas, Beni Lar, Khadija Bukar Abba-Ibrahim, Elizabeth Ogbaga ati Peace Uzo.Ní ọdún 2015, a yàn sí ipò Sẹ́nétọ̀ Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn obìnrin mẹ́fà tí a yàn sí National Assembly kejo. Awọn obinrin yooku ni Rose Okoji Oko, Stella Oduah, Fatimat Raji Rasaki, Oluremi Tinubu ati Binta Garba. Nitoripe Ekwunife yí padà lati egbé oselu kan sí imiran láti jawe olubori ninu idibo odun 2015, a yó kuro nípò Senato ní December 2015, a si yan Victor Umeh sí ipò Senato.O jawe olubori fún ipo ile igbimọ aṣofin agba ti ipinlẹ Anambra ni ọdun 2019 labẹ egbe oselu People's Democratic Party(PDP) , o se asoju Anambra Central Senatorial District, Nàìjirià, oludije alatako rè, Victor Umeh fìdíremi."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'biar miring asalkan jangan tertelungkup'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tidak mengapa rugi sedikit asalkan jangan habis semua sekali"},{"question":"ஒரு பொருளைப் பல பாடலில் பாடும் பதிக மரபை முதன் முதலாகத் தொடங்கி வைத்தவர் யார்?","answer":"ஒரு பொருளைப் பல பாடலில் பாடும் பதிக மரபை முதன் முதலாகத் தொடங்கி வைத்தவர் காரைக்கால் அம்மையார்."},{"question":"Hoggaamiyeyaasha dhaqanka ee Soomaalida","answer":"BoqorBeeldaajeUgaasImaamSuldaanGaraadMalaaqIslaan WabarIslow"},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে নিচের অনুচ্ছেদটি পড়ুন এবং প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিন |অনুচ্ছেদ :কম্বোডীয় জনতা পার্টি (Khmer: គណបក្សប្រជាជនកម្ពុជា, Kanakpak Pracheachon Kâmpuchéa) কম্বোডিয়ার বর্তমান ক্ষমতাসীন রাজনৈতিক দল। পূর্বে এ দলের নাম ছিল কম্পুচিয় জনতা বৈপ্লবিক পার্টি (কেপিআরপি)। ১৯৭৯ থেকে ১৯৮৯ মেয়াদকালে গণপ্রজাতন্ত্রী কম্পুচিয়াসহ কম্বোডিয়া রাষ্ট্রের প্রথম দুই বছর একমাত্র বৈধ দল ছিল। কম্বোডিয়া রাষ্ট্রের ক্রান্তিকালীন সময়ে এর নাম পরিবর্তন করা হয়েছিল। এ সময় মার্কসবাদ-লেনিনবাদের মতাদর্শ স্থগিতসহ একদলীয় ব্যবস্থার প্রবর্তন করা হয়। ১৯৭৯ থেকে কম্বোডিয়া সরকারের আমল থেকে এ দলটি দেশ শাসন করছে ও বিশ্বের অন্যতম দীর্ঘস্থায়ী শাসক দলের মর্যাদা পাচ্ছে। বর্তমান প্রধানমন্ত্রী হুন সেন দলের সভাপতির দায়িত্ব পালন করছেন।প্রশ্ন :কম্বোডিয়ার বর্তমান প্রধানমন্ত্রী ?","answer":"কম্বোডিয়ার বর্তমান প্রধানমন্ত্রী হুন সেন |"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي كان يطلق عليه لقب أسد الله ورسوله؟","answer":"الجواب: عم الرسول حمزة بن عبد المطلب رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"Qual é o evento importante citado nesse trecho: Em 20 de abril de 2011, foi relatado que Hondros foi mortalmente ferido em um ataque de morteiro por forças do governo em Misrata durante a cobertura da guerra civil na Líbia de 2011. O fotojornalista Tim Hetherington também foi morto no ataque, que feriu dois outros fotógrafos. O fotojornalista Guy Martin disse que o grupo estava viajando com combatentes rebeldes. De acordo com o The New York Times, Hondros morreu devido aos ferimentos como resultado de um trauma cerebral grave.","answer":"guerra civil na Líbia de 2011"},{"question":"வினா:நோய் தடுப்புத் தன்மைக்கு தேவையான புரதம் எது?","answer":"விடை: நோய் தடுப்புத் தன்மைக்கு தேவையான புரதம் க்ளோபுலின் ஆகும்.குளோபுலின்ஸ் என்பது இரத்தத்தில் காணப்படும் புரதங்கள். நோயெதிர்ப்பு அமைப்பு கல்லீரலில் அவற்றை உருவாக்குகிறது. கல்லீரல் செயல்பாட்டிற்கு குளோபுலின்கள் முக்கியமானவை. இரத்தம் உறைதல், மற்றும் தொற்று எதிர்ப்பு போன்றவற்றை உருவாக்கிறது.குளோபுலின் அளவு இந்த சாதாரண வரம்பிற்குக் குறைவாக இருந்தால், அது பல தீவிர உடல்நலப் பிரச்சினைகளைக் குறிக்கலாம். குறைந்த குளோபுலின் அளவு ஏற்படலாம் சிறுநீரக நோய், கல்லீரல் செயலிழப்பு, செலியாக் நோய், குடல் அழற்சி நோய் மற்றும் கடுமையான ஹீமோலிடிக் அனீமியா உண்டாக்கும்."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _ \\" Toy ny parakin'Amboatany:misy ihany fa _ \\"","answer":" Toy ny parakin'Amboatany:misy ihany fa mampandozaina "},{"question":"\\"සපත්නී රෝෂය\\" පහදා දෙන්න.","answer":"එක පුරුෂයෙකුට භාර්‍යාවන් කීපදෙනෙක් ඉන්න විට එක් භාර්‍යාවකට අනෙක් භාර්‍යාවන් (සහ පත්නීන්) කෙරෙහි ඇතිවන රෝෂය (තරහව)රෝෂය කියන්නෙ තරහ, කෝපයට.සපත්නී රෝෂය ඊර්ෂ්‍යාව නිසා ඇතිවෙන එකක්.උසස් පෙළ කාලේ අපි ට \\" රත්නාවලී නාට්‍ය \\" තිබුණා. මේ නාට්‍යයේ එන චරිතයක් තමයි \\" වාසවදත්තා \\"මේ බිසව තමන්ගේ ස්වාමියා වන උදයනි රජු \\" සාගරිකා \\" නැමති කුමාරියකට ඇල්මක් දක්වන අවස්ථාවේ වාසවදත්තා බොහෝ සේ කලබල වුණා. සාගරිකාගේ සුන්දරත්වය ට ඇය ඊර්ෂ්‍යා කළා. රජුගෙන් සාගරිකා ඈත් කර තියන්න බොහෝ උත්සාහ ගත්තා. ( සපත්නීරෝෂය ) කියන එකෙන් හැඟවෙන්නේ ඔය වාසවදත්තා බිසව ඇගේ ස්වාමියා ප්‍රේම කරන අන් යුවතිය කෙරෙහි දක්වන ඊර්ෂ්‍යාව"},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai. Datuk Kamil __ ada di pejabatnya kerana sering menghadiri mesyuarat di luar daerah. Pilihan:  A) jarang-jarangB) kadang-kadangC) bukan-bukanD)  jarak-jarak","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A) jarang-jarang"},{"question":"ਵਿਦਿਆਰਥੀ ਨੇ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਤੋਂ ਗ੍ਰੈਜੂਏਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤੀ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੀ ਭਾਲ ਕੀਤੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਸ਼ੌਕ ਪਾਲਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸਨੇ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਦੀ ਭਾਲ ਕੀਤੀ।"},{"question":"La domanda: I Green Bay Packers hanno vinto il Super Bowl XLV?","answer":"La risposta è: si."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚Ж. Садыковдун Манастын уулу Семетей драмасында Каныкейдин ролун ким аткарган?а) Бакен Кыдыкеева б) Даркүл Күйүковав) Назира Мамбетова г) Сабира Күмүшалиева","answer":"а) Бакен Кыдыкеева "},{"question":"வினா : தன்மை அணியின் வகைகள் எத்தனை.அ) மூன்றுஆ) நான்குஇ) ஐந்துஈ) ஏழு","answer":" விடை: ஆ) நான்கு"},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هو حكم التسوية في صلاة الجماعة؟","answer":"الجواب: سنة مؤكدة."},{"question":"実家が魚屋をやっていたことから師匠が芸名をつけたお笑いタレントといえば誰？","answer":"明石家さんまです。"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو ربك؟","answer":"الجواب: ربي الله ورب كل شيء."},{"question":"كيف يمكن الحصول على رقم 100 عند استخدام رقم (1) 5 مرات ؟","answer":"111 – 11 = 100"},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: Όταν η είδηση του θανάτου του Αλεξάνδρου Α΄ έφτασε στην Αγία Πετρούπολη, ο Μιλοράντοβιτς απέτρεψε την άνοδο στο θρόνο του μέλλοντος αυτοκράτορα Νικολάου Α΄, για δύο περίπου εβδομάδες, μέχρις ότου οι Ρομανόφ να λύσουν το θέμα της διαδοχής. Την ημέρα της ενθρόνισης του αυτοκράτορα (14 Δεκεμ.1825) ξέσπασε η","answer":"εξέγερση των Δεκεμβριστών, που προκλήθηκε κυρίως από νεαρούς αξιωματικούς, οι οποίοι υποστήριζαν τον μεγαλύτερο αδελφό του Νικολάου, τον Κωνσταντίνο, για τον οποίο πίστευαν ότι θα ήταν περισσότερο δημοκρατικός. Παρόλο ότι ο Μιχαήλ Αντρέεβιτς Μιλοράντοβιτς είχε σαφείς ενδείξεις για την κίνηση των Δεκεμβριστών, δεν είχε επέμβει εγκαίρως, παρά μόνον όταν αυτοί κατέλαβαν την πλατεία της Γερουσίας (Senátskaia Plόschad). Τότε προχώρησε μεταξύ των επαναστατών με σκοπό να τους μιλήσει, δέχθηκε όμως θανατηφόρο πυροβολισμό από κάποιον με το όνομα Καχόβσκι (Pyotr Kakhovsky), έναν από τους πρωταγωνιστές της εξέγερσης."},{"question":"翻译下面的古文：包孝肃公家训云:“后世子孙仕宦,有犯脏滥者,不得放归本家;亡殁之后,不得葬于大茔之中。不从吾志,非吾子孙。”共三十七字。其下押字又云:“仰珙刊石,竖于堂屋东壁,以诏后世。”又十四字。珙者,孝肃之子也。","answer":"包孝肃公（包拯谥号）包拯在家训中有这样一段话：“后代包家子孙做官的人中，如有犯了贪污财物罪而撤职的人，都不允许回归老家；死了以后，也不允许葬在家族祖坟上。如不继承我的志向，就不是我的子孙后代。”原文共有三十七个字。在家训后面签字时又写道：“希望包珙把上面一段文字刻在石块上，把刻石竖立在堂屋东面的墙壁旁，用来晓喻包家后代子孙。”原文又有十四个字。包珙，就是包拯的儿子。"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. මල් සූටික්කෝ සිංදු කියාපන්මා දං අත්තක වාඩි වෙලාපිලේ ඉඳන් ඒ සිංදු අහන්නම්හිතේ කඳුළු බිඳු නෙතින් හෙලා","answer":"මල් සූටික්කෝ සිංදු කියාපන්මා දං අත්තක වාඩි වෙලාපිලේ ඉඳන් ඒ සිංදු අහන්නම්හිතේ කඳුළු බිඳු නෙතින් හෙලාඅමතක නොමවන මතක සිහින ළඟමා හද ඉකි බිඳ හඬන වෙලේපිපෙන කුසුම් ගැන සමනලයන් ගැනඑපාගයන්නට සූටික්කෝලොවකට නෑසෙන මගේ ගීතයටනුඹේ මියුරු හඬ දීපන්නේකණාමැදිරියන් වගේ නිවී ගියආදරයක් ගැන ගයපන්නේඉන්ද්‍රානි විජේබණ්ඩාර"},{"question":"ਖਮਾਣੋਂ, 30 ਅਕਤੂਬਰਪ੍ਰਿੰਸੀਪਲ ਐਸਐਸ ਬਰਾੜ ਤੇ ਮੈਨਜਮੈਂਟ ਕਮੇਟੀ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਜੇਤੂ ਤਲਵਾਰਬਾਜ਼। -ਫੋਟੋ: ਜਗਜੀਤ ਕੁਮਾਰਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਅਖਿਲ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਫੈਨਸਿੰਗ ਖੇਡ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ (ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਪੱਧਰੀ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ) ਸਰਵਹਿੱਤਕਾਰੀ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਮੰਦਿਰ ਬਰਨਾਲਾ ਵਿਚ ਸਮਾਪਤ ਹੋਏ। ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਿਆਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਸਰਵਹਿਤਕਾਰੀ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਮੰਦਿਰ ਖਮਾਣੋਂ ਦੇ ਤਲਵਾਰਵਾਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੇ ਵਧੀਆ ਪਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ 14 ਸਾਲ, 17 ਅਤੇ 19 ਸਾਲ ਦੇ ਲੜਕੇ ਲੜਕੀਆਂ ਨੇ 35 ਸੋਨ ਤਮਗੇ, 11 ਸਿਲਵਰ ਅਤੇ 8 ਕਾਂਸੇ ਦੇ ਕੁੱਲ 64 ਮੈਡਲ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਕੇ ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਕਾਇਮ ਕੀਤਾ। ਸਪੋਰਟਸ ਡਾਇਰੈਕਟਰ ਤ੍ਰਿਲੋਚਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਡੋਗਰਾ ਨੇ ਕੰਪੀਟੀਸ਼ਨ ਡਾਇਰੈਕਟਰ, ਕੋਚ ਵਜੋਂ ਸਰਬਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਅਤੇ ਫੈਨਸਿੰਗ ਕੋਚ ਹਰਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਨੇ ਬਤੌਰ ਟੈਕਨੀਕਲ ਆਫਿਸ਼ੀਅਲ ਰੈਫਰੀ ਦੀ ਸੇਵਾ ਨਿਭਾਈ।ਫੈਨਸਿੰਗ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ 19 ਸਾਲ ਲੜਕੇ ਫੁਆਇਲ ਈਵੈਂਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਰਸ਼ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਟੀਮ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਗੋਲਡ ਮੈਡਲ ਜਿੱਤੇ। ਗੁਰਤੋਜ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਗੋਲਡ ਅਤੇ ਇਕ ਸਿਲਵਰ ਮੈਡਲ ਜਿੱਤੇ। ਗੁਰਕੋਮਲ ਸਿੰਘ ਇਕ ਗੋਲਡ ਅਤੇ ਇਕ ਕਾਂਸੇ ਦਾ ਤਗਮਾ ਜਿੱਤ ਕੇ ਇਸ ਈਵੈਂਟ ’ਚ ਸਰਵੋਤਮ ਰਹੇ। ਇੱਪੀਈਵੈਂਟ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਰਸ਼ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਗੋਲਡ, ਗੁਰਜੋਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਸਿਲਵਰ ਅਤੇ ਅਰਸ਼ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਕਾਂਸੇ ਦੇ ਤਗ਼ਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ। ਸੈਬਰ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੁਰਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਟੀਮ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਸੋਨ ਤਮਗੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ। ਤਰਸ਼ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਇਕ ਸੋਨ ਤਗਮਾ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ। ਅਰਸ਼ਦੀਪ ਸਿੰਘ ਅਤੇ ਕਰਨਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਜੁਆਂਇੰਟ ਕਾਂਸੇ ਦੇ ਤਮਗੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੇ। 17 ਸਾਲ ਲੜਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਫੁਆਇਲ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਸਕੁੰਵਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਫੁਆਇਲ ਟੀਮ ਅਤੇ ਫੁਆਇਲ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਸੋਨ ਤਗਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ। 17 ਸਾਲ ਲੜਕੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਮਨਜੋਤ ਕੌਰ ਨੇ ਇੱਪੀ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਕ ਸੋਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਕ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਦੇ ਤਗਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ। ਸੈਬਰ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਲਕ ਨੇ ਸੋਨ ਤਗਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ। 14 ਸਾਲ ਲੜਕੀਆਂ ਫੁਆਇਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਹਿਕਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਨੇ ਦੋ ਤਗਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ। ਕਸਕ ਸਾਹੀ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਸੋਨ ਤੇ ਇਕ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਦਾ ਤਗਮਾ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ। ਇੱਪੀ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਹਿਕਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਨੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਸੋਨ ਅਤੇ ਕਸਕ ਸਾਹੀ ਨੇ ਦੋ ਚਾਂਦੀ ਦੇ ਤਗਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ। ਸੈਬਰ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੁਪਿੰਦਰ ਕੌਰ ਨੇ ਸੋਨ ਤਗਮਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤਾ। ਸਿਮਰਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਕੌਰ ਨੇ ਕਾਂਸੇ ਦਾ ਤਗਮਾ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ।ਪ੍ਰਿੰਸੀਪਲ ਐਸਐਸ ਬਰਾੜ ਨੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀਆਂ ਲਈ ਖਿਡਾਰੀਆਂ ਸਣੇ ਸਪੋਰਟਸ ਅਤੇ ਫਿਜੀਕਲ ਐਜੂਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਸਟਾਫ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਲਾਘਾ ਕੀਤੀ।ਅਰਸ਼ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਟੀਮ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਸੋਨ ਤਗਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ?","answer":"ਤਲਵਾਰਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਰਸ਼ਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ 19 ਸਾਲਾ ਲੜਕੇ ਦੇ ਫੁਆਇਲ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਟੀਮ ਅਤੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਮੁਕਾਬਲੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੋ ਸੋਨ ਤਗਮੇ ਜਿੱਤੇ।"},{"question":"Ahitsio izay diso fanoratra na diso tsipelina anatin'ity fehezanteny ity:\\"ny tena tsara aloha tonga maraina e, amin'izay tsy tratran'ny fitohanana no sady mba mahavita zavatra raha manam-pikasana amita zavatra ny maraina.\\"","answer":"Indro ilay fehezanteny rehefa voahitsy ny diso:\\"Ny tena tsara aloha dia ny tonga maraina e, amin'izay tsy tratry ny fitohanana, no sady mba mahavita zavatra raha manam-pikasana ny hamita zavatra ny maraina.\\""},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా పద్యం రాయండి:భూత వర్తమాన కాలాలు రెండూ కత్తికున్న రెండంచులు. నేను మాత్రం రెండింటిని సమంగా చూస్తాను అని ఇందలి భావం.","answer":"ఇవి రెండూ ఒక కత్తికిఅటూ ఇటూ రెండంచులు.నే మాత్రం రెండంచులుసాము చేయగలను లెండి!"},{"question":"Pazar Rize dolmuş kaç TL?","answer":"20 Temmuz 2022 - 9:31 'de eklendi ve 1.402 views kez görüntülendi. Rize'nin Pazar ilçesinde 20 Temmuz Çarşamba itibariyle yürürlüğe giren zamla birlikte Pazar'dan Rize'ye sivil dolmuş ücreti 25 TL'den 32 TL'ye , öğrenci ücreti ise 20 TL'den 25 TL oldu."},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke teks dalam Bahasa Indonesia.The cloud filled everybody's heart with joy. It moved on. All the children waved goodbye.Terjemahan:","answer":"Sang awan membuat setiap orang gembira. Waktunya untuk berpindah tempat. Anak-anak melambaikan tangannya."},{"question":"Shin batun me ake magana a wannan mai zuwa? \\"masanan lafiya sun kiyaye ranar cutar ciwon hakarkari ta duniya\\".(a) Lafiya(b) Afirka(c) Najeriya(d) Siyasa(e) Duniya","answer":"Jumlar : \\"masanan lafiya sun kiyaye ranar cutar ciwon hakarkari ta duniya\\" na batu ne a kan lafiya."},{"question":"Ipinlẹ Ogun ni Babatunde atọrẹ ti ji mọto, lasiko ti wọn fẹẹ ta a n’Ilọrin lọwọ tẹ wọn","answer":"Ọga ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Kwara, Bagega Lawal, ni awọn afurasi mẹfa ọtọọtọ lọwọ awọn tẹ laarin oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun yii, fun oniruuru ẹsun kaakiri ipinlẹ naa.Bagega sọrọ yii lasiko to n ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii. O ni ọkan lara wọn, Akinṣọla Babatunde, tawọn eeyan mọ si ‘Mr White’ ti wọn fẹsun kan pe o pe pati onihooho niluu Ilọrin.Akinṣọla to n gbe Ojule kẹrindinlogun, Opopona Achimugun, lagbegbe Flower Garden, niluu Ilọrin, ni ọlọpaa fẹsun kan pe oun atawọn ẹgbẹ rẹ kan maa ṣe pati, nibi tawọn obinrin yoo ti maa jo nihooho lawọn ile-ijo ati ibi igbafẹ lati da awọn eeyan laraya.O ṣalaye pe kete tawọn araalu ta awọn lolobo pe Mr White ṣe pati onihooho ni opopona Joab, lẹyin ile itaja Shoprite, n’Ilọrin lawọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ bẹrẹ iwadii tọwọ fi tẹ afurasi naa.Ọga ọlọpaa naa ni ohun ti afurasi ọhun atawọn ẹgbẹ rẹ to ti sa lọ ṣe naa ta ko ofin ati ilana Covid-19.O ni awọn ti n ṣakitiyan lati mu awọn to sa lọ naa, lẹyin eyi ni wọn yoo foju bale-ẹjọ.Bakan naa, ọwọ ti tẹ afurasi meji; Umaru Mohammed Tambaya ati Muhammed Tambaya Bell, ara awọn ajinigbe to ji awọn ọmọ ilẹ Turkey mẹrin gbe loṣu keje, ọdun 2019, labule Gbugbu, nijọba ibilẹ Edu, nipinlẹ Kwara.Bagega ni awọn afurasi ajinigbe tọwọ tẹ nigba tiṣẹlẹ naa ṣẹlẹ lo darukọ awọn mejeeji tawọn fi bẹrẹ si i tọpinpin wọn ko too di pe wọn ko si pampẹ.O nigba ti wọn gbero lati tun ji eeyan gbe lọwọ awọn tẹ wọn. O ṣalaye pe lasiko tawọn beere ọrọ lẹnu wọn, wọn jẹwọ pe loootọ lawọn wa lara awọn to ji awọn oyinbo ọmọ ilẹ Turkey gbe, wọn ni ọpọlọpọ awọn ijinigbe lawọn ti kopa nibẹ lọna Enugu si Abakaliki.Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa tun mu afurasi kan, Abbey Adeyẹye, ẹni ogoji ọdun, fẹsun jiji mọto gbe labule Gbugbu lọna Lafiagi.Wọn ni ẹnikan torukọ rẹ n jẹ Edwin Nwakanude lo fi to ọlọpaa leti lọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021, pe wọn ji ọkọ Golf 3 oun ti nọmba rẹ jẹ; PTG 01 XA, niwaju ile oun.Ọna Ndanaku si Isanlu, nipinlẹ Kogi, lọwọ ti tẹ ọkunrin naa pẹlu mọto ọhun. O jẹwọ pe ọkọ meji loun ti ji, toun si ti ta si Kogi.Awọn ọlọpaa tun mu afurasi meji; Sunday Babatunde ati Adebisi Ọlatunde, tawọn mejeeji n gbe agbegbe Ibafo, nipinlẹ Ogun, fẹsun jija mọto gba.Ọkọ Toyota Yaris kan ti nọmba rẹ jẹ; EPE 971 DY ni wọn ji gbe, ibi ti wọn ti fẹẹ ta a ni Ipata Ọlọjẹ, niluu Ilọrin, lọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ wọn.Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa naa sọ pe awọn afurasi naa jẹwọ pe ọwọ ẹnikan torukọ rẹ n jẹ Adekọya Ayọdele lawọn ti ja a gba lagbegbe Ejigun Agbẹdẹ lọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun yii, nipinlẹ Ogun."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది ప్రశ్నలకు జవాబులు రాయండిప్రశ్న : కింద ఇచ్చిన పదార్థాలలో ఏవి అయస్కాంత పదార్థాలో, ఏవి అనయస్కాంత పదార్థాలో ఊహించండి. తర్వాత ఒక దండాయస్కాంతంతో పరీక్షించి మీరు ఊహించిన వాటిని సరిచూసుకోండి. అన్ని పదార్థాలనూ పరిశీలించాక మీరేమి చెప్పగలరు? ప్లాస్టిక్, ఇనుము, సీలు (ఉక్కు, కర్ర అల్యూమినియం, బంగారం, వెండి, రాగి, కాగితం, గుడ్డ.","answer":"అయస్కాంత పదార్థాలు : అనయస్కాంత పదార్థాలుఇనుము, స్టీలు : ప్లాస్టిక్, కర్ర, కాగితం, గుడ్డ, బంగారం, వెండి, రాగి, అల్యూమినియం."},{"question":"ප්‍රාථමික වර්ණ නම් කරන්න?","answer":"රතු, කහ සහ නිල්"},{"question":"وجدت هذا السؤال: كم تبلغ اقصى درجة حرارة في الصيف في الاردن؟ في موقع ثقافي ، ماهي الإجابة؟","answer":"الإجابة على السؤال هي 115 ف."},{"question":"নিচের অনুচ্ছেদের বিষয় কি ?কলেজ যখন পুরোদমে কার্যক্রম চালিয়ে যাচ্ছে তখনই শুরু হয় স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধ। ১৯৭১ সালে কলেজের অধ্যক্ষ এবং এডজুটেন্ট দুজনই ছিলেন পাকিস্তানি। রাজশাহী ক্যাডেট কলেজে যেখানে এডজুটেন্টই যুদ্ধে যেতে ক্যাডেটদের উৎসাহিত করেছেন সেখানে মোমেনশাহীর অবস্থা ছিল সম্পূর্ণ বিপরীত। মেজর কাইউম ছিলেন এডজুটেন্ট। এই প্রতিকূলতা সত্ত্বেও বেশ কিছু ক্যাডেট যুদ্ধে অংশগ্রহণ করে। শহীদ খোরশেদ তারই উদাহরণ। এছাড়াও আরও কয়েকজন যুদ্ধে অংশ নেন এবং তাদের মধ্যে কয়েকজন আবার যুদ্ধ শেষে কলেজে ফিরে আসেন।","answer":"স্বাধীনতা যুদ্ধ |"},{"question":"Naon patarosan pikeun: \\"Super Bowl Super Bowl XLV dilaksanakeun di daérah Dallas-Fort Worth dina 6 Pébruari 2011, di Cowboys Stadium di Arlington, Texas, \\"? Topikna nyaéta Super Bowl XLV.","answer":"\\"Di mana jeung iraha Super Bowl XLV dilaksanakeun?\\""},{"question":"අවස්ථාව යන්නට සමාන පද කිහිපයක් කියනවද?","answer":"ඉඩ, අවකාශය"},{"question":"Indro  misy fanehoan-kevitra:\\"Olom-boaozona ireny sarim-bavy ireny.\\"Maneho endrika fanavakavahana na ahitana teny mety hanafintohina ve io fanehoan-kevitra io?","answer":"Maneho endrika fanavakavahana ny lehilahy manana toetram-behivavy ary mametraka azy ireo ho voaozona izay mety hanafintohina;"},{"question":"\\"සුවඳයි මල් සුවඳ සේ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"සුවඳයි මල් සුවඳ සේමිහිරියි මී පැණි වගේජීවත් වෙන්න ආසයිහැමදාම හිමිදිරිය සේමල් පියලි විසිරෙයි වනේරොන් සුවඳ සුළඟට දැනේනැහැ පුඩුව සිනිඳුයි ඒ සුවඳ පුරුදුයිමල් කැකුළු පූදින්න වාගේදිය කඩිති නිල් බර වුණේපොඩි තිත්ත පැටවුන්ටනේඅල්ලන්න ආසයි උන් එක්ක යාළුයිපීනන්න දිය කඩිති ගානේසමන්ත පෙරේරා, ඉන්දිකා උපමාලිලූෂන් බුලත්සිංහලප්‍රේමසිරි කේමදාස(ඇසළ කළුවර ටෙලි නාට්‍යය)"},{"question":"Menene amfani da Alamomi?","answer":"Amfani da alamomi tsohuwar, daɗaɗɗiyar hanyar sadarwa ce a wajen Bahaushe tun kafin gaurayuwarsa da kowace baƙuwar fuska.Ta wannan siga Bahaushe yana amfani da zane-zane, zanen suna, zanen fuska da kuma sana’ar fiƙe da sassaƙa wajen sadarwa."},{"question":"ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਬਿਪਾਸ਼ਾ ਬਾਸੂ ਨੂੰ ਬੀਤੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੇ ਸਮਾਰੋਹ ਵਿੱਚ ‘ਗੋਲਡਨ ਸਕਰੀਨ ਐਵਾਰਡ’ ਨਾਲ ਸਨਮਾਨਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਐਵਾਰਡ ਲੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਠੀਕ ਦਸ ਮਿੰਟ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮੀ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਹਾਸ਼ਮੀ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਨਾ ਕੇਵਲ ਗਾਲ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੀ ਕੱਢੀਆਂ ਸਨ ਸਗੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਜ਼ੋਰਦਾਰ ਥੱਪੜ ਵੀ ਮਾਰਿਆ ਸੀ। ਦਰਅਸਲ ਉਪਰੋਕਤ ਸਾਰਾ ਕੁਝ ਨਕਲੀ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਬਿਪਾਸ਼ਾ ਬਾਸੂ ਦੀ ਅਗਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਰਾਜ਼-3’ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੂਟਿੰਗ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਇੱਕ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਸੀ। ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਜ਼ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਭਰਾਵਾਂ ਮਹੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਅਤੇ ਮੁਕੇਸ਼ ਭੱਟ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਇੱਕ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਤਿਕੋਣ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਹਾਸ਼ਮੀ, ਬਿਪਾਸ਼ਾ ਬਾਸੂ ਅਤੇ ‘ਰਾਜ਼-2’ ਦੀ ਹੀਰੋਇਨ ਰਹਿ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਈਸ਼ਾ ਗੁਪਤਾ ਦੀਆਂ ਮੁੱਖ ਭੂਮਿਕਾਵਾਂ ਹਨ।ਤੇਜ਼ ’ਚ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਤੇ ਕੰਗਣਾ ਆਹਮੋ-ਸਾਹਮਣੇ  ਹਨ। ਰਤਨ ਜੈਨ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਨਾਲ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਰੈੱਡੀ ਦੇ ਸਿਤਾਰੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਨਗਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੇਜ਼ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਵਨਾ ਹੈ ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਕੁਝ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਮੋਟੀ ਹੋ ਰਹੀ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਦੀ ਪੁੱਛਗਿੱਛ ਕਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਤੇ ਮਲਿਆਲਮ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਵਧੇਰੇ ਹੈ। ਸਮੀਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਪਸੰਦ ਕਰੇ ਜਾਂ ਨਾ ਕਰੇ ਪਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਾ ਕਮਲ ਹਸਨ ਨੇ ਸੁੰਦਰਤਾ ਤੋਂ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਤਿਭਾ ਤਕ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਪਸੰਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਸਮੀਰਾ ਦਾ ਚਮਕ ਦਮਕ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਇੱਕ ਯਾਦਗਾਰੀ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਕਮਲ ਹਸਨ ਨੇ ਖਾਸ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਚਿਆ ਹੈ। ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਤਕ ਮੋਟੇ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਮੋਟਾਪੇ ਦੇ ਅੰਸ਼ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਰੈੱਡੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਖ਼ਾਨਦਾਨੀ ਹਨ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਦਾਦਕੇ-ਨਾਨਕੇ ਵੀ ਮੋਟਾਪੇ ਦੀ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਨਾਲ ਜੂਝਦੇ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਦੇ ਹਿਸਾਬ-ਕਿਤਾਬ ਦਾ ਮੋਟਾਪਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਸ ਆਇਆ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਕੰਨੜ ਤੇ ਤੇਲਗੂ/ਮਲਿਆਲਮ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਾਇਕਾ ਮੋਟੀ ਹੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਜੱਚਦੀ ਹੈ। ਗੱਲ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਦੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਕਰ ਲਈਏ ਤਾਂ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਅਜੈ ਦੇਵਗਨ, ਅਨਿਲ ਕਪੂਰ, ਮੋਹਨ ਲਾਲ ਤੇ ਜ਼ਾਇਦ ਖਾਨ ਜਿਹੇ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਸਿਤਾਰੇ ਹਨ।ਵੱਡੀ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਗਨਾ ਰਾਣਾਵਤ ਤੇ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਰੈੱਡੀ ਦੀ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਹੈ। ਸਮੀਰਾ ਵਿਅਕਤੀਗਤ ਤੌਰ ’ਤੇ ਪਤਲੀ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਪ੍ਰਿਆ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਨੇ ਅਗਲੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਾਅਦੇ ਉਸ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤੇ ਹਨ। ਤਦ ਤਕ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਕਸਰਤ ਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਕਰਕੇ ਜਿਸਮ ਨੂੰ ਥੋੜ੍ਹਾ ਲਚਕੀਲਾ ਬਣਾਏਗੀ। ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਅਤਿਵਾਦ ਦੇ ਵਿਸ਼ੇ ਉਪਰ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੰਡਨ ਤੋਂ ਪੈਰਿਸ ਤਕ ਦੀਆਂ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ ਲੋਕੇਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਹਨ। ਸਮੀਰਾ ਵੀ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਮਨ ਚੈਨ ਰਹੇ। ਪ੍ਰਿਆ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਨੇ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਨਵੇਂ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਤੇ ਮਨੋਰੰਜਨ ਦਾ ਵਧੀਆ ਸੁਮੇਲ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਸਮੀਰਾ ਨੂੰ ਅਜੈ ਦੇਵਗਨ ਜਿਹੇ ਸਟਾਰ ਨਾਇਕ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਜਾਣੀ ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਦਾ ਸੰਕੇਤ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜੇ ਪੀਜ਼ਾ, ਕੋਕ ਤੇ ਪੈਟੀ ਆਦਿ ਖਾਣੀ ਸਮੀਰਾ ਛੱਡ ਦੇਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਅੱਜ ਵੀ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਕ ਨਾਇਕਾਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਚੋਟੀ ’ਤੇ ਸ਼ੁਮਾਰ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ।ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਬੇਂਦਰੇ ਦੇ ਵਧਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕ ਐਨੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਬੇਂਦਰੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਨੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਿੰਨੀ ਛੋਟੇ ਪਰਦੇ ਨੇ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ। ਅੱਜ ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਚਹੇਤਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਘਾਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਆਕਰਸ਼ਕ ਤੇ ਦਿਲ ਖਿੱਚਵੀਂ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਨਾਲ ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਨੇ ਵੱਡੀਆਂ-ਵੱਡੀਆਂ ਕੰਪਨੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦ ਵੀ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰੀ ਲਈ ਆਪਣੇ ਕੋਲ ਖਿੱਚ ਲਏ ਹਨ। ਹੈਦਰਾਬਾਦ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਗਹਿਣਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਦੁਕਾਨ ’ਤੇ ਅਕਸਰ ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਦਾ ਆਉਣਾ ਜਾਣਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੁਕਾਨ ਦੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਦੁਕਾਨ ਦੇ ਮਹੂਰਤ ’ਤੇ ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੱਦਿਆ। ਇੱਕ ਮਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਥਿਤ ਇਸ ਦੁਕਾਨ ਦੇ ਉਦਘਾਟਨ ਸਮੇਂ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਭੀੜ ਇਕੱਠੀ ਹੋ ਗਈ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕ ਸੋਨਾਲੀ-ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਅਰੇ ਲਾਉਣ ਲੱਗੇ। ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਭੀੜ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਖ਼ੂਬ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ ਹੋਈ ਪਰ ਘਬਰਾ ਗਈ। ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਦੋ ਦਰਜਨ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਕਰਮਚਾਰੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਬੇਕਾਬੂ ਭੀੜ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਦੁਕਾਨ ਮਾਲਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਐਨੇ ਹੀ ਹੋਰ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਕਰਮਚਾਰੀ ਬੁਲਾਏ। ਸੋਨਾਲੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਅਥਾਹ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਨਵੀਂ ਊਰਜਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਵਾਪਸ ਪਰਤੀ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਮੁਖ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਕੀ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਤੇਜ਼’ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਮੁਖ ਵਿਸ਼ਾ ਅਤਿਵਾਦ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਅਨੂਪ ਪਦਾਰਥੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਸੁਨਹੁ ਸਗਲ ਧਿਆਇਲੇ ਮੀਤਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਅਉਖਧੁ ਜਾ ਕਉ ਗੁਰਿ ਦੀਆ ਤਾ ਕੇ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਚੀਤਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਅੰਧਕਾਰੁ ਮਿਟਿਓ ਤਿਹ ਤਨ ਤੇ ਗੁਰਿ ਸਬਦਿ ਦੀਪਕੁ ਪਰਗਾਸਾ ॥ਭ੍ਰਮ ਕੀ ਜਾਲੀ ਤਾ ਕੀ ਕਾਟੀ ਜਾ ਕਉ ਸਾਧਸੰਗਤਿ ਬਿਸ੍ਵਾਸਾ ॥੧॥ਤਾਰੀਲੇ ਭਵਜਲੁ ਤਾਰੂ ਬਿਖੜਾ ਬੋਹਿਥ ਸਾਧੂ ਸੰਗਾ ॥ਪੂਰਨ ਹੋਈ ਮਨ ਕੀ ਆਸਾ ਗੁਰੁ ਭੇਟਿਓ ਹਰਿ ਰੰਗਾ ॥੨॥ਨਾਮ ਖਜਾਨਾ ਭਗਤੀ ਪਾਇਆ ਮਨ ਤਨ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਿ ਅਘਾਏ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਤਾ ਕਉ ਦੇਵੈ ਜਾ ਕਉ ਹੁਕਮੁ ਮਨਾਏ ॥੩॥੧੨॥੧੩੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 208 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮਿੱਤਰੋ! ਸੁਣੋ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਇਕ ਐਸਾ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਰਗਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ । (ਇਸ ਵਾਸਤੇ, ਹੇ ਮਿੱਤਰੋ!) ਸਾਰੇ (ਇਸ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ) ਸਿਮਰੋ । ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਦਾਰੂ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਚਿੱਤ (ਹਰੇਕ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਰ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਤੋਂ ਸਾਫ਼ ਹੋ ਗਏ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ (ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਪਣੇ) ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਆਤਮਕ ਗਿਆਨ ਦਾ) ਦੀਵਾ ਜਗਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚੋਂ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਦਾ) ਹਨੇਰਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਸਾਧ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਸਰਧਾ ਬਣ ਗਈ, (ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ) ਉਸ (ਦੇ ਮਨ) ਦਾ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ) ਭਟਕਣਾ ਦਾ ਜਾਲ ਕੱਟ ਦਿੱਤਾ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ-ਰੂਪ ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲਿਆ, ਉਹ ਇਸ ਅਥਾਹ ਤੇ ਔਖੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਗਿਆ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲ ਪਿਆ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਦੀ (ਹਰੇਕ) ਕਾਮਨਾ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੋ ਗਈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ) ਭਗਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਨ (ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤ ਹੋ ਗਏ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਤਨ (ਹਿਰਦੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜ ਗਏ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਮੰਨਣ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਨਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।੧੨।੧੩੩।\\""},{"question":"இந்தியாவின் தேசியக் கொடியில் உள்ள மூன்று நிறங்களின் அர்த்தம் என்ன?(அ) பச்சை: வளர்ச்சி, வெள்ளை: அமைதி, மஞ்சள்: தைரியம்(ஆ) பச்சை: இஸ்லாம், வெள்ளை: கிறிஸ்தவம், மஞ்சள்: இந்து மதம்(இ) பச்சை: வளர்ச்சி, வெள்ளை: சுதந்திரம், மஞ்சள்: சகோதரத்துவம்(ஈ) பச்சை: இஸ்லாம், வெள்ளை: கிறிஸ்தவம், மஞ்சள்: பௌத்தம்","answer":"பதில்: (அ) பச்சை: வளர்ச்சி, வெள்ளை: அமைதி, மஞ்சள்: தைரியம்"},{"question":"विशेष गरी मल्टिप्लेक्स र डिजिटल प्लेटफर्मको उदयसँगै नेपालमा चलचित्र वितरण च्यानलहरूको विकासबारे छलफल गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेपालमा चलचित्र वितरण च्यानलहरूको विकासले मल्टिप्लेक्स र डिजिटल प्लेटफर्महरूको उदय देखेको छ। मल्टिप्लेक्सहरूले आधुनिक सिनेमाई अनुभव प्रदान गर्दछ, जबकि डिजिटल प्लेटफर्महरूले दर्शकहरूलाई नेपाली चलचित्रहरूसँग संलग्न हुनको लागि सुविधाजनक र पहुँचयोग्य तरिका प्रदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਦੀ ਉਤਪੱਤੀ ਦੇ ਕੋਈ ਦੋ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਇਕ ਵਿਆਹੀ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ਅਤੇ ਪਿੱਤਰ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਸਿਧਾਂਤ ।"},{"question":"كم خلية عصبية يحتويها مخ الإنسان ؟","answer":"13 مليار خلية"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini? Apa yang berkaki lapan tetapi tiada tangan, bermata dua dan perut dipenuhi sarang.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah labah-labah"},{"question":"¿Quién es la segunda esposa de Enrique VIII?","answer":"La segunda esposa de Enrique VIII de Inglaterra fue Ana Bolena. Se casaron en enero de 1533, y su matrimonio tuvo un impacto significativo en la historia, ya que llevó a Enrique a romper con la Iglesia católica y establecer la Iglesia de Inglaterra. Ana Bolena fue coronada como reina consorte de Inglaterra, pero su reinado fue breve y tumultuoso, terminando con su ejecución en mayo de 1536."},{"question":"අන්නාසි වගාවේ රෝපණ ද්‍රව්‍ය නම් කරන්න.","answer":"අන්නාසි වගාවේ රෝපණ ද්‍රව්‍ය ලෙස විවිධාකාරයේ මොරෙය්යන් වර්ග භාවිතාකළ හැකිය. ඒවා පහත දැක්වේ.කරඬුව = ගෙඩිය මුදුනේ ඇති කොටසනටුමොරෙයියන් = ගෙඩියේ නටුවෙන් මතුවන මොරෙයියන්අක්ෂිමොරෙයියන් = පත්‍ර අතරින් මතුවන මොරෙයියන්මුල්මොරෙයියන් = කඳ පාමුළින් මතුවන මොරෙයියන්"},{"question":"ข้อความนี้เกี่ยวกับเหตุการณ์สำคัญอะไร: ตลอด ปีที่ผ่านมา สถาบันศิลปะและวิชาการทางภาพยนตร์ได้มอบรางวัลออสการ์ สาขานักแสดงสมทบชายยอดเยี่ยม ให้แก่นักแสดงชายทั้งหมด 75 คน ซึ่งทุกคนได้รับรูปปั้นรางวัลออสการ์รูปแบบเดียวกัน นักแสดงชายคนแรกที่ได้รับรางวัลนี้คือ วอลเทอร์ เบรนแนน ในงานประกาศผลรางวัลออสการ์ ครั้งที่ 9 (ปีค.ศ. 1936) จากภาพยนตร์เรื่อง \\"Come and Get It\\" และ \\"The Way of All Flesh\\" ส่วนนักแสดงชายที่ได้รับรางวัลนี้คนล่าสุดคือ แดเนียล คาลูยา ในงานประกาศผลรางวัลออสการ์ ครั้งที่ 93 ประจำปีค.ศ. 2021 จากภาพยนตร์เรื่อง \\"Judas and the Black Messiah\\"","answer":"งานประกาศผลรางวัลออสการ์ "},{"question":"uZintle ulangazelela impumelelo.","answer":"Zintle desires for success. "},{"question":"What does a traditional Burmese meal include?","answer":"A traditional Burmese meal may include steamed white rice as the main dish accompanied by Burmese curries, a light soup, and other side dishes, which can consist on fried vegetables, Burmese fritters, and ngapi yay gyo, a plate of fresh and blanched vegetables served with pickled fish dip."},{"question":"మ అక్షరంతో మొదలయ్యే పదాలు మరియు వాటి అర్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి","answer":"మందకొడి = సోమరి, జడుడు, చురుకుగా సాగకపోవడంమంద్రం = గంభీరధ్వనిమచ్చెకంటి = మీనాక్షి, చేపలవంటి కన్నులు గల స్త్రీమతిహీనులు = తెలివిలేనివాళ్ళుమదీయ = నా సంబంధమైనమననం = చింతనమనోహరం = ఇంపైనమహాప్రస్థానం = దీర్ఘప్రయాణం, లోకాంతర యాత్ర, మరణంమాధుకరభిక్ష = ఇల్లిల్లూ తిరిగి అన్నం సేకరించు కోడంమిక్కుటం = ఎక్కువమీలనము = కళ్ళు మూయడంముక్కంటి = మూడు కనులు కలవాడు (శివుడు)ములుగర్ర = ఎడ్లను తోలడానికి వాడే ములుకోలుములుకి = మొనదేలిన భాగంమూర్ధం = ఉన్నతమైనదిమెండు = అధికం, ఎక్కువమోడు = ఆకురాలిన వృక్షంమోహం = అజ్ఞానంమోక్షలక్ష్మి = మోక్షమనే లక్ష్మి (ముక్తి)మౌళి = సిగ"},{"question":"Qui était l'artiste Diego Rivera ?","answer":"Diego Rivera, un muraliste mexicain, est célèbre pour ses fresques monumentales qui dépeignent l'histoire, les problèmes sociaux et la culture indigène du Mexique. Ses peintures murales, comme celles du Palais national de Mexico, traduisent son engagement à transmettre des récits puissants à travers l'art public."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"பெண்களுக்குக் குத்துச் சண்டை முதற்கொண்டு சொல்லிக் கொடுத்து ஆண்களைப் போலவே வளர்க்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"ਲਾਹੌਰ, 3 ਮਾਰਚਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ’ਚ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰ ਦੇ ਆਗੂ ਅਤੇ ਪੀਐੱਮਐੱਲ-ਐੱਨ ਮੁਖੀ ਸ਼ਾਹਬਾਜ਼ ਸ਼ਰੀਫ ਨੇ ਬੀਤੇ ਦਿਨ ਆਪਣੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਭਰਾ ਤੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਵਾਜ਼ ਸ਼ਰੀਫ਼ ਨਾਲ ਇੱਥੇ ਕੋਟ ਲੱਖਪਤ ਜੇਲ੍ਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਮੌਜੂਦਾ ਹਾਲਾਤ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣੂ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ। ਮੀਡੀਆ ਰਿਪੋਰਟ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਇਸ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਦਾ ਮਕਸਦ ਨਵਾਜ਼ ਸ਼ਰੀਫ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਵਧੀ ਤਲਖੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣੂ ਕਰਵਾਉਣਾ ਸੀ। ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਸ਼ਰੀਫ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿਰੁਧ ਅਦਾਲਤੀ ਕੇਸਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਵੀ ਚਰਚਾ ਹੋਈ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਾਹਬਾਜ਼ ਨੇ ਨਵਾਜ਼ ਦੀ ਸਿਹਤ ਬਾਰੇ ਵੀ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ।ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਦਾ ਮਕਸਦ ਕੀ ਸੀ?","answer":"ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਦਾ ਮਕਸਦ ਨਵਾਜ਼ ਸ਼ਰੀਫ਼ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਵਧਦੇ ਤਣਾਅ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਦੇਣਾ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Inona ireo vokatra ateraky ny famadihana ?","answer":"Misy karazany roa ny vokatra ateraky ny famadihana.Ny vokatra tsara :-Fitazonana ny fomban-drazana-Fanamafisana ny fihavanana sy ny firaisankina-Fifankahalalan’ny mpianakavy-Ny fiezahana hitady vola-Mahavita adidy amin’ny razana-Fikarakarana ny tanin-drazana (trano, tany, fasana …)-Miteraka fialam-boly ho an’ny fokonolona mpiray tanindrazanaNy vokatra ratsy:-Mandany vola-Mandany fotoana-Mety hampiady ny fianakaviana ny fanantanterahana azy-Mety hanimba fahasalamana-Mety hisy ady noho ny hamamoana-Mampitamberina ny alahelo-Mampisara-bazana ny te hamadika sy ny tsy te hamadika"},{"question":"Ijọba ni kawọn ọga ati olukọ awọn ileewe to n fa wahala hijaabu pada sẹnu iṣẹ kiakia","answer":"Lẹyin rogbodiyan to bẹ silẹ laarin awọn ẹlẹsin Kristẹni atawọn Musulumi lori ọrọ lilo hijaabu lawọn ileewe tawọn ọmọlẹyin Kristi da silẹ, eyi to mu ki awọn ileewe mẹwaa kan di titi pa, ijọba ipinlẹ Kwara ti paṣẹ fun awọn ọga ati olukọ awọn ileewe naa lati pada sẹnu iṣẹ wọn bẹrẹ lati ọjọ kọkandinlogun, oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii.Alaga ajọ to n mojuto eto ẹkọ nipinlẹ Kwara, Teaching Service Commission, TESCOM, Mallam Bello Tahueed Abubakar, lo paṣẹ naa l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, ninu atẹjade kan ti akọwe iroyin rẹ, Amọgbọnjaye Peter, fi sọwọ sawọn oniroyin.Abubakar ni o ṣe pataki fun awọn olukọ naa lati pada sẹnu iṣẹ ki wọn le ṣeto imurasilẹ fun idanwo aṣekagba fawọn akẹkọọ to n mura WAEC.O ṣekilọ pe olukọ tabi oṣiṣẹ to ba kọ lati wa sẹnu iṣẹ lọla (Furaidee) yoo da ara rẹ lẹbi.Bakan naa lo ṣekilọ fawọn tọrọ kan lati ma fa wahala kankan nitori pe ipade alaafia pẹlu ijọba ṣi n tẹsiwaju."},{"question":"BMC Euro 6 kaç beygir?","answer":"* 6,7 litrelik 320 BG Euro 6 motor."},{"question":"Meme kanserinde kemoterapi ne zaman başlar?","answer":"Amaç, vücudun başka yerlerine gitmiş olma olasılığı olan kanser hücrelerinin yok edilmesi. Adjuvant kemoterapiye, ameliyatınızdan sonra en kısa zamanda başlamanız gerekiyor. Eğer bir engel yoksa, ameliyat tarihinden itibaren, yaklaşık 3-6 hafta sonra başlayabilirsiniz."},{"question":"*من هو مخرج ثلاثية الكاتب نجيب محفوظ ؟","answer":"حسن الإمام"},{"question":"Wayengathethi manga okaNdabaNgesikhathi ethi ziyofa izinsizwa kusale izibongo.Kula mathafa ezwe lethu kwake kwaphila izinsizwa,Ezazigijima mzila munye nezinyoka ezibulalayo,Zibhukuda mfula munye nezingwenya ezibulalayo.Zibanga amaqele namabhubesi abulalayo,Zidwanguza amahlathi nezigwe ezibulalayo.Ekuhambeni kwami nginqamula izwe lakithi,Ngibona inhlaba imile ngezinyawo ihlobile,Namatshe elele ngezisu elanda ezasendulo,Notshani kukhwele ngezidindi kukhinindelana ezasendulo,Kuyaye kube sengathi ngamehlo ami,Ngibona amaqhawe akithi evunule ngamabheshu,Ezandleni ebambe amahawu amaqhabanga namaklwa,Ezinyaweni embethe ukushesha okungathi okombani,Esho ingoma yempi esenukelwa yigazi,Edinwe evevezela okweminyovu ngokudlokodlwa ehlweni.Ngiwabona ethi shalushalu,Egane unwabu, ngifung', uNonhlanhla kababa,Elwa engakhokhi moya noma seyaphela impi,Elwa ngemimoya ekhathazekile ngoba engagezwanga,Futhi kungekho namunye owathi shwele.1. Tomula imigqa EMIBILI enokuxhumana esitanzeni soku-1 beseusho ukuthi hlobo luni lokuxhumana.","answer":"Ezazigijima mzila munye nezinyoka ezibulalayo,Zibhukuda mfula munye nezingwenya ezibulalayo,√Ukuxhumana sigcino/ okusekugcineni.√ NOMAZibanga amaqele namabhubesi abulalayo,Zidwanguza amahlathi nezingwe ezibulalayo.√Ukuxhumana sigcino/ okusekugcineni.√ NOMAEzazigijima mzila munye nezinyoka ezibulalayo,Zibhukuda mfula munye nezingwenya ezibulalayo,√Ukuxhumana maphakathi / okuphakathi. .√"},{"question":"මිනිසුන් වෙරළ තීරය භුක්ති විඳින්නේ ඇයි?","answer":"බොහෝ අය නිවාඩුවක් ගත කිරීමට හෝ වෙරළට දිවා චාරිකා කිරීමට කැමතියි. වෙරළ ගමනාන්ත සාමාන්යයෙන් උණුසුම්, හිරු කාලගුණය සහ සුන්දර දර්ශන ලබා දෙයි. ඔබ විවේක ගැනීමට හෝ ක්‍රියාශීලී වීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන ඕනෑම අයෙකුට වෙරළ තීරය කුඩා දෙයක් ලබා දෙයි. විවේක ගැනීමට බලාපොරොත්තු වන අයට කියවීමට හෝ හිරු එළියේ වැතිරීමට ප්‍රිය කළ හැකිය. ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සොයන අයට පිහිනීම, රළ පැදීම, ස්නෝකර්ලිං හෝ බීච් වොලිබෝල් ක්‍රීඩා කිරීම ප්‍රිය කළ හැකිය."},{"question":"ما هي لغة الجملة الأتية:\\"C'est la vie\\"","answer":"الجملة \\"C'est la vie\\" مكتوبة بالفرنسية."},{"question":"కింది వాక్యముని ఆధునిక వ్యవహార శైలిలోకి మార్చండి. (ఈ మార్పులు చేసేటప్పుడు “ము” వర్ణాలు, బిందు పూర్వక ‘బు’ కారాలు, అంబు) యడాగమాలు, క్రియా స్వరూపాలు (చేయును, జరుగును, చూడుము వంటివి మారతాయి. గమనించండి.)వివేక హీనుడయిన ప్రభువును సేవించుట కంటె వనవాస ముత్తమము.","answer":"వివేకం లేని రాజసేవ చేయడం కన్న, అడవిలో ఉండడం మంచిది."},{"question":"\\"Ny tsy fahampian'ny fotoana hikatsahana ny filàna manokana sy ny tombontsoany dia mamela ahy hahatsapa tsy feno sy tsy mifandray amin'ny tenako.\\" inona ny fihetseham-po tamin'ny fanambarana teo aloha?","answer":"Ny andian-teny dia miteraka fihetseham-po ratsy, mamaritra ny fihenan'ny fihetseham-po sy ny tsy fahatomombanana noho ny fotoana voafetra ho an'ny tombontsoan'ny tena manokana."},{"question":"Milaza fitaovana ampiasaina amin'ny ala volon-jaza?","answer":"Ireo fitaovana ampiasaina amin'ny ala volon-jaza dia :-Fary raiki-bololona.-Akondro velon-dreny. -Sahafa vita amin'ny hazo famelona.-Vary masaka Trafon-kena,-Saonjo masaka.-Tantely.-Hety."},{"question":"පකිස්ථානයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"පකිස්ථානයේ අගනුවර ඉස්ලාමාබාද් වේ. "},{"question":"السؤال: من فتح القسطنطينية ؟","answer":"الإجابة: محمد الفاتح"},{"question":"ما هي الألوان التي ذكرت في سوره البقرة ؟.\\t","answer":"الأصفر –الأبيض- الأسود."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai.  Jangan mudah terpedaya dengan ayat-ayat manis pemuda yang __ itu. Pilihan:  A) lidah bercabang B) pisau cukur C) curi tulang D) mati kutu","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A) lidah bercabang. \\"Lidah bercabang\\" bermaksud percakapan yang tidak boleh dipercayai kerana selalu berubah-ubah."},{"question":"من النبي الذي طلب منه قومه أن ينزل لهم مائدة من السماء ؟","answer":"الإجابة: عيسى عليه السلام"},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 ミャンマーの選挙管理委員会は、アウン・サン・スー・チーさんの政党を29日になくすと発表しました。ミャンマーでは2020年の選挙で、民主的な考えを持つスー・チーさんの政党が勝ちました。しかし2021年2月、軍がクーデターを起こしました。スー・チーさんやこの政党の多くの人は、軍に捕まったり外国に逃げたりしています。スー・チーさんの政党は、次の選挙に出ることができる人が、軍が法律で決めた数に足りません。選挙管理委員会は、このため政党をなくすと言っています。ミャンマーでは、民主的な考えの人たちが軍に反対して、今も戦っています。軍は「公正な選挙をする」と言っていますが、軍に反対するスー・チーさんの政党は選挙に出ることができなくなりました。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- 政党: 1）政治について、同じ考えを持つ人たちが集まって作った団体。- 発表: 1）多くの人に広く知らせること。- 選挙: 1）ある役目につく人を、大勢の中から投票などで選ぶこと。- 民主的: 1）大勢の人の考えを、だいじにするようす。- 考え: 1）考えること。また、考えた内容。- 軍: 1）兵隊。兵隊の集まり。2）いくさ。戦争。- クーデター: 1）武力などによって政府をたおし、政権をうばい取ること。- 起こし: 1）（横になっていたものを）立たせる。2）目を覚まさせる。3）（何かを）始める。4）生じさせる。5）ほりかえす。- 捕まっ: 1）とらえられる。つかまえられる。- 数: 1）一つ、二つ、三つなどと数えた物の数量。すう。2）いくつもあること。たくさん。3）数え上げる値打ちのあるもの。仲間。- 戦っ: 1）戦争をする。2）技を比べて、勝ち負けを決める。- 公正: 1）どちらにもかたよらないで、公平で正しいようす。"},{"question":"Wo kann ich Bafög beantragen?","answer":"Die offizielle Webseite für Bafög ist https://bafög.de. Dort finden sich alle nötigen Antragsformulare."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકનુ એક લેખન નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે. આ લેખનનું તમારી ભાષામાં અર્થઘટન કરો અને આ લેખ પર તમારા શુ વિચારો છે એ જણાવો.“રાયચંદભાઈ ! જરા છોટુને નજરવગો રાખજો. કાલે ઓલ્યા પાડોશીના કોળીના છોકરા સાથે ભૂંડું બોલતો હતો ને કાદવ ચૂંથતો હતો.”⁠“રઘુભાઈ, આ તમે શું બોલ્યા ? છોટુ કોળીના કાના સાથે રમતો જ નથી. ને એવી ટેવ તો એને છે જ નહિ. છોટુ ભૂંડું બોલે જ નહિ ને !”","answer":"આ મા અને બાપ છોટુ તરફ એટલાં પક્ષપાતી છે કે છોટુમાં દોષ હોવાનું વિચારી જ શકતાં નથી; છોટુમાં તેઓ આંધળાં છે. પણ ખરી વાત એ છે કે મેં મારી સગી આંખે એને ઉપરનું બધું કરતાં ભાળ્યો છે. એનાં માબાપ નથી ઓળખતાં પણ હું એને ઓળખું છું. મારો વિચાર છે કે એનાં માબાપને છોટુ વિષે સમજાવીને કહું. જો માને તો ઠીક છે, નહિતર છોટુ જાણે ને એનાં માબાપ જાણે. એટલું ખરું કે એમાં છોટુનું તો બગડશે જ."},{"question":"kuthetha ntoni ukubukuca ngesixhosa.","answer":"kuthetha ukucinezela"},{"question":"గుడ్లగూబను చూసి భయపడిన ఎలుక తన మనసులో ఏమనుకొంది?","answer":"చంద్రకుడు అనే గుడ్లగూబను తన సమీపంలో చూసి, ఎలుక చాలా భయపడింది. తనకు దాని చేతిలో మరణం తప్పదనుకొంది. ఏం చేయాలో తెలియక మనసులో దేవుడిని తలచుకొని ఏడ్చింది. రోమశుడు వలలో పడినందుకు ఆనందపడడం తప్పని తెలుసుకొని బాధపడింది. ఐనా తెలివైన వారికి ప్రమాదం ఎదురైతే ఏడవరు. భయపడరు. ధైర్యం తెచ్చుకొంటారనుకొని తనకు తాను ధైర్యం చెప్పుకొంది. ఒకే చోట నివసిస్తున్నాం కనుక రోమశుని ప్రార్థించి ప్రాణాలు నిలబెట్టుకోవాలని నిర్ణయించుకొంది. రోమశుని దగ్గరకు వెళ్లింది."},{"question":"Inona no planeta antsoina matetika hoe \\"Planeta Mena\\"?a) Venusb) Marsc) Jupiter","answer":"Safidy 2 - Matetika no antsoina hoe \\"Planeta Mena\\" i Mars."},{"question":"What is the correct answer to this question: Qual filme da série Duro de Matar arrecadou menos dinheiro no mundo inteiro?","answer":"A resposta correcta e \\"Die Hard.\\""},{"question":"Title: ఐఎంఎఫ్ ప్రధాన ఆర్థికవేత్తగా నియమితులైన గీతా గోపీనాథ్nGiven the above title of an imaginary article, imagine the article.n","answer":"గీతా గోపీనాథ్ఈ విషయాన్ని ఐఎంఎఫ్ ట్విటర్ ద్వారా వెల్లడించింది. ఆమె మౌరీ ఓస్వాల్డ్ స్థానంలో బాధ్యతలు చేపడతారు. మౌరీ ఈ ఏడాది చివరిలో రిటైర్ కాబోతున్నారు. కేరళలో జన్మించిన గీత ప్రస్తుతం హార్వర్డ్ యూనివర్సిటీలోని ఇంటర్నేషనల్ స్టడీస్ అండ్ ఎకనమిక్స్‌లో ప్రొఫెసర్‌గా పని చేస్తున్నారు. ఆమె ఇంటర్నేషనల్ ఫైనాన్స్, మాక్రోఎకనామిక్స్‌లో పరిశోధన చేశారు.  ప్రధాన ఆర్థికవేత్త పదవిని చేపట్టబోతున్న మొదటి మహిళ కూడా ఆమే. పోస్ట్ of Twitter ముగిసింది, 1గీతా గోపీనాథ్ నియామకం గురించి వెల్లడిస్తూ ఐఎంఎఫ్ చీఫ్ క్రిస్టీన్ లగార్డే.. ''ప్రపంచంలోని ప్రముఖ ఆర్థికవేత్తలలో గీతా ఒకరు. ఆమె పాండిత్యం, మేధస్సు సాటిలేనివి. ఆర్థికశాస్త్రంలో ఆమెకు విస్తృతమైన అంతర్జాతీయ అనుభవం ఉంది'' అని తెలిపారు. ఐఎంఎఫ్‌లోని ఈ పదవిలో నియుక్తులైన రెండో భారతీయురాలు గీత. ఆమెకు ముందు భారత రిజర్వ్ బ్యాంక్ మాజీ గవర్నర్ రఘురామ్ రాజన్ కూడా ఐఎంఎఫ్ ప్రధాన ఆర్థికవేత్తగా పని చేశారు. గత ఏడాది కేరళ ప్రభుత్వం గీతా గోపీనాథ్‌ను తమ రాష్ట్ర ఆర్థిక సలహాదారుగా నియమించుకుంది. కేరళ సీఎం పినరయి విజయన్ ఆమెను సలహాదారుగా నియమించినపుడు ఆయన పార్టీకి చెందిన వారే కొందరు దీనిపై ఆగ్రహం వ్యక్తం చేశారు. దిల్లీ నుంచి గ్రాడ్యుయేషన్ గీత గ్రాడ్యుయేషన్ వరకు భారతదేశంలోనే చదువుకున్నారు. ఆమె 1992లో దిల్లీ యూనివర్సిటీకి చెందిన లేడీ శ్రీరామ్ కాలేజీ నుంచి ఎకనామిక్స్‌లో హానర్స్ డిగ్రీ పూర్తి చేశారు. ఆ తర్వాత దిల్లీ స్కూల్ ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్స్‌లో మాస్టర్స్ డిగ్రీ పూర్తి చేసి, 1994లో వాషింగ్టన్‌కు వెళ్లారు. 1996 నుంచి 2001 వరకు ప్రిన్స్‌టన్ యూనివర్సిటీ నుంచి ఆర్థికశాస్త్రంలో పీహెచ్‌డీ పూర్తి చేశారు. ఆ తర్వాత 2001 నుంచి 2005 వరకు చికాగో యూనివర్సిటీలో అసిస్టెంట్ ఫ్రొఫెసర్‌గా పని చేశారు. 2005లో ఆమె హార్వర్డ్ యూనివర్సిటీలో అసిస్టెంట్ ప్రొఫెసర్‌గా నియమితులయ్యారు. 2010లో ఆమె అదే యూనివర్సిటీలో ప్రొఫెసర్‌గా పదోన్నతి పొందారు. 2015 నుంచి ఇంటర్నేషనల్ స్టడీస్ అండ్ ఎకనమిక్స్‌లో ప్రొఫెసర్‌గా బాధ్యతలు నిర్వర్తిస్తున్నారు. గీతా గోపీనాథ్ అమెరికన్ ఎకనామిక్ రివ్యూ పత్రికకు సహ సంపాదకురాలిగా ఉన్నారు. ఆమె నేషనల్ బ్యూరో ఆఫ్ ఎకనామిక్ రీసెర్చ్‌లో ఇంటర్నేషనల్ ఫైనాన్స్ అండ్ మాక్రోఎకనమిక్స్ ప్రోగ్రామ్ కోడైరెక్టర్‌గా కూడా బాధ్యతలు వహి0చారు. "},{"question":"Ayat 1: Masalah ini dinyatakan dalam bentuk matriks seperti yang ditulis di bawah: Ayat 2: Masalah diberikan dalam bentuk matriks seperti yang ditulis di bawah: Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama?","answer":"Ya."},{"question":"Tóm tắt đoạn văn bản sau: Tất cả ba người phát ngôn giáo dục của các đảng chính đều tiết lộ rằng họ không có vấn đề gì nếu Bộ trưởng Giáo dục tiếp theo gửi con cái của họ đến trường tư nhân. Sự bùng nổ của sự trung thực giữa các chính trị gia đã xảy ra khi người dẫn chương trình Chính trị hàng ngày của BBC Andrew Neil, hỏi liệu nó có thể được chấp nhận cho một bộ trưởng giáo dục gửi con cái của họ đến một trường tư nhân không. Tristram Hunt, thư ký giáo dục của Đảng Lao động trả lời đầu tiên và nói: \\"Vâng. Trong một số trường hợp\\". Ông cũng xác nhận đảng Lao động có thể sa thải hàng ngàn giáo viên \\"không đủ tiêu chuẩn\\" trên toàn bộ khu vực nhà nước. Tất cả ba phát ngôn viên giáo dục chính của các đảng - được chụp trên chương trình Chính trị hàng ngày của BBC hôm nay - tiết lộ họ sẽ không có vấn đề gì với Bộ trưởng Giáo dục tiếp theo nếu ông gửi con cái của họ đến trường tư nhân. Hai trong số ba đứa con của ông đến một trường tiểu học nhà nước ở phía bắc London, với đứa con thứ ba dự kiến sẽ đến cùng một trường. Nhưng ông ấy không loại trừ việc chuyển chúng sang các trường tư thục. Ngược lại, nhà lãnh đạo Lao động Ed Miliband từ chối công khai ủng hộ Phó lãnh đạo Scotland của Lao động, Anas Sarwar, khi ông chọn gửi con trai mình đến một trường tư thục ở Glasgow. Bộ trưởng Giáo dục tư nhân David Laws - người không có con - ngay lập tức nói \\"có\\" khi được hỏi liệu một bộ trưởng giáo dục trong tương lai có thể gửi con cái của họ đến trường tư nhân hay không.","answer":"Cả ba người phát ngôn về giáo dục từ các đảng chính đã thể hiện sự trung thực khi khẳng định họ không có vấn đề gì nếu Bộ trưởng Giáo dục tiếp theo gửi con cái của họ đến trường tư nhân. Sự kiện này diễn ra trong bối cảnh cuộc phỏng vấn trên chương trình Chính trị hàng ngày của BBC, khi người dẫn chương trình Andrew Neil đặt câu hỏi về việc có nên chấp nhận cho một bộ trưởng giáo dục gửi con cái của mình đến một trường tư nhân hay không."},{"question":"Кайсы жаныбардын кулагы жок?","answer":"Бир гана жыландын угуу органы жок. Алар үн толкундарын тили менен, а кээ бирлери бүтүн денеси менен сезет жана үн толкундарын ажырата алат."},{"question":"Inona no iantsoana ny olona tsy mbola lehibe?a) ray aman-drenyb) Ankizyd) Tanorae) Dadabe","answer":"b) Ankizy no iantsoana ny olona tsy mbola lehibe"},{"question":"ફાલ્ગુની પાઠકના પ્રખ્યાત ગીતોની યાદી બનાવો.","answer":"૧. મૈને પાયલ હૈ છનકાઈ૨. યાદ પિયા કી આને લાગી૩. મેરી ચુનાર ઉદ ઉદ્ જાયે૪. અય પરદેશ સે પરિયોં કી રાની૫. સાવન મેં૬. ઓ પિયા૭. વાસલડી૮.  ચૂડી જો ખનકી હાથાે મેં૯. મધમિથુ નામ"},{"question":"શિલ્પકલા વિશે જણાવો","answer":"ગુજરાત ભવ્ય સાંસ્કૃતિક અને કલાસભર શિલ્પ વારસો ધરાવે છે. હવેલી સ્થાપત્ય, મંડપ પ્રવેશદ્વાર, ખડકી, માઢ, ઝરૂખો, વગેરે લાકડામાં અને પત્થરમાં સારી રીતે કંડારાયેલા મળે છે. ગુજરાતનાં પ્રાચીન તળાવો, કુંડો, કુવા અને વાવ જેવાં કૃત્રિમ જળાશયોમાં કરેલી કોતરણીનો જગતભરમાં જોટો જડે એમ નથી. જેમ કે પાટણનું સહસ્ત્રલિંગ તળાવ અને રાણકી વાવ, અમદાવાદની અડાલજ વાવ વગેરે.અમદાવાદની સીદી સૈયદની જાળી, મોઢેરાનું સૂર્યમંદિર, દેલવાડાનાં અને કુંભારિયાનાં જૈન મંદિરો, સોમનાથનું પ્રસિદ્ધ શિવમંદિર, શત્રુંજય, તારંગા અને અન્ય સ્થળોનાં જૈન મંદિરો, શામળાજીનું મંદિર, અમદાવાદના હઠીસીંગના દહેરાં, અમદાવાદની રાણી રૂપમતીની મસ્જિદ, સરખેજનો શેખ સાહેબનો રોજો વગેરેનો સમાવેશ થાય છે"},{"question":"Apakah nama lagu kebangsaan negara Jepun? ","answer":"Nama lagu kebangsaan negara Jepun ialah Kimigayo (君が代)"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Ny fitiavana dia toy ny ody .............................  \\"","answer":"\\"  Ny fitiavana dia toy ny ody mahajamba \\""},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية: يمكن للكافيين عبور المشيمة بسهولة، ويواجه كبد الجنين غير الناضج صعوبة في تحطيمه. على هذا النحو، من المرجح أن يتعرض الأطفال الرضع لآثار جانبية؛","answer":"على هذا النحو، من المرجح أن يتعرض الأطفال الرضع لآثار جانبية ناتجة عن تأثير الكافيين، حيث يمكن للكافيين عبور المشيمة بسهولة، ويواجه كبد الجنين غير الناضج صعوبة في تحطيمه."},{"question":"ગિરનાર વિશે કહો","answer":"ગિરનાર  ગુજરાત રાજયનાં જુનાગઢ શહેરથી પાંચ કિલોમીટર ઉતરે આવેલ પર્વતોનો સમુહ છે.  આ પર્વતમાં પાંચ ઉંચા શિખરો આવેલા છે. જેમાં ગોરખ શિખર ૩૬૦૦, અંબાજી ૩૩૦૦, ગૌમુખી શિખર ૩૧૨૦, જૈન મંદિર શિખર ૩૩૦૦ અને માળીપરબ ૧૮૦૦ ફુટની ઉંચાઈઓ ધરાવે છે. જેથી ગિરનાર પર્વત ગુજરાતનો પણ ઉંચામાં ઉંચો પર્વત છે. ગિરનારના પાંચ પર્વતો પર કુલ થઇને ૮૬૬ મંદિરો આવેલા છે. પત્થરોનાં બનાવેલ દાદરા અને રસ્તો એક ટોચ પરથી બીજી ટોચ પર લઇ જાય છે. એવુ કહેવાય છે કે કુલ ૯,૯૯૯ પગથિયા છે,દર વર્ષે ગિરનારની પરિક્રમા થાય છે, જેમાં લાખો લોકો જોડાય છે.હિંદુ ધર્મમાં શ્રદ્ધાળુઓ માને છે કે ઉઘાડા પગે ગિરનારનાં પગથીયા ચઢવાથી સ્વર્ગની પ્રાપ્તિ થાય છે. ગિરનાર ગુજરાતનાં ધાર્મિક સ્થળોમાંનો એક છે. પ્રાચીન અને અર્વાચીન, બન્ને રીતે આ પવિત્ર સ્થળ ગિરનાર છે. જે હિંદુ ધર્મ અને જૈન ધર્મનાં લોકો માટે મહત્વનું યાત્રાધામ છે. અહીં આવેલું મીરા દાતાર મુસ્લિમોનું પવિત્ર સ્થળ છે.ભવનાથનો મેળો ગિરનારનાં પ્રથમ પગથિયાની આસપાસ આવેલી ભવનાથ તળેટીમાં દરવર્ષે મહા વદ નોમ થી મહા વદ ચૌદશ એટલેકે શિવરાત્રિ સુધી ભરાય છે. આ મેળો સ્વંયમભુ છે તેમજ આ મેળાના કેન્દ્રસ્થાને સંસારીઓ નહીં પરંતુ સાધુઓ છે. આ મેળાનો પ્રારંભ નોમને દિવસે ભવનાથ મહાદેવનાં મંદિરે ધજા ચડાવીને કરવામાં આવે છે. તે સમયે દેશ-વિદેશમાંથી વિવિધ સંપ્રદાયોના સાધુ-સંતો-મહંતો એકઠા થાય છે. આ મેળામાં સાધુઓને રહેવા માટેના અખાડાની વ્યવસ્થા જુનાગઢનાં અધિકારીઓ દ્વારા કરવામાં આવે છે. એક બાજુએ સાધુ-સંતોના ઉતારા તો બીજી બાજુએ આ મેળામાં સેવાકીય પ્રવ્રૂતિ કરતી સામાજીક સંસ્થાઓ, ધાર્મિક જગ્યાઓની રાવટીઓ ગોઠવવામાં આવે છે.ગિરનારની મહત્તા ધાર્મિક દ્રષ્ટિએ પણ ઘણી મોટી આંકવામાં આવી છે. જૈન ધર્મના જે પાંચ યાત્રાધામ આવેલા છે તેમાનું એક યાત્રાધામ એટલે ગિરનાર પર્વત પરનાં નેમીનાથજીનાં દેરાસર. ગિરનાર સાથે નેમિનાથજી અને રાજમતીનું નામ જોડાઈ ગયુ છે. પોતાના લગ્ન સમારંભ વખતે વધ કરવામાં આવનારા પશુઓનાં ભાંભરડા સાંભળીને રાજકુમાર નેમીનાથનું હદય હચમચી ઊઠયું. જેથી રાજપુત કુંવરે ત્યાગની દિશા લીધી, રાજમતીએ પણ સ્વેચ્છાએ ત્યાગની વાટ પકડી. ગિરનાર એમની તપસ્યા ભુમિ બન્યો. નેમીનાથજી અને રાજમતીની અપૂર્વ ત્યાગભાવનાથી ગિરનાર જૈનોનું તીર્થધામ બન્યો છે. આ જૈન દેરાસરનું જમીનથી લગભગ શિખર ૩૩૦૦ ફુટ ઉંચે છે."},{"question":"Zer da paleontologia, eta nola ulertzen du izaki bizidunen eboluzioa?","answer":"Paleontologia da izaki bizidunen fosilak aztertzen duen zientzia. Izaki bizidunen eboluzioa ulertzeko, paleontologiak erakusten du nola izaki bizidunen taldeak aldatu diren milioika urteetan zehar."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Ibu bapa Jolly menetap di Rajshahi dari Bengal Barat. Adik perempuannya Sharmili Ahmed adalah seorang pelakon. Ayat 2: Ibu bapa Jolly menetap dari Rajshahi di Bengal Barat, kakaknya, Sharmili Ahmed, adalah seorang pelakon. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"Quem pintou o quadro Guernica?","answer":"O pintor espanhol Pablo Picasso."},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:\\"અબૂકલું ઢબૂકલું, પવનથી હલકો થઈને આકાશમાં ઊંચે ચઢું છું મારા અનેક રંગ છે, નાના મોટાઓનો આનંદ મારી સાથે છે.\\"","answer":"ઉખાણામાં કહેવામાં આવ્યું છે કે તે અબૂકલું ઢબૂકલું છે, પવનથી હલકો થઈને આકાશમાં ઊંચે ચઢે છે એ પતંગ છે. ઉખાણામાં વધુમાં કહેવામાં આવ્યું છે કે તેના અનેક રંગ છે. આનો અર્થ એ છે કે પતંગો વિવિધ રંગોમાં આવે છે.ઉખાણામાં છેલ્લે કહેવામાં આવ્યું છે કે નાના મોટાઓનો આનંદ તેની સાથે છે. આનો અર્થ એ છે કે પતંગો બધી ઉંમરના લોકો માટે આનંદદાયી હોય છે.ઉખાણામાં આપેલા બધા સંકેતો પતંગ સાથે સુસંગત છે. તેથી, ઉખાણાનો જવાબ \\"પતંગ\\" છે. "},{"question":"Đặc trưng cơ bản của truyện cổ tích thần kì là gì?A. Có sự tham gia của các yếu tố thần kì, kết thúc có hậu.B. Phản ánh những sự kiện lớn của cộng đồng, thường kết thúc có hậu.C. Có sự tham gia của các yếu tố thần kì, kết cấu truyện tương đối thống nhất, thường kết thúc có hậu.D. Kết cấu truyện tương đối thống nhất, thường kết thúc có hậu","answer":"C. Có sự tham gia của các yếu tố thần kì, kết cấu truyện tương đối thống nhất, thường kết thúc có hậu."},{"question":"Dagaalkii U Dhaxeeyey Sayid Maxamed Cabdule Xasan Iyo England (British) SanadkiiUu Bilowday?","answer":"Dagaalkii U Dhaxeeyey Sayid Maxamed Cabdule Xasan Iyo England (British) WuxuBilowday Sanadkii 1900-Kii."},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 去年の1月15日、南太平洋のトンガの海の中で、火山の大きな噴火がありました。15mの津波が来ました。この噴火で4人が亡くなりました。噴火から1年が過ぎました。首都のヌクアロファにある教会では、1000人以上が集まって亡くなった人のために祈りました。祈りに来た女性は「津波から逃げた1年前のことを思うと、今でも涙が出ます」と話していました。トンガでは日系人が農業や水産業の仕事をしています。海で、もずくを生産している男性は、津波で道具が流れて、船も壊れました。去年日本に輸出したもずくは15tだけで、噴火の前の10％以下でした。男性は「火山の灰がもずくに悪いかもしれないと考える人もいて、注文が少なくなってしまいました。今できることをするだけです」と話していました。","answer":"トンガの火山の噴火から1年　亡くなった人のために祈る"},{"question":"Tôi năm nay 80 tuổi, tôi đã nằm viện rất lâu và rất nhiều bệnh viện tuyến trung ương. Bác sĩ chẩn đoán tôi bị crushing do thuốc, huyết áp, tim mạch và thoái hóa cột sống. Và gần đây nhất tôi bị nhiễm Covid-19 (do chưa tiêm mũi vaccine Covid-19 nào) sau khi cách ly được 12 ngày tôi lại nhập viện và chuyển lên tuyến tỉnh. Bác sĩ chẩn đoán và chỉ định đặt mạch vành vì mỗi khi đau lên là tôi rất mệt, đau thắt ngực khủng khiếp và rất ho, và da mặt tôi tím tái. Bác sĩ có trao đổi với tôi là đang cân nhắc về việc đặt mạch vành vì do lo sợ bị xuất huyết bao tử. Và trường hợp của tôi có nên tiêm kháng thể đơn dòng không? Xin bác sĩ hãy cho tôi lời khuyên, tôi vô cùng biết ơn và trân trọng!","answer":"Trường hợp của bác đã bị hội chứng Cushing và tuổi trên 80 là hai trong số những nguyên nhân gây suy giảm hệ miễn dịch. Vì vậy, nếu có thể bác nên tiêm kháng thể đơn dòng để phòng ngừa Covid-19."},{"question":"Rabe-Raben Adabin Hausa Guda nawa ne?","answer":"Adabin hausa ya kasu izuwa kashi biyu kamar yadda masana suka kasa shi tare da kowane kashi sunaye daban daban amma ma’anar duk dayace. Adabin hausa ya ķunshi:Rubutaccen Adabi (Adabin Zamani)Adabin Baka (Adabin Gargajiya)"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para o parágrafo a seguir - Uma nova sondagem publicada hoje pela revelou que novamente o \\"não\\" se impõe na intenção de voto dos escoceses, que em 18 de setembro decidiram se ser independente ou permanecer no Reino Unido","answer":". A nova pesquisa sinaliza que os unionistas superam por quatro pontos percentuais aos separatistas, ou seja, 52% dos eleitores disseram \\"não\\" diante os 48% que querem uma Escócia independente (excluam-se os indecisos)."},{"question":"බෝතල්වල පොරොප්ප මූඩී ගලවන උපකරණය හදුන්වන්නේ කෙසේද","answer":"කස්කුරුප්පුව. ඇයි ඉස්සර සීයලා පොඩි ළමයින්ට බනින්නෙ, කස්කුරුප්පුව වගේ කොහෙ රිංග රිංග දුවනවද කියල එහෙම. "},{"question":"Utilize a passagem abaixo para responder à pergunta na mesma língua que a passagem:  Mátyás Szűrös (pronunciação húngara: [ˈmaːcaːʃ ˈsyːrøʃ]; nascido em 11 de setembro de 1933 em Püspökladány) é um político húngaro. Foi Presidente Provisório da República de 23 de Outubro de 1989 a 2 de Maio de 1990. Sua presidência ocorreu durante a transição da Hungria do comunismo para o governo democrático. Szűrös atuou como presidente da Assembleia Nacional da Hungria de março de 1989 a maio de 1990. No outono de 1989, como parte de um acordo entre os comunistas e a oposição para estabelecer a democracia multipartidária, a Constituição de 1949 foi quase completamente reescrita para remover seu caráter comunista. O Conselho Presidencial, a presidência coletiva da era comunista do país, foi dissolvido. Sob a Constituição, Szűrös tornou-se presidente provisório até a eleição. Logo após assumir o cargo em 23 de outubro, ele fez a proclamação oficial de que a Hungria havia removido a \\"República Popular\\" de seu nome constitucional e agora era a \\"República da Hungria\\".  Pergunta: Quem é Mátyás Szűrös?","answer":"Mátyás Szűrös é um político húngaro."},{"question":"问题：最常见的零食是什么","answer":"答案：最常见的零食是薯片"},{"question":"Ny tsy fanarahan-dalàna no mahatonga fihidina any am-ponja. Valio eny sa tsia?","answer":"Eny, ny tsy fanarahan-dalàna no mahatonga fidirana am-ponja."},{"question":"சூரியக்குடும்பத்தைக் கண்டறிந்தவர்?","answer":"கோபர் நிக்கஸ்."},{"question":"Manana ity teny mikorontana ity ianao:aailkVinavinao io teny mikorotana io.","answer":"Ny teny azo amin' ilay teny mikorotana dia  \\"alika\\"."},{"question":"Wo Aisha Shoneye, akẹkọọ ọmọ ọdun mẹtadinlogun to dari ikọ elere idaraya to gba N100m ẹbun ẹkọ ọfẹ","answer":"Ko si ohun ti ọkunrin le se, ti obinrin kankan ko le se, bẹẹ si ni ọmọ ti yoo ba jẹ asamu, kekere ni yoo ti maa jẹnu samu-samu.Bẹẹ ni ọrọ ri nipa awọn akọni ọmọdebinrin ileẹkọ girama kan nipinlẹ Ondo, ti wọn soriire lati ipasẹ ere idaraya.Iyalẹnu si lo jẹ pe akẹkọọbinrin akẹẹgbẹ wọn, toun naa n kopa ninu ere idaraya yii, lo jẹ alakoso ikọ elere Football naa, ti wọn n pe ni Captain.Aisha Shoneye ni orukọ rẹ, ọmọdebinrin ọmọ ọdun mẹtadinlogun to tukọ ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa, titi wọn fi se oriire.Ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu Football naa si lo gba ipo kinni ninu idije ere idaraya naa to waye yika Naijiria eyi to ko ogo ati oriire nla ba ileẹkọ ati awọn akẹkọọ elere idaraya naa.Nibayi yii, ikọ agbabọọlu Football naa ti jẹ ẹbun ẹkọ ọfẹ ti owo rẹ to Miliọnu lọna ọgọrun Naira.Mo dupẹ lọwọ iya mi, to gba mi laaye lati se ere idaraya to wu mi, ti a fi jẹ ẹbun ẹkọ ọfẹ N100m – Aisha ShoneyeNigba to n ba BBC Yoruba sọrọ alakoso ikọ agbabọọlu naa sọ pe ere idaraya naa da lori ki awọn maa le ara awọn kiri lori papa bii ẹni pe wọn fẹ ja nnkan gba lọwọ ẹnikan.Wọn salaye pe aago mẹfa aarọ ni awọn akẹkọ naa maa n bẹrẹ igbaradi wọn lojoojumọ nile ẹkọ wọn.Amọ aago mẹjọ aarọ si ni igbaradi wọn naa yoo wa sopin lati lọ bẹrẹ eto ẹkọ kikọ ni Kilaasi eyi ti ko jẹ ki ere idaraya naa pa eto ẹkọ kikọ lara.Aisha sọ pe “Mo dupẹ pupọ lọwọ iya mi, to fun mi laaye lati se ere idaraya to wu mi, eyi to ko oriire ba mi.A kii ri owo lati na lasiko igbara wa amọ awọn olukọ wa maa n da owo laarin ara wọn lati ra awọn ohun eelo to wulo fun wa fun igbaradi ere idaraya naa.Ẹni ti mo n wo niwaju mi bii awokọse rere ni Tobi Amusan to maa n sare lori ọdan, mo si fẹ ga julọ ninu ere idaraya.”Iru ere idaraya wo ni Football yii, ti wọn kii fi ẹsẹ gba a?Nigba ti BBC Yoruba se abẹwo si ikọ agbabọọlu naa, a gbọ ẹkunrẹrẹ alaye nipa ere idaraya naa.Football ni wọn pe orukọ ere idaraya naa amọ kii se ere bọọlu alafẹsẹgba nitori ẹsẹ kọ ni wọn fi n gba a.Olukọ ati ọga ile ẹkọ ti awọn akẹkọọ to gba ipo kinni naa ti wa sọ fun BBC Yoruba pe ere idaray Football naa jẹ ajeji si orilẹede yii, ilẹ Amẹrika si lo ti wa.“Soccer ni Amẹrika n pe ere idaraya bọọlu alafẹsẹgba lori ọdan amọ ere idaraya tuntun yii, ni wọn n pe ni Football.Ileesẹ Nigeria-America Flag Football association si lo se agbtẹru idije naa laarin awọn ile ẹkọ.Ilẹ Naijiria ni orilẹede akọkọ nilẹ Afirika ti wọn yoo gbe idije yii wa, osu Kọkanla ọdun 2022 si lo gberasọ nilu Eko.Football ni ere idaraya yii lootọ amọ wọn kii fi ẹsẹ gba a gẹgẹ bii Soccer.Wọn maa n le ara wọn kiri bii ere bọọlu lootọ amọ wọn ko gba bọọlu.Bakan naa ni wọn maa n ju nnkan soke bii Basket Ball amọ ko jọọ rara.Wọn tun maa n le ara wọn kiri lori papa bii igba ti wọn n gba Rugby amọ kii se Rugby rara.”Wọn salaye siwaju si pe asia wa lara awọn agbabọọlu naa, ti wọn so mọ wọn lara amọ ko gbọdọ jabọ.Wọn ni ẹni ti ko ba ni okun ninu, ko le kopa ninu ere idaraya naa, ti wọn si gbọdọ ni ọgbọn ori pupọ.Awọn obinrin si lo n gba ere idaraya naa ni Naijiria.\\"Ọna iwe kọ nikan lọna ti akẹkọ le gba doke, ere idaraya naa dara\\"Awọn olukọ ati ọga ile ẹkọ ikọ elere idaraya awọn obinrin naa wa dupẹ pe awọn akẹkọọ naa gba ẹbun ẹkọ ọfẹ ti owo rẹ to ọgọrun miliọnu naira.Wọn ni owo yii ni yoo ran awọn akẹkọọ yii lọwọ lati ka iwe de ibi to ba wu wọn.Bakan naa ni wọn salaye pe iwe nikan kọ ni ọna abayọ lati soriire laye amọ ere idaraya naa dara, ọkan si ni yoo ran ekeji lọwọ."},{"question":"Pasadas las 7 a.m. en la plancha del Zócalo de la Ciudad de México se izo la bandera nacional a media asta, recordando el siniestro ocurrido en 1985, donde se estima perdieron la vida mas de diez mil personas.Dame un buen título para el texto anterior. ","answer":"Título : \\"Conmemoran los 29 años del terremoto ocurrido en México en 1985\\"."},{"question":"బల్బ్ నీ కనిపెట్టింది ఎవరు","answer":"తోమల్ ఎడిసన్"},{"question":"Quel est le nom du supercontinent le plus récent ?","answer":"Le supercontinent le plus récent est connu sous le nom de « Pangaea Proxima » ou « Next Pangaea ». Ce futur supercontinent hypothétique est prédit par des géologues et des scientifiques sur la base du processus en cours de tectonique des plaques et du mouvement des plaques tectoniques de la Terre."},{"question":"हिराकुड धरण कोणत्या नदीवर बांधले गेले आहे?अ. यमुनाब. गंगाक. महानदी ड. गोदावरी","answer":"क. महानदी ओडिशा राज्यातील हिराकुड धरणाची पूर्ण लांबी जवळ जवळ ३० किमी एवढी असून हे धरण 1957 मध्ये बांधून पूर्ण झाले होते."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي ولد من غير أب؟","answer":"الإجابة: نبي الله عيسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Ungu di luar, putih di dalam.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah manggis. "},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధం మరియు తాత్పర్యం ఇవ్వండి:తే|| హర తనుస్రుష్టమగుటచే నతిపవిత్ర,మయ్యె నమరాపగాతోయ మనుచు నింద్రముఖ్యసురయక్షగంధర్వమునిగణములు,కోర్కులలరంగఁ బలుమాఱుఁగ్రుంకెనందు.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :హర = శివునితను = శరీరాన్నిస్ర్పుష్టము + అగుటచేన్ = స్పర్శించినందునఅతి పవిత్రమయ్యెన్ = ఇంకా పవిత్రంగా మారిందిఅమర + ఆపగ = దేవనది యొక్కతోయము = జలముఅనుచున్ = అనుకుంటూఇంద్రముఖ్యసుర = ఇంద్రుడు మొదలైన దేవతలుయక్షగంధర్వ = యక్షులు, గంధర్వులుమునిగణములు = మునుల సమూహాలుకో ర్కు లలరంగఁ = వారి కోరికలు తీరేలాగా అనేకసార్లుపలుమాఱు = అనేక సార్లుగ్రుంకెనందు = అందులో దుమికారుతాత్పర్యం : శివుని శరీరాన్ని తాకినందున మరింత పవిత్రంగా మారిన దేవనది యొక్క జలములు అనుకుంటూ ఇంద్రుడు మొదలైన దేవతలు, యక్షులు, గంధర్వులు, మునుల సమూహాలు వారి కోరికలు తీరేలాగా అనేకసార్లు నదిలో స్నానం చేశారు."},{"question":"Какие процессы включают химическую реакцию при приготовлении пиццы? Выберите правильный ответ.(1) Смешивание специй для соуса;(2) Нарезание пепперони для начинки;(3) Нанесение сыра на пиццу;(4) Выпекание теста для формирования корки.","answer":"Химическая реакция происходит во время выпекания при высоких темературах, происходит реакция Майяра. В результате этой реакции аминокислоты и сахара в пищевых продуктах реагируют с теплом, образуя коричневые пигменты и придавая пицце характерный аромат и вкус. Таким образом, правильный ответ: (4)."},{"question":"கேள்வி : மன்னனது போரை மட்டும் சொல்லாது பிற மாண்புகளையும் பாடும் திணை …………………….அ) பாடாண் திணைஆ) பொதுவியல் திணைஇ) வாகைத் திணைஈ) நொச்சித் திணை","answer":"பதில் : அ) பாடாண் திணைவிளக்கம் : பாடாண் எனில் பாடப்படும் ஆண்மகனுடைய ஒழுகலாறு என்று பொருள்படும். அரசனுடைய புகழ், கொடை, அளி முதலானவற்றைக் கூறும் புறத்திணை பாடாண் திணை. வெட்சி, கரந்தை, வஞ்சி, காஞ்சி, உழிஞை, நொச்சி, தும்பை, வாகை முதலானவற்றில் சிறப்புற்ற ஆண்மகனது ஒழுகலாறுகளை உணர்த்துவது பாடாண் திணை.வெட்சி முதல் வாகைத்திணை வரை பூக்களால் திணைப்பெயர் அமைந்தது. வெட்சி முதலான போர்களை மேற்கொள்ளும்போது அவ்வப் பூக்களைச் சூடுவர். வாகை வெற்றியைக் கொண்டாடும் நிகழ்வு எனினும் வாகை மாலை சூடுதல் மரபில் உண்டு. ஆனால் பாடாண் என்பது ஒருவனைப் பற்றிப் பாடிச் சிறப்பிப்பதாதலின் இதற்குப் பூமாலை சூடும் மரபு இல்லை. ஆகவே பூவால் அன்றிச் செய்தியால் இப்படலத்திற்குப் பெயர் ஏற்பட்டுள்ளது. பாடப்பெறும் ஆண்மகனது ஆளுமைப் பண்புகளைக் கூறுதல் என்பது இதன் பொருள்."},{"question":"ፔሌ የምን ሀገር ተጫዋች ነበር?","answer":"የብራዚል"},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 野球の世界一を決めるWBCで、日本が優勝しました。23日、試合があったアメリカから選手たちが日本に帰ってきました。大リーグのチームに入っている大谷翔平選手などはアメリカに残りました。成田空港には1200人のファンが集まって、選手たちを迎えました。そのあと、監督や選手たちが記者の前で話をしました。栗山英樹監督は「日本でたくさんの人が応援してくれたことが、空港でわかりました。みなさんの気持ちが私たちの力になりました。ありがとうございました」と話しました。村上宗隆選手は、準決勝の最後にヒットを打って、決勝ではホームランを打ちました。村上選手は「次の2026年のWBCにも出て、全部の試合で活躍できるように頑張りたいです」と話しました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- 野球: 1）九人ずつの二チームが、たがいにバットでボールを打って攻め合い、点を争う競技。ベースボール。- 優勝: 1）競技などで、一位で勝つこと。- 選手: 1）競技に出るために選ばれた人。- チーム: 1）競技や仕事をするときの、組や団体。- ファン: 1）スポーツや映画・演劇などが、特別に好きな人。または、ある俳優や、選手などを熱心に応援する人。フアン。2）扇風機。送風機。換気扇。- 監督: 1）指図や取りしまりなどをすること。また、その人。- 記者: 1）新聞や雑誌などの記事を、取材したり書いたりする人。- 応援: 1）味方をはげますこと。2）力をかして助けること。- 準決勝: 1）勝ちぬきの試合で、決勝の一つ前の試合。- ヒット: 1）野球・ソフトボールで、安打。2）大当たり。- 決勝: 1）最後の勝ち負けを決めること。2）第一位のものを決めること。- ホームラン: 1）野球・ソフトボールで、打った球が外野のスタンドに入ったりして、打者が一気に本塁まで帰ることのできるヒット。ホーマー。本塁打。- 活躍: 1）めざましく働くこと。"},{"question":"Fan mooy gêblag réewum Tonga ?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Tonga mu ngi tudd Nukualofa."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Tiako ny tenako, .............................. \\" ","answer":"\\"  Tiako ny tenako,fa ianao mbola tiako lavitra \\" "},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Kpossi tävlade för Togo vid olympiska sommarspelen 2012 i London, där hon blev utslagen i försöksheatet på 50 meter frisim. Vid","answer":"olympiska sommarspelen 2016 i Rio de Janeiro blev hon utslagen i försöksheatet på samma distans."},{"question":"كيف يُوزَّع يوديد البوتاسيوم؟","answer":"عادة ما يشمل التأهب للطوارئ النووية خططا تضمن سهولة الحصول على أقراص يوديد البوتاسيوم. ويمكن أن يعني ذلك أن هذه الأقراص تُوزَّع مسبقاً على مواقع استراتيجية مثل الأُسر والمدارس والمستشفيات والصيدليات ومراكز إطفاء الحرائق والشرطة فضلا عن مراكز الإجلاء والدفاع المدني. وعندما يكون تطبيق إجراء إحصار الغدة الدرقية باليود باستخدام يوديد البوتاسيوم مبرراً، ينبغي لسلطات الصحة العامة أن تحدد المنطقة الجغرافية التي ينبغي أن يأخذ فيها السكان أقراص يوديد البوتاسيوم، وأن تحدد كذلك وقت وكيفية القيام بذلك والأشخاص المعنيين بذلك. ويمكن أن تصدر هذه التعليمات عن طريق الراديو والتلفزيون والإنترنت ومكبرات الصوت وغيرها من القنوات المتاحة وينبغي اتباعها بعناية. وتبت السلطات الوطنية في كل بلد في طرق التجهيز والتوزيع المسبقين لحبوب يوديد البوتاسيوم في بلدانها."},{"question":"පහත මාතෘකා ව ඇති කතාව ලියා  දක්වන්න. (ඉඟිය: මෙය රසවාහිනීයේ එන කතාවකි)","answer":"1. ලෝ වැස්සා ධර්ම අමෘත රස පානයෙන් නිවන් මහ නුවර පුරමින් අපගේ භාග්‍යවතුන් වහන්සේට පෙර කාශ්‍යප නම් බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ ලෝකයේ පහළ වූහ. එකල්හි දනව් වැසි මිනිසෙක් වෙළෙඳාමෙන් ජීවත් වෙමින් වසයි. ඉක්බිති පසු කාලයක හෙතෙම හිරියල් සුණු විකුණමින් ගම් නියම්ගම්හි හැසිරෙයි. එකල්හි එක් ගමෙක යොවුන් ස්ත්‍රියක් එය දැක කැඳවා මිළෙන් මනො සිලා සුණු ගත්තේය. ඉක්බිති වෙළෙන්දා විසින් බඩ සා ඇත්තෙමි මෑණියෙනි යි කී කල්හි ඕ තොමෝ ඔහුට මොනර මස් රසයෙන් සුවඳ ගිතෙල් සමග ඇල්හාලේ බත් වැඩුවේය. එකෙණෙහි එක් සුනඛයෙක් වෙවුලමින් බඩසයින් යුක්ත වූයේ කෙළ ගිලිමින් ඔහුගේ ඉදිරියට ගියේය. ඉක්බිති හේ ඔහු දුකට පත් වූ බව දැක කරුණාවෙන් කම්පාවන හෘදය ඇත්තේ මොනර මස් රසයෙන් හා තෙලේ මිශ්‍ර‍ කොට මහත් වූ බත් පිඩක් දුන්නේ ය. ඒ බල්ලා බත් අනුභව කොට සතුටු වූයේ වල්ගය හොල්ලමින් ඔහුගේ ඉදිරියට පැමිණියේය. මේ දැක වෙළෙන්දා ද සතුටුව මෙසේ ප්‍රාර්ථනාවක් තැබීය.2. මේ පින්කමින් ජාතියක් ජාතියක් පාසා මම ගිතෙල් හා මොනර මස් සහිත උසස් ඇල්සාල් බත් ලබම්වා අවසානයෙහිදී නිවන් පුරය භජනය කරම්වා!3. ඒ වෙළෙන්දා මෙපමණ පිංකම් කොට ජීවිතය කෙළවර දෙව්ලොව ඉපද බුද්ධාන්තරයක් මහත් දිව සැපත් අනුභව කොට එයින් චුතව මිනිස් ලොව පන්සියයක් වරක් ඉපදී මොනර මස් ගිතෙල් සමග ඇල්හාලේ බතම ලැබීය. එහෙයින් මේ බුද්ධොත්පාද කාලයෙහි බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ පිරිනිවන් පෑ කල්හි සිංහල රටෙහි මහවැලි ගං ඉවුරෙහ පූගලු නම් ගමැ එක්තරා ගෙදරක පිළිසිඳ ගෙන පිළිවෙලින් ගැබ මෝරා මවු කුසින් නික්මුණේය. ඔහුගේ මවුපියෝ තිස්ස යයි නමක් කළහ. හේ වැඩිවියට පැමිණියේ ගිහි ගෙදර විපාක ද පැවිද්දෙහි ආනිසංස ද අසා සියළුම සම්පත් අතහැර පූගලු විහාරයට එළඹ පැවිද්ද ඉල්ලීය. භික්‍ෂූහු ඔහු පැවිදි කොට උපසම්පදා කළාහු ය.හෙතෙම බොහෝ කලකින්ම උත්සාහ කරන්නේ උසස් ඵලය වූ රහත් බවට පැමිණියේ පින්වතෙක් හා නැණවතෙක් විය. තිස්ස තෙරණුවෝ යයි මුළු සිංහල රටෙහිම ප්‍ර‍සිද්ධ වූහ. ඒ තෙරුන්ගේ පාත්‍ර‍ය යම්කිසි ඉසුරුමත් කෙනෙක් හෝ දිළින්දෙක් ගත්තාහු නම් හේ වනාහි ඔහුට මොනර මස්, සුවඳ ඇල්හාලේ බත් හා ගිතෙල් සමග පුරවා දෙයි. මේ ක්‍ර‍මයෙන් මොහුට සැට අවුරුද්දක් ඉක්ම ගියහ.4. ඉක්බිති මෑත කාලයෙහි එක් ඇමැති පුතෙක් මෙසේ සිතී ය. මේ තෙරුන්ට නිතොර මොනර මස් සුවඳ ගිතෙල් සහිත ඇල්සාල් බත්ම උපදී යයි බොහෝ දෙනා කියත්. මෙය අප විසින් වනාහි මේ කරුණ පරීක්ෂා කරන්නට සුදුසු යයි සිතා ගෙදරට ගොස් රෑ යාමයෙහි භාර්යාවට මෙසේ කීයේය. සොඳුර, පූගලු විහාරයෙහි වාසය කරන තිස්ස ස්ථවිරයන්ට අද දනක් දෙනු කැමැත්තෙමි. තෙරුන් වහන්සේ මෙහි පැමිණි කාලයෙහි නිවුඩු සාලෙන් කුඩුමුසු කැඳ පිස වළඳවා වේලාව සමීප වූ කල්හි පලා මාලුවක් හා කාඩි ඇඹුල් දෙවැනි කොට නිවුඩු සාලේම බත් දෙන්නැයි කියා රැය පහන් වූ විට තමාම විහාරයට ගොස් තෙරුන් වැඳ ස්වාමීනි, අද අපට අනුග්‍ර‍හය කරන්න යයි ආරාධනා කොට තෙමේ අන් තැනක ගියේ ය.ඉක්බිති ඔහුගේ ගෙදර අධිගෘහිත දෙවියා රාත්‍රී භාගයෙහි භාර්යාව සමග කථා කරන ඒ වචන අසා මොවුහු ඒකාන්තයෙන් මේ තෙරුන් විසින් පෙර කරන ලද කර්මය විපාකය කිසිවෙකු විසින් නොවැලැක්විය හැකි බව සිතා ඒ ගෙදර මහළු මිනිසෙකු මෙන් ඇල්සහල්, මොනර මස් සහ ගිතෙල් කළයක් ද ගෙන ගෙදරට පැමිණ ඔහුගේ භාර්යාවට දුන්නේය. ඈ විසින් කොහෙන් ගෙන එන ලද්දේ දැයි ඇසූ කල්හි දේවතාවා මෙසේ කීයේය. මෑණියෙනි, අමාත්‍ය පුත්‍ර‍ තෙම මා දැක පින්වත, මා විසින් පූගලු වාසි තිස්ස හිමියන්ට දනට ආරාධනා කරන ලදි. තෝ මේ උපකරණ ගෙන ගෙදරට ගොස් ගෘහණියට දී මෙසේ කියව. මෙයින් බත් පිස ව්‍යඤ්ජන සහිතව තෙරුන් වළඳවන්න යයි මට කීවේය යයි කියා අතුරුදහන් විය.5. ඕ තොමෝ ද ඔහුගේ කථාව අසා මස් සහිත බත් පිළියෙල කොට තෙරුන් වහන්සේ පැමිණි කල්හි පාත්‍ර‍ය ගෙන වැඩ හිඳුවා ව්‍යඤ්ජන සහිත බත් වැළඳ වීය.තෙරුන් වහන්සේ බත් කිස නිමවා විහාරයට වැඩි සේක. ඊටපසු ඇමැතියා පැමිණ භාර්යාවන්ගෙන් තී තෙරුන්ට ආහාර දුන්නේ දැයි විචාළේය. ඕ තොමෝ නුඹ වහන්සේ එවූ උපකරණයන්ගෙන් බත් පිළියෙල කොට දෙන ලදැයි කීවාය. ඇමැතියා, සොඳුර, මා විසින් නොඑවන ලදි. කා විසින් එය ගෙන එන ලද්දේ දැයි ඇසීය. අසුවල් මහල්ලා විසිනැයි කී කල්හි ඔහු ද විචාරා ඔහු විසින් මෙවැන්නක් නොගෙනෙන ලදි යයි කී කල්හි එය තෙරුන් වහන්සේගේ ආනුභාවයෙන් මේ දෙවියන්ගේ වැඩක් යයි දැන කළ පින් ඇත්තහුගේ කුසල් විපාකය වලක්වන්නට නොහැකි යයි කියා බුදුසසුන්හි පැහැදුනේ දානපතියෙක් විය. ඊට මෑත භාගයෙහි තෙරුන් වහන්සේ පිරිනිවන් මඤ්චකයෙහි වැදහොත්තේ වෙහෙර බෙර හසුරුවා භික්‍ෂූන් කැඳවා තමන් පිරිනිවන් පානා බව ප්‍ර‍කාශ කෙළේ ය. ඉක්බිති භික්‍ෂූහු නුඹ වහන්සේ මහ පින් ඇත්තෙකි. නුඹ වහන්සේගේ පින මුළු ලඞ්කාවෙහිම ප්‍ර‍කටය. අතීතයෙහිදී කවර නම් පින්කමක බලයෙන් මේ විපාකය ලැබී දැයි විචාළහ. එය අසා තෙරුන් වහන්සේ තමා විසින් අතීතයෙහි කරන ලද කර්මය ප්‍ර‍කාශ කරමින් මෙසේ කීය.6. මේ භද්‍ර‍ කල්පයෙහි කාශ්‍යප නම් බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ නමක් මුළු සත්වයන්ට හිතවත්ව උපන්නේය.7. මම එදා හිරියල් වෙළඳාම් කරන වෙළෙන්දෙක් වීමි. ඒ වෙළෙඳ කර්මයෙන්ම ඒ ඒ තැන ඇවිදිමින් ජීවත් වූයෙමි.8. ඉක්බිති එක් දවසක වෙළෙඳාම සඳහා ජනපදයකට ගියෙමි. එහි එක ගෙදරක කුලදැරියක් මා දැක,9. මගෙන් බඩු රැගෙන බඩසයින් පෙලුණු මා දැක්කාය. ඉක්බිති ඇය මොනර මස් සුවඳ ගිතෙල් සමග,10. ඇල්හාලේ බත් ද කරුණාවෙන් වැළඳීමට මට දුන්නීය. ඉක්බිති මම බත් කනු කැමැති බල්ලකු දැක,11. ගිතෙල් සහිත බත් පිඩකින් සතපවා මෙසේ පැතීමි. මම ඒ පින්කමින් දෙව්ලොවට ගියෙමි.12. එහි දී දෙවියන් සමග රුවන්මය ප්‍රාසාදයෙහි මිහිරි නෘත්‍ය ගීත වාදිතයන්ගෙන් සතුටුව,13. දෙවඟනන් පිරිවරා දිව්‍ය සේනාව මුල් කරගෙන දිව්‍ය සම්පත් අනුභව කොට බොහෝ කාලයක් ගත කෙළෙමි.14. එයින් චුතව මිනිසුන් අතර ජාති පන්සීයක් මහත් ධනය ඇති මහා භෝග ඇති විශාල වූ ලෝකයා ගරු කිරීමට භාජනය වූ.15. නෑ සමූහයා විසින් පූජා කරන ලද උසස් කුලයක උපන්නෙමි. කර්මයට සුදුසු සම්පත් මම අනුභව කෙළෙමි.16. ගිතෙල්, මොනර මස්, ඇල්හාලේ බත් පන්සියයක් ජාතිවල නිතර වළඳන ලද මගේ ආහාරය විය.17. මේ අන්තිම ජීවිතයේදී එවැනි භෝජන හැම කල්හිම ලැබීමි. මගේ එක බත් පිඩක ආනිසංස බලන්න.18. පින්වතාගේ පින්කම මාරයාට ද වැළැක්වීමට නොහැක. එය වැළැක්වීමට සමත් අන් කවරෙක් වේද?19. තිරිසන්ගතයකුට පවා යමෙක් දන් දේද මා සේ හේ සියළුම භවයන්හි ත්‍රිවිධ සම්පත්ති විඳින්නේය.20. මෙසේ උන්වහන්සේ භික්‍ෂු සංඝයා මැද තමා විසින් කරන ලද කුශල කර්මය ප්‍ර‍කාශ කොට අවවාද කොට පිරිනිවන් පෑ සේක. තෙරුන් වහන්සේගේ වචන අසා මහාජනයා දන්දීම් ආදී පින් කොට මැරී ගොස් දිව්‍ය ලෝකයෙහි උපන්නාහ.21. ඉතා සුළු දන්දීමකින් පවා මිනිස්සු මෙසේ පුදුම විපාකයක් ලබති. බොහෝ කාලයක් මුලුල්ලේ දුන්නාවූ දානයාගේ විපාක බුදු නොවූ කිසිවෙකුට මෙපමණ යයි කියා නිම කිරීමට නොහැක."},{"question":"\\"තුන් තුඹ මල්\\" ගීතයේ ඉතිරි පද සම්පූර්ණ කරන්න.","answer":"තුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් රෙද්ද ඇඳලබණ්ඩි වළලු දෑත දමාලාමම දොර ළඟ බලා ඉන්නවාඅනේ තාම ආවෙ නැහැනෙආවෙ නැහැනෙ ආවෙ නැහැනෙමල් දුන්නෙන් වඩින ඉලන්දාරියාතුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් රෙද්ද ඇඳලබණ්ඩි වළලු දෑත දමාලාගෙදරට එන පාර කිව්වපණිවිඩ හත අටක් යැව්වඅනේ තාම ආවෙ නැහැනෙආවෙ නැහැනෙ ආවෙ නැහැනෙමල් දුන්නෙන් වඩින ඉලන්දාරියාතුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් තුඹ මල්තුන් තුඹ මල් රෙද්ද ඇඳලබණ්ඩි වළලු දෑත දමාලාරටක් වටින කෙනෙක් එක්කමටත් හනික දීග යන්ඩඋදව් දෙන්ඩ ආවෙ නැහැනෙආවෙ නැහැනෙ ආවෙ නැහැනෙමල් දුන්නෙන් වඩින ඉලන්දාරියාචන්ද්‍රානි ගුණවර්ධන"},{"question":"सौर ऊर्जेचा शोध कोणत्या शास्त्रज्ञांनी लावला?उत्तर :","answer":"कोपर्निकस"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Goormay Dhacday Hijradii Uu Rasuulka (NNKH) Ka Soo Hijrooday Maka Una SooHijrooday Madiina?","answer":"Jawaab: Waxay Dhacday 29-Kii Bishii Safar Sanadkii 14-Aad Ee Bicthada."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : జంతువుల నుండి ఆహారం కాకుండా, మనం పొందే ఇతర వస్తువులు ఏవి?","answer":"జంతువుల నుండి ఆహారం కాకుండా, మనం పొందే ఇతర వస్తువులు:జంతుచర్మాలు, జంతు కొమ్ములు, దంతాలు, గోళ్ళు.జంతు క్రొవ్వు, జంతు శ్రమ (ఎద్దు, గాడిదలను బరువు మోయటానికి ఉపయోగిస్తాం.)జంతువుల వెంట్రుకలు (బొచ్చు)"},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai.  Pihak sekolah akan mengkaji __ keruntuhan akhlak dalam kalangan murid-murid.  Pilihan:  A) langkah-langkahB) kalau-kalauC) faktor-faktorD) gara-gara","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) faktor-faktor"},{"question":"Iru ki waa leleyii, wọn pa Rotimi sinu oko l’Ọka Akoko, wọn tun ge ori rẹ lọ","answer":"Baba agbalagba kan, Rotimi Olukoju, lo ti pade iku ojiji lọna oko rẹ niluu Ọka Akoko, nijọba ibilẹ Guusu Iwọ-Oorun Akoko.ALAROYE gbọ pe oku oloogbe ọhun to n ṣisẹ ọdẹ ni ileefowopamọ alabọọde kan to wa niluu Ọka, ni wọn ba nibi ti wọn pa a si loju ọna marosẹ to wa laarin Ọka si Iwarọ Ọka Akoko lalẹ Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, *ọsẹ yii.Ṣe lawọn onisẹẹbi ọhun ge ori ọkunrin naa lọ lẹyin ti wọn pa a tan, ti wọn si fi iyooku ara rẹ silẹ sibi tawọn eeyan ti ba a lọjọ keji.Iṣẹlẹ yii atawọn iwa ọdaran mi-in to n waye lati nnkan bii ọsẹ kan sẹyin ni wọn lo ti da jinnijinni bo awọn eeyan agbegbe Akoko, eyi naa lo si ṣokunfa bi wọn ṣe n bẹ awọn ọlọpaa lati tete waa bẹrẹ iṣẹ wọn gẹgẹ bii ti ateẹyinwa.Ọkan ninu awọn agbaaagba ilu Akoko, Alaaji Ibrahim Killani, to fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ ni iwa kokanmi tawọn ọlọpaa n hu lẹyin rogbodiyan to suyọ lori iwọde SARS ti wọn ṣe kọja ti mu ki iwa ọdaran tun gbilẹ si i kaakiri awọn ilu to to wa l’Akoko. O ni Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, yii kan naa, ni wọn ji awọn arinrinajo mẹta gbe pẹlu ìbọn niluu Ikakumọ Akoko to wa ni aala ipinlẹ Ondo ati Edo.Ọlọkada kan to rin si asiko ti awọn ajinigbe naa n ṣiṣẹ ibi wọn lọwọ lo ni wọn fipa da duro, ti wọn si lu u ni aludaku ki wọn too fi i silẹ ninu agbara ẹjẹ, ti wọn si ba tiwọn lọ.O ni ileewosan ijọba to wa l’Akunnu Akoko, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Ila-Oorun Akoko, ni ọkunrin naa ti pada ji saye. Awọn mẹtẹẹta ti wọn ji gbe ọhun lo ni wọn ṣi wa ninu igbekun awọn to ji wọn gbe lasiko ta a fi n kọ iroyin yii lọwọ.Adele Ọba Akunnu, Ọmọọba Tọlani Orogun, ni ohun to le fọkan awọn eeyan ilu balẹ patapata ni ki wọn gbe ibudo awọn ọmọ ogun wa si agbegbe naa, nitori pe ipinlẹ meji ọtọọtọ, Kogi ati Edo lawọn ba paala.O ni awọn aginju nla nla to yi ilu awọn ka lawọn oniṣẹẹbi naa n lo gẹgẹ bii ibuba.Pupọ awọn eeyan ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ agbẹ ni Ikakumọ, Akunnu ati Auga ni wọn ko laya lati lọọ ṣiṣẹ loko wọn mọ nitori ibẹru awọn ajinigbe gẹgẹ bi ọkunrin naa ṣe sọ.Nigba ta a kan si Ọgbẹni Razaq Rauf to jẹ ọga ọlọpaa patapata fun ẹkun Ikarẹ Akoko, ṣe lo rọ awọn ara agbegbe ọhun lati fọkan balẹ.O ni awọn ọlọpaa ti n gbaradi lati peṣe aabo to peye fawọn eeyan ilu, ati pe ko ni i pẹ rara ti ọwọ yoo fi tẹ gbogbo awọn ọdaran to n fi agbegbe Akoko boju ṣiṣẹ ibi."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਜੋ ਤਿਨਿ ਕੀਆ ਸੋ ਸਚੁ ਥੀਆ ॥ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਨਾਮੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰਿ ਦੀਆ ॥ਹਿਰਦੈ ਨਾਮੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਮਨਿ ਭੰਗੁ ॥ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਨਾਲਿ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਸੰਗੁ ॥੧॥ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਰਾਖਹੁ ਅਪਨੀ ਸਰਣਾਈ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਨਾਮੁ ਪਦਾਰਥੁ ਨਉ ਨਿਧਿ ਪਾਈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਕਰਮ ਧਰਮ ਸਚੁ ਸਾਚਾ ਨਾਉ ॥ਤਾ ਕੈ ਸਦ ਬਲਿਹਾਰੈ ਜਾਉ ॥ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਤੇ ਸੇ ਜਨ ਪਰਵਾਣੁ ॥ਤਿਨ ਕੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਪਰਮ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ॥੨॥ਹਰਿ ਵਰੁ ਜਿਨਿ ਪਾਇਆ ਧਨ ਨਾਰੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਰਾਤੀ ਸਬਦੁ ਵੀਚਾਰੀ ॥ਆਪਿ ਤਰੈ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਕੁਲ ਤਾਰੈ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਸੇਵਿ ਤਤੁ ਵੀਚਾਰੈ ॥੩॥ਹਮਰੀ ਜਾਤਿ ਪਤਿ ਸਚੁ ਨਾਉ ॥ਕਰਮ ਧਰਮ ਸੰਜਮੁ ਸਤ ਭਾਉ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਬਖਸੇ ਪੂਛ ਨ ਹੋਇ ॥ਦੂਜਾ ਮੇਟੇ ਏਕੋ ਸੋਇ ॥੪॥੧੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 352 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਸ ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਬਣਾ ਲਿਆ, ਉਹ ਉਸ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਰੂਪ ਹੀ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਅਟੱਲ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹਰੀ-ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤਾ । ਉਸ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ (ਸਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ) ਨਾਮ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਕਦੇ ਵਿਛੋੜਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ, ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ (ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ) ਪਿਆਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸਾਥ ਬਣਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੀ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਸਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈਂ,ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਚੱਖ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ; ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਤੇਰਾ ਉੱਤਮ ਨਾਮ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜੋ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ, ਮਾਨੋ) ਨੌ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਹਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਧਰਤੀ ਦਾ ਸਾਰਾ ਹੀ ਧਨ-ਪਦਾਰਥ ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਟਾਕਰੇ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਤੁੱਛ ਜਾਪਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਸ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਟ ਕਰਮ ਤੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਫ਼ਰਜ਼ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ । ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਕੇ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ ਵਿਚ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਕਬੂਲ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ,ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਕੀਤਿਆਂ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਕੀਮਤੀ (ਨਾਮ) ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਉਹ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪਤੀ (ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ) ਵਿਚਾਰਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ ਆਪ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਪਾਰ ਲੰਘ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਸੰਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਕੁਲ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਰ ਲੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ,ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦੱਸੇ ਰਾਹ ਉਤੇ ਤੁਰ ਕੇ ਮਨੁੱਖਾ ਜਨਮ ਦਾ ਅਸਲ ਲਾਭ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਰੱਖਦੀ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ) ਤੇਰਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਉੱਚੀ ਜਾਤਿ ਤੇ ਕੁਲ ਹੋਵੇ,ਤੇਰਾ ਸੱਚਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਕਰਮ, ਧਰਮ ਤੇ ਜੀਵਨ-ਜੁਗਤਿ ਹੋਵੇ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉੱਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਉਸ ਦਾ ਜਨਮਾਂ ਜਨਮਾਂਤਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਲੇਖਾ ਨਿਬੜ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਪਾਸੋਂ (ਫਿਰ) ਕੀਤੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਲੇਖਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ,ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਹਰ ਪਾਸੇ) ਇਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਹੀ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਦੀ ਹੋਂਦ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਿਆਲ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਮਿਟ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੪।\\""},{"question":"ઈન્દિરા એકાદશી વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"હિંદુ ધર્મમાં એકાદશીનું વ્રત મહત્વપૂર્ણ સ્થાન ધરાવે છે. પ્રત્યેક વર્ષ દરમ્યાન ચોવીસ એકાદશીઓ હોય છે, જ્યારે અધિક માસ આવે છે ત્યારે તેની સંખ્યા વધીને છવ્વીસ હોય છે. આ પૈકી ભાદરવા માસના વદ (કૃષ્ણ પક્ષ) સમયે આવતી એકાદશી ઈન્દિરા એકાદશી તરીકે ઓળખાય છે."},{"question":"यत्र नार्यस्तु पूज्यन्ते रमन्ते तत्र देवताः ।यत्रैतास्तु न पूज्यन्तेसर्वास्तत्राफलाः क्रियाः ।।-मनुस्मृती","answer":"जिथे नारींची पूजा केली जाते तिथे देवता रमतात. जिथे त्यांची पूजा केली जात नाही अशा ठिकाणी कुठलीच क्रिया सफळ होत नाही."},{"question":" Inona no anaran’ilay fifanarahana namarana ny Ady Lehibe I tamin’ny 1919?","answer":"Ny anaran'ilay fifanarahana namarana ny Ady Lehibe I tamin'ny 1919 dia ny Fifanarahana Versailles."},{"question":"Şahislar e-fatura mükellefi olabilir mi?","answer":"Şahıs şirketleri e-fatura kullanabilir mi? Şahıs şirketleri e-fatura kullanabilir, bunun için önlerinde herhangi bir engel yoktur. Ticari firma olarak anonim şirket, limited şirket, gerçek/şahıs şirketi statüsünde bulunan ve e-fatura kullanmak isteyen herkes elektronik fatura uygulamasından yararlanabilir."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిశృంఖల చర్య అంటే ఏమిటి?","answer":"శృంఖల చర్య :అత్యధిక శక్తి నిచ్చే స్వయం పరిపోషిత కేంద్రక విచ్ఛిత్తిని శృంఖల చర్య అంటారు.శృంఖల చర్యలో న్యూట్రాన్లు జ్యామితీయ శ్రేణిలో పెరిగి, పదార్థం అంతా విచ్ఛిత్తికి లోనవుతుంది. ఇదంతా అతి తక్కువ కాలంలో జరుగడం వల్ల శక్తి పెద్దపెట్టున విడుదలవుతుంది."},{"question":"Ile-ẹjọ ni ki wọn lọọ fi Chidinma to pa baba alaaanu ẹ lọjọsi sẹwọn fun ọgbọn ọjọ l’Ekoo","answer":"O kere tan, ọgbọn ọjọ, ni Chidinma Ojukwu atawọn afurasi ọdaran ti wọn mọ nipa iku Ọgbẹni Usifo Atanga, ọga agba ileeṣẹ tẹlifiṣan Super TV, yoo fi maa gbatẹgun lọgba ẹwọn Kirikiri, l’Ekoo, ki igbẹjọ lori ẹsun iṣikapaniyan ti wọn fi kan wọn too tẹsiwaju.Adajọ ile-ẹjọ Majisreeti to fikalẹ si Yaba, Majisreeti Agba Adeọla Adedayọ, lo paṣẹ naa lọjọ Aje, Mọnde yii, nigba ti wọn foju awọn afurasi ọdaran naa bale-ẹjọ.Ninu alaye ti agbefọba Cyril Ejiofor ṣe niwaju adajọ ni kootu ọhun, o ni oun rọ ile-ẹjọ naa pe ki wọn ṣi fi Chidinma ati ekeji rẹ, Adedapọ Ojukwu, sahaamọ na, ki ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa le raaye fikun lukun pẹlu ajọ to n gba awọn adajọ nimọran, DPP, lati pese itọsọna ati amọran to yẹ lori ẹjọ wọn.Darẹkitọ DPP, Ọmọwee Babajide Martins, toun naa wa ni kootu ọhun sọ pe wọn o ti i fi awọn iwe ẹsun to kun rẹrẹ lori ẹjọ yii ṣọwọ sawọn, afi tawọn ba si ri isọfunni to yẹ gba lawọn too le pese amọran bo ṣe yẹ. Nitori bẹẹ, oun o ta ko ẹbẹ ti agbefọba bẹ kootu naa, oun fara mọ ọn.Ẹsun ti wọn fi kan Chidinma ati Adedapọ ni pe wọn mọ-ọn-mọ ṣeku pa Oloogbe Atanga lọjọ kẹtalelogun, oṣu kẹfa, ọdun yii, sinu otẹẹli kan lagbegbe Lẹkki, toun ati Chidinma ti jọ n gbadun ara wọn fun ọjọ mẹta ṣaaju.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, nigba tawọn ọlọpaa ṣafihan afurasi ọdaran naa, Chidinma, lọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹfa, akẹkọọ Fasiti Eko yii jẹwọ fawọn oniroyin pe loootọ ni, oun loun gun baba alaaanu oun, Atanga, lọbẹ pa, nigba to fẹẹ ba oun laṣepọ toun o si gba fun un, tori ibasun tawọn ti n ṣe bọ ti jẹ ko rẹ oun, ṣugbọn ọkunrin naa ko fẹẹ gba, gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi.O tun jẹwọ pe oun ati oloogbe naa lawọn ti jọ n fa egboogi oloro loriṣiiriṣii kiṣẹlẹ yii too waye, lẹyin toun si gun un lọbẹ pa tan loun lọọ fi kaadi ATM gba owo jade ninu akaunti oloogbe naa, ti oun si ba ẹsẹ oun sọrọ, kawọn ọlọpaa too waa mu oun nile awọn obi oun ni Surulere.Ṣugbọn laarin asiko ti Chidinma fi wa lahaamọ awọn ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ti wọn n ṣewadii lori ọrọ yii ni Panti, wọn lo tun yi ọrọ pada fawọn oniroyin kan ti wọn lọọ bi i leere, o ni oun kọ loun gun oloogbe naa lọbẹ, awọn kan ti pa a silẹ koun too wọ yara naa, awọn ti wọn si pa a naa ni wọn da yara ọhun ru, ti wọn sa lọ, koun too de lati ibi toun ti lọọ ra egboogi oloro tawọn fẹẹ fi gbadun ara awọn.Ṣa, Adajọ Adedayọ ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn lọọ fi Chidinma ati ẹni keji ẹ sahaamọ ọgba ẹwọn fun ọgbọn ọjọ, gẹgẹ bii ibeere agbefọba.Ọjọ karun-un, oṣu kẹsan-an ni igbẹjọ yoo bẹrẹ ni pẹrẹwu."},{"question":"De que categoría es esta pregunta : ¿Cuál es el apodo de Las Vegas, Nevada?.","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es geografía."},{"question":"Korona: Ijọba ni kawọn ileewe girama ati alakọọbẹrẹ ṣi wa ni titi nipinlẹ Eko","answer":"Eto ẹkọ fun saa tuntun to yẹ ko bẹrẹ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kẹrin, oṣu ki-in-ni, ọdun 2021 yii, ko ni i waye mọ, latari bijọba ipinlẹ Eko ṣe paṣẹ pe kawọn ileewe pamari ati sẹkọndiri kaakiri ipinlẹ naa ṣi tilẹkun wọn na.Atẹjade kan lati ọfiisi Alukoro fun ẹka eto ẹkọ nipinlẹ naa, Ọgbẹni Kayọde Abayọmi, sọ lọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, pe ijọba ti wọgi le iwọle awọn akẹkọọ lawọn ile-ẹkọ naa, ati ti aladaani ati tijọba.O ni igbesẹ yii ko ṣẹyin bijọba ṣe n kiyesi arankanlẹ arun Korona to tun fẹẹ burẹkẹ lẹẹkeji nipinlẹ Eko, ati bi ọrọ aabo awọn ogo wẹẹrẹ ṣe jẹ ijọba logun gidi.Atẹjade naa sọ pe ko ti i sẹni to mọ igba ti saa tuntun yoo bẹrẹ bayii, o ni kawọn obi ati olukọ ṣi lọọ mu suuru, titi tijọba yoo fi kede ọjọ iwọle fun saa ẹkọ tuntun laipẹ.Wọn waa gba awọn obi niyanju lati ri i pe wọn tubọ daabo bo awọn ọmọ wọn lọwọ arun aṣekupani ọhun, nipa riri i daju pe awọn ọmọ naa n lo ibomu, wọn n fomi ati ọṣẹ fọ ọwọ wọn deede, wọn si n lo kẹmika apakokoro, sanitaisa, to yẹ nigba gbogbo."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ayam baru belajar berkokok\\"?","answer":"Baru saja cukup umur, baru mencuba hendakkan perempuan"},{"question":"Apakah maksud itik pulang petang? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut. ","answer":"Maksudnya adalah amat lambat berjalan. Contoh ayat:  Adik berjalan bagai itik pulang petang sebab itulah akhirnya dia terpaksa didukung oleh ibu."},{"question":"Ẹwọn ọrinlelẹgbẹrun ọdun (1,800), ni wọn ju Abram to fipa ba obinrin mẹrindinlọgọta lo pọ si","answer":"Bo ba jẹ pe eeyan le ku ki wọn tun ji tọhun dide pe ko maa waa ṣẹwọn rẹ lọ ni, afaimọ ni wọn o ni i ṣe bẹẹ fun ọkunrin ọdaran ẹni ọdun mẹtalelọgbọn ti wọn porukọ ẹ ni Abram Sello Mapunya yii, tori o daju pe ko si bi ẹmi rẹ ṣe le gun to, ko le pari ẹwọn ẹgbẹrun kan ati ọdun mejidinlaaadọrun-un tile-ẹjọ sọ ọ si, latari bo ṣe jẹbi ẹsun fifipa ba awọn obinrin mẹrindinlọgọta lo pọ.Ọmọ bibi orileede South Africa ni Abram, ile-ẹjọ giga kan to fikalẹ siluu Pretoria, lorileede naa lo gbe idajọ rẹ kalẹ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii, wọn ni laarin ọdun marun-un ni baale ile ọdaran yii fi ṣe awọn obinrin olobinrin baṣubaṣu, o si jẹbi ẹsun mọkanlelọgọrin (81) ninu ọgọrun kan le ọkan (101) ẹsun ti wọn kọkọ fi kan an.Mọkanlelogoji (41) lara awọn ẹsun ọhun lo da lori ifipa ba ni lo pọ, nigba ti ẹsun ogoji yooku jẹ mọ ole jija, ṣiṣe akọlu sawọn ẹni ẹlẹni, fifọle, ati hihuwa to le da omi alaafia adugbo ru.Adajọ to dajọ ẹwọn fọpa-wọn ọhun, Papi Mosopa, sọ pe ọmọ ọdun mẹrinla lọjọ ori ẹ kere ju ninu awọn ti jagunlabi yii fipa ṣe ‘kinni’ fun, ẹni ọdun marundinlọgọta lo dagba ju ninu wọn.Wọn ni bo ṣe n lọ lati agbegbe kan si omi-in lo n huwakiwa ọhun, lara awọn ilu to gbe iṣe ẹ de ni Nellmapius, Mamelodi, Silverton, Olievenhoutbosch ati Atteridgeville.Wọn lọkunrin naa ati ọrẹbinrin kan ni wọn jọ n gbe, ko fẹ ẹ bii iyawo o, ṣugbọn wọn lo lọmọ meji, ọmọkunrin to jẹ ọdun mẹjọ, atọmọbinrin ọdun mẹrin kan.Adajọ naa ni lati ọdun 2014 ni ẹri to wa niwaju ile-ẹjọ ti fihan pe Abram ti gbegba ṣina ati gbewiri ẹ, ko si jawọ, bẹẹ ni ko ronupiwada titi tọwọ awọn agbofinro fi tẹ ẹ loṣu kẹta, ọdun 2019, ti wọn si ti foju ẹ bale-ẹjọ.Sibẹ, lasiko igbẹjọ, adajọ ni oun o gbooorun ironupiwada kankan lara ẹ, wọn niṣe lo n rẹrin-in musẹ ni kootu, ko tiẹ huwa bii ẹni to mọ itumọ aburu to ṣe rara.Latari eyi, adajọ ni iru ẹ kọ lo yẹ ko tun maa gbe laarin awọn eeyan gidi, ko lọọ maa fi aṣọ penpe roko ọba ni, ẹwọn si ni ko ti lo iyooku igbesi aye rẹ, koda to ba tun aye wa paapaa."},{"question":"Firy ireo kandidà nirotsaka ho fidiana tamin'ny taona 2023?","answer":"Ny isan'ireo kandidà nirotsaka ho fidiana tamin'ny taona 2023 dia  13"},{"question":"Inona avy ary ireo tombontsoa ara-pahasalamana azo avy amin’ny fihomehezana ?","answer":"Mampisinda ny rarin-tsaina ny fihomehezana, mihena ny tebiteby sy ny adin-tsaina ka lasa misinda ny rarin-tsaina. Ankoatra izay dia manampy betsaka amin’ny fisorohana ny fahaketronan'ny tarehy ihany koa ny fihomehezana. Manjary mitombo ny famokarana serotonine sy dopamine ao amin’ny vatana ka lasa falifaly lalandava ilay olona mihomehy matetika. Mampitombo ny hery fiarovana ary mampihena ny fanaintainana ihany koa ny fihomehezana."},{"question":"Nêu các việc cần chuẩn bị để thực hiện bài tập: Em hãy viết đoạn văn phát biểu cảm nghĩ về một trong các bài thơ có yếu tố tự sự, miêu tả đã học (“Đêm nay Bác không ngủ”, “Lượm”, “Gấu con chân vòng kiềng”).","answer":"- Xem lại nội dung văn bản Lượm: Kể về cậu bé tên Lượm làm giao liên và bị hi sinh trong một lần làm nhiệm vụ.- Hoàn cảnh ra đời cả bài thơ là năm 1949, trong thời kì kháng chiến chống thực dân Pháp.- Chú ý các yếu tố tự sự, miêu tả trong bài thơ và tác dụng:+ Ngày Huế đổ máu, chú từ Hà Nội về gặp cháu ở Hàng Bè.+ Lượm kể về công việc liên lạc.+ Tưởng tượng chuyện Lượm hi sinh khi đi giao liên.+ Trang phục, cử chỉ, điệu bộ của Lượm: Cái xắc xinh xinh, cái chân thoắn thoắt, cái đầu nghênh nghênh, ca lô đội lệch, mồm huýt sáo, nhảy trên đường vàng.+ Hình ảnh Lượm hi sinh: một dòng máu tươi, tay nắm chặt bông lúa,…→ Tác dụng: Người đọc cảm nhận rõ hơn tình cảm sâu sắc, sự xót thương, cảm động mà tác giả dành cho chú bé Lượm."},{"question":"Opisz historyczny kontekst powstania rugby siedmioosobowego?","answer":"Rugby siedmioosobowe narodziło się w południowej Szkocji najprawdopodobniej w 1883 r. za sprawą Neda Haiga i Davida Sandersona z Melrose szukających sposobu na wsparcie finansowe lokalnej drużyny rugby[2]. Do okresu międzywojennego odmiana sportu zyskała na popularności na pograniczu szkocko-angielskim, jednak nie była znana gdzie indziej. Dopiero po I wojnie światowej rozegrano pierwsze turnieje w pozostałych częściach Szkocji i Anglii, w ramach zbiórki funduszy na cele charytatywne.Po II wojnie światowej rugby siedmioosobowe dotarło do innych państw i stopniowo zyskało na popularności. W 1973 r. rozegrano pierwszy międzynarodowy turniej siódemek na stadione Murrayfield w ramach obchodów stulecia szkockiej federacji rugby."},{"question":"Mitanisa fiara vokatra malagasy?","answer":"Ireo karazana fiara  vokatra malagasy4×4 MazanaLa FaokaMAZANA IIKarenjy"},{"question":"వాల్ట్ డిస్నీ ప్రొడక్షన్స్, Ltd. తెలప0డి. ","answer":"పెద్ద మాధ్యమ మరియు వినోదాల మిశ్రమ సంస్థ.[4] 1923 అక్టోబరు 16న సోదరులైన వాల్ట్ డిస్నీ మరియు రాయ్ డిస్నీలచే డిస్నీ బ్రదర్స్ కార్టూన్ స్టూడియో గా స్థాపించబడిన ఈ సంస్థ, 1929లో , మరియు 1938లో వాల్ట్ డిస్నీ ప్రొడక్షన్స్ ‌లో బహిరంగ ప్రజానీకానికి వర్తకంలో భాగం కల్పించబడింది. లైవ్-యాక్షన్ చిత్ర నిర్మాణం, టెలివిజన్, మరియు ప్రయాణ రంగాలలోకి ప్రవేశించక ముందు వాల్ట్ డిస్నీ ప్రొడక్షన్స్ తనకు తానే అమెరికన్ అనిమేషన్ పరిశ్రమలో ఒక నాయకుడిగా స్థాపించుకుంది. 1986లో తన ప్రస్తుత పేరును పెట్టుకున్న ఈ సంస్థ, ది వాల్ట్ డిస్నీ కంపెనీ తన ప్రస్తుత కార్యకలాపాలను విస్తరించింది మరియు నాటకం, రేడియో, ప్రచురణ, మరియు ఆన్ లైన్ మాధ్యమం వంటి విభాగాలను ప్రారంభించింది. దీనికి తోడు, మరింత పక్వత చెందిన విషయాన్ని అమ్మడానికి దాని సహ-సంబంధ సంస్థలు మరియు దాని జాతీయ బ్రాండెడ్ సంస్థలకు బదులు సంస్థ తన నూతన విభాగాలను సృష్టించింది.ఈ సంస్థ తన చిత్ర స్టూడియో ఉత్పత్తుల గురించి ప్రసిద్ధి చెందింది, వాల్ట్ డిస్నీ మోషన్ పిక్చర్స్ గ్రూప్, నేడు హాలీవుడ్లోని అతి పెద్దది. "},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික ගංගාව නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ගංගා යනු ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික ගංගාවයි."},{"question":"Kintana ao amin'ny rafi-masoandro misy antsika ny Masoandro. Inona no safidy heverina ho diso momba ny masoandro?1. Ny masoandro dia mamoaka hazavana.2. Ny masoandro dia vita amin'ny fromazy.3. Mafana be ny masoandro.","answer":"Ny safidy 2 no diso,  Ny masoandro dia tsy vita amin'ny fromazy."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക:  1916 ൽ ചിറ്റഗോഗിലെ ഒരു സമ്പന്ന കുടുംബത്തിൽ മുൻ ബംഗാൾ എന്ന സ്ഥലത്ത് സുബോധ് റോയ് ജനിച്ചു. 1930-31 കാലഘട്ടത്തിൽ വിപ്ലവ നേതാവ് സൂര്യ സെന്നിന്റെ നേതൃത്ത്വത്തിൽ നടന്ന","answer":"ചിറ്റഗോംഗ് ആയുധപ്പുര വിപ്ലവത്തിൽ പങ്കെടുത്ത ഏറ്റവും പ്രായം കുറഞ്ഞ വ്യക്തിയായിരുന്നു അദ്ദേഹം. റോയ്ക്ക് ആദ്യ ബാച്ചിൽ ശിക്ഷ വിധിച്ചു. 1934 ൽ വിചാരണക്കുശേഷം പോർട്ട് ബ്ലെയറിലെ സെല്ലുലാർ ജയിലിലേക്ക് 1934 ൽ സുബോദ് റോയെ നാടുകടത്തി. ജയിലിൽ വെച്ച് ഡോ. നാരായൺ റോയ് സുബോധിന്റെ ജീവിതത്തെ സ്വാധീനിച്ചു. അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ മാർഗ്ഗനിർദ്ദേശത്തിൽ മാർക്സിസ്റ്റ് സാഹിത്യങ്ങൾ പഠിച്ചു."},{"question":"Lagos Terminus railway station","answer":"Lagos Terminus, ti a tun mọ ni Lagos Iddo, ti jẹ ibudo ọkọ oju-irin akọkọ ti ilu Eko titi di ọdun 2021. Ibusọ ọkọ oju irin naa wa ni Iddo Island, nitosi Lagos Island ati ni aarin ilu naa.Ibusọ naa, ti o wa ni iwaju Afara Carter ati lẹba Lagoon Eko, ni ile ebute ilẹ nla meji kan . O tun ka bata meji ti awọn ọkọ oju irin : ọkan ti o wa ni ita awọn iru ẹrọ ibudo ati ọkan ti o tobi julọ ti o wa ni 2 km ariwa, ibudo Yaba ni Eko nitosi.Laini ti n ṣiṣẹ Terminus Lagos, ati gbogbo nẹtiwọọki orilẹ-ede, ko ni itanna ; ati orin dín (1,067mm).Ibusọ Lagos jẹ ebute oko oju irin ati awọn ọkọ oju-irin jijin, gẹgẹbi apẹẹrẹ ọkọ oju-irin ti o han si Kano, ni ariwa ti Nigeria ati 1,126 km jina si Eko. Laini iyara giga ti boṣewa, ti o so Eko si Abuja, ti gbero ni ibẹrẹ awọn ọdun 2010, gẹgẹ bi apakan ti ero idagbasoke ti awọn ọkọ oju irin Naijiria.Lagos Terminus yoo wa nipasẹ laini meji (pupa ati buluu) ti ojo iwaju Lagos Metro, labẹ ikole, ni ibudo metro Iddo."},{"question":"Makinde darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ APC l’Ondo","answer":"Aṣofin to n ṣoju awọn eeyan ijọba ibilẹ Ila-Oorun ati Iwọ-Oorun Ondo nile-igbimọ aṣoju-ṣofin l’Abuja, Ọnarebu Abiọla Makinde, naa ti kẹru rẹ kuro ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu African Democratic Congress (ADC) to wa tẹlẹ, o si ti lọọ darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu All Progressives Congress (APC).Aṣofin ọmọ bibi ilu Ondo ọhun fi eyi lede ninu lẹta kan to kọ si Olori ile, Ọnarebu Fẹmi Gbajabiamila, lasiko ijokoo awọn aṣoju-ṣofin to waye lọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii.Makinde fidi rẹ mulẹ ninu lẹta to kọ naa pe ija ajakuakata to wa ninu ẹgbẹ ADC, eyi ti wọn ko ti i ri yanju lo ṣokunfa igbesẹ ti oun gbe lati lọọ darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC.Ọkan ninu awọn ọmọlẹyin gomina Ipinlẹ Ondo ana, Dokita Olusẹgun Mimiko, ni Ọnarebu Makinde, ẹni tawọn alatilẹyin rẹ tun n pe ni Osaparapara.O ti figba kan ṣe alaga ijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ondo kí aarin oun ati ọga rẹ too daru nigba naa.Ọnarebu Joseph Akinlaja to jẹ alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu Zenith Labour Party bayii ni aṣofin to n ṣoju awọn eeyan ijọba ibilẹ mejeeji ọhun ki awọn eeyan too fi ibo wọn le e danu lasiko eto idibo gbogbogboo to waye lọdun 2019, ti wọn si fi ibo wọn gbe Makinde wọle.Lasiko eto idibo gomina ipinlẹ Ondo to waye ninu osu kẹwaa, ọdun to kọja, lawọn eeyan ti n fura pe o ṣee ki ọkunrin tí wọn n pe ni Osaprapra naa darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ APC pẹlu bi oun atawọn alatilẹyin rẹ ṣe ṣatilẹyin fun Gomina Akeredolu, to si kẹyin si Agboọla Ajayi to jẹ oludije ti ọga rẹ atijọ fa kalẹ ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu Zenith Labour Party."},{"question":"الكوكب الذي يبعد عن الشمس 778,4مليون كم هو كوكب..؟","answer":"المشتري"},{"question":"Question: వెలిగంటిపాలెం గ్రామ Hint: వెలిగంటిపాలెం ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రం, శ్రీ పొట్టి శ్రీరాములు నెల్లూరు జిల్లా, పొదలకూరు మండలంలోని గ్రామం. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన పొదలకూరు నుండి 15 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన నెల్లూరు నుండి 45 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 115 ఇళ్లతో, 419 జనాభాతో 384 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 220, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 199. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 3 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 128. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 592048[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 524309.విద్యా సౌకర్యాలుగ్రామంలో ప్రభుత్వ ప్రాథమిక పాఠశాల ఒకటి ఉంది. సమీప బాలబడి, ప్రాథమికోన్నత పాఠశాల తాటిపర్తిలోను,  మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల నవూరులోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప జూనియర్ కళాశాల, ప్రభుత్వ ఆర్ట్స్ / సైన్స్ డిగ్రీ కళాశాల పొదలకూరులోను, ఇంజనీరింగ్ కళాశాల నెల్లూరులోనూ ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వైద్య కళాశాల, మేనేజిమెంటు కళాశాల, పాలీటెక్నిక్ నెల్లూరులో ఉన్నాయి. సమీప వృత్తి విద్యా శిక్షణ పాఠశాల పొదలకూరులోను, అనియత విద్యా కేంద్రం, దివ్యాంగుల ప్రత్యేక పాఠశాల‌లు నెల్లూరులోనూ ఉన్నాయి. వైద్య సౌకర్యంప్రభుత్వ వైద్య సౌకర్యంఒక సంచార వైద్య శాలలో డాక్టర్లు లేరు. ముగ్గురు పారామెడికల్ సిబ్బంది ఉన్నారు. ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, ప్రాథమిక ఆరోగ్య ఉప కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. పశు వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 5 నుండి 10 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. సమీప సామాజిక ఆరోగ్య కేంద్రం, మాతా శిశు సంరక్షణ కేంద్రం, టి. బి వైద్యశాల గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. అలోపతి ఆసుపత్రి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయ ఔషధ ఆసుపత్రి, డిస్పెన్సరీ, కుటుంబ సంక్షేమ కేంద్రం గ్రామం నుండి 10 కి.మీ. కంటే ఎక్కువ దూరంలో ఉన్నాయి. తాగు నీరుగ్రామంలో కుళాయిల ద్వారా శుద్ధి చేయని నీరు సరఫరా అవుతోంది. బావుల నీరు కూడా అందుబాటులో ఉంది. గ్రామంలో ఏడాది పొడుగునా చేతిపంపుల ద్వారా నీరు అందుతుంది. పారిశుధ్యంగ్రామంలో మురుగునీటి పారుదల వ్యవస్థ లేదు. మురుగునీటిని శుద్ధి ప్లాంట్‌లోకి పంపిస్తున్నారు. గ్రామంలో సంపూర్ణ పారిశుధ్య పథకం అమలవుతోంది. సామాజిక మరుగుదొడ్డి సౌకర్యం లేదు. ఇంటింటికీ తిరిగి వ్యర్థాలను సేకరించే వ్యవస్థ లేదు. సామాజిక బయోగ్యాస్ ఉత్పాదక వ్యవస్థ లేదు. చెత్తను వీధుల పక్కనే పారబోస్తారు. సమాచార, రవాణా సౌకర్యాలుసబ్ పోస్టాఫీసు సౌకర్యం గ్రామానికి 5 కి.మీ. లోపు దూరంలో ఉంది.","answer":"None"},{"question":"ය​ම් මූලද්‍රව්‍යක හෝ සංයෝගයක අණුක සූත්‍රය දන්නේ න​ම් එහි සාපේක්​ෂ අණුක ස්කන්ධය ගණනය කළ හැකි ද?","answer":"ඔව්. මූලද්‍රව්‍යක හෝ සංයෝගයක අණුක සූත්‍රය දන්නේ න​ම් එහි සාපේක්​ෂ අණුක ස්කන්ධය ගණනය කළ හැකි ය.මන්ද මූලද්‍රව්‍යක හෝ සංයෝගයක සාපේක්​ෂ අණුක ස්කන්ධය වන්​නේ එහි අඩංගු පරමාණුවල සාපේක්​ෂ පරමාණුක ස්කන්ධයන්ගේ වීජී​ය ඓක්‍යය වන බැවිනි."},{"question":"Quem descobriu o rádio?","answer":"O rádio foi descoberto por Marie Curie e seu marido Pierre em 1898. O rádio é um Elemento Químico com o símbolo Ra, pertencente à Família dos Metais Alcalino-terrosos da Classificação Periódica dos Elementos. É um metal altamente radioativo, que deu origem à palavra \\"radioatividade.\\" "},{"question":"👨‍⚕️ Кыргызстандагы белгилүү хирург Мамбет Мамакеевтин сыйлыктары кайсылар?","answer":"Көптөгөн мамлекеттик сыйлык жана наамдардын ээси. 2004-жылы \\"Кыргыз Республикасынын Баатыры\\" наамы ыйгарылган. СССРдин Жогорку Кеңешинин 4-чакырылышынын, КРдин Жогорку Кеңешинин 2-чакырылышынын депутаты. КРдин Хирургиялык коомдор ассоциациясынын президенти."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Ucrânia?","answer":"A capital da Ucrânia é Kiev (ou Kyiv em ucraniano), pronunciada como \\"kiev.\\" Kiev é a maior cidade da Ucrânia e seu centro político, econômico e cultural. É uma cidade histórica que desempenhou um papel significativo na história da Europa Oriental."},{"question":"السؤال: ما معنى لا إله إلا الله؟","answer":"الإجابة: نفي استحقاق العبادة لغير الله تعالى، وإثباتها لله وحده."},{"question":"2023 yılı konut kira gelir vergisi muafiyeti ne kadar?","answer":"2. Kira geliri istisna tutarı323 seri no.lu Gelir Vergisi Genel Tebliğinde yapılan açıklamaya göre, 2023 yılında elde edilecek konut kira gelirlerinin 21.000 lirası gelir vergisinden müstesnadır."},{"question":"Duba wurin da ke ƙasa sannan ka amsa tambayar daga baya a cikin harshe ɗaya kamar yadda wurin yake:  Labari: Musulunci shine mafi yawan addinin da aka yi. Majiyoyin hukuma sun kiyasta cewa kashi 87,6 na yawan jama'a Musulmai ne. Littafin CIA na Duniya ya kiyasta kashi 85%. Kusan dukkanin musulmai Sunni ne; akwai 'yan Shia a kasar (kimanin dubu). Hakanan akwai wasu Musulman Ahmadiyya, kodayake kasar ba ta yarda da su ba. A cewar SARA, a watan Mayun 2007 akwai masallatai 1,650, wanda aka yi rajista 1,623. Akwai kuma cibiyoyi bakwai don koyarwar Musulunci mafi girma.  Tambaya: Wane addini ne ya fi kowace addini yawan mabiya?","answer":"Bisa ga labarin snsar zai zama Musulunci."},{"question":"දකුණු අප්‍රිකාවේ මානව සංවර්ධන දර්ශකය (HDI) ශ්‍රේණිගත කිරීම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"2021 වන විට මානව සංවර්ධන දර්ශකයේ (HDI) දකුණු අප්‍රිකාව 109 වැනි ස්ථානයේ සිටී."},{"question":"\\"Ny piramidan'i Ejipta dia tsangambato famantarana ny Ntaolo. Naorina an'arivony taona lasa izay izy ireo ary manohy manitikitika ny mpikaroka sy ny mpanao dia lavitra eran'izao tontolo izao. \\"Manomeza fanontaniana iray izay hita ao amin'ny lahatsoratra ny valiny.","answer":"Firy taona izay no nananganana ny piramidan’i Ejipta?"}]`),M={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:x},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:I,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},B={class:"search-container"},C={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],D={key:0},P={key:1};function K(e,a,u,g,t,r){const k=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",B,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=s=>t.searchQuery=s),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[c,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",C,[(i(!0),o(w,null,p(r.filteredPoems,(s,m)=>(i(),f(k,{key:m,poem:s},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),r.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...s)=>r.loadMore&&r.loadMore(...s))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",P,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",D,"See more"))],8,O)):j("",!0)])}const L=d(M,[["render",K],["__scopeId","data-v-fe253181"]]),W=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"people/5.md","filePath":"people/5.md"}'),E={name:"people/5.md"},R=Object.assign(E,{setup(e){return(a,u)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(L)]))}});export{W as __pageData,R as default};
